[
	{
		"unique_id": "010101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rz5/oIuUwr7yvO/MWLUQ20Et2yKVqZmYzHiR7TLaeO+3ZgxM1SMzV515n/UpuX+9kcGgKYXqYCefSsNectm3JCI0fDy1jFVO8MEjIVg/doNdeJF3n25fNXPYPhn3H2UZ0fiaCy6DGQ0gDnThzxfppe0tSS0Ws42wwFygY5s5Yg1KMTf0Kab6U+xkgeMyGjOCiHc0wIgSMze84m7Xh0FLkA=", 
		"answer": "252xZpXmwg3r+cdQrcxVJfpHstIT8gR+eFru", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liehf8wcG9dWTCQ15Ti3aNVrZIMjHsRq7FZ+P/3ZJiZ1qbglY75n7D45bx+UAEnaFPqZqaYi9DQslcwd6N3/HLhjF1O9NX1sBm7J9fcPVOyH26dcebI/Z8x32UIkv1Y3mBRlh9mjXDmWhXpr/5tS61FM4/xVUgk4Z04Nt8M9Hf6a2B+0S5iEaD0n/Raa9lE12a9cKp5USJoYU9po94R3ZJQjyLyUG1my7IEJmr", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Aryavarta", 
		"option_b": "Hindustan", 
		"option_c": "Bharatavarsha", 
		"option_d": "Sindhu", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRHj5JEvQBfxxPG/OGTeAnASqzPDW600ZHnmFKLQb63xz9dlL1nJmVNy4HKGoKD+40Ydluh5ysLffSMEcIJpwdWNl+z+1zFFPMtNlIl96toLc7RFwj6iecTaM+0u2maFZ0D+czCvAWRt1D7QylVYrIq6uWe5VcglyRs11pNw6Ig6KcWL0a2A/A2riROW1H6DRv12FFWavcu7tAHDHf7sIf6c0xu9dkR5IVgK", 
		"answer": "25SrYJ740Fvy5z7da3XrRxoMu0yRACAp", 
		"explanation": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgRhb71/m/Nm7eF3cDuj+hce80UWLrW6zDKf6+zZh8LlKAglU7927Woqv08ldPm6cb7ICcfy8Tf5h8iN2GxPC3y3cBGshAk4E+pI0WaPwAxTO+d8bSMOpnwWCTZ0H5dCq4CXl6lSXTjjxCoJG04CCzW88jgAE6k8dr+Mo/M9mL0KaW5ln6h2g/aD8FShwpKlCGMMmwHg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Samudragupta", 
		"option_b": "Pulakeshin", 
		"option_c": "Ashoka", 
		"option_d": "Harshavardhana", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0An68oksUwr7yvO/NmPREWMSt3qRW7lxYzH3XKKCYOLs3Z90NVLJjFV/snXDrbHi9l9PirBL6ICMdWIMeMtGxtSA1qi312FAPchNlIcy4ogQcbRUxDjtZ8HVMvd9yy6TL0riYir9EH80gDnTym9DppC+4We4W9sk1AZt1OqTBEkFvmt3zxxmfNujnf8=", 
		"answer": "25SqcZDl0Av+9sfAAEeu1XU89OZg9q/7teCj", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7licwzrxOv+J3/RPyBRp3qQW6R6cWXmR+fWZui+x5hjM1SMn1U783jC46b1+UcdjqQb+4uecyoGbctgzpCg2eD+xT0BPNRNnYl85Y4WcvMAzS7tdZTJJfhr3GuOJECwczb9EHhx1DnZh3laqY2/tSi9FM4/xVUThJ5549t+ua7A36iWYHWXK86ItbVIEw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bharatavarsha", 
		"option_b": "Aryavarta", 
		"option_c": "Sindhu", 
		"option_d": "Hindustan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXj+YI1Ww3mzP6/MHPAEWcCsHaMXONwdWLqU6nDeujtiZYxNFSIn15/snrHraLl9lQKz7xT6JrfeCcPest839GQl+XkhGVJNoZHlY1/65RfcfFExSigNNvdYP1hw2OVKUzzZi20C340gDnEhWlRoIyu4We2W8kjgBo01q526cE9fNOKy6Gd7w2sjgPCyHOYWrkkElGXodu68gO+g916uFpLQjiPFIgFCaAIInrrBw==", 
		"answer": "24WqaZrh2A2oOgYE+m3qqcuGA7F7lSJ3Sw==", 
		"explanation": "24WqaZrh2A2q8ZAuUQr7yvP6MSvRECIFq3rDXqp6d2TiFKHQb+P9yNdwJE6Gnkg78zbVqqL+/lUGjKlV/c6PfzAXd4RhiN+Pl835wHhAc8JRiIl849oLdPEA2DWkZtCbI/tg2nuSPgXSRHX9BWM0kSffjnlYq4a/tSWiFNM50xYgn5ds5McyL5ebzLqa5kr4pxWK03CQD64kA1GQssDq3toKEhpfCWmQqgwAD2Sm2w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Sanskrit", 
		"option_b": "Tamil", 
		"option_c": "Prakrit", 
		"option_d": "Pali", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010105", 
		"question": "24G3KIb70A2q8IAvVQzz1fX2NivVG3YUrWvDVqpwMGXrUefWa//ziaszBFSIhkl65HfUt6zMtRMfirpP6IeRPGIAdop9ydOd0vb+3nhPNIZQkoUy4JUSdfpJwzPtZ9vOJ/Z6jmyZZ0b1dS28DX40nzjYjW8J6mbiDi8dCrZG24WyUh8eYB8=", 
		"answer": "25OqZ5yzxRHvt60pXx/+xOT+JivEDCIyom+GEoB7fX7xXamAZPbzIMaj9FeWEbWbPVhdcg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn2A3m8sUcED36xPbtNH3REXYYnz3DRaJnMHLsWqHHfP/7zddkN1OHzVZ0/HfUoK3jt0QHgOha+p6WYicHPp9giNGcw+z41nhVKoZXjpJ38JkXdfpHjDu/e9mbNPZrjkaJKkT8ZiC8FzBgm3HCgnkWvIqrtSi9FPk20BBytYh14to1MpUE3rdmXQbBsnWnnHzh1jQc", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "From the Himalayas to the Ganges", 
		"option_b": "From the Ganga to the borders of the Tamil land", 
		"option_c": "From the Himalayas to Cape Comorin", 
		"option_d": "From the valley of the Brahmaputra to the land beyond the Indus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010106", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vwz/1r32OyvzDG4ErnHDc+NjeWXrFLPKa+TsiZR+NU6Mjk879nPVoLf550cGgKZIqYeRMAEMcp5ixpCrlcq7iOpGjn+tMRlRlqBBp0M=", 
		"answer": "25SqcZDl0Av+9sgMUxD2he7rJ27EAGoYrXjDVLF7fTH3XKKCRuTzyJtwPl2azU90smLOpuXj8lJDz4BS54qKYzYCcMZfx9yAw+30xX0BJshNjpky5ZkXdfFWyTntds2bAe1mwWWBZ0z+JzizB3lxmiWWo3JSoYL3tRG6RtQ2jzYzhZN9rdslL8Oa1OWg506xhwrCz2KCXLhpUV2Xs8K97k2fqYw/9cibtDyb1/zrk+vH+d8FaxxL/4dxZxuVhKQI9WZ4csC1YwBK5+XCdV3+bRisKwcJ8Mji2jR8yIs9RCk19xdPh5VTZoBxz9jFrzo/NMwqHD36okpDzpFyS1e/ermx0Sri8qP8Hy1lkWzzEp00DDQj", 
		"explanation": "25SqcZDl0Av+9sVodleyzO6/IWPVQ2wQrnrDVapidX+jQKiCYOLs3Z90NVLJjFV/snXDrbHi9l9PpqZf4I/fdToXe4Vrwd6Ol+Lly3wBJ85B2oVz944abvoA2DLtYNzeYOlr3XqFNUuwdDy8RHN7lSLCmTxqpquy+yOuR842zlV6tc445Nt8ONKN0L6W7A2+lAmPnG+ZTf1UFEaKvM+mq0KSpMIZp8yPuDGb+PX3ne3S99sYIglcu8ZoYkj8g6AMuCQ5XM30bxtd9OqQdVutNCCmZz0U98/rlnV7w4NpXmY65QpDkIZSIsJqlrH2vTw5PsMqBya2plZT+5pIVxLWQryq3mmrw1QsYX9rdpN+qCg44Ue9YRRtn3mKSSgRlZMr6tgc1Qhqc2hVnTbmkD6Fg2TPfZDx5JPvxeX/s60j/aVnAE+EPF2YX4NccbvFZ3N6w/ufTaVZPYtyBTumH/Zu3zH4K4SVyTgfxNAzbz/FvWqOl9/weXevv5frnZRhHLBAN9jI7M/3pFOHZDD1IH+fb9j8GRz4SnXqkw9woxAq2igE8SLXHoxttTsMjWrwXUF2gC70Y26ok60QqoONd4c0xfzi2nIAl/hxi5L01RF8UgqymWYBWvVWbTk3eVuLsnjHNz31AQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Aryavarta,Land stretching from the Himalayas to the sea", 
		"option_b": "Hindustan,Political unity achieved by Ashoka in ancient India", 
		"option_c": "Varna/Caste system,Social system influencing even Christianity and Islam", 
		"option_d": "Chakravartis,Political unity achieved by Ashoka in ancient India", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010107", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUoWw3myu/2NmrcQ3IUsXaMVrA0eX+jd6jOe+DwibYxMFWdhRtv+nOGoKri5VYcn6dV7YeRd2IGaI5h3MPJ2Pa3wHRXNspLio136o4MPP1OjB6ieMHWLr5MjAbGrU83Q5X4q8urmRDcswY=", 
		"answer": "24GwYYP3kRrv+ZE1QAeyjd/cfCudQ0MCq3CIU+RnMHTuRK7Qa63x35JjZ3WHiVJ6sj7Du6b150dPm6BeqYuHZDAGc44v29+cw+y+iDFnPNNWjogy558RaOFS1X3lVfCSYLMu/GeTIgX/YXmpDHU0gjDEhH0Zq4Ko4SL7R8Mk1BA/1o52rcYzLsOXmYGd7ES5ykak1X2FQM53GEyNvY6r7k2ItZAxsN7N+RD4vbS02t3A5N8JbgFBt4t6bU/8mK5J7C8qQ8GgZwBC8OiQaFDoLjyqMxdd8MWj/3ptz4NlHVox4hpIlosWYcV9wo32pXJ9f+5lGyKvpldUh5t6HwOecf2M0WXt7BUzdHQvJYh0/B40rBqYOlV5j3uITW6LPnx1UxlgH17gzcNQaKgu", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYP3kRrv+ZE1QAey596/eCaYJytRqmzDU7Bnf3LqVbPHaq3pwIN5Z32ahVRw8zHV46Do41YBnKFU586QdmILd5gvzd2Z3vbyhH5XNtQEjoh3pI0Xc/hFjDKrNP3VJPdvjmuYJEDgc3mpDHU0kSnCmHlbrcOo+jKvXOY5gDM9g5Vs5Yg/OdmLzLqKqGycxkvPlFrYCL5rA0acpt6n5UeP4JY39dmFtHLL8ebwlfyT59YObEhhvotqZ0m9kL0Z7Ct4UsmmehtO9aTYaEetNiGgMwEP8MT2xTRo1I86HW8m+xIGlotTIudy2J/l/CY/f9liEHO4rFZEwoZvHxiQNKmw1SjQ4Vg2eTonZIRpgCMTqAmIICdtk3OIRGxSkY5/68IQkBcjX0wA0TuooXbLjWSdd9P344W8ge3mpbVs4q4iJ1XAOlqYQogOd7rUKHV7y+XbBKJZPYtuAzumNNtu1Tf9KZfU4zc+1c8lIWPvtCmcnNngK3z6/t+xrJ02HaxAN8LW5si+sUjCZWP2KGmbJt/8XEjTR330xgV8tlguwS8XpCLoHYV+/igelne+BQRglyHlbWiomLkcwoOcbIYwxfT+2ToRlvU4iJP4lAo9VES4gnFQu4CaXVlLjUDeG40LyxsqTLsHVILZ9y2BnXncTjwCeY74DrqTy2xh1Of4jyNwzC5viXozTW1d/gN+A5D6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Third century (BC),Ashoka's empire over India (except the extreme south)", 
		"option_b": "Fourth century (AD),Rise of the varna/caste system in north India", 
		"option_c": "Fifthâ€“sixth centuries (BC),Establishment of territorial identity in India", 
		"option_d": "Seventh century,Conquest of the Tamil land by Samudragupta", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010108", 
		"question": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Ejf8wfT+OyvTFm4Ftm2GEqd9Y2HvVb7Haq3/iYV0Kl2bhlp5/nOGnJrPyGwwsJdk1rHffyRDfZ5j3MWb1ui3wX1EPsNKjpMy4ogQcbRWzS+ke8HIYPpn3GuDM0z/aSrxRGJxhyTannVYr8Oy+2e6FMg+wx1ygoZo6NsoLs7f1q7T4UO+ihOH0niUW/+BrT42AEzQUwpCDV1TyUow", 
		"answer": "25a3Zof2wx7v+YYlEEkOGebZzmPhjmvU1a/R3nA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHPkxrl+ogpXBn+zPP4dWTWQ2EEr2uWQKJ4MHTvUarHYPnthaszZ0uBhFhzsn/Ls6n58kBPjuhY5oCJdTAEe4VszZCGxaT1yHRPN89KncB94tobdfJGyS+oesCbI+ti2nuSJkmwbje7CGVxmjLTmT73Fgoi5iBnBtd8hzTG/fIj", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Co,nv,er,ge,nce,nee", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010109", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSHNhf7qOX/FEWdRrHnDRqtxMH/sRrPKLuTtiZR+KlGGg1disnfVsKrz/lIbiqwb/oeLeGIXdo4v/tWN3ue3xX9Fc/ZRiIF87ZlfaOZByDS5fdvVM7wbgOGMP167FSYQ63KBKbOF", 
		"answer": "24WqbdzSwwDr+ccVmZ8/U6hR5ZnMGYRkMZmg", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwwDr+cUlXhv/wPPrJivRECITpnaNVeN1Y2LsV67Deuj6iYB4M1TJmVN+skDDp6zzt1IBi+hr/JyefisAPoh6xMScxeG3y3cBJ85B2o599o4XMLRBwjntZMbebd9812+OZ0D8YjS4CmRn1CbfnnQWjJG64y6/Xds5gBQ8ksdM7MU1MJeczKSH/V+9xgmEnG+ZTf13HkGNvYwgGoZtr7MEv02fg7sN/wnF", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pr,e-,Ar,ya,n", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010110", 
		"question": "25i5Zoiz3xbkurYhXA351/TrPGiQF2cDrmzDVKxhfnWjXamCWOj6wJQxM1mRmUg7+3jCqqbx41ZPjKdV54ucZCsMcJgv39md36TnwX9IPdVRloFgpJsReLROwzPgQtHfKf0u3GuHLkr+dHmyAjBdmjXfizAWvIuu5mepUdw7xRYmn4l/rdw0OZeg5pes13KHuTm94zueTv1nBFiNoNyp5wOVroQ0oMiDsjfItjh74qc1l5Jz9LOu+SdS2LY=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5j+2BXr44wvXFwyPbAJwcsBpUWbGriVdgLW", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w73xOmWdMGMfsHSRW7d9czH3UbXPfa33x9dHIliAjhtv927SsOX5+VcGjKlP7J3fcSxDf5h8wd2A2+XjzX5Pc8lW2o139p0WcvMAwzvtd8HXNOt8z2LALkv2ayy4CnNxh3HQmHNb6Iey8yG+Rt851FUgk4Bx4sYvfhVGtJxY6OTMkzK4+BGL1Nk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "As,si,mi,la,ti,on", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010111", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7licRbzzu/+I2rCF2st4T+UU7A0YnTwUbXUa+m+z5hjZ1eAg1xosmHOrOXj+EYIh7wb/YHfdToXe4VriMSB0u3lhHBUJ85LiIlm/doZbvtNjCmlcZTkH8FR8VG/GHrPWAaCO09Lqw7ptTAWrY24+iqrVckkyRs11oNx+80uL9Lfy62U4UK2lUQT5W6FHFjxDYgeqB5SbsSC", 
		"answer": "252xZZD/0ADr5MU0XV7RxO36dUjfDm0DqnHB1jlLZHQytzm9mVMwjly3+A==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJD90hDv+ZFgexD2zPzxdXvfD2sFqnyCXuNgeH72U6/WIq3qwZIxM1mbgBtHsFXOoq7i9kUOnbxS1czfOC8Gf4VmxtfJ66biynhXNtRXm4wy9o8TeeZ8jn2iZpTnYulmy2uMalHldTe0Cnc0mT7Yi25VoL/5vGesVcl31QY3ksds4og4OcScy6GR7Q25xg2L0nzRX7VrUVWKpce67kfctI14ut/NsDHT/fHvn/yT9NEGawZTsYV6I1SqkrpJ7CI9Ec26fBtZ9KT5b1DkISbjNBsf+sTtwn1nw4w9ESkn5B5IjIpYZYB1xJfp/CY4Oo1CHD67r0VZxoc8VhnWYLW9kGbr8kE3NW4kJalsrCh1ggCRJ0Z3lCvUQSNVkZJls9QYjERIfGFZnX31jz6ZiSzPdZ2j/4j5xfv/ta1rvOMTIUTANlPWVYgMcfPPISdRwuiQH6dKMo1zHmLxPMZu/jjqJZLU0DdNxNElb37j8SuV0sLzeWT6oYf1i8YxB/8EOdzM58K4vhzIdybzYWmbY4vyVh3iD3/5wQpsuRkpiCUZ+mfbHIBw+z5B3m2pREZrni76aXjhlKcc/oqLP5w4x+Dt0XIRm+A4kJ23wAguSQ21ij9C8pOXSllDjRzVFswM1ghnQvaw3fHidNdN8CFFZr3cfjO1", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Eastern coast to the Western coast", 
		"option_b": "Himalayas to Cape Comorin", 
		"option_c": "Deccan plateau to the Northern plains", 
		"option_d": "Indus valley to the Brahmaputra valley", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010112", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSHNhen6J2bDQ3YZomvDV65xYnbmUOfLYK3qwZIxDlKNghZa4G/HreX89l0Imqlc7J3fZycRe8tmxtaFwuH5x3RFc8hLjsB96pYGPPZZjCmlcZT2NfBqzy6DMknkciu4RHJhgHHXhm9Z6IGitQOpVcw+xBwzmMdx484wKdKR2q2ApA29nhaO3XKfQbNjUUeRvMi8+AOVrsIovcKDtCbS9+e5m/bXsMgEYQlQqop+cUL+y/QIT3pkokj5YiOsRAlfyg==", 
		"answer": "25e3eoP8xhzutd5KTsF9M+p6G3/EBtzkZS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avn5MUpXF7by/nweErCGmMf43OCXKRhcXbmR+fVa//7iZ5/IVCciFV493KGobyw9Vwbh+h2/ICbcWICcI8v7MKIwe3zzXBPc8VRlpRn9p8MMLRMyTypfdrcYOphjm2IJkv3Yir9DX40hDnZhHlCoYCotSa1UJohzxYzlJJ07Nolfioo2X3fY82KB9dZuOVXLjA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bo,rr,ow,ed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010113", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUhXB37wPPrdWjFD3YEsXqQErR9ZHmjQK/HZ/++yIRiKF+AjE9+9jbBpqr35VIfh6FY6ILfYicEd4Rh25CI2eC3x35PJ9RNmJVm7ZURb7aqhPhwmhdXbIZkObIxmalk", 
		"answer": "25SqcZD9kTr/+5E1QBuyiL3ROnnEC2cDrT+CXKc0U3TtQLXDYq3Xx5N4JhDJqUl65H/CqqT+t3Aag7xO+4vfPWIwcZ57wJCg2eD+xT0BHtNKnoEyx48TaOFSyX3gNPHaM+pr3GDAFUD3bjazSDBEhjSbq25PqY371jK3QM8lxVV/1rd948EyL8KT2LrT6UO8xiiN0janTbltEhSwu8qh6gG2Rx9qWSIOUWRlpKSzjdPx", 
		"explanation": "25SqcZD9kTr/+5E1QBuohdzsJmTTCmMFpnvDRapgeDH3XKKCWOj6wJQxJlKNzWtu4HfIqqaw40EOi6FP4IGRY25DbplmxdGb3ujuhHhPNcpRn45x7ZQYPOBIyX2je8bPKPt8wC6BKUGwZDyzEGJ1mHHEj3tfp42otSi9FPM5xBwzqolc/8kqNdOW2KbTy1i0khOQ2SHRZLRqGlGd9dqnq1eUpcIcp8ybuDbS9fq5m/bXsOoKbwFe/4Vqb0+pha1J9yx4RcCxKAFE5PDYLRTgISGtKxdd8Mbz13d9z4wuHVo74QtOwqpYZsly6pbJqTw0Po1JAD+utlZFndRTTR6RfbO5xGHq5xU5Z3UmJZ5luW0woByILUZw2nmZSyVemswr/d8XgRZqf3pUlXjnwiuEwHGKbp7wq4Hygaj5rr9v56YpKkSTdVXWFpkUZKeAJnV3y9WVPbRZfr51DiPoffY78C3sMpPOnwsIwMslPHLp4COXlY3hMWD6sIf1msFkEaxAJsPA6s6zuVLAIQLzOHydJsb9XhrxW3X33R0p9xk22y4T4WPMDY0/4iQZlj6gTEptnDT1YH2z1r9S7sKAcIB85fDo1DFQmeZ9noi32xt8bgq/hH4Bo6JMXCiwGcodYSXkbDE1EA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Aryan Culture,Northern and Central India", 
		"option_b": "Dravidian Culture,South India", 
		"option_c": "Munda Culture,Eastern Region", 
		"option_d": "Pre-Aryan Culture,Peninsular and Non-Vedic India", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010114", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqyzvTxMivUBmQUomuGVuNccWPwXKbUb//6wZZ/JhDJhlV05XiGoraw41sKz6RU+4rffyRDaoNqiMeB2OjyhH5Hc8hLiJR6pLMReP1BgH2kepTPKPsu3WuWIkvkb3m+AX5ggSPPyLV4J3F0SHW23WMF9TZ3Y+k=", 
		"answer": "24WtZJD41Ari/otiLXvcFkPzrxJ6oCwgfVOe7Q==", 
		"explanation": "24WtZJD41Ari/otgVhv0wPzrMG+QK2MDsHeCRKJmdHniWqaOLujt3ZZzK1WahVJ19TbOqraw9kYbh6dJ4JqGMC0Ve5kvxt+bw+y37X9FOscG10yS4SqPA26QY/VLny7b0g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Samudragupta", 
		"option_b": "Pulakeshin", 
		"option_c": "Ashoka", 
		"option_d": "Chandragupta Maurya", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010115", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liehf8wejDdyvfEWsWqnGCXq9tMGPmUqLQfOj6iYN+fR77ZrsjDXf5AsqgcMlgodGe", 
		"answer": "25T4b5T81gvr540pUR/+hejxPH+SyLhixq7jeF7Kk7bUskEIWg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liehf8wejDdyvZDWsFqn6PXro0YnTlUbXQa+m+3ZgxJhyOiFR84HfWq6zz9l9PmqZS/cLfdCcRd51qzJCPxev6hGVJNoZ3m45h74gWaLRUyS+gNOiZE/dgymaVZTiDn9j0KzVQrNaKT0TGJ08=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A religious community", 
		"option_b": "A cultural group", 
		"option_c": "A geographical unit", 
		"option_d": "A linguistic group", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010116", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5IoWx36he7rNH/VDmcft2zDQKZzcWPnXanFLvn2zNdyMlCdmEl6/jbPraP84lYBjK1IqYGRMCMNfYJqxsTJ/urzzXABOtUEmY9g9p8caK58wgGjJZqbFv98x2GVNAX1czGzDXM0kyPZn2xF6JCu9i/7Vcl30Ac326Zq9MkyL5vf8KaX5wCZlB+D0mjdCJp2FFGSpoLo2ECFtIoxtMOe/XLz4fr4ibSTxMsZaRse/4NrYBf8lKcH7DgxU92gbRYL5euQSFrpKSnkNE4O9sjq13gp1Zs6SWw5uF9HkJcaIsxy2J/xvTU1c41rGzf6r01UwoZ9SwKEcYG2kFTqsht/VHQobI9jqG0crwuVKVo+mX6QWDlDkcB49t8OkAAjfC9CkHPuhjaFhyWAetPm54XxgObks/ll4KwqaUWJM1rdRIgScfPHImh12OiLBa9fMpMnEyv0ONY69Tb3M8zU0TYfxNFgLnnjtDmWh9n9dSW/soHtztV4EP8XM8LRqfe5jFKULxfpJD2lY8/9WkjxQXi44xt3thYsy2ET/W7MHZt6tSIL3mq4TARqnTX0ZDyohf5Z+5ePa4s1k+LlyTpQueZhnpW30RE5SgG1mWwP8pOXRlBKjXDEH9sOwAAvAvQAGpKRxmybnHqQSGkBa9vkBOiIxWxc0uaxnW5oq5hOXJ/OLQrIhd0vyQO0Bb1uXHPl6JbrOLE0GH0t9PJ0xuisssSvZrFWRo4PdO/gEMwOZEC09EfN", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqylL32JivEEXcU7z+BR7c0eWWkR+fMYfm+wJlyK0mNiF87+3iGt631t1wfm6FU553fQzYCao5izd6dxKSlhHBPN4YX2oFg4dodc+BIjCm/YdGZYpgNsQZTZ6kKcghAsSy6/w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010117", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5IoWx36he7rNH/VDmcft2zDQKZzcWPnXanFLvn2zNd/JlGAg1w783jC46L1+FQdjrhT4I2efGIWcIJ70ZCG0aT2ynJINshQ2ql84JMePP1TjD6iZsbeI+o0jlKOG0uhKQ21ATBgkSPbykAUgIq18TKHFpo40hw1n4l5+c04fNGN1qXT/EW9xjWD0miaWrRwUUCcp8Po1wGvqYw8vdix83La+vC5iP3V9cwZZwwSq4k/Yhu4nrsd6iM7RYi7ZlJf+eGQSFrpNTvjLgBd0Nni2H1oyMIgU3o35hZWlopZbNMz6pbYsmB+C8VvVSe/sUkA+9ZdTQ6XYryqxGnYohU7cHQkcY9p/CM6sxuULUZw2mqSSGxSkY5/7NEV1S1teWZB3Hfuhn+OmHGKcpfm78D6l+f94K1r9+MiKFKUME7WFpkTJafIIidlz/qPCLRSc4xiFmLlMtQ96Cq5HJio0WpDkO0oKjfy+iONi436PyWTvZbwj5RhFaxAJsPM5MqluVDeITHkInKUaMLuXAywTWW4+gBhvhkriCIf5nPNDZtw5z5Nn3C0CUdxnjP1fn2t1rJZ64aLbZ19k/f5yXIWl+Z9lpz50Q8vBwCyiT9NvZDfX1ldzlHfCMhHzR1uDadBFdbC+2ORmXOQTHkCeNz3EaCOwC1Emvb/h3U/0aLnl8ysH7Vh96M+vmqwsQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhentIG6cQ2MC42uLV+NgdWPuFJuARuTwzYJNZRyAnht/92TPtaD0t1UdgKUb1cyseSwHdp5TipCI2eC3xWFRNsdWicB76to2bvVOxTyjNN3VM/18x36ULkr+dHmOEHFgkTzThGgW+sOy5me6WMk4gAEgg4I0rckvfOvd+LqK6Vu5lBKD4DnRQbNgFFGd9dyt7UaOsoc89dmC8TOb5+T8mfHV+d1LcA1VtolxI1Ky16YG6j4wVNq6KBNF9aTTZFr5MimvZycT/cLilkd9x5YsUGw64F8VwopFIs58wtjhsiY5LchmDHO7oEdV1ZVoWkzWcrKq1WHj7lAtZjovbI4trig2rgiSIU572n+USWxEmol/55AWk0RKc2tJnTqggyzLlG2KZdPt6o35gajkqLwj8awyJ1WSLBzaV54ZYfPPKSdmwuzbJKhYJownBSvwOMdutAW7CJ+a2wVPkNAub0fi5jmQk8O1OGu+87Prj9Z/F/ZCJowsV7+Te+xtcyyoiyzXHA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1,2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010118", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5IoWx36he7rNH/VDmcft2zDQKZzcWPnXanFLuH3x5BkLk+dhFg783jC46bl+0canalXqZuReTYaPoJhiNGH1O3yymUBGshAk4Ey7Ylff/tS3jiuYI7nLsJgn0eOZ1H4YnmpDHlmkHHVj3JCvZGitQWYGJoEwRshnZVx+YgvOcWJ3KzT6V74kg6HnHeYRrpxEBSfp8+m6ELcoYEqut6e8SbT8bT0m/Lc4p4bYxpG/4l5I3Kyk6EIxCQEX5r0TAdZ+OrXIUDlJWiEMh4J+Ivz02ZgyYZpVGd04BdDwoVZd9Jn3tjnuTwkKt9zWXOKsUVL1Z1oHxWTd7y11Sjw6FB/Zm4qcY8tsCw7phqdL1E+k2XcWi1DnY9+7ZALkANqcmFT3HnmwhaFhGyOQJ3f5dO8seD14Lht8aoiJ1XAMEzRVZ5QJYHBKmZry+eaTadSN99KFirnP90v7jjtIdrUyDwf1ZkvPX7g/SSYnsHseWa1voL2ndFyVLAOOsiF4MX3g13JcijzKGnTZ8XwGR/1XXm43QFx9ww3yS8D5GPMDY0//CMZkT68RkdlnmfsbXKmg79b75HMxY9oC0h/StkQ/2XH6hwRdw==", 
		"answer": "2+T4Z5//yFtqIB4th9O9apMH4n7ZyUrT", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZd436QEpNmcXrxXbOCeeztiYJiIljJjEg78zbKqqv34lJPibpa542eMCsNPp9nzZCd3+3lwDFCNshQj5JrpLg8PNxP2zi7ccaXYO16z3qFKkD+c3nvRHln1DjYi39VvZG64SLgFOk2zgY5hI5soYgyM8Pf6bqS41+xkkrCz36DXrhgUVWK9dqg7gOPtIMssI2BsDzc4fX+n7jX5cwCbA8Sq456I3yph7wIuDo9Q8G7bFJ45eXEZFnoLjzjdE4U6ovt2WApx4EqSHs14BoGg5AWdcV/2tSkvSFwK8VvVQG7rkVZxpp9HxaYcP2V0WDl4l0+Z3s/ZMp6uT8w4QaSLFF7niufQyFBm5Nu+pAQm0RQfGFTl2TplnPLgnCbPIfr7pm8ku3ipfli/rAoaVWSNFLLWowIYLeAJml2iuifDLZINpsnHizyMpU4/SvwL4OHnzUC09gsb3vm+i2Mk8rwKiW1pZfrzsB/GbpCrjtj9uZAnuzNSnzH/1IUEQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 only", 
		"option_d": "2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010119", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5IoWx36he7rNH/VDmcft2zDU6F7ZWWjQK/HLvjwwINoZ12HiRt/+2DDsbb540pPhqYb6ICceScNastGxtSA1uq3zHhSJ8lWg8B799occ+ZSyT65SNrnLq8u72CDLkD+c3mUCnR9lT+WiWlavJap8GesXc45xQYhk4M4+cA5fNSQ3LCa+1m9iAWHnHSXCKtlA12WoN3o+UaQqYUxusOe/XLS+vf1j/za/tlLQBpTt4t+bVKvmugG6moQWMawfRtY/KiQS1XkLiGwKkJd+MXnllZ8woYhVHo5uF9RiopVaoB62IzhrjMzK8huVTK0pwRJyZJwShKYd7i8kG3l411/em4jYJhRshE780+oIFE+jm6OQWxt1qhi8NQMqUYjcn1Jm3/ugzOHmSWGcpfq6IHogOywoflx968uLkiPIE+YVYIRaKbOLnNriuCVTadSMJZiGTamFMcv8jD4Ltad0SoOwtAwO37o+jmlnPH7aiWOu5e5jdVlALpAJcjW/c668EjPYDehJXiFY8f7SQ30D3X2kyBqpQwtiAge7GvZSJpv5ygMmj6kQVZrhyDoY2m11qpU78KNcJs/x+f1nTMenLR7kJXj3RMpQgD7mXADu4qZQ0lKw1fTXt8CyAApBbsUB9bS/WCbgHjZX3UIbI76CKOCgw9AyOrimmh8sYNOVIKKbDTOmdIvxQTznO7rmFjtsGMvGe4lfUjyUA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhentIG6cQ2MC436NUapxfmWjfanGZ+y+3pZiZ1GIn1B+9jbEuuXk/1ZPjKde8YeMZCcNfY4vyd6Nl+350HRTMsVQk498pJUZPOJB3jSiYcebMvtix2mJKEvjJwqpBWRxmTTYnjwE6IqotSm0QJo0zwcgk4RsoYg9L5eW1+iS5k6xgwiWnFKDSbNtEFrZvMC76FGVsJYxusOe/XLP/PG5jv3B/Z43ICBbsYJqXxn8ha0P/TgqVMz0fB0L8KTEZEb/KTysNQcc9Yv22H19isInUn109V9Uh49fZcl8w4ukvz09MthkHCej43dUxoB5UhKYYP3rkGH3oFQzZnVrZIluqT80tQrQaFVt2n+USWxSlZN/+5AKjBd3eGIAmH/kwiybkmCOeNPi5YS8jOb2rKxm/KAiaVeBJ1XXQ55cd7bMLmB7xfyITaVTPpJyGSvyNNA9sHn8NpOanzsIydYuKzfP/SSdh8TmNCf2nYPR8+xQ3hi3sJrzkCfk", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010120", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t7IoWx36he7rNH/VDmcft2zDU6F7ZWWjRKjOZ/n3ypZ9Z0mHhE9isnfIp+X38lwInalL4YeccS5Dbo59y9WZw+34yjFONYZFlIN74ZQLPN1OyDSsNN3IYP1h3HyFJFGqWzeBCiE0oDnTyn9ZpoC+5TP7W9x36Rs2n4Y47Nt8PZeM0KaU5Ej4gQON22mQWLVtElWV9dum4lfcsIcqpsSepTfftPD8ieja5NtLdgBX/4p+YFD8mK5J6CU0WNy9axNHsfHeaED0bGiiNE4O/M7tln1nhpYhWCkm8RZBjJAWbcYz94vsszkxf8xkEXOJoklVw4Z9WAKGYLyE3lTqshULfX9rcY9/sW0J4yeVJlBriX+dQhAT1I9599cQmwV3eGsAmmTvj3+fiGDPT5Lt+IvujPywtLxx/+Mba3KJO1jQQ7FeJbLOIydly/rbDLZMP5ZiE2LyMpU69Dy5E5+a2zFNwtwnJnjptCiA0uTnOGuzspy5nMF6Ea0TCt/555j3hFTCITfkM3DTWonWUQniTmj5xQ93pBAk9GNQ/2PLSJlt/CAMjHe8UARxgSLkLHWv1qpU78K8dolx5fDo3HIEl7Rqmp3yxl0oSES0g3oDvYLfW1RKjVrfEMhHwAA4BacIG5jCsmKQ1WLYTjwIftziCeoN2yHE9eE5emkgXboGZDjy", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfz8Nn7CAnYU+D+HV7BkeWXmFLfNYuTqwJRwKxyNhE1y4X/Jrba8t0cHiuhS7YueMC0FPqJhzNmIl+XkhHABNMNLnZJz9JIWf/VMjCijfcCbMPt83WeTM0D0Jy21Fn9hkzmWnH1EoYyu5mepQdYy0gZypZN5+c0xOdmLmfrT4V74iAmWnH6fXLR2FFiA9c2n+VGZo5Zj9dqFuD7etMi7svHd9MsYdglcg8Q/Z1S5hOgB+Tw9EcemYRVC//eQc1HhITymI04J9ovflEdgyIYhSCUItl9PlsNBY9N9kYykvSIgM8RvEXO4ugRp1ZVyVhaYNK+t3G328xU9YG5rd4t5tCgn4Q2FaHlriWeVQT8RkJV5994e1RBreC9NmXLphymKjCWfeYHq5IS8tvzxtLxu960zaRLAPE+YQp8JYOiAGyVQwuiJDLJdJZ51BCrnAZdu6zjqYIOH2j1N2ddgO3/itBiQlY3DPGG7/9L7m8A2HatANNTG6May8FHIcyahNnSXY8ftGQP+QGv2kw929xll3CQC5SLeB5s/3CMJl3/wQEoknib0aW7hgrtE/pHMP20ypb5Eya/ekD0exj8opg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010121", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hen6J2aQPyAzq36RU7d1ZnDxR6/DUq++3pZiZ12ZnVdy93KGt6qw+F0Kz6ddqZqXdWINd4VqiNSAwe3kzX5PIIZLnMBm7J9fefVS2DWReujVEvtv3WGOfQXEbzz9EHVmmXHqyF5eqZG64SatVcgkyBQO1Mdx/ogxOdmL0Ked7Un4jwjCyHOUCI9tFhSvsMqppwOPqYU2vMuUuDzctPW5jv3B4tcfbRpbvoo/Z1KqnrsA9yR6T11HoVlJMNHODtOGWs1lIA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStzPDU7A0TDPBXKbQb/n/35ZjNFSIsRk75XfV46Tg518Giqwb/YHffywGPoRpiMSB0qTzzWdIIM9LlJMy65xfaPxFjDisZsDTYPdgjm+OJEz1aS39EHVsgCKWvnRT6JG+9DS0Wpo+01UzmpR3rcszLsWa2rzfqEyrxhKK2TuFTa9pUV2K9cOt5VeVr4w9sY2Ev3LP/PG5qPHUsOgOZgke/5F3ali017sA/yQxV8Gxe1JKsfDVc0bkNCexLg8Ruc/qwH16z40nHV088V9Uh4JFbc4z04D0sDM5Md4qAjuj41BIwtRoWgWbNIH68mDl8lQrdGwqd5llvRF34RidOxRriW6YDq+wrTHbAHfxpV4cMxIcAsk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010122", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf7wO2jVE3ZRrHnDe61weXCjVbSCb63twJl2K1nJil509WTHs6359FIDz71V4JrfYCcRbYJ83NWNl+Dy12FIJ8MEjoh3pJYef/8AwzvtZNvXKepnzW+MZ1D+bi2kOH5ImgPTi29Zptn7wyapXdUi01Ugg4t9/9t8MN6U3Oiy+0W3jQfC3XWVCI5lHEGdp8+v/lOIocIqoMGItXLU4vHr2vmT49cMbAFUtoV+bU/8h6kb7Go3V4igYBcL2OrUaFXjYDu2JQ0S99/q2HFn0sBeJIQyabdIDxT5jDFwFhgU", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NGjTFnAQt3rYErd8dTHgW6nBa/3qiZh3Z3WHiVJ6snfV46Sw8FYAiLpa+YaWcyMPPp5hwcTJx+Hl13hSJ8NA2oR394oWaPEA3DKhfcDSI/9ijmqJMUzjbjazFzBAnDSWmHlXu4y1tS6oFNs70xpygpVt6IR8PcTfy72f7V+rxgqL137Raa5sHl+Y9c+m7wOvoY8tsd+MtifL4PW5nvHXsNsTdg1cu8Zra161hegI7T4wXtq9fAsL/vLVcxT+KS+tLggU+srtwjR5yZA9VGY6519JhMNCasUz/5bgtTM+f95/FzC1rVBJyZFyS1vWd7K2xHrt4kArfHQsJZ5i/Dk9qBzcOFFsmW6MWCVemsBk+JAMmw13ZC2mpl5G5NUVBpyd0dp2Fjxe", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010123", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hen6J2aQPyA5qnGHR7BgcX/fFufVb/6+zZJjLkqMiRt94HnL47H48hM8jqZI4pyWZGIXe5liiOzL5O35wHlUD4R4lLx81p8eb/tOln2EepTPKPsu/muSNEzxaXm8CnQ0tSPXiHVV6I+6+yCuVd0y01lyqsVQ5MY4KcSL2Kavqg2qgwCHzmmUTP1wHhSNvcvo2EqSpIp4p8iKuD3Vtn3X4KLhso6zfrlhAgtxdZA=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NGjTFnAQt3rYErd8dTH3UbXPLtG84Z5/I0mamVp1zjSGqraw81Ydhr5e7c6ZYi0OPrct4NmH0/HLhjFOIYZ42LN76p4XacgCjBWiY9HNJewijnqIIgXiYjiuC340nSKWhHNC6IC0+De3Uc4yzAxylYhq/80/KJeo0aGf7Q2ExC6L0n+EW6llH2jb9cqh7wOOpYQ9p42ZvnLP/PG5qfHd9NZLcA1VtolxI1Ky17wB/WoIVNqnYRNFseXeZRTMMimhLg1d9crt0WFowYc6ESk94F9DlIZYdtVy2pT9/DExMsgqATz6oUEA0od5W1ebe6+9kGr271Q7eWNrcYUtrigzpB3cPFs+jmOZDClfgIl5+5AwmwBqfGEAj2PigTCFlGyBeZ33p8DuhPz4pasj5qsmJwGKIE/MFpkUYPPzLml2wqmJCKFVPJEl9UJOhfdP8x8opxJyaafbTQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010124", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf7+Jn/VQ3EIsGuGX+N9fnfvQaLMbej6iYFwNVWGmEg74HPKqqL5+EYcz6tU5IOKfisXd458hJCA2ef70XVIPcEEuYhg7YkLdfVO332setCbDet9wmeNNAX5aXmUCnR9lQ3YtnJkrYKo+inhFO4/xVUxl5Rs6IgvJcSL3KXT4Ey8xgfCz3KWRrRiGFeYu9ro4k6MoYEs9cKD8SbT8bTqlfva8dJLcRxAqoVrdkm516kH/GooQ8m3fBtI9PeQblKtCSanLg8Tudjs1X1s0ptrX4xhf+J/nXyQkcm/IJ2jxA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NGjTFnAQt3rYErd8dTHgVbTWa63t0IRlIlHJhFV/93PC463x8xMOgehS54iTZScNfY4vx97JweXlzX5UIIZWn4x745MQaecAzzKgecHVKepny33MZ0DmYjf9BnVtmz/SylRfpoeu/DS2FO4/xVUgk4Zr4sZ8NcTf2KSA5w27iRSQ2XiFE/1wGVHZts+7/0bcs5srociA9iGb/fnpm/vHsNEFIhtdvI9+bxuvg7oc+z4tQ830aRxPsfTCYFf5KSumNE4U6ov003hli4YmXnw58RFSh4cWa84z/5bgtTN3LI1iHCCurFZZhRAsrwGm4ubK0DTQM0MTZso=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010125", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYgzzzu/2ISvDBnAHpnvDU7A0cTHvXanFe+y+z4VwKV+IzVp44HnVsOXk/1ZPgqlR5pzfYCMRastgzpCg2eD+xTFIPYZQkoUy8JIWbvAAzzijYMHJOb5M7VKOG0vCYjiuC34u1AHEi3dEoZf74iaoFNt3wxo/m4h2rcQ9MtCK2K+WqFirgwLC2nSDCLJiF12avM+kq0qSs4EqvN2ZuD3V57T9j+ra/tlLdgBX/6t+dkmllqZJ6C8qWMewKsl69nQx5eqDTbrzu2FBiTA=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NGjTFnAQt3rYEpNmcXrxXbOCauT6iYR0NUqMzVposneGoKr9+lwBz6Ra54mKcSUGPoJhiPmH0+32hHhPc9JMn8Bm7JMNeLRDyTO5YcbCYNxNjkaPMEDmYivxRGR8kXHEj31Fp4375TW0QtMzxRFyn5Q448cofNSQ1Lif7Vm9ih/C33SDWrhnBRjZtN3o21Gdq5AxoY2PtDvV87Tsif3XsNgEcEhduYB2YFK9m+gA9jk7Q8GkfBtE//eQZUH/KSakZxoV/IvO12F734MnHXkx5hZJhsNfcYBylpDtryY/LcRpFD/6pUVD09g8XQKCNLSskGzr5UYxMm5rYIR5tT8wrRbcLUxulmqVQmxGnJkrzsIYnhZqaS9TmWT2hzvLgXbPfdPv4o77kOmwpqti/KAmaUCDJ1PLRc01a7fJJid23/uSA6EcJ5dmA2LyNNgrvqK8KpIRTcGcAdm9Xsa9JFg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010126", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/NmTeAGcDrT+KXONgeHSjRqLUZ/v/xdd+IRyIg1hy93jS46bl+0cana0b6ICbMCEKaIJjwcqIw+34yjFIPYZtlIR75cVdR3OQQKGEfSba/KhwFaZCPw==", 
		"answer": "25ysKJL8xBXut5clQQv+0b32OyvEC2dRs3qRQqZgZXD3XajMLuL4iYR+JFWIgRty/HPXtqT8/kcGirsZEnCvoNZXkxKpMHmfj7SRUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1A/j4YQsEhH0hfzxNmLVDXZRoGqPRrZmdTHiWqOCbeTowJt4PV2dhFR1snvPpK3kt18Kjqwb/YHfZCoGPplq3tmf1ui3y3cBIMlHk4F+pJMReeVVxSmkccebNPZv2i6XIlf1JymvAWNxmiWWg3IWvIu+tTe6R851kD+xH8eg/Fzg0cDY81lFuw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It might lead to the loss of historical artifacts", 
		"option_b": "It could result in the perpetuation of social inequalities", 
		"option_c": "It may discourage the study of art and architecture", 
		"option_d": "It could hinder the development of modern science", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010127", 
		"question": "26KwaYWz1B/s8oY0Ehr7wb3rPW6QAG0drHGKU680YHTxXajGLuX/35IxKFLJmVN+smbDsbb55EcKgateqYGZMCMNfYJqxsTJ2evlyWIBOsgEs4527ZsRPOdPzzSoYM2EYhN9SFj746q5p/t6jH+N9jE=", 
		"answer": "25ysKJX23RDo8pchRhv+3L35OnjEBnAUpz+XWqY0c37tQK7Me+zqwJh/Z1OPzU9z92XD46v/5V4czctSCBe9gBOxpGpNDu7/4mM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw1Av+9owuEg3n1+v2I2rcECIXsXCOEqJ6c3jmWrOCeuTzzIQxMFmbiBt/93rPoaDi9kcKg7Eb74GMZCcRe48vzMWb3urwhGVJNoZHlYx96pMecLRQyS+ke9CXYPdgxmeCLlH5aT79EHhx1DXTnHlap5O28CmvFp7UGHJxaGi0XQ7HKvqvoe8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "It promoted the eradication of such norms", 
		"option_b": "It had no impact on the persistence of ancient norms", 
		"option_c": "It deliberately fostered the continuation of these norms", 
		"option_d": "It led to rapid societal changes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg37wvP2M2LTAmwSpj+MVONnZGTnTa7Maa3/x5R4IlKdzXJ19n/HreX4/kAbgLpCpc6eY2IQaop7zdTJ3uq30HlEc9ZFiZNz459APhvKXcvP0g6h4mlq7AI4iJ4=", 
		"answer": "25ysKJDgwhD545ZgWxCy0PP7MHnDF2Mfp3aNVeNgeHSjW6XReuz9xZJiZ0iGzXJ19n/H5Law50EAiLpe+p3dbgR55meGjMaVcNfX3P8IKg==", 
		"explanation": "24asfZXq2Bftt4QuURf3y+m/HGXUCmMf43eKQbd7YmijXbSCfOjyzIFwKUjJmVQ753jCprfj41IBi6FV7s6LeCdDfYNuxNyM2ePy1zFVO8dQ2oh76p4abrRpwjmkdZPIYO58wWmSIlbjJziuRHE0mjDCg3NY6vO9w8COwIZ/clsFM4byMNY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It helps in promoting religious sectarianism", 
		"option_b": "It enables the revival of the caste system", 
		"option_c": "It assists in understanding the obstacles to India's progress", 
		"option_d": "It prevents the development of the individual", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010129", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kRzr9I1gRhvgyL3oPH/YQ2sFsD+AXbFmdWLzW6nGZ+P5iZN0NF+bhEtv+3nI4aMuNJ6UtCQktRfpGgEZWT0=", 
		"answer": "24a5Zpby3Fnm/pElQB/m0O/6dSaQIG0dr3qARqp7fjHsUuf2b+D3xddhKFmdn0I783jC46n541YdjrxO+4vfdjAMc8s8mIDJ9ceE5VUBZZYU1sBC9psUbv1UjHDtWNXVJ+tvyWvANEDicTCzAzB1h3HXynBfpoSu9Ge9Rts5wxRyn4k4+cA5fISN3eiQ7UOskxSbnFmyBP1XEFqKvtyh/w6woYw/oMyKtHLO5/H92vnAsMoDZ0hBq4drZhuwlqYO7Ss/VIiyeh1GsbDEaRTuJSa3MhwEuerHlntn0YM7WSV01x5VloYWcdlgwp3p8QE/PMRrGXOyqkFSxoZ/Vw7WZ6SrxG3poEUtcGwqaY9jqG08r0+dJld3n2WIDAVfkIlq8JAKmgdqeHtZ3nZxW70501RIC2HfXommVHk=", 
		"explanation": "24a5Zpby3Fnm/pElQB/m0O/6dXnVBWcDsD+XXeNgeHSjV6jOYuj93Z5+KRyGixtP83vPr+Xg+FYbnbEb6ICbMC4Kao59ycScxeG3wmNOPoZQkoUy9J8NdftEjD+oYMPeJfAunT7QZ2fTJzizADBVsHGA2ixqprOp9CypXc531xQh1oY44ckyO8Ke3q3T/EW5kkaR2WmHTbkkEEfZtI6k4k2btYN4s9+MvzHatP332uzb9Z5YcAwSvINxd06ujugr22Z4RNuxbFJN/vaQYlvgLT2tLg0c7cLs2DRoxZAmTnp08BZAhIZEZ85nlorhuzs/Md5WGwC7rVdL1Z1oHxWTd7y11Sjw6FB/Zm4qcY8tsCw7phqdL1E+nHmTQWxFnIUrqsQR1Qdmc3tVjm+goxvLj2uYfYHn+MD9i+ywt7hwsrQuLUSMLBzNRYgYJbXPNSd+w/2eH6dIJo1iW2L2Ndwi8yr2MJ6Nk3kM3t1gPXLr/S2QndjmeXG/q4bqstpCHLpANdDW/c73o0XUdSbsYWqSdYv1GRv/THX5305tvh03yTMT4HuYGJt64ywBm3CkCU1q0ibub3WkmKocw4yKdo8/k+bj3jsVjO06EcALnRBOcFnfqm8cQVV40Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Sangam literature,Collection of Tamil poetry and literature from 300 BCâ€“AD 600", 
		"option_b": "Prakrit,Language serving as a lingua franca in the 3rd century BC", 
		"option_c": "Sanskrit,Language used as the state language from 4th century AD onward", 
		"option_d": "Caste system,Social hierarchy system prevalent in ancient Indian society", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010130", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Av5/pY0VxDxwL3wMyvRDWEYpnGXEq17YnzwFKbMaq393IRlKFGazVJ1+n/EqrHjt1EAm6Ab4ICbeTQKep5uxJCOxevg0HkBMshA2pR64dobeeJFwDK9edHVNL5hyC6UL0CwWAaCO09Lqw6Uh4E9oBZp8CZFtSEPaKRBHw==", 
		"answer": "27a3fZ/nwwCoQVs+iELP7e6DTDk/245G/A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYWz0hz444QpXF7h0O/pPH3RD3FRrHnDU613eXTtQOfMYf/z2td5LlKNiEk7/HnS46r++0pPhqZf4JiWdDcCcstrzcaM2+vnyXRPJ4ZGj5Qy5ZYMc7RUxDjtZMbUJ+xr3X3AKEOwczG4RHN7gT/CmGUUUI+jrJRAhRub/9kgdp20Ug==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "co,un,try,tey", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010131", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw0Ar+8sUzSw3mwPC/NGXUQ3EUoGuCQKp1fnjwWefKZ+P6zIUxM1SMzV9+/3nFsaTk/lBPhqZP7ImNcTYKcYUvyd6Nl9vI+05+DPl72o90pLMReP1BjrfoijuhuMWkOeEhyqOnTWQ=", 
		"answer": "26C2YYXqk84cDEmNEqEu2byz2vjrcLc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw0Ar+8sUzSw3mwPC/NGXUQ3EUoGuCQKp1fnjwWefSYf77iZhzNEiIjld+4TbSrOXk/1ZPi61W5o2NcTYKfctmxsSM0Pb20HhOPYZFlIQy8ZQWaO0AwzvtXdrfKf8sVn1HgI02ASemHBEm7epFmw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "un,ity,tyu", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010132", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh1Ar++JchRhf9y73wMyvRDWEYpnGXEqBhfGX2RqKCb+P6iZR4MVWFhEF65n/JreX9/lQHm+hX7I+bMDYMPp9nzZCb0vL+0nBNc8lC2pN955MecLR/8wKSS+vkH756xm+UZ1L1dTz9AHVxhD3PynVYr5G6/Cm+UJo+zlU6n5Rs4to1P9aTmbiB6U6sjwWHzzkzduV2gBhQuzb0QGBV/ga1", 
		"answer": "272xbYPywxri/oAzECF7E6c7ihEIxqFK40ym2wo=", 
		"explanation": "24e9fpjl2Bftt4QuURf3y+m/Nn7cF3cDpj+AXbZ4dDHhRq7Maa38yJR6Z0+GjlJ6/jbOqqDi9kEMh6Fe+s6PYicVf4dqxsTJ3uq3zHhSJ8lWk4Nz6NoLdflF33/QtFMoqpJDO9HrkgQNK7oS", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "hi,er,ar,ch,ies", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010133", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he/6I2LGAm5RrHnDU613eXTtQOfBe+Hq3IV0Z12HiRt4+2DPr6zq9kcGgKYb4IDfWSwHd4ovxdGQl+jyxXUBJ8kEjoh3pIoabuRF2CisYN3ULr5hyC6TKEb5ZjX9DX5xhSTXhnVCoYaoySmHWugywQY9mN04zMY/NdKRzei65kmxhwjCz3SSQbhwCBSOtN3o5kKOq4c89c+U8TXJ++fq2uvc89cKbkhbsYxqcE+1lK1FuCs2VYimbQFf/vbZb1OtNCCmZwER/Yv0120pyYRpUWAy8V9Li4RedoBh047tqjdwK8VvBjb6qkpF1oF1Sx6TZ//6xH/++Br3UNewHzmxyXih", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhDJjFV/smLOpuXi8lIcgKYb4J3fZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQf7Tohs58DQBb8tv3cmf+/q", 
		"explanation": "24e9e4X8wxDk8MU0WhuyyvH7dXzRGiIepT+PW6VxMHzqU6/WLv/7355nIhyaglhy83qGqqv64kAbhqte+sLfZyoKfYMv28WZx+vl0GIBMclQksBm7J9ffedTyS+5fdvVYP9gyi6UL0CwdTy8F3961l6XE6Uz5YNoSroHDSEX9lM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010134", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he7rIG/JQ20X436NUapxfmWjWKbMafj/zpJiZ1WazV5o4XPIt6zx+xMJgLob/ICbdTAQaophzNmH0KTjzHQBO89Xjo9g7ZkecLRF2jKhYcDSL/AuwWjAJFD8cyyvAWNImg3YuHlXu4y1r2eaWtk+xRsm1pN99dwvfMCN0LyH7UP4jwjCyHOUW7gkHVWXstup7EaP4JIqutuEtTeb/frqk//b5M1LawZGsMZra178la0F8S8+QoT0awdY5evdchitISanZwUT9tzv03Buw8ImWykk9QxSwpBZYcl2wpHhr3BNOneBe7K2rD8BCVMDrLRM", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhDJjFV/smLOpuXi8lIcgKYb4J3fZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQf7Tohs58DQBb8tv3cmf+/q", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCy1un+IW7DQ3YZomvDRqtxMGL3QaPbLuL4iZZ/JFWMg087/nfIpLDx8FYcz6FIqYuMYycNaoJuxJCP2Pa30X9FNtRXjoF84JMRe7RIxS65e8bSI/9ijm2VK1HldTixRHVimz3DnnVZpsOP/SL7Rt820xo81pdq4t41ONKbmbuG+F23lBKRnG+ZQa4kEEeKsNy84kyS4IAh9ciVoT7a/frwlP+T5NYKdkhTsYV2ZlWo17wM4D4rEd+mYQZf9OqQaFqtNCCmNAtd9crt0WFowYc6HWYy8hpUwpVXbtVy1JTh/Ds+LMRtHSep401O05s8Sx+TNL+93GHh5kZzNXk+dp5isT554Q6SLBR1lGSLQClVk4Ur8dZZhQVwaS9Tk3XphyuChXbDPIfr7pL5h/GwobBn+60gaU6VJxzNWIkZd6DUJml2w+ecTalac4tvEiv0fdY78C3sMpOHnTNznWVQiXGW6ujrSO3qXRU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010135", 
		"question": "26KwaYWz2Aqq9sUwXQr3y+n2NGeQAG0fsHqSR6Z6c3SjW6GCb/nqzJphM1WHihtv/TbUprbk+EEKz7xT7M6QfCZDbop73NWb2aT4wjFSPMVNn5RrpJsReLRD2TG5YcbeYPdgjkeOI0zxOHvHWIacxkQ16k1CbVtVX9SR", 
		"answer": "24W9eoH2xQzr44wvXF79w73sOmjZAm5RqnGGQ7Z9ZHjmR+VJ9LJz2gpq+hHUvH5NaVlw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1Ar++JchRhf9y73wMyvEC2dRrHOHErR1aTHsUufOZ+v7iYB+MlCNzUl+5H/QpuXx+VdPnLxJ7ICYZCoGcMt8x9OA1ui3zX9EItNNjol399Zfb+FDxH2sZ5TPKPsuymeTJFf5ajCzBWR9mz+Wi3tXoY2o4We3W80y0lU9hIN9/9t8Pdmbmb+c5Ui2xhKK3W/RSbtiHV2aocusq0KSo4s9u9nNmDzf/fX32uvc89cOdhESi452cBuvgq8O/TksQoigYBNfseXEdVHgMDyqKQld7cSj1GZgyIVpX2g3/19SioYWcsFgwtjzsyc8O41mEDK+41BPh4B0WleVe7Os2Wbx4UE2enRraowtrzg2qU+JJlJ/k3ncXD5Ql5Ri/dUK1yv/R+K1Rfo+xjpujIRX1xI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Strengthening of social equity", 
		"option_b": "Preservation of ancient art and architecture", 
		"option_c": "Revival of past glories", 
		"option_d": "Perpetuation of social inequities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010136", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdX7eCnZRtH6QEqdxfn73UaOCbPS+3Z90Z0iMn1Y7zjTnsbzx4VIdm6lnq86WfmICcIhmzd6dl835wHhAbIQxp7jdmIEbaCkNr2RxJ+e/", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX71Avkt4QuVl7RwPPrJ2rcQ0sfp3aCEL0x+gLgEfzu3J6soXQ2wFs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7licwzrxOv+J3/RPyBRsXqFV7FmdXWjQKiCYOLs3Z90NVLJjFV/snXDrbHi9l9PpqZf4I/TMCcbao5hzNmH0KTx1n5Mc9JMn8B35YkLeeZOjCmiNMDTJb55y32UIlf+Jyq4BTB3mzDFnm8UpbUdiRBlfZDgWig99qjXtw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Southern India", 
		"option_b": "Eastern India", 
		"option_c": "Northern and Central India", 
		"option_d": "Western India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010137", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy7PP7PGreQ3AEr3qRErR1YzHoWqjVYK3/2tdlL1nJsRl3/WTC46r2t0cHiuhM4YGTdWIMeMthx8Kd36TeynVIMvoGxcIIJQIrAUjX95m0wUH9+2eF", 
		"answer": "24a5ZYT3wxjt4pU0U1zUnrpQi1iZ1S0YHyAXVmIH", 
		"explanation": "24a5ZYT3wxjt4pU0U1KyzPO/IWPVQ2Qetm2XWuN3dX/3QbXbLszahddyJk6bhF5/sn7PsOXm/lAbgLpS5puMMCMRc5gvzsKG2qTjzHQBFMdKnYEy8JVfaPxFjD+iZtDeMu0uwWjAM031Jw28CXl41D3XhHgWqY2/tTC6R5olxRM3hJV96YgoM5eeyuiH4Ej4ukSO02mVCLJiUUCRsI6/40yQpcI3s42DviDP/LTQlPza8Zy5uHCVN+rZV4CJjExg65SM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Samudragupta", 
		"option_b": "Ashoka", 
		"option_c": "Harsha", 
		"option_d": "Chandragupta Maurya", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010138", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXr+YI1Uxn3he76J33VByIQsD+CEq99fnb2VefEfOzwypYxJl+bgkhosnvHqarit0MOnbxIqYGZMAsNeoJuiNScxe35wzFVO8MEio9h8Nc4aeRUzX29ccbSL/oxjN41ESakIZdD++lFQsUTRGE=", 
		"answer": "24a5ZoL4wxD+tdPvQBhPfD9x5lmUI6yltdk=", 
		"explanation": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgQhHh0bDYIHvEAiIBpm2KXac4MELiWrTJfOTqiYR0NUqMiRt64TbH46n5+VQajuhd+4+RcyNDf4h9x8Oal+n2zn5Tc9ZFiJRhpJUZPN1OyDSsOJTaLvouwWiGLkb5ZjX9AH93gTzThGhF6JS+5yL7W9wjxRtygZVx+dw5MpeW1+ig6UOrjRSLyDn91tMfHq8kyNTt8+8akDEY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Sanskrit", 
		"option_b": "Dravidian", 
		"option_c": "Pali", 
		"option_d": "Prakrit", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010139", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTDk84whXF731fT8JivHBnAU43yMX7N7Y3TnFK7MLt7/x4R6NVWdzVp19jbVt7D0/lYLz79S7YuTaWICfZlg28PJweXlzX5UIIZWn4d765QMI7Z0pDLCbeqpfjdM66UiZl5W", 
		"answer": "25i5YJDx2Rj49pEhEh/8wb3NNGbRGmMfoj2uZ3izIjgp6PCMpIhMU95f", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe0BHr9Y0hQB/mxL3+O2+QMWMcomaCXKI0Z3TxUefNfOT5wJlwK1CQzVh0/2bJsKD0t1oBz5ta552UYisXPophzJCe0vbyhGZIN8NIg8Bh8I8bdfFEjDyuZtvIM75qx2iGIlf1aS39FnVznT7YmTxZrsOS+yOyVZjRjrC5MTBeq+1d75vBDeP3", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mahabharata and Ramayana", 
		"option_b": "Bhagavad Gita and Upanishads", 
		"option_c": "Rig Veda and Atharva Veda", 
		"option_d": "Arthashastra and Manusmriti", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010140", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3v5YhgQRf1y/T5PG7DQ3YZpj+WQaY0f3ejV6jWeuLwhdd/JkqAilpv+3nI7+Xx+VdPi6Fc7oeRd2IQaoJsw5CA2aTjzHQBGshAlc1T9oMecrRMzTOqYdXcJe0xjI8tyfo9p+mrtoRR5rmOO9o=", 
		"answer": "25itZpXyk46Z1ZUrJO1SakPyULRIW5I=", 
		"explanation": "24a9fpTh0BWq44AyXw2y0fX+ISvDCmUfqnmaErd8dTH2R6KCYeu+yphlM1OHwRt182DPpKTk/lwBw+ha54rfdCsEeYJhz5Caw+30zzFIPYZQkoUyzZQbc7lh3iSsepTXIfBp22+HIlawbzirATB2kTTYymhEqYC+8WevW5ojyBByu5J26cl8MNaR3r2S70irykaL0n+YS7xwGFqe9c2951eJsoM09cSDtz7O8fr6n7p7fVxT49S6Zk/RNnTIC605", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Dravidian", 
		"option_b": "Munda", 
		"option_c": "Indo-Aryan", 
		"option_d": "Vedic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010141", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfH2O2zFCnEFqnzDU61wMHL2WLPXfOzyiZN4MVmbnlJv6zbPreXx+VAGiqZPqaeRdCsCPoNmxtSMxeHzhGVJNoZBiZRz5pYWb/xNyTO5NNvdYP9g1y6GKFf9Jza7RGB7mDjCg39XpMOu+y6vTZoLzik8pIJ5/scyZpe73LuD4Vm9xhKK2TuUTrtrA0CK9dqnq0COpYMssI2ZtCDJ/eD2iPHS/J4CZg1cq49ral6v2+gd8C94Ut24fAdZ8OiQZV3rJi2xIgAe/Nij13lmyIVpSWExtAtUi4FTcYBy2Jykvz09MthkHCezplcA14Z5SRafeLi8ku7FgjmXv1RK0VPj1l79Vho=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMH3qWqDXZ/7qwJQxJlKNzVhu/mLTsaT8t1cGma1J+oeLaWIHd48v2N+a0qT0zHBNP8NKnYVhpI4QPORPwDS5fdfaLL57wGeUPgXYaC64EnVm2HHCgnkWuoa65ii1FNMkgBw8lYhq/80/KJed3KuS/V69xhKK2TuUW6llE1iQpsal7k2I4I0+9dmIoyDS4Pvrk/nfsNcPZwZGtpJ2Zkj8lqEE/S54Rcf0ZwRO4+ffbFGtNCCmZw0I9d/2xHVlhoYgW28x5hpIgYZFIsF90tjisyEkOt8qFHO5rElNyJo8VhOTeqmxxHGmWFQ8M0aWRZjJZXCcxuODQw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010142", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf7wOGbZDWUdqnGEEqxyMHXqUqHHfOjw3dd0M1SHhFg79WTJtrXjt1oBz6lV6oeafjZDV4VrwdHJ2+HzhGVOc8cEmY9/9JYaaPEAzS6+fdnSLP96x2GOZ0r2Jy21AXlm1DLDhmhDuoK3tTOpVdMj01U7mJN3rcl8KdmW36GW7A2RiAKL3XXRS6hoBUGLsI6U5X+Skoc5psKD63Lv/PG5k/bX+dkObAdHrMZrcVK+krtJ9yx4eMawYRML5+vcdFr5ITqqKxdd/MbhxHVqw4ZpSWExtBxTjpdDcMF/loj2vTEkNs5vBnO4sUtVwJxoHxWPNKmw1Sji70c6fH0lJY1/szglsk12fWxT0xdpRo2/225+3j8U", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMHXqUqHHfOjw3dd0M1SHhFg79WTJtrXjt1cGi+hY5oCLYisBa59qiMSGl+W30X9INc9BnsBx8ZYLaeZFjBWiY9HNJewijnqIIgXiYjiuC340nSKWg3JVp5Gp8CSvFNskgBQhhY515MQ9KN6Q1+iE6V62wRLC3XeGSaR3UUKWudum/0KOudl4tsKDtz7S9+Dq2vnd9J4ZZxtbrJJ+bVi5178M6i94UMSnZ1Jb4+HDZFr5YjIRPYmCHU+q4nyjReBoCO4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010143", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hev+J2XRTGEQsGuGErBtY2XmWefLYK3/x5R4IlKdzXJ19n/H46Px9FoDhrxa/YubMDEMfYJuxJCE2Ob+yHhVKoZFlIQy5ZYTc+NFyH2ketDSNvdq22+MNAXkaHm+DHF6kzSWnnRToZH79iaoQN93zwM3hMd/6MY5LtaL0Ked+w2EiDqM7n6QW7JqSxStvcvo/UKOroN3tsyepTeb5+3qjv3esMkKcUhWupV2ZFW5k+gd92o5VcmkfFJf/qTDblfkJTyiK04e8crt0XF6hoMnWSkx+gxTkIYWZ9Fm15SksyIgMN9+AD2zt01F1NR6UAXWdbG0kGXh7Vc6Z2lp+86BWB73XgYpoiBtd7b43A==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMGXrUefUb//wyNhyJk+diBto62XSpqiw81oLz7hJ5piWdCdDcoJiwcSM06Tky3JIMsoEl49w7ZYWaO0MjD+4YJTSNL55z32OYFGwZDawCX961AXejzxErYKo+in7Xcl3yRsxmZVq6MsofNWa2qmG+0j4kg6HnGiIW6lhHBSOtN3o40qZsoMqtsWEsjPXtPX3nrjX+dpLbAdG/4NxcE6ukugM6T85XYi7eAJE4/DFb135KS2wZwgS64vi2ngrfTJIjcSp3Oqx1yltYEcrJQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010144", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfzxNmLVDXZRinGHW6J6MGLsV67HevS+zI95Ll6AmV5/snLDprWw9EYDm71J6ILfZSwKapIvydOb2PfkhHBNP4ZWn4d765QMPMhO8DOfcdXIL/A0jlqIIgX1ajyvA3V6lzSWhXoWuoa8/Ci1VdZ3zBQ8kZJ56s0vfNaR3eif4Vm9lAeQxTuGR69vAhSdvMro5UyI4I49tMnNpT2b5/3+lPHV+d0KbBwSvJNzd06ulqRJ/CMuVNqnYQZSsz+g7puzsslge8sr/Y07y7Q=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMHDtV67HYPm+4Jl1Ll2HzUh08X/Dt7yw81oLz61D4YedeTZDfZ5j3MWb1ui30X9IJ98Eso9l4YwabrgA2DWoNMbeIe1hwC6JNAX5aTqyFmJxlyWNym5Tr4q0+ya3FNY2zhInl4B9/og9MtPf1aGH7V+5lB/Cy3SDQ64kFV2d9c2n5VeOqYAtocjNpT2b5/v0n7jQ5dIfdxpTs8Z7ak25hbsA7DN6WR2kuE56wAAPl4nEeAGocw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010145", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hen6J2aQPyA5qnGHR582MHjtXbPLb+Hy0NdjIlqMn0l+9jbSrOXxt0EKg6Fc4IGKY2IAcYZi3d6Aw/23zX8BMshHk4V88No2cvBJzX2ReujVEvtv3WGOfQXEbzz9LWJ1mjjXhDxfppC45y6rQNM4zgZymYE4+cA5fNGW37ybm16xnhKKnHiURqlxA12cpo6KyAORpYwsvMKD8SbT8bTtn+resOJJSgFcu5NDIRu9hOgIuC49QsumYQJf+OveIVvrYDqmKwca8MT2xTRrw44gWG8ntgHK4aku4bAs5HPv9Eh3KFY=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMGXrUefWa//ziaszD1WHiU5HsDbJsaz3/l0Og6RCqZyadicRbI5riMSGl+W3w3RONNRFioh759oecvAAzyihYMHJIfIux2qFKVH5cyD9MHhx1CPTi29ZpsOy5merVcgjyRQ+mp44+dopOZvf272HqEO3kkaW1H7RS7J2A1GaoY6t81OQoYw5ocSCv36b9ee5jvDWsMoOcAUSu497bRyo17gb8Sc5Q8G4cVJC/+DZYlX5JWixIgIU/sLsw2cpxIclVGwy519PjMNfdtMz05n2sCtwKt5rEjb4XitMEm9rKgMINPgu3D3n/g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010146", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/r9JEvQF7xyvPrJ2LSFnYUpz+XXeNgeHSjRKLQfeTt3ZJ/JFnJgl078XfVt6Cw50EOjLxS6ouMMCMOcYVoiNOG2fLy1mVSc9JL2qN69pMMaP1BwjS5bZTaLvou532MJkiwbjf9BX53nTTYnjx/poey9Hj5LyICRrRgzrKZYaEXimlSwA==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdH31Bz6upcvXQr3wb3xNH/FEWdRrHnDRqtxMHLiR7PHLv7n2oN0KhyKglVv+3jTpqGw41xPhqZd5ZuafiEGPphgy9mMw+X7hH9OIctX2C6d2GcllU7vJ/x9SaKx5ng=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH31Bz6upcvXQr3wb3xNH/FEWdRrHnDRqtxMHLiR7PHLv7n2oN0KhyEiFp15jbSq6Tkt1YZiqYb6IiLdTBDfYRh3tWbw+35wzFVPIZAk4Z04YgacuAA3jihfdPSL/B9gi6JKUH5cTC5EXF4h3HVhXJCoY2u8CP7QNV3wRE6k5V9rdwzfNSay7yS4UP4hQeRyH7RWK9lEkCQtsu7q0eJpcIsuo2ZuTeb9+H1ju3B8dJLYwZW/5VwYFK9m+gA9To5Utz0ZxQL5ezVIUf0MzymKky6hCdPakQhb6iQwr9W2c3S", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The fluidity of caste boundaries allowed easy integration", 
		"option_b": "Religious conversions led to the complete abolishment of caste practices", 
		"option_c": "The rigid caste system prevented any form of religious conversion", 
		"option_d": "The deep-rooted nature of the caste system continued to influence societal norms", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010147", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q440lEh39y/76JX+QDGRRgm2aU7V1YmXiFKLPa//5zNd4KRyIg1hy93jS44z+81oO0OoSZ+EfKFS2uqAxgtMI1PQL", 
		"answer": "24G3KJf8wg3v5cUhEg33y+76dWTWQ2EernKMXON9dHTtQK7Wd63/x5MxJEmFmU5p83qGtqv540pNM9o7mifBBjxXgxOuftIVHA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hfp8pU0EhH0hdztLGrGAnAFoj+UU7A0eX/3RqjGe+77zddlKByKn1565nOGouXj/1Idiqwb6puTZDcRf4cvyd6Nl+Pyy3ZTMtZMk4Nz6NoWePFO2DS5bZibMOxhw2GULkv3JyyzDWRt1DDbhXJR6Iey4yKpR993wxo/m5J25Nw1OcTf0KbT6UO7jwOMyDu4RrltEBbcxkI1UxQX6vRJte+F7QeC", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To establish a distinct geographical region for religious practices", 
		"option_b": "To promote regional diversity and cultural uniqueness", 
		"option_c": "To foster a sense of common identity and cultural unity", 
		"option_d": "To segregate different ethnic groups based on their origin", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010148", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxbm8sUkWxqy1/j4PGTeAm5Rr36NVbZ1d3TwFLfOb/S+wJkxJlKKhF515jbvraH59hQcz6tO5ZqKYiMPPoduxtSa1OXnwS4Dj9GGmWI/mHZwNI+uwY1v9g==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz0hbk45cpUAvmwPm/IWSQF2oU43qbQrFxY2LqW6mCYeu+yoJ9M0mbjFc75HfKtqDjt0QGm6BS586JcTAKe48vxNmH0PH+12VIMIZHlY5m4YILb7YpDlsVvP2liyKZ1wWKcWlw", 
		"explanation": "24e9b5j83xjmt4khXBnnxPr6JivRD24etHqHEqV7YjH3XKKCa/Xu25JiNFWGgxt09DbFtqnk4kEOg+hN6IKKdTFDd4UvzNmf0vbkwTFNOshDj4lh8JMcPPdPwimobMDIbL5twWCUNUzyci20Cnc0gD6WnnRT6Iyt8DW6WNZ31Rs7gp444s58Fdmb0KmdqE6tihKXzn7Tif/bdhc2BCatY3EeZs34cA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "They led to significant cultural diversity and fragmentation", 
		"option_b": "They had no impact on the overall cultural unity", 
		"option_c": "They served as barriers to communication between different regions", 
		"option_d": "They contributed to the expression of cultural values within varied linguistic contexts", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010149", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q440lEgjz1/P+emjREHYU42yaQbdxfTHgW6nWZ+PrzNdlKByAg11353PIoKCw3l0LhqlVqZ2QcysGapIvzNWax+3jwTFTNspNnYl98Ylff/tO2ji/Z93ULu0xjHnq62SWuAUf7MP6M2TZhjg=", 
		"answer": "25atZIXmwxjmt4QuVl7hyv72NGeQCmwUsWuKU+NkdWPzUbPXb/n7zddyJk+diBt1/WTLsOfXp6Mll+OuxIyVNBj1pav6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHl0Avk9sojUw3mwL3sLHjEBm9WsD+HV6ZkPWPsW7PHaq393JtlMk6IgRt6/HKGsKrz/lIDz6FV74KKdSwAe8tsx96d3uriwXUBJ8kEiYhz9J9fb/tDxTi5ddibLvF8w33AJkv0JymvBXNgnTLTmTxTvoa1tSa2W9QwgAc3mo5/5McpL5ec1qaF7V+slURZLkuKNIwX/OPJJvC7iotL", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The caste system was attractive to religious converts", 
		"option_b": "Religious leaders actively promoted caste-based practices", 
		"option_c": "Cultural and social inertia perpetuated caste norms", 
		"option_d": "Foreign rulers enforced caste-based divisions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010150", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b3+NmjFEWMFpnOaErFxdn3mV7PRLvn2zNdlIk6EzWc52n/Ip7DMtRMGgeha542WdSwXPqJhzNmIiKZCnxDicYQT+caXPVsKvaVo", 
		"answer": "252xZpXm7Vuq+JcpVRf8xPHzLCvUBmwet3qHEqI0d3TsU7XDfuX3ypZ9Z12HiRt453rStrfx+xMGi61V/YeLaWBVbAY++1tUCYYru9UYuyI5", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJD90hDv+ZFgexD2zPyzdVeSK2sfp2q/EON7YnjkXanDYuHniYV0IVmbn15/smLJ46Sw8FYAiLpa+YaWcyMPPophzJCKwujj0WNAP4ZNnoV88JMLZbgA3jy5fNHJYOpmz2DAIl3zayyuDWZxmCiWg3JSoYC64S61U5o2gAc3mo5/5McpL5ec1qWe/UOxkh/AsuQzmodKnLQdkvskfaXAwg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "The term exclusively referred to a religious community", 
		"option_b": "Hindu\" originally denoted a geographical and cultural identity", 
		"option_c": "The term was introduced by foreign rulers to label a specific group", 
		"option_d": "Hindu\" was never used to describe ancient Indian societies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010151", 
		"question": "24GwbdHk3gvut/0IWxD20IS/NHiQEWcXpm2GXKBxMGXsFLPKa63uzJhhK1nJgl072n/Ip+W43l0LhqkS1YCIcTFDeIJ928TJwvfywDFDKpwE0tErvc9WPsgOBOUZ3s3TLY/t97eA9q0=", 
		"answer": "26GwbdHSwxjo5MeqrW14tDpY8mzEfBoad3Fs", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH90BTvt4omEjf8wfT+dWLDQ2NRoHCRQLZkZHjsWufNaK3qwZIxMFObiRtI+3jCq7DM+WAGgaxT/M6WY2IXdo4vxtGE0qT4wjFVO8MEs4528YlfTv1WyS/hNNneLupnwWCFIwX5aXmpDHU0pjjRvHlSqcOV8C68XNg40hw8kcdZ/8k+L5vf8LqS5kS5iBXCyW+FTa9hFRTgpono6lDc54p/9cyDtXLY9fj1n/zv/soDaxsSs4dxZxuUnqYN7WofQ82xYwEL4fbfb1v4LiumI04J8cLwlnpoy4dpXHp03RFCl5AU6XjVRTxG8HWWOn4eJ5Fekg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Unity in Diversity & Past to Present", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "the Greeks", 
		"option_b": "the Romans", 
		"option_c": "the Chinese", 
		"option_d": "the Arabs", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020101", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7xyvHwO2LRD2sCtz+QUat7fHDxR+fOZ+b7ibExCl2RzXZu93rKpre8t0QHjrwb7ouRdTACcoJ1ycSA2Oq3wHhFc9JMn5ky6ZsUebRBzjK4YJTPKPsuz2CDLkD+c3mUCnR9lT/FzTxGrZG48DevXdU5gBo01pNx4M18Pdmbmaub+kK2iQqN22LOCmKIuLhoR95CRRX69j/r0VI=", 
		"answer": "25S2a5j23w2q3oskWx/81r38OmbAD2cFpnOaEqd9Y2PmU6bQauj6iYN5IhyKglV492bS46r2t0cGgq0b6ICbMCELbIRhx9yG0P21DPbh/q7HSFyycR2mGkEHEw==", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZJ792Bjm/pY0Eg3xzfLzNHnDTyIYrXyPR6d9fnajcufvb/W+5IJ0K1CMnxc7/XDSpquw8FYBirpa5YeFdSZDaoNu3JCI2ef+wX9Vc+9Knolz6olfcPVDxzipNNWbM/tg3WvAKEOwbzCuEH9mjX2Wj29GrYCy9Cu3TZojyBBylYh27s0sKJeQ3+iH4UC9xgeM2DuSQK9rH1uVusmxq3eUqZF4pcifoiLe9+DwjP2T598YIh1BuoI/d1T8gqYN/Tg1WMaxKAZD9KTYaEf5LzqqJA8Rucrg3n1s0IckWGcg519JhMNXbMN605bw/Bs+O8RrG3O5qlJJy51mXgOfe7P40WbgoF8qZm4iY5MtvyI5rgGVKVg+iH6QSW6Rd6a54VVjM9VUH8aNGHS2", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ancient Indians had a meticulous sense of time and chronology", 
		"option_b": "Ancient Indians completely disregarded the concept of time and chronology", 
		"option_c": "Ancient Indians had a vague understanding of time, but no sense of chronology", 
		"option_d": "Ancient Indians only focused on the future and neglected the present and past", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ20TqXqARqpidTHsUufWfOzw2ptwM1WHiht6/HXPpqvkt3oBi6Fa586MczAKbp962tWal/H5wHRTc9JMn8B34JMLc+ZTxDS9NNvdYNNv1i6tMkD8azyvSDB1h3Hbj3JCoYy18CP7XdR31B031pd5/ts9O9LAmzs2Y8i5k82IlX3GaqLq5p4=", 
		"answer": "24G3KIL2ww/vt5EoV17Q1/TrPHjYQ2Eer3CNW6J4MHDnWa7MZ/7q25ZlLlOHykg7/HPDp+X2+EFPhKZU/oKadCUGPoptx8Wdl835wHhAPYZXlYN74Y4GPPVOyH2uYdjPNexrjD/qOwjW2AlSeKGS2iBgOZM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEg3mxOn6JivEC2MF42uLV+NgYnDtR6vDeuTxx9d+IRyIg1hy93jS44z+81oOgehI6pyWYDYWbI58iMWH0+HlhFxAK4Zpj4V+6J8NO+cAyTmkYNvJM/Zn3i6XJlawdyu0CXFmnT3Pyn1fpYa/tSavFMolzwM7ko526ogoNNLf+7qa/ESrjkaB03eeRrRlHRSYscOh5UqPtJA5ocSCv3LM/eDx2vzW9c4OcEhbsZV2ZFOohOgA9j43Edy8bVJG8OreZEb+bGiwKA0U+MejxW160ockTiV09RFCwpVDbs52xJnmtT45K8RvBnO1pQRUz5E8dhmSfby2kHjr8EAzdG4iaoQtqCUwuE+OPVh7niuTWilD1uQrhIHoT17ei526uk5/dDE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To facilitate cross-cultural understanding between India and the West", 
		"option_b": "To encourage the preservation of ancient Indian languages", 
		"option_c": "To analyze the linguistic similarities between Sanskrit and European languages", 
		"option_d": "To serve the British colonial administration's need for knowledge about Indian society and culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020103", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q1oklSh/8wfjtcniQCmwHomyKXa00eXzzVaTWLvn2zNdhIk6KiEtv+3nI46r2t1IBjKFe55rfWSwHd4phiNiAxPD41mgBOsgEjoh3pJkQcPtOxTyhfcfPYOhny3nfZZalwrJBCcTim/BMYaI0hHI=", 
		"answer": "25ysKJL83w34/oc1Rhv2henwdX/YBiIBrG2XQKJtcX2jW6GCR+P6wJYxJk/JjBt383jC46r2t1cKnLhU/YeMfWICcI8v2N+F3vD+x3BNc8JNiZV87Y4GPtcsrbUqTeTlHp+qj9zN0M4=", 
		"explanation": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7xyvHwO2LRD2sCtz+KXLdxYmHxUbPDeuTxx4Q9Z32FiEN6/HLDseLjt1oBmalI4IGRMDUCbct629WNl/D4hGNEOshClZJx4doLdPEAwjK5fdvVYPFojkeOI0zxJziuRHE0mDDYjjxaqYCw/Cm8FMo4zBwmn4R54YgpMt6LwOiS5kn4gx6S2WmYTbNnGFqe9cqt+FOTtIs79d+YvTeXtPLsiOzb9cxLaB1Bq495elKykOgr6iMsWNu8KBFE/eveaFXhYCusKRoP9sehZ4exTFAIs4no0KtcAybSNg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It demonstrated ancient India's strong political unity", 
		"option_b": "It proved that ancient India had a history of self-government", 
		"option_c": "It showcased the resilience of ancient Indians against foreign invasions", 
		"option_d": "It contributed to the portrayal of India as a land of despotism and political disunity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020104", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17/xPTxdXvFEXIesHrDXaU0ZHnmFKLReuz8xZ5iL1GMg087/XCGt631t3IchqlP4I3fQy0Ad4570ZCG0aTVwX9GMsoEk44yx5sTf+FU2Dztfdqbcak2mjHCfZz9aCjF8WqG3hgq50vNLA==", 
		"answer": "24G3KJfy0hDm/pEhRhuy1/jsMGrCAGpRqnGXXeNgeHSjXK7ReuLs0NdwKVjJjk535mPUpuX/8RMOgatS7ICLMAsNeoJuiNaGxaTjzHQBEdRNjolh7Nocc/hPwjSseJTaJPNnwGeTM1fxczCyCjLc41cc5qURPfpaiibDcRWi", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwhDr44wjEi39xvT6IXKQDGRRgXqNVaJ4PDHmR7PDbOH32p90IxyAgxtY83rFtrHk9hMGgegKvtbLPGICd4ZqzJCd2KTn1n5MPNJB2pJ3958ebvdIjDSjNMDTJb5mx32UKFfpJzizADB3gT3Cn25T6Iy9tSa1V9MyzgFyv4l85MlwfMeN0KWS+kS0n0aW0zuCTa9yFBSNvcvo5UaZpJF4usvNpTretNbrk+za49ZLYQdesIh2Ylf8lqwE8SQxQtymaQZC/uqS1A3Ejm1Ppv7UvathzkvhEQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "To promote the study of ancient Indian epics and Puranas", 
		"option_b": "To foster cooperation between British judges and Indian pandits", 
		"option_c": "To support the translation of European languages into Sanskrit", 
		"option_d": "To facilitate research into the history and culture of ancient India for the British colonial administration", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020105", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7xyvHwO2LRD2sCtz+VW6ZjYz2jQ6/bLvr725IxJlKKhF515jbvraH59l1PnKtJ4J6LZTAGbct72tGHxOj20HRFc8NcjoV895MJefhZjDm4Zt3VJ756xmvAdhzkb3m+AX5ggSPP1T5T2OCcxajh4UUuC09kctkk", 
		"answer": "24G3KIL2ww/vt6cyWwr71vW/PGXEBnAUsGuQEqp6MGTtUKLQffn/x5N4KVvJpFV/+3fI47b/9FoKm7Eb6ICbMCEWcp962tXJ0evlhHZOJcNWlIF8559fffpEjDCkZ8fSL/Bv3HfAJkbkbi+0EHlxh3PoUHYozfgQLA+0xuswhp+6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2yQ3v+ZYpRBuy0e/+O3jcAnYYrHHDXaU0cX/gXaLMeq3Xx5N4JlLJnlhp+2bStrf15BMLmrpS54nfZCoGPto23NjJ1OH50GRTKoZTm5My9IgWcfVSxTG0NNDJKehrwC6CPgXSdTCpDWN81DjYnnlErZCv5meyWpo4wgEzn4lx4898N9mQzqSW7Eq9xgeA026FCJRqFV2Yu4675ECVpZYh9cyDtXLY4fjtj+rWsNgEcEhVsJB6cVW9masMuCs2VYi5YQFY+OveYEb0YC2lIQEP7dihN24XcngfsHXQn3AW+PbeHQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To facilitate global cross-cultural exchange", 
		"option_b": "To promote religious harmony among different communities in India", 
		"option_c": "To analyze linguistic similarities between Sanskrit and Chinese languages", 
		"option_d": "To serve British interests in understanding Indian society and culture for governance and missionary activities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020106", 
		"question": "25S0fJn8xB7it4AkRx3z0fj7dULeB2sQrWzDQKZgcXjtUaOCeuX7wIUxM06IiVJv+3nIoqmw/1ocm6dJ8MLffS0He5lhiMKMxOH21nJJc89K2pR64doXdedUwy+0NNvdYP9gzWeFKVGwTje5DXE0ljTRi3IWoY374S++FMkywxo8ksdw7MQ6fNiZmbyb7Q29jwGKyH6URqlsUVecu9q9+VrctI14psifpzeb4Pz82vbW9doYIgdU/5J3ZhuDqJc2xxUHbveLVy10ztvvIVXpLSGtLh0J68r333tnhPHCVI4cQc/gCBwca8yjegs=", 
		"answer": "25eqYYX6whGq9IosXRD7xPG9+UmgF6mp2cMXNV5OMBS7BQ==", 
		"explanation": "25i3bJTh31n48pYlUwzxzb32OyvEC2dRq3aQRqxmaTHsUufDYO73zJllZ3WHiVJ6smHHsOX5+VobhqlP7IrfZC1Dc45q3JCd3+G3ynREN9UElYYy8JIaPNZSxSmkZ9ybI/FiwWCJJkmwZj2wDX59hyXEi2hfp4378TKpXdQwgAE6k8dr6MszMtPf0amf7g23gEaW1H7RTbRjGUCcsMC84wOfpYwsoN+U8/jVjFmPxzku8orlS+jytFE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Br,it,is,h co,lo,ni,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020107", 
		"question": "24GwbdHU1Avn9ottUBHgy73sNmPfD2MD41nDf6JsMFz2UavOa/++gcYpdQ/63AIroD+Gs6nx7lYLz6kb+oeYfisFd4huxsTJxev7wTFIPYZUiI9k7Z4WcvMA2DWoNNPJJf96y32UZ0z9dzypEWM0gD6WtUNpl7yEyhiEa+UI/yoNqcdr+d04NdKMm4hQiORk1i1dcHi9aUT4r9Q=", 
		"answer": "25mxZpbm2Ar+/oZiqIZX7Nfg0xZzemKyvSZWpg==", 
		"explanation": "25P4RZDrkTT/8oksVwy+hfy/Em7CDmMf7n2MQK00Y3LrW6vDfKG+zoV0JkiFlBt4/XjSsazy4kcKi+hP5s6TeSwEa4J83NmKl+X5wDFoPcJLlo917ZkecLRT2CipfdHIYPp73GeOIAXkbzz9VSlgnHHVj3JCvZGit5LUK55Z7p089wTseYvjuQE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Li,ng,ui,st,ic", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020108", 
		"question": "24GwbdHRwxD+/pYoEhvh0fz9OWLDC2cV42uLV+NVY3jiQK7BLt7xyp50M0XJgl070HPIpKT8t1oBz/kMsdrfZC1Df49r2tWaxKT2wHxIPc9XjpJz8JMJebROyTipZ5TaLvouy2CDKFDiZj64RGJxhzTXmH9e6Iq14Sj7QNIygB07hZN3/9F8M9Hf2KaQ4Ui2kkar0n+YSf1QGV2K9d2n6EqZtJt4osye8SHe4LTsirjR6Z4KIgtbqY9zI0i5hb4I9j54Xs70fBpOscHRckCtCSanLg9d2sTuxnVn385pYlYLyyB5vbxpXf9M6afbg3DMBaUKEHckFAt7MUDq/GDO", 
		"answer": "24axetHE2BXm/oQtEjT9y/jsd75tIiUqO5zgzcRlMy3cLG8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwhDr44wjEi39xvT6IXKQDGRRgXqNVaJ4MGbiR+fHffn/y5t4NFSMiRt56zb1qrewwFoDg6Fa5M61fywGbccvyZCK3vL+yDFSNtRSm45mpJUZPOBIyX2IdcfPYNdgymeBZ2b/aim8Cmk41DjYyi0B8Nf50aDzm0ND4rJz1uSF120/kA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Si,r Wi,ll,iam jo,nes", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020109", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJjlR3/XjPoqn55EdPmaFe/p3ffyxDV4VrwdGHl+z+12VOId8Em452pI4Xef1SjDSgZNXYNL5n3S6DKFfiYjqpXkx6qD+Hyl9ZpIy1/Ca3FMgy0xAzhIRwrcEyfMOX3Oib4V6siRSbnHSXCLxqEl2cu9rowk2YqYN4t8iKsDyb/fq5jvDWsM0OYQdcu8Z3Yle616cPuD4wVIixYRVD5eHVb0DlYCumKRoI69Kjwnsp1Yc7S2x04BdDwo1TZ8Rglpfi/CY4Oo1IBzquqldIh5dzUxiYfby0kGng7VwxfGk/d4t5tSI7nQGgJgY+rmOZDClCgIFp8tkKnQlmc3sAk3CgljeOwEScdZL34oO8tufzqbx36+MoLwGiMFLfV4FcbL2AdjAqnqmZFOZvOo0nICvqMdwv8XnTL5iRzHkA0csrKnOn9WqKm8r7MGOzsJP3mpRlALoQdtjLqd65tFnVcjfgL3maaMy0WAbzRnn2x05MuRwsyS9Q4GvLHIZt7BEDonDjCWllimfNeXmtmrtOrZHOa5ww3ebg3CYZl/o4mp3x2w8oVES6g3sDpoyaD29OzkbTGo0lywYlH/QOEtbF+mjWsHfDXzweetz/BLvH0yBJw+b1zmA9spEEWp7OPhbXj54vxle1CO5qUGrkpoftNPISSmUi+bt0xPnhnsS/fPKqbHYpfROnTfpL9oYRYQw7BQPYRRNKc6zs/egr3+hpHhSRpPxJ13Drjg==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXArhhay/NGXUQzBRom2GEqB7YmPmV7OCTeLyxpl4JlDJn15o93fUoK2w/l1Pm6BeqYaWYzYMbJIvx9bJ1ur0zXRPJ4ZtlIR75dobdfAAxTOpcdHfYPxryWeOZ0z+Jy21ATBnkTLZhHgWoIK382e0UpojyBByk45/5dw5OdmL0eiQ7UOskxSbnG+eCK5hA0Kc9dqg7gOSpYc8po2Ct3LP/PG5uOra5NcYakhRsIpwbVK9m+gI/CcxX8GnfABK5e3fbxTZKC3jIh0J+Mnv32dhy4cnSSk78l9SioYWQ9N614ztv3IDMM5jECej40tGh7Z5URCXeP2x3ii1tw1rNXgyJblkrm0CqAOQIVVz2kGTQilC1Jdq7ZAY1RdqemFJmn/jgzGfwGaAcofx4oLpkeH/rvl3/eMzIUiTdVneUIIOcfGTjGAWBGxCBHbg+NYdLzbZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020110", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJjlR3/XjPoqn55EdPmaFe/p3ffyxDf4VswdWHw6TeynVIMsgEiY9x7Z8LZbRJ332ue8bJJf16lFKOG0uhJxqyCH96nTDaym9VoIy39DWoFNgyzBw3gIJ8rdw0PcPf2KaQ4Ui2kkar0n+YSbN3UViYtsWt7wOd4JE9u96I8T3dtPzwiezc4sdHIg1Br4N8alqwm7FJ8SR4Rc2mZQEL/uKQdV3gJWiiKQpd+sPx2Xpmyo0uRFU6yBEUwrRTcdR2xJakrzE4MMFrByD2401OxJhpWx6Yc/2V0XCkzUA6eXYud8YtvT4mpB2ILVA+jmOdWGx4moRi/94K1RNmb2oAjGTpjz6ZiWmWPJDs5YP5l+b1pPl0+7cvaVKQPE7RQpgdafPNJnNmz/uITadSN990Hy3xONFu8ja5KZiA2isIw81gJnmn4yWLnsn5ICWqoZ37gtF7B4MOCt+Wqei4vFPJaCLtYXSdcs7mSRr1W33s2gFrpFgqzmE55mbRCYc//SQeinGiUARlmyrlaDy1mf5Z55KGfp04yfCsyToV2PFglojj0RM/QkS0iz9C8peLXVNByhTFG8MUwUkhCvQPFYLY/WOemnnUC30De47lBKSBjitHzObjgGx4sYROXILOLRfYg9so3FeYD/lwVCXHWKEqLzjTM77/tYRJwoc1", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRgHCPXa19cX2jR6TKYeH/24QxI1WNzVJ19nPDp+X4+F8Lz7xT7M6ddS4Ke40v3NiIw6T2ynJINshQ2ql84JMecucAwDyuf9HfYP8u2WuMKwj0Yi+4CH9kkTWWmXlYu4b7+iH7XNMk1Bogj8s4/ckuKN6czKSS+kGhxg+MnG+UWrB3UVuf9c2g+UySr443stTNsDzftODwl/2Tw8oKdg1fuohrIwn8nrtJ+SYrXoi3ZwBZ9OfEIWPoMzymNQBd6sjr2Xho1JFlHWA69xNThopYZYBe14CkkSc1M8FvB3/6oldTwoZoWhPWYLW5xCjN7lE2dHQ4JZ1orih1rACOLRR4lWiJXylV1I9lvsMJnBZqaXpBkDbhjDvLkmCDdZTq5JXvxeXxtK1m4LBraU6GIVnWFowIJafIIid30vmeA7VZc5BhVzXpL9kq8CC5I5ma3Dwf3spgHGPm4C+Ul8PheTb6uoG5h9p1G60SM9LRqei4vFPJaCLtYXSdcs7mSRr1W33s2gFrpFgqzmE55mbRCYc//SQeinGiUAgkkzSgfG6khbtS/oeKP4c/k+Hk2HIAmedrnpzymF09Tgm+iT9XvcSXRltHwV3RFtlH0AErTLUDB5Pf8WjWmnCQSjwea9z5D6/H0ClGyeaxgWc9sZEaXIOAJBbUjp4nxhPxEvh1Uyrqp5D8L/IYD2o4urt/iuyvtMO+e+fkBWsuZhv7Gf1Y551UekJvGQrTRSFCcLCvRZQERKBb2nDDhUdNX3ZaEV/C+K1Kd5Rczds6fPPwwQ/1aze+OA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020111", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cV6Ej39yfLxPGrcCnEF42yAWqx4cWPwFKvLZei+5JZpZ3GciFd392SGoaD8/lYZiqwb/YaeZGICcIhmzd6dl835wHhAPdUEloFx758bPPUA3zijZ9GbL/guxmeTM0rifnm8CnQ0lznEhXJZpIy87Bu1aNQFxRQhmYkirfw0Oc7f1qqA7V+ugwLCyHOQXP1lH1eQsMC8q2qSpIs5u42ZtCrP57T4lPyT5MwKZgFGtolxcBu6mKsc6y88EcW7ehcL/uqQckTkMiG3Mg8RucbiwmBs1JFpXGcwtAtOh8NYZ9hnlo/rrj40c414FCeyplYA05x9UVeTea2w0Xvt+lwxcjoqJY5oqCw8rQqYaEd7lHiZDCNX1Ihi7cQWhw1gfGMAmWDljCuYwGSBeNP34o35x8VaLk+ud0hdfCEmFlm29Q4=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I422GVK9xc2XwFLPKa638zJt4IlrJgl078XnKrKv59l8GnLwb+o2Xfy4CbJgv3NiIw6T2ynJINshQ2ql84JMecucAwDyuf9HfYP8u2WuMKwj0Yi+4CH9kkTWWmXlYu4b7+iH7XNMk1Bogj8d548x8P9+N1qac5EK/n0a21H7RWrhlAluX9d665FWVpIc89cuYoybT8ea5n+DD/N8CbBsSq452cBu9hLsM6j4xXsb0agsL/+vEaFrqYDyrJhpd7cPmxXEp1YEhUmU15gwGgIZaa8Vl05ykqDo5LI1mFDCx40tGh5x1TAOZZrS70WSk5lo8YGlrcot+/CkgpE+IJxRqkm7cSSFBnIF498NZmgojbn9Jjn/0lz6HwGiOaIfm+ZO8hOb04K1r9+MpLFmUdUvXRIEYJbrOZ058zuCaA+ZINodzBGLnM9Fu6Cv4JJ+A1jYDw5tB7LqKaPfN9QQemsPyVC/K", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020112", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cV6Ej39yfLxPGrcQ2sft3qRQrFxZHD3XajMfa3xz9dYKViAjFU7+n/Vt6ri7hMOhqVe7c6Lf2IHe4Vmz8KIw+G37X9FOsdK2oFx7JMaavFNyTO5Z5TaLvouxHuTM0z2fnm+C3x7mjjXhjxEvY++ySmHWugywQY9mN04z9F8LNiNzbqS8US2gUar0n+YSbN3UVWK9cem6EKMoYA0sI2Ct3LI8fj/1//c5tsZbAlcvIM/YlW416AA/yI0WM+8fBtF9qTEaVHkMmivJg0WucTllnxg1ZYmT2A39RMGgYxYccN62Y33sjcjLIEqFjy2rEpJxph1TAOFNL63xWTgoFQtcm8uJZ5lvTl1gx2VPF1tkiuOWSBU1Jdq7ZAXkAdmbnxBjm+gljDLh2qZeYHtq5T0gKjZrr1q861nOU6QIFDZQoQTa/Eeb4ws2exStQfT9qMbZ5M+", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NGjTFnAQt3rDU7A0YHTxFLPKa63uyIRiJluMwRts+n/Fq+Xj41Ibirsb/YaeZGIAcYdgxtmI26T+ymVEIdZWn5Rz8JMQcucAwzvtXdrfKf9gjmaJNFH/dSD9BXl5kTWWnnMWrIa1/CCpVc4ygDw8ko5544g/NNaN2KuH7V/4hwiGnHqSQLRhB1GUsMC8+AOLqIs0sI2HpCHP/fLgk/bUsPwZaxxbrI4/YFSwmKYA+SZ4Q924bVJ/+eGQc1HsMyetZx4P9t3q0nFthocxTWU1/RFVwpdeY9Qz1IGktDs3N8FjEjuuqkpHh4B0WleGca+71WHy5VF/ZnIkd55usyA8rwiPaFt42kKSSCVQmpMr995ZgQFxcHwAk3CgkTqHhiiIc4Xm+Y79i+v14Lht9uMvIFKUOk7RVYwQJbLXJnV3xOyIHuocMJBrGCzvPNkn7y3qYJWbyjUJkNgyKGLitD6Rk9m1G3ezp5vqhpRkAbMFdsbE+ou5tV/CcjDgM2TTYMTmGQ32SXn7xwdzslgixzcV+mzZBop6tzApLVmXYthg058JmBRpb9U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020113", 
		"question": "25mxe4WzgEOq1IosXRD7xPH2Jn+QNWsUtGzDH+NYeWL3FPWYLs7xx4NjLl6cmVJ0/GWJgKr+5FYemq1V6ouMMq+44jCdUnHuHRkA9F2Aybc=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjy3wqq+4QjWRf8wr33PHjEDHAYoH6PErBxfmLmFKbMaq39wYV+KVOFglxisjv1q6Tg/l0Iz61a+4KGMCoKbZ9g2snJ2eXl1nBVOtBB2o90pLMReP1BgH2EetDSIfB9jnyVK0D0JzukRHRxhyHZnnVV6I++9CO+Rsl3zhpyhoh05Nw1P9aTmb2d4VmhxkvC9m6CXLRiGFeYocen5QOar5B4l9+EpTvI/LT6lfTc/tcKbkhAqop6LxuVmawA+SQrEcG6bBtN9+HCZFr5YDysZxkS68fn2m0py4M9SWwm519Cl4YWds8zxYjtrjskKsxmVTW1oFFTh9k8ahmSca+12Wbt7lJ/XHQvbItj/Cw2qQaZPlFzn2WIX2ARvY5v99EXhkRneHlPlXKgjTnLjmSbdZzt44/zgajxrr0j4aYrLwyHOkrdRIMRYL3UZyoy+fyLHalOJ99hGDCmH8cn6DDqKNaV2zQE3tAzO2Xm4COWnI+xfIGY6t3zynOTudnbbl/t", 
		"explanation": "2+T4W5L73hXr5ZZgXhf5wL3SNHOQLncUr3OGQON3f3/3Rq7Ae/n7zddlKByKglVo5mTToLH5+VRPpqZf4I/YY2IGf5lj0ZCB3vfjy2NYc8Rd2oh745ITdfNI2DSjc5TPKPsuz2yTIkvzYnmyAjB8nSLChW5fq4K3tSasVcgyzhAhhcd548x8P9+N1qac5EK/n0aD0XSfT/1lH1eQsMC8q2qSpIs5u97N43KW1/v1lfba8dICcRwSt49sd1SunqkH62otQs2wKAZD+PeQd13oN2i3KE4X7Nj333JwhqA7VH095xcGgYxYdtJ82tSkryc3OMh5ATq0pARUz5VoHz6YcLS5kGbh5VE6cToJd4N5tT494QiTPlFslGqSTykRgI8r+8MNlAZvdHxI3HnyhjqZwGSBeNP25YnonLu94I1r+7BnOUSSJkzdVZkVc7aAMGZhiuyWHapTKppjVzbpfdEn8TD3KYWcnxAD1NAhITfm9ymWn935MHayvpf3msc6VLYNJt3c4MWw8EjPYDehCHOXb8r6SkjzQGn01wAio1g12i4X+mfLG8lw520KkWi1W0okhi/lYW+kmqhZ+cKZdpo53OD4nRACkeBxjJO30wg1QwW1jnoD5sm8QFBAw13XEsQU0BpuDaYGAZPVsnmelGKQYnIJds/4EuiLwi9D3+exgGBptp8AGI6bJRXfg9AhiAakAPFwQW7ou8q5LukFGms+7rt/za21v8/7fPehLSU+ZxujGc1L+oFYewo7EgTRCipGYbTuRIgSRKBY02aKmQJLQmxaBEjVu64HT0StpdLNfGTfbbIZTh/sZ/MEF8PxQE7cIeOo3DnGCP2fAYv3ma573R2f0Ok6Ldtx", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indians lacking historical sense and chronology,Shaping early history narrative of India", 
		"option_b": "Indians ruled by despotic leaders no political unity,Justification for British colonial rule", 
		"option_c": "Indians indifferent to worldly matters due to spiritual focus,Undermining Indian achievements", 
		"option_d": "Indians devoid of nationhood and self government, Support for British administration", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ28et3aVU7d9f3+jVqLKZ+P6ib5/I1WIgxto8X7Jr6Ti5BMdiqtU552LYjcAaoJhz5CI2ef+wX9Vc+9Knolz6toXdedUwy+0K5alh8PWTBaJRfo1El1LwuNt", 
		"answer": "24G3KJzy2hyq9sUjUw33hfvwJyvDDGEYonPDQKZyf2PuR+fDYOm+2pJ9IRGOgk1+4HjLpqvktawHGGR9MYo89xbMV7r+79A=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjy31nZ9I0vXh/g1r3oNGXEBmZRt3DDQKZyf2PuFI7MauT/x9diKF+AiE9isnfIp+Xi8lAAgbtP+5ucZGILd5h7x8KQl/D4hGJUI9ZLiJQy95UcdfVMjC+octvJLe0uz2CEZ1b1az/wA39ikSPYh3lYvMG6qfji/NvHa9qdaIT/uasa", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To glorify the colonialist distortions", 
		"option_b": "To preserve the caste system", 
		"option_c": "To advocate child marriage", 
		"option_d": "To make a case for social reforms and self-government", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrp/4osUwyywPDvPWrDCngUpz+XWqY0dWnqR7PHYO77iZh3Z06MnU55/n/FsOXx+VdPnK1X78OYfzQGbIVizd6dl+35hHBPMM9BlJQyzZQbdfUfjvy/lmHk0akrpt+Z6+3oEVg=", 
		"answer": "256IKLvyyBj54IQsEOqd0HP3DPFoLgpAKDHfN6U=", 
		"explanation": "256IKLvyyBj54IQsEhv/1fX+JmLKBmZRsXqTR6F4eXLwFKbMaq3tzJt3aluGm15p/HvDrbGw/l1PjqZY4IuRZGIqcI9myZCd3/b40XZJc85NicBl64gUPMgC5DSjcMGbEPFix3qZZR8zPZjUJVsKjlWhy22IWlo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Vishwanath Kashinath Rajwade", 
		"option_b": "Hemachandra Raychaudhuri", 
		"option_c": "Ramakrishna Gopal Bhandarkar", 
		"option_d": "KP Jayaswal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020116", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hh1Brl+ZY0QAvx0fj7dX/YBiIZqmyXXbFtMH7lFKbMbeT7x4MxDlKNhFo79GTJruXk/1ZPraBa+4+LcWJLU4pnydKB1vb20HAIc9FFiMBm69oLdPEA6yi9YNWbJfN+x3yFYFawYje5WzJRUT2pt5vbjjMRu2/psFFv", 
		"answer": "2529ZZDw2Rjk85chEizz3P73NH7UC3cDqj0HmcF+U4F9iAUFmVOYsBsi", 
		"explanation": "2529ZZDw2Rjk85chEizz3P73NH7UC3cDqj+RV6B7fmL3RrLBeuj6iZZ/JFWMg08723jCqqT+t1sGnLxU+5ffdjAMc8t7wNXJ9ez21nBVMoZTm5Iy8JVfaPxFjBq4ZMDaYPtj3meSIgLjJzyzADIkIwKTL7rpHqhClsOU2I23", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Devdatta Ramakrishna Bhandarkar", 
		"option_b": "Rajendra Lal Mitra", 
		"option_c": "Hemachandra Raychaudhuri", 
		"option_d": "Pandurang Vaman Kane", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020117", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrp/4osUwy11r3oOnnbQ2QeoGqQV6c0f3+jQK/HLuX32oN+NUXJgl075n7D45bx41IZjqBa54+MPGI1f4J8wN6Iwe3kyT0BMshA2oF28pUcfeBFyH2+e9fSIfIu3GuGKFf9dGb/r7XHHKNDQkctbKpihBbmTQ==", 
		"answer": "24e5ZZD4wxD5/4shEjn91fzzdUnYAmwVom2IU7E2bdPkMb0v6fjwvUKrcAEqeg==", 
		"explanation": "24e5ZZD4wxD5/4shEjn91fzzdUnYAmwVom2IU7E0dn7gQbTHaq3xx9dlL1nJvlpv82DHq6T+9kBDz55a4J2XfiMVd5hihJCI2eC3xXVXPMVFjoV2pIkQf/1BwH2/cdLUMvN9jnqINUrlYDH9DHln1CPTmXlXuoCztwX/b2aB+sExHXYAHzuLDzU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Rajendra Lal Mitra", 
		"option_b": "Vishwanath Kashinath Rajwade", 
		"option_c": "Ramakrishna Gopal Bhandarkar", 
		"option_d": "Pandurang Vaman Kane", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020118", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV175wOS/NmTeF3AYoWqXW6x6MH7lFJHpLt//w4BwI1nOnhtp92XDorfz/wxNHHSez/2+ag/gUVtlW9ywmw==", 
		"answer": "24a9aYPw2RDk8MUmXQyy9vzxJmDCCnZRrn6NR7B3YnjzQLSCZ+O+5JZ5Jk6InlNv4HeEDLrkmY9hBWlEMFDkUdEOwA==", 
		"explanation": "24OTKKPy2w7r84BnQV7gwO76NHnTCyIYrWmMXrVxdDHwUabQbeX3x5AxIVObzWh6/GXNsazkt14Ogb1I6pyWYDYQPoJhiP2I3+XlxWJJJ9RF2oF84NoPafZMxS6lfdrcYOpmy2PMZ0b/aS2vDXJhgDjYjTxCp8OW9DW6QNI2gB07hZN3/9F+cGQf/2r3K8GsojiAIgKUtg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Reconstructing the history of the Satavahanas", 
		"option_b": "Advocating widow remarriage", 
		"option_c": "Searching for Sanskrit manuscripts in Maharashtra", 
		"option_d": "Criticizing Ashoka's policy of peace", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020119", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ28et3aVU7d9f3+jVqLKZ+P6ib5/I1WIgxto8X7Jr6Ti5BMdiqtU552LYjcAaoJhz5CI2ef+wX9Vc+9Knolz6toXdedUwy+0K5TvKPt3jm+JKkD0Jy2yRH11nzSWizxVqZC+tSG0RpoI/yoNqbhH0vcDfNaR3eiA7UG+ywGNyn6DRrBhH0DbGfU4LSvF2k/6TRH6JJ/TuA==", 
		"answer": "24a3a5jy3Vn48oMvQBPhh8r+/wCI4uyopWTKrGqnE9s=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjy31n59I0vXh/g1r3oNGXEBmZRt3DDQKZyf2PuFI7MauT/x9diKF+AiE9isnfIp+Xi8lAAgbtP+5ucZGILd5h7x8KQl/D4hGJUI9ZLiJQy95UcdfVMjC+octvJLe0uz2CEZ1b1az/wA39ikSPYh3lYvMFgSewE/+49CACAJf0uo/ja", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "So,ci,al re,fo,rms", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020120", 
		"question": "24e5ZZD4wxD5/4shEjn91fzzdUnYAmwVom2IU7EzYzHxUbTHb//9wdd3KF+cnl5/snnI47H48hMHhrtP5pyGMC0FPp9nzZC26NvI+05+DPl71sBE5ZMMdPpB2jS+eZibIfBqjm+EMUrzZi24ADBnmzLfi3AWuoa9+jW2R5ict8vHNGby1qFbM3/g6Sb7", 
		"answer": "24a5fJDl0BHr+YQzEBqA52aMBtLElvrjeuRASR8=", 
		"explanation": "24e5ZZD4wxD5/4shEjn91fzzdUnYAmwVom2IU7EzYzHxUbTHb//9wdd3KF+cnl5/snnI47H48hMHhrtP5pyGMC0FPp9nzZC61vD20nBJMshFicwy0psWb/xOzSukZ9mXYP9gyi6BI1P/ZDipAXQ0hz7Vg31a6JG+8yipWcl1CRo9njTayBz4C8R7MzLEUQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Sa,ta,va,ha,nas", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020121", 
		"question": "256IKLvyyBj54IQsEhv/1fX+JmLKBmZRt3eGEqZseWL3UanBa63xz9dOGGO2smREzUn546T+8xMciqRdpImQZicRcIZqxsTJ3uq3xX9COsNKjsBb6p4WfbRUxC+iYdPTYPZn3S6XKFf7JwX/LHl6kCSWunNaoZeit6lbJoKKWJQ/y6987ywe2Rk=", 
		"answer": "24e9eITx3RDp5Mf0fN030fP8pjdmQuGIE9y6", 
		"explanation": "256IKLvyyBj54IQsEhv/1fX+JmLKBmZRsXqTR6F4eXLwFKbMaq3tzJt3aluGm15p/HvDrbGw/l1PjqZY4IuRZGIqcI9myZCd3/b40XZJc85NicBl64gUPMgC5DSjcMGbEPFix3qZZR8zPZjUJVsKjlWhy22IWlo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Re,pu,bl,ics", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020122", 
		"question": "2529ZZDw2Rjk85chEizz3P73NH7UC3cDqj+RV6B7fmL3RrLBeuj6iYN5IhyBhEhv/WTf46r2t1IBjKFe55rfWSwHd4ovzsKG2qTjzHQBJ89Jn8B94toLdPEA7jWsZtXPIb4m42+IJkf4Ziu8EHE91CbXmDxCp8Ov/SL7UdQzgBo01pNw6IgbKceL2OiW5V2xlAPOnGyZQb5sUV2K9c+4+1GTuIs1tNmIvSub8ub2l7jH+NtLdg1cq44/YF6yg70b4WoacoigZ1Jf+eGQXmvSHxecGDEixovg03p905AwHUgQtoBsKwhDlYUNVILAjK6kCpw=", 
		"answer": "24axcIX7k3wpaM8zngCdDqoZPSuJZn0=", 
		"explanation": "2529ZZDw2Rjk85chEizz3P73NH7UC3cDqjiQErR7YnqjV6jUa//7zddwKV+AiFVvsl/Ip6zx+RMHhrtP5pyGMCQRcYYv3NiMl8b/xWNAJ8cEjYFgpI4QPOBIyX2oetCbL/gu2maFZ2Lldy28RHV5hDjEjzAWu5e05TeyWt131xwmnsds5c18L96HzaDT60i2khOQxTuwbP/p5YfyEmdIvfOvZsuKJrh8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Si,xth,ev,th", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020123", 
		"question": "24OTKKPy2w7r84BnQV7gwO76NHnTCyIYrWmMXrVxdDHwUabQbeX3x5AxIVObzWh6/GXNsazkt14Ogb1I6pyWYDYQPoJhiP2I3+XlxWJJJ9RF1sBx65QLbv1C2SmketObNPEu8VG/GHrPWAaCOzB8nSLChW5P6jLZ/Z0PfbaAcPE4chh2k/U=", 
		"answer": "25i5epDn2Riobv/ztHTHT03t+aIoTx7AEA==", 
		"explanation": "24OTKKPy2w7r84BnQV7gwO76NHnTCyIYrWmMXrVxdDHwUabQbeX3x5AxIVObzWh6/GXNsazkt14Ogb1I6pyWYDYQPoJhiP2I3+XlxWJJJ9RF1sBx65QLbv1C2SmketObNPEu42+SJlH4Znm1DWNgmyPPyPN771cbV34vIzCT5zUA7wY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ma,ra,tha,the", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020124", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMGXrUefBYePq255zMkiAglVosnnA44z+81oOgehI6oaQfCMRbct7x5Cd3+G312VUN98ElYYy5ZQcdfFO2H2EetDSIfAuxmeTM0rifmOBCkx6xX/ki3FXo5Gy5i+1VZoQzwUzmsda5ckyONaN0qmBqF20hx+H2DuQCK5tFlqQs8er6k2I4JA3ucjNuDyb9fDvlfvS5NcFZUhUsJQ/d1O516sI6z49EdutewZO/KTRb1CtIyCqKwpd9MrxxH1owYcVU1U6plFwqcNkY8pk15zh/DcoK8hkBjqspkhZh4NuUAOTNLy6333woHg+Z3s/bYsttCQmtQCOMRR8m3iZSGxemsBj98NZgRZia2pMjzbhjDvLkmCceZLx6Ii8jOawjbhr87EmOkmUJ13kWLESNv3wJml23/uaA6EcBZ5qFiymFtQg+X7qYIGbzTJBkOViB3704CWLi436PyWuu5e5qtx3BrIBJdDW/dm2/GCFITPzLmuaYs7wGQH+XHX/2xp29xEr3C5Q6WzbAYxx4W0ekX25SEgknib3fzygmLoc6Zeda4E8wLcd8Pi43pp1a1MqeUgcluk+", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12Av548UzRh/mwPD6O3+QCnFRqnGAXbFmdXL3FJXDY+z1255iL1KIzXx04nfK44f49l0LjrpQ6JzfcSEXa4pjxMnJ1uDhy3JAJ8NA2oZ99toMc/dJzTHtZtHdL+xjgi6JKUb8cj20Cnc0lyPfnnVVoZmy+yD7QNIygBYzhZN9rdslL8Oa1OiS5kn4hQ6L0H/RRbx2A12Yssvo30uZ4JE9tsKDtXLI4PXtn/XW/spLaxsSvoV8dkm9g61JzgF4Y8m+fxNP9KTUaFCtKSanIgsZud/x12JsysI9VXs74RhOjZZCIu1y3pn2vSE4K99rVSe140NB05x5TVeefa6s33rt41QzNWkkcJhuuT51oAGYaENslX+ZDClJgIVl7dkPkAh6PW5Ck2P0whKKkmSbdJKj44nvkefiuflX+qZnPUmJJ1iYRZkdcbbNImlmiuCITadQIJAnFiHlKMcv6Dy5EJea2ywf0dcnb0Hm+SuX0ub0N2D9oNLugcZ9VLkPNcTW7M/3v1KHYC3iKHidcovnVgv5TnC43w9ypFgkxiVQ63fLHIZy5m05lnuiTEJrgCKsLHOxgrdT5MKsP4cik+Hk2HITl+ZqmpjjlBwyVBO+nz1PMVxUS0P4imnmJTDeDhPb", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020125", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMFjtUK7DYK3typ9+K12bnhw74nPUsLX19EcGma1IqYGRMDIMcoJ7wdOI26T/zWJVPNRd2olhpJkQbuZFzyn3SNrnLq8g52CELkT+Jyq+DH94lSPFymxXoYf75i68WtMxyRYzmJM47NwoOdmL0KedqFm3xieO2WOQRrlhAxOK9cem/UKPqY029cSD8SbT8f3r2vDa48oEcAFRvoo/dEm1g6EH/zkEX/S6Olxv9PLUYED5IWiRJgMc8tnqxXxnx8ILVWg68B5UiYJEItdyxdjlsnI1L8RtBzKqq01T09RrVxjWZK+x3Wn26VkmNW05ap5o/Cw3rhqIaHFriGSMSS1f1Ihi7cQWhx1fc1NOzzjLsn+hgXyOb4Ti58D/jen8rLxt9aYjaVWIMBzWWZkVar2AKGEy4+efBKdSc5tiBDLpKdw98Xn4LpLU1zAK2NUpKH/z8S7ZhsXweWCiuoHti9p1Ef8PMJHX7NuislDOYjChKHPTZ8X3UA3+Wzzs2gNgpFpWfahx5t9/afIDBby64fNg", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12Av548UzRh/mwPD6O3+QCnFRqnGAXbFmdXL3FI7MauT/x9diJFSGgVpp4TbCqqGw+Vwbz61W+YaeYysZe8tOxNWR1urzwWMGIIZNlJZz95MQcrRB332gYdfTYP99jn2PKkCwaC21AWI0lSLGj39Cu8O082ezXckjzwcr1rNw6IgvOdSQ16zT+1m5kgOP2XWFCLR3UV2XtsG6+UaftMIcsNuJsCbP9bTLm/XS+8wCcQBcvsZda1qyk6kb8ysqEd+1e1JK/6TVcV3qMimzLwcO7Yv03nsp0ZAmSWx09R1Jl5cWY85w353qqHIZMcljFD36s0tMzoB1XBaaNLS2w3zt9EArfHUldsYtsiIh4SqJOltun2qSDCRYh5Rk7MlZoQxmPXtIlWTkwiyfgXGKcZbt/8D1lqjxo7p24KIzLAGrBRzyV5QddqTBKyd7xO2eCKIcMJdmGy7jM9Ir+HntKJPU1j0I0ZkvKTfO+i6Qk8O1PWCpo53th8d7VL4OMpHE+8yitViHZyzzYWmbY4vxQQHjW3n20AsluB5l2iQA/WDUAYpstSQD3n++Sk1hnDOgRXKln78c2Y3Oa4Y0k+b43CYVlfF2i9uklBIySx37jnBRoIGcWx45ap2GoC7a1jj8a+XhLFXk", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020126", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gexD2zPzxdXjTC20dom2QEqV1c3TnFKTKb+HyzJl2Ik/JiU5+smLJ46b/+1wBhqlXqYqWYzYMbJ9mx96al+X5wDFSPMVNn5Rz6Nocc/pU3jy+YMebIvt62WuFKQXZaT20BTB1mjWWqG5fvIKy+xu1aNQFxRQhmYkireszMNiR0KmfqF+tigPCzn6CXbFwFFDZvMDo70qPtI0qociJ8SLU5uDrm+HS/M1LbQ4Sloh7alqy16AA6z43Q9H4KBNF9aTEaVGtJCGlIQsP/MXg02cpxIc9Smwx+l9vjIdfY4dglp7hqTYxM415GjCzplBZh5VyW1e0ZrSs0WHqp0Z/ZWgkYphorz48twrcK1Vuk3+dQCVCgMB48dMQkBB6PWxSmXf0hzvLgSWceZ3w7sDzg6j0qap34KY0OgGBOFPWUc01a7fJJmky2eqTAqpdIYwlNH2giuAHQvyP8GNVUNaMLw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhaqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgElYYy8JIaPPVT3zi/YN3ULrzqQuThvkUBrerE5DivBQ0s", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I42yXU7dxYzH3XKbWLsTwzZ5wKRyajlN0/nfUsOX29lAKi+hY4Y+TfCcNeY58iNSc0qTjyzFCPMpLlIlz6NobdedUwy+5fdvVM75vwGrANErzbjypBXw0lz7Ynm5Xu5eotROzUZolxRQhmYk4/dozKt6b3LvT6UP4hwWByWmQXLgkFEyJuc+m6leVr4x09cye8THU+Pv3k/nfsMwebg0Su497I1Kyk60M/Go0VMmwKAZEseDZckDiMjymI04L/Nnw33tn1cImWykd+htPg40Waslgwpf2pX5wPsNuVSeypgREzpJ6WgWTer69wyjt7hUsenkiYJ5ssG0muByILVlt2miTQjhDnYJ+6tUd1RBsPXtImTbzgTeEjGSdb9Sj74nvkfr1s6ohjZKe2QsUJvz0xRrCU7IYKQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is NOT a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020127", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geS6y7/zmNHjHAm5RoHeCXq9xfnbmUOfWZui+x5hlLlOHzVR9sl/Ip6zx+RMLirtL5pqWYy9Df4VriNiA0Oz7zXZJJ8NA2pR64doaZP1T2Dijd9GbL/gu3GuQMkf8bjquRHl61DDYiXVTppf74S62UckLzik8pIJ5/scyZpe06ei56VS5lRGD0DuGSa4kEBSRvN285FGVoYx4osWC8TTU9+Hqn/yT/9BLRx1AsJZ6YlX8h6cF8T4xUsm4KAFS4vDVbEetMim3LwsPud/r13op74wtVGg6tBdPkZdZcNkxyZ3hwudgLreI1baZ7OUO9A==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+QRqJgdWKjf5eCROznyIRmJlDOnht4/XjSsazy4kcGgKZIqZqQMCELf4djzd6O3urwhGVJNoZKlZR765Rfc/IA5TOpfdXVYPpr3X6PM0zjanm8CnQ0nDjRgnBfr4uv/Cm8FM4/xVU3jo5r+c0yP9Lf1q7T+kiokwSO1XiCCLRqUVWXtset5VfciYw8vMzNhTretOb8m+vc/p4CcUhbsYVwcUm5lLxFuCsrEeK1cRNY5uXcIUPsM2iqKQoY/M+j1zRhz5E9Uns99REGlYtZIsZ81Y33uTZwMMMqPD2+qkVOh5x1TAOZZqT0kHjl8kE2dm8nZJhhpW0hqQrcOFtyk3+VTy1d1JNy7cQcmBcjcmkAnXjjizqFlCWmcpfq6sIor59QbRsZSD2HweRjJKaP", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is NOT a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020128", 
		"question": "25mxe4WzgEOq34wzRhHgzP7+OSvjAGoer36RQeN1fnWjd6jMev/3y4JlLlOHnhs2slrPsLGwpQlPrrtI5o2WcTYGestMx96dxe310WVIPMhX2LMc3WAYgPC1hffMdTgI7EQ=", 
		"answer": "24e5ZZD4wxD5/4shEjn91fzzdUnYAmwVom2IU7E0PTHCULHNbezqzJMxIVObzUh08X/Hr+Xi8lUAnaUb6pyWZCsAd5FqzJCK1vfjwTFSKtVQn40y5ZQbPPdIxTGpNNnaMuxnz2mFawXUYi+5BWRglXHki3FXo5Gy5i+1VZoVyBQ8koZq5skufJrf/6eQ/V69gkaN0ju4RrltEFrZpcGk4leVo4M09cSDoibS4OHtk/fd454KbAwSvoh8al6yg+gB8TksXtqtKBxE5aT1dEbiMC2iKU4V8Nj32WZwisIZXGcw4Q1HjIQWVMF+15aklzM+Oo0nVRKvt0xP1ZF4HxqZeqi11Wbw4Vl/YnU5bspism00rwyVLVpq2niTTyVQmMBn/8cK1QVteS9DiWX0jTKYzCWkTNPJ6pn9lv/xrPkusoAvKE2MMFLfU4lccbvFZ2l93uCUA+ZTNd9OGSbvPNtu+DzqMJmA1ioAkNguKzfv/S2RnsTyMXG/t9Lri8RjFrMJNcKF4MX3sVLEaCbvNT2Hb8bxSkoB4QNVvNNAk4nkptzHzKPd", 
		"explanation": "24e5ZZD4wxD5/4shEjn91fzzdUnYAmwVom2IU7E0cXX1W6TDeuj6iZF+NRyaglhy83qGsaD2+EECw+hY+4eLeSEKZI5riMSB0qT0xWJVNoZXg5Nm4ZdTPPVOyH2ufN3XJL5jz3ySLkT3YnX9E3h9lzmWg28WpYa14S60Wt8zgBw81oho+cEzMpe95aa37Vu8hxKW3TujSbBlGkaQpsam6gO+qIM2scyfujPJtPL2me3A9dpLbQYSloh7alqy17gG9CMsWMu1ZFJC//fEaED4NCGsKR1d+MXnlnVnxYssU310/BZVloxEe4wz2Jfw/BclLcJ6EDK040xJ1IBzTQ7aNKqw2WvsoFwsNWk/ZJ5ouG08r0+TOEB3lWXcbRBfpIFl+sULlApkPVlBkXfuwhSKjmDPfYb344/ugOywoflu/a0yJESOIV3UFpoTd7iAKGkyy+eYBKNSJ990GCHvPNlu8DjuM9aV0T1N08wzO3jq52bZhcX8Om36uoG5i8xmGL4JONTBqcK58FPXdSruLz23WsXfaUjaTmX5wBlku1gmwCAc5GfWD4x7tTkFmz6+RlBtnSmgY3rhv7BY44OAP4o0wOXjyTsDlbR5kZ+33BQ7TwiyindXt4DfXVlf2FbaF84UhAAgTLUPF5/U/HnWgX/dTm9BP8/lQbuTwjhN3qP4gCFyr4QHWoLODVtTVBqNxATntKCZAVjHLzN7", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ramakrishna Gopal Bhandarkar,Advocated for social reform criticized caste system and child marriage", 
		"option_b": "Devdatta Ramakrishna Bhandarkar,Focused on Indian political institutions and ancient history not European history", 
		"option_c": "Pandurang Vaman Kane,Authored monumental work on ancient social laws and customs", 
		"option_d": "KP Jayaswal,Challenged the notion of Indian despotism and highlighted republics in ancient times", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020129", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrr44AnXQzrhfL5dXjTC20dom2QEqJwf2H3UaOCb63syIN4KFKIgVJo5jbHraGw+FEFiqtP4JiaMCMTbplgydOBl/D403BTN9UEiIVx65QMaOZVzymketObIfBtx2uOMwXZaT20BX40nDjFnnNEsdz5GzweyR7W+tJX7r8/PQmgRQ==", 
		"answer": "24a7YJ7/0Av5t5IoXV7wwPH2MH3VByIYrT+rW61wZTHxUbHLeOzywIR8ZbYAfgNnY1SRYSUXn05EIoE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYP2kQ7v5YBgQR36yvH+J3iQFGoe436HXbNgdXWjVefQb/n3xplwK1WamRt6/HKGrKf68lAbhr5eqY+PYDAMf4hniNGF2Orw13hFNoZQko9h4doYaf1EyTntds2bLv96x2GOJkn5dC39DXRxlSKWonVYrJb75yKtXcw2zBwhm8dx/og9fNqQz62e7UOsxhKK3W/RW7hhGkfZocHo+UaKqZQ99cyDtXLJ8eLwjvnf+cQOIiBbsYJqakix14EduCMrEceyfBdFseXDclvuKSm3Igpd7sL33jRohoYsTmAm8V9SjcNGcM9n05vw/Bo5Mcl/HCC340JSyJk8WRiEcbS/3ijt7lMzYH8lZo9+/razKJjftnwWTlXZ9AbcQks=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Scholars who received Western education", 
		"option_b": "Scholars who believed in Hindu revivalism", 
		"option_c": "Scholars who focused on social reforms", 
		"option_d": "Scholars who advocated for self-government", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020130", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut7chXx/51/TsPWXRQ0Ues36PEoF8cX/nVbXJb/++yJNnKF+ImV479HnU47H45VwaiKAb4YeMMDAGbY5u2tOB0veohtjuWgNCe3x2xd71iifkOfo=", 
		"answer": "24WqbYL2ww/r44wvXF79w73+O2jZBmwF43eGQKpgcXbmFjLIYsfzDggx8uiDAHzzcH0=", 
		"explanation": "25ewaZ/30Avh9pdgUxrkyv7+IW7UQ3UYp3CUErFxfXDxRq7Daei+yJl1Z1+bhE9y8X/cpqGw41sKz6ta+pqaMDEabZ9qxZCI2eC3x3lIP8IEl4Fg9pMee/ECR7UVmJAmeEJmaRYLAGNEbQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Preservation of ancient heritage", 
		"option_b": "Rejection of Western education", 
		"option_c": "Caste system reinforcement", 
		"option_d": "Widow remarriage and social reform", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020131", 
		"question": "2529ZZDw2Rjk85chEizz3P73NH7UC3cDqjiQErR7YnqjUqjBe/77zdd+KRybiFh0/GXSsbDz41oBiOhP4YvfeCsQaoR90ZCG0aT2ynJINshQ2ql84JMePPJSwzDtY9zSI/Yu2meNIgXgYiu0C3Qr1hI98qcNMAnjF+6gnbUwiDo=", 
		"answer": "24WqbZn6wg3l5YwjEjf8wfT+dw0q0cfl6rhEpf5ZSdjGwvs=", 
		"explanation": "24e5cZL70Azu/5AyW17gwP7wO3jEEXcSt3qHErd8dTHrXbTWYf/niZh3Z12HjlJ+/GKGiqv0/lJPibpU5M6LeCdDaoJizZCG0aTjzHQBEc5FiIFm5dpXUfVIzT+ldcbaNP8njnmBNQmwcDG0B3g0nSKWnnRT6Je++zOzFNkyzgEnhJ44z+t8KNjfzaCWqEi2gkaN2juFQLgkNkGJoc/o7k6MqZA99/TwQ1WraGzNzVp0exFHV8M=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gupta empire to the present day", 
		"option_b": "Prehistoric India", 
		"option_c": "Indus Valley Civilization", 
		"option_d": "Bharata war to the Gupta empire", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020132", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut6wuVhfzy73sNmPfD2MDsD+GX7N8cWLqTqKCY+LszNdlL12HzXp3927HraH15RQcz6FV/4+MeS0NPoJhiMSB0u3lhGZTOtJNlIdhu9gtcKTxbZCvp56VPXzlzzzY", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/3wxjt4pU0U17fxOjtLGqXECIYrWmCQap7fjMeO/dOcypyO4xxJZyJxrNM", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjy31n59I0vXh/g1r34NH3VQ24UsGzDW65kf2P3VanBa63qxtdQK1mRjFV/92SBsOX5+UUOnKFU586efiZDe4Z/wNGa3v7ywDFVO8MEnolz6JUYafEAwzvtRNvJNe0u2WeULwXRazylBX5wkSOWi3JS6KCz9Cm/Rtsw1QUml8dV7N0uJdbYyuif4U+9lAeW1XSfCLJiUVqWp9qgplSZs5Y9p8PNmDzf/fW5nOrc/Z44ZwRXqoVqcBlxRwXuydVr0xlgo37Z+Gk9", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Alexander's strategy", 
		"option_b": "Porus' dialogue with Alexander", 
		"option_c": "Chandragupta Maurya's invasion", 
		"option_d": "Ashoka's policy of peace", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020133", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut64QEjTz3PzsImrcRHFRtHCRWeNIMlnqWqPXLt3xxZ5lPmDLzV108WPV46r+qBGY+d2xOqMmgKCDel2yojtO", 
		"answer": "25i3bJTh31nk9pEpXRDzyfTsISvZB2cQsD3IjY+qvbMhu/D+dcEf8Oay", 
		"explanation": "256IKLvyyBj54IQsFQ2y0vLtPivsQUoYrXuWEpN7fHj3TZuALujm2Zt+I1mNzU9z9zbLurH4t1wJz4FV7YeefmIHe5h/x8SAxOm3xX9Fc9VMlZd34NoLdPEAySWkZ8DeLv1rjmGGZ1f1dyy/CHl3h3HfhDxXpoCy8CmvFM4+zRAh1pBx+cB8PZeS3KmA/V+9xgmEnGiURLspFluPsNym5kaStMB1pDYS4OB6sqBmdhzGhRp5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indian despotism", 
		"option_b": "Modern nationalist ideas", 
		"option_c": "Early Indian society", 
		"option_d": "Republics and self-government", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020134", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhHj8ZFgWxCyzfTsIWTCCmEQrz+TV7FnYHTgQK7Ua636xpJiZ32lzXl64X7HruLjt1EAgKMb1cyreCdDSYRhzNWbl9D/xWUBBMdX2ql84JMeQLYA3ji9ZtHIJfB6kSwcVRZP47uLPnaC3B5KenKw", 
		"answer": "252xb5n/2B7i44wuVV7Q1/TrPHjYQ0Eer3CNW6J4MEP2WKKATeJA9dk6/iE062SeVOCYkg==", 
		"explanation": "25e5e5ny3F75t4cvXRWyyPztPniQAiICq3aFRuNyYn7uFLfNYuTqwJRwKxydght1/XiLs6r8/kcGjKlXqYaWYzYMbJIjiMCb2PL+wHhPNIZF2pNr6YoeaPxF2DSuNMfOMuhr1y6PIQXxaTq0AX5g1BjYjnVXpsO44CuvQcgygBQ8ksd75N41MN6F2Lya50P638o5Z45KmUfPi6K/EUkrIA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Emphasizing India's Cultural Richness", 
		"option_b": "Highlighting British Colonial Rule", 
		"option_c": "Analyzing Economic Structures", 
		"option_d": "Exploring Political Dynasties", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020135", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2B3v+IkvVQeyzPP5OX7VDWEUpz+nduNff2LiWaXLKf6+yIdhNVOIjlM75nmGoqvz/lYBm+hy54qWcSxDdoJ83N+bzru1XQ2tqyxhL26GDa3wV89ang==", 
		"answer": "25Gxe5Lmwgrj+YJgcwzxzfz6OmffBGsSonPDZqZ3eH/qRbLHfa9ROrWJT44NSO76Tg7WYsNp", 
		"explanation": "2563e5D+0xCt5MUhQg7gyvz8PSvZECIVpm2KRKZwMHfxW6qCRezsxddcJk6Rykg7/3fSprf59l8GnLwb4ICLdTATbI57ycSA2Oq7hHdOMNNXk451pJURPOBIyX2pccLeLPF+w2uOMwX/YXm7C2J3kSKWi3JS6JG++SavXdU501U9kMdo/8c4KdSL0KedqnARBFGfkG+zjnQzAXA+rqI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Examining Philosophical Sects", 
		"option_b": "Emphasizing Religious Rituals", 
		"option_c": "Discussing Archaeological Techniques", 
		"option_d": "Exploring Linguistic Diversity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020136", 
		"question": "2523f9H70A/vt5YjWhH+xO/scivdBnYZrHuMXqxzeXTwFKTKb+P5zJMxLlLJnk9u9m/PraKw9l0Mhq1V/c62fiYKf8tg3tWbl/D/wTFRMtVQ2oZ99o4GPO1FzS++K5ah3HWixnheRaLSZiekWfPW", 
		"answer": "25O3a4Tg2Bftt4ouEiz3yfT4PGTFECIlsX6HW7d9f3/wFkLfDUOxqJerolqEGmYWxD0=", 
		"explanation": "24a7YJ7/0Av5t4svRV73yO33NHjZGWdRsHCAW6J4PDHmV6jMYeD3ytsxJlKNzVhu/mLTsaT8t0MdgKte+p2aY2ICcI8v3NiM3va31nRNMtJNlY4y8JVfbPtMxSmkd8eXYPJrz2qJKUKwczb9BTB5myPTyn9ZpZOp8C++Wsk+1hByno5r+ccuNdSe1eiS+F2qiQeB1DkzhBEoqUwWthuo/wgMU41c", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Focusing on Religious Traditions", 
		"option_b": "Analyzing Political Dynasties", 
		"option_c": "Studying Economic Transformations", 
		"option_d": "Examining Tribal Societies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwQz454ozV172yr3sOmbVQ1UUsGuGQK00Z2PqQKLQfa3/x5MxJFOFglVy83rPsLHjt1sOma0b4IDfdS8Tdop8wcqA2eO312VANMhFjol96toWcrRpwjmkdZPIYPZn3XqPNVyvJftPtHrf6+2OBBxPcYVlJDM=", 
		"answer": "24WqZ4Hy1hj+/osnEi3mxPrxNH/ZDGxTwm/8PvbFn1LNuIqla3wlVw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxArvt5EoV17h0ej7LCvfBSI4rXuKU+RnMGHiR7OCeuK+2YV+N12OjE9+smLOpuX581YOz6ddqZ2LcSUNf59mx97Fl/TlwWdEPdJNlIcy9IgQe+ZF3y7tddrfYO5r3H6FM1DxczCzAzBgnDTfmDxZv4379y66R98kgoASVKWNm3mhGwZ0VDTxfvU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Highlighting India's Progress", 
		"option_b": "Promoting Cultural Diversity", 
		"option_c": "Emphasizing Social Mobility", 
		"option_d": "Propagating Stagnation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020138", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwRz45JUlUQr70/i/MWSQAGcDt36KXONdfnXqVamCef/33ZJjNByBgld/smTDpKTi81oBiOhP4YvffzAKeYJhiN+Pl+P4y3UBMshA2odg4ZsLPOBIxTOqZ4uZKW/LQmQSqdKBOjtpH0GyQA==", 
		"answer": "25a9ZJTxwxj+/osnEjn+yv/+OSv5DWQdtnqNUaZnMl4S+cGfFN2/GkGl8dUDfX4=", 
		"explanation": "25a9eoXy2Beq3oskWx/8hertPH/VEXFRrn6EXKpyaTH3XKKCfOLyzNd+IRybiFdy9X/JreXx+VdPja1X4IuJdWIXdop7iNGF26TjzHhPNNUEnY994NoecvAAyy+odcCbL+xnyWeOJlH1Y3m0CjBgnDTfmDxZv4379iiuWs4l2VehTuk2Dy+aO6OCKSoYiQy5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Focusing on Technological Advancements", 
		"option_b": "Celebrating Global Influences", 
		"option_c": "Emphasizing Scientific Discoveries", 
		"option_d": "Highlighting Cultural Achievements", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020139", 
		"question": "25SUKLPywhHr+sIzEhz9yvazdVeSN2oU40iMXKdxYjHXXKbWLtr/2tdYKViAjBdHsDbUprXi8kAKgbxIqY/fYyoKeJ8vzsKG2qTI+05+DPl7pb9N26VfaPsAwjKjNOTULPd6x22BKwX4biqpC2Jt2HHZjHpTuoq18me6FMkuzQUzgo99+cE/fMSKy76W8Q23gEaD0niYTbNwUX2Xscep5QOftY4soN+I8TPV8LT6k+7a/NcRYxxbsIg9GnMZ78qXxzxhy9bCLqpA7Q==", 
		"answer": "26W3ZJjn2Brr+8diPe2BuBrw5+nvi7yfSh0Q", 
		"explanation": "25e5e5ny3F75t4cvXRWyyPztPniQAiICqniNW6V9c3DtQOfRZuT43dd3NVOEzV108WPVqqv3t1wBz7hU5YeLeSECcstu28CM1PDkhGVOc8Nciox99pMRe7ROwzPgZNvXKepnzW+MZ0Tjdzy+EGM0mzeWi3JVoYa14WeSWt4+wRtyno5r+ccuJZe30LvT/0KqjUaG2XeHTa4kGFqNuo6+6lGVr5cr9cuMsjfP57T2nLj6/toCYwYSvJNzd06ukugI9i54UsGiYR5C6+XEaFvjbGilNQsYuc3x2Xkp0oosHWs99QxDkcNZZNR22Njisyc+O41jG3O/olZMzpFuHzWEfamxw2Ck90c2YXMlYpkvlNv9UqTZEO1YEz5C9chp0A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "po,li,ti,cal,cel", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020140", 
		"question": "25GcKLr8whjn9YxnQV7z1e3tOmrTCyIFrD+CXKB9dX/3FI7MauT/x9d5Lk+dgklisn/V46z+8V8aiqZY7IrfcjtDf8tiycSMxe32yHhSJ4ZNlJR39ooNeeBB2DSiepTfJexn2GuEZ0PiaDT9EHhx1CbEg2hfpoSotSi9FOUI/yoNqbhH0vcDA5XqoXF5GDVRVxmkR2vxOuQM", 
		"answer": "2565ep2z/Bj478de6/gVgAnihgw5Lk92KLLP", 
		"explanation": "2563e5D+0xCt5MUhQg7gyvz8PSvEDCICt2qHS6p6dzHiWqTLa+Pqib5/I1WIgxtz+2XSrLfpt1UAg6RU/p3fcWIOf59q2tmI2+3k0DFIPdJBiJBg4Y4eaP1PwnHtY9zSI/YuxmvAI0Dibi+4ADByhj7bymhercOs5y6vXdQw01U9kMdT7NowfPqey7DT3EWxlUaS2WmCWLhnBV2PsI6t5lOUoZExr8ie8SbT8bTrlfTWsNENIg1RsIhwblK/16kH/GorXsu9aR4L9+vCYlH+YCGtZx0V+Nvq2HMpzos6SWYm/RxHjsNSZ9Z22pf0sTc+K94qFD2+41dPxJ15Sx6TZ/9JaD5X0tJhoIdFqTjOSK0U", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ka,rl Ma,rx", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020141", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC422GVaJmdHjtU+fWZui+2p94IUjJhFU7+n/Vt6ri/lAOg+hL7JyMYCcAaoJ5zcPJw+vgxWNFIIZFlIN74ZQLPN1OyDSsLujVHPA/gE+sZ2fxdDG8CTdn1DPZhXcWlMGP/SL7Y9U5xBAg1rNw7Nx8C9aMmYGd7ES5ukTClCrIHewtUUSLutih70aP4IN4uMKJtCDVtOLwn+/D/9cFdkhdscZ+bVi1kqYduAM2VcG1JFJO/PTYYEfkOiGtIE4U7dij1WFl0pc7XGV08h5Fh5dFIs9l04qktSYjf91lGTquqkdBy9R9TAeTd6mr7GbY7gdxNV4PJaFiryw4owbbOxR8lWSXDBAToIhuvvMQgw1vdHxBiH/vjH+EhiWucpDq7o7oxcH+pLBisqopaWmJJkjXRIQfZL+ACHJmxuCVCJoec9c2TnSzdJUv+DbpNIXU3nkA0c0lPX7m+COKho38N3G/oYLri8B3ALYPOJHM5827pVnJYiblYX+KJuD1SwSwYn3qy0IlsRcm3TIZ5mWYB4c/4SUI3nq1X0FonTftaXK11rFaqoSBbY00wLXt0zZQivF0no/+2xMvBwu9zW9RvYCKTEhGwlrqEPEJl0cZCacVEYTfsnqEnGLVWW9NccHhQb2JyjpNyPDwgm1k/5EJR4mLbA3Ti8pmyRu9Qf5sWXP4uof1ffkZD2kp9KZiiuSv9+O1cfqlbGo4Zh2+V+5N9pERbhB0HEvSEDBcabyrFpQQR+xa13vJkhQKSdfWGvK6S3gnImi1fz6hkA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxb8/oElVl7mwOXrdW/fBnFRrXCXEq5xfmXqW6mCeuX/3ddGIk+diEl1smHUqrH15UBPmqZS/4uNYyMPcpIvydeb0uG30HlAJ4ZFlowy548TaOFSzTHtcdjeLftg2n3ALkuwTje5DXE0myPfjXVYqZe+8We9RtU6gBongpRx6c18NdmZ1b2W5k69lURHsTYn+xjNbFQHzre8j11j", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020142", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gczKy5/zsPWrdRHFRoXCMWeNIMkXrUef1YeP6zIUxE1SImRtM82WGiqv0/lIzzehJ7J6NdTEGcJ98iNHJ0+HnxWNVJtRB2oZg65dfaPxFjC2/ccLaKfJnwGnAN0r8bi20B3F41DfZiWlF6Je0tSb7WdUlxVU6mYtx/tw1P5eK16yW+l6shwiG1XWWCLJiUVWXtset5VfciYw8vMyD8THO+ODsiP3v/uIFUA1TrIlxORudu+gr+TkwUMXze1JO8PbcaFH/YCGtMwsP/Nj3ln1nho8oSWwm/R5Ki5BCItB735Trrz0gN9QqBSG1rlRUwpA8Vx6bNKm3kG3p8F0+ZnMxYMp5tCh1pBeMJFtsm3+VQyIRm4Yr6NELnAt2bi9GnXXllizLj2PPfZ3g4oXykajZrr1q861nKlSMIUnKU80ad7bFZ2FgxeTbD69dIJp0VW4Gd0uuXKXtR0/aY9EQAgo=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I43eKVat4eXbrQLSCT8G+65ZiL12Eykg74X7PpbGw41wYjrpf+s6eMCwMcMZ/x9yAw+30xX0BMtZUiI9z55JfdfoAxDS+NNbUL/Uu8iy0L0CwUDazAHVm1AXei2gWn4KotQ61UNM2/Fdyoo99rdo5PcSQ1+iD+kKujwKHzzuQCKtlHV2d9cuw+0+droMsvMKD/XLa57Txk+uT+dAfZxpXrJI/alX8mqkd/TgxUMS9ewYL4ezZbVv+LzirPk4R8MDm2m0pxY0nSXs99gpSh4cWds8z3pH3/DY1LMR4EHO8rFYAxtRxUAWTNL633Xj25V06e2kic48tuTUlrQCOKUB3lWXcQyoRlY5o99UXgURKc2tJnXiggSqHlHCdedHqZcY9+wTLzk/2PepCOJ1o", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020143", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdjqy7vLsNGbSCiUC436TQrF7cXLrFLPNLsTwzZ5wKRyBhEhv/WTf7+Xi+Fwbiqwb4IDfcWIOf59q2tmI2+3k0DFIPdJBiJBg4Y4eaP1PwnHtZMbSL+xn2meaIlawczG4RGJ7mDSWhXoWrYC0+yi2Xdl3xhQxgohq/og1MpeM0amD4UO/xgeM33KURqkkOFqdvM+mq1CTo4s9odSxvw7VxvH4iffdqp4vRkh5sJV+blm10LtJ+iU3WoiIKjNFsc3edUbiJD2gMwcS94v32TR9zodpbn0h8AYGjYUWS85335nq/Bo5LNllByqG4QRBy517UQTWY7Ss2CjP4UczNVcqd5Iqr20iswaIIVp5iSfcSSFBnIF498oQmwMjaWdF3GXphTGChmyMfZ3g7sDzg6j2r6tg97BnKE+EdU7dWowIbLzONCd9zKmLH6lYJpxzHi3ofdwgvDHwM4KbzTAO0dVgK3Lx8SaWgsDwN3H4p8LnQxcxWcAxYDjVi/tIJg==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I43eKVat4eXbrQLSCSsm+4phiJlGLhBxosnvHt6Di/lIDhrtPqY+PYDAMf4hniMSGl835wHhAPYZMk5Nm64gGMLRC2SntYNzeYOxrz32PKQX5aTqyFmJxlyXakzxFvYS88DSvR5ojyBQm1o9x/og+M9iUmbuD7U6xgA+B3XedUf1lHV2eu93o/EqIqMITtN+B8R/a5uy+ibjE4tcfawZVrMZIa1Kwkugi9zk5XMq9LwEL8PTAc1vsIyDjMA8OucLt0Hh8w4wqWG109gYGr4JEeodglpHguTMjc41+HTb6rFZJwJ1yXhvWZLyrw2nj5RU7en84a815/CgtsQOVK11qlnLcXzhQgIUr6tgYgURrdHwAnnnviX+PiXeKf4fv8sD5iPj4oapq6KY0aVWIMBzeWZ8fYKCAJml2ivueAadIOpBpBGLpO5U+7jb9NZWA1jYDktjEgu9efY1dWaeTSnZiZqA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Significance of Ancient History >> Colonialist view to Communal Approach", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/M2TTFnFRrHnDQrFxeHjwQKjQd633x9dwNV+BjF50/nnBuvqyqTSnKi4NJ7oocMbJVSzmig==", 
		"answer": "24C2bJThwg3r+YEpXBmy0fX6dWLeF2cDonyXW6x6MHPmQLDHa+O+wYJ8JlKazVp19jbSq6D55RMKgb5S+4GRfScNasmiEpboaoAWhOxQwB4YCOQx", 
		"explanation": "24WqbZn6wg3l5ZxgWxCyxO/8PWrVDG4epGbDVKx3ZWLmR+fNYK3rx5N0NU+djFV/+3jB463/4BMHmqVa553feSwXe5luy8SM06TgzWVJc9JMn4lgpJ8Rav1SwzOgcdrPbL5v3S6XIkn8JziuRGR8kTjEymhZp4+ouWe4QdYj1Qc3hcs47MY4fNuW362A/FS0gxXASL4n605SxNHsxxKbsEttiQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Studying written records from ancient times", 
		"option_b": "Analyzing historical artifacts and structures", 
		"option_c": "Understanding the interaction between humans and their environment", 
		"option_d": "Exploring religious practices of ancient civilizations", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDs8YAyVxDmzPzrMHiQE3AUq3aQRqxmeXKjR67Wa/6+z4V+KhyBhEhv/WTPoKT8t0AGm61ItswCMLHGWhkI0BeaEPSiY5wD", 
		"answer": "25O3e4L63Qqq+INgQhLzy+nsdWreByIQrXaOU69nMn0lKU2P6p0Fu2zbHat8c9Y=", 
		"explanation": "24WqbZn6wg3l5YwjEg370fjsdWrCBiIepWuGXON3eHDxVaTWa//305J1Z16QzU9z9zbWsaDj8l0MiuhU786ZfzEQd4d8iN+Pl+ziyXBPIIoEioxz6o4MMLRBwjntddrSLf9i3SLAJkv0Jy21AWk0lSPTymlFvYK3+T77UtUizhFymYk45cEwMJeM1aeD7V70xhSLyn6DSrxqGkfV9c+m7wOIpZAqtM6IonLz/eftlera898HIhtbq4NsLxuzmegd8C94Xty8bQAL+eXeZRitITqmZwwc6s7nlntnhpU7VH0g8REGj4JCZ9J615SkvTw0f8BjEjuu40xB0ZE8TwWZebS21WbwoF0+d3M/ZJ5ksyN1swqRKV1wiSuQRSdU1JRu88AVkBcjfGFE3HvvjD6YlGCddZbwqUu3gJU+Oh1cVSm/ALIEpEo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Prominent habitation remains", 
		"option_b": "Large stone temples", 
		"option_c": "Written sources", 
		"option_d": "Fossils of plants and animals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiywfzrPGXXQ28Ut3eMVuNmdX3qUbSCYeO+3Z90Z1iMjlpisnnA47fx81oAjqtP4JiaMCECbIlgxpCAxOvjy2FEIJkGGCtmCM0aaQv+bWznBlxCFA==", 
		"answer": "24e5bJj80hj49YouEhrz0fTxMik9KeT6pEhgrILBrDRBYSWO", 
		"explanation": "24e5bJj80hj49YouEhrz0fTxMivdBmMCtm2GQeNgeHSjUKLBb/S+xpExNV2NhFR68WLPtaCw9FIdjadVqYeMfzYMbo58iJiqhrC+hHhPc8dKmYl36o5fc/ZKyT65Z5TPL75qy3qFNUj5aTz9EHhxnSOWi3tT6Lez8GepVc4ygBo01oN97sklfN6Mmauc5l6xlRKH0m/dCLxoHVuOvMCvq1CfqYc2ocSepSGb4Pu5n+vH+dMKdg0Sq456I1q7kugG/mo5Q8u8aRdE/evXaFfsLGixIgMc8MXwlEpO4ONmwRv7H39nzyLFaGE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Radiocarbon dating", 
		"option_b": "Dendrochronology", 
		"option_c": "Stratigraphy", 
		"option_d": "Thermoluminescence dating", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/r9JEvQF72yvjsdXnRB2seoH6RUKx6MHXiQK7Maa3zzIN5KFjJn1536zbJreX2+EFPjqtY/JyeZCdDf4xqiNWaw+36xWVIPMgb2KPTQIQeiiSXk/RmDX0KGfA=", 
		"answer": "2525ZJe+3RDs8sUvVF7RlKm9qlEFibIbKnSTjJ4R7Mr9OQ==", 
		"explanation": "24e5bJj80hj49YouEhrz0fTxMivCBm4YpmzDXa00ZHnmFK/DYuuzxZ53IhyGixtYoyKK47L4/lAHz6FIqY+dfzcXPt46nojJzuH21mIBB85NicBz6JYQa+cA3z6kcdrPKe163S6UKAXzZjW+EXx1gDSWgnNB6I6u9i/7d4tjgB0zhcd86Ms9JdKbmaGdqEy2xgmA1n6SXP1lH1DZsN284k6dtId4vNme8TPc8bYz1qp6e8mFzVAbWUjsWIba", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Half-life of C14", 
		"option_b": "Atmospheric conditions", 
		"option_c": "Geological layers", 
		"option_d": "Written records", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiywOX8NH3RF2serT+TQKxieXXmR+fDLu7225h/KFCGilJ483qGsKDh4lYBjK0b5ojffSMXe5lmydzJ1PH70GRTNpkGajzygH+YA2dGe9SdNbX4vQ==", 
		"answer": "24O9eoX60hjmt4A4UR/kxOn2OmWSfomfd/3UlFxBB3fcad6jRg==", 
		"explanation": "24O9eoX60hjmt4A4UR/kxOn2OmWQCmwHrHOVV7A0dHjkU67Maa3yzJl2M1SehEh+smLJ47D+9FwZirob/YaaMCELbIRhx9yG0O30xX0BIMNVj4V8559fc/IAzyihYMHJJe0u53rAN1f/cTC5AWM0lXHRhXNS6Ja18SKpR842zhE7mIA44s58KN+amaub+kK2iQqN23KSSbEkFVGPsMKn+06ZrpZ4usvNvDPP8ebwm/ST88sHdh1AusZ+dxu917sA7C96b3D6LzCjWCca3m6AJZKgmw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Horizontal excavation", 
		"option_b": "Vertical excavation", 
		"option_c": "Geographical excavation", 
		"option_d": "Lateral excavation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7/yujxMSvCBnIDpmyGXLdnMHz2WLPLfuH7iZRkK0icn15osn/I47bl9FAKnLtS5oDTMC0AfYp8wd+H1uj73TFOJcNWloFi9JMRe6sCwB9h1ROfS0USAZIyWNO0sw==", 
		"answer": "25itZIX6nBr/+5E1QBuyyPLqO2+SUthLsM8cK9IGowf/m28scw==", 
		"explanation": "25itZIX6nBr/+5E1QBuyyPLqO2/DQ2EerWuCW600YnTuVa7Mfa3425h8Z0+Mm15p83qGqqjg+EEbjqZPqY2KfDYWbI58iNmHl/fix3JEINVNlY4+pJsReLRUxDi+cZTYNfJ623yFNAX9bj61EDB7lzLXmXVZpoK3+T77W8wy0hkzhsdv5Nw0fNKe2qDT51mwgxTAvorUbor2cl0HqyLqPiqXJA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Single-culture mound", 
		"option_b": "Major-culture mound", 
		"option_c": "Multi-culture mound", 
		"option_d": "Complex-culture mound", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030107", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhrj8os0Wxj7xr3yMH/YDGZRq3qPQrA0ZX/nUbXReuzwzddwKV+AiFVvsnXKqqjx41ZPjqZfqZiadycXf59mx97WleY4Ro02E+5CpP5kkVcUbZ4=", 
		"answer": "24W5ZIj93hXl8JxgGg79yfH6OyvRDWMdumyKQeo2UWOOyzGb/Bx4rMjfIZSMJw==", 
		"explanation": "24W5ZIj93hXl8JxsEhHghe3wOWfVDSIQrX6PS7B9Yz2jXbSCb63zzIN5KFjJmEh+9jbSrOXj40YLluha542WdSwXPohjwd2Iw+G3xX9Fc9BBnYVm5Y4Wc/oAziTtcczaLfdgx2CHZ1X8ZjepRGJxhzjSn3lF6Iq1tTS0XdZ30xQ/hot9/oqd/i4lFuCZJoNnWZKEUI1x", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Radiocarbon dating", 
		"option_b": "Stratigraphy", 
		"option_c": "Palynology (pollen analysis)", 
		"option_d": "Dendrochronology", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQE3cDs3CQV+N7djHuUaDDYuTqwYQxIVOcg187+3iGsKrl41tPpqZf4I/AMn8aEjHqvncTIHSM7glTSz8=", 
		"answer": "25etepjy3Vnl8cUkVx33xO76MSvZDWYYtXaHR6J4YzNj3dNU+iS+5OAQVZDPLIz4", 
		"explanation": "25i9b5D/2A3i5MUpXF7hyujrPSv5DWYYoj+UV7FxMGTwUaOCaOLsiZVkNUWAg1w75n7D46H19ldPjqRU54nfZysXdst7wNWAxaTjy35NIIoEjYVz9JURb7gA3DK5YNHJObIuz2CEZ0f1azazA3l6kyKWvnRTscOr5yitXd4ygBw8hY5/5dwvfN6RzafT/EW9xgqL2n7RR7skAVGWpcKtq0qS4JYwsI2ptDHY9fq5nOrc/Z4fag0SlpRwbRudkK1J9yQvUNqwe1DIJgFtYEJD4CsI2MX59toA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Religious rituals", 
		"option_b": "Burial of deceased individuals", 
		"option_c": "Commemoration of historical events", 
		"option_d": "Housing for ancient communities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030109", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhrj8os0Wxj7xr3+MX3RDWEUsD+CQKY0fnTgUbTRb//niZF+NRyIzVh0/2bUpq31+UAGma0b+pqKdDtDcY0v2MKM3+3k0H5TKoZFlIQy7JMMaPtS1WLv9XwrGDS+KdB/rsISD4+cIw==", 
		"answer": "25K9Z5381hDp9olgUxD2hf/2OmffBGsSonPDQbdhdHjmR+XTrCC9jUHFcdmgVhkYn+/n", 
		"explanation": "25K9Z5381hDp9olgUxD2hf/2OmffBGsSonPDU6dicX/gUbSOLuzyxpl2Z0uAmVM782TFq6T1+F8AiKFY6ILfYicOf4Jh25zJ1vbyhHJTJsVNm4wy4pUNPOFOyDi/Z8DaLvpnwGnAJUrkb3mtFnV8nSLChW5P6IK18WezXckjzwcr2sd5/ogoNNKGmaCW5F34gx6S0HqYRv1wGVHZvMC87lGdo5YxusOe8TDe4OP8n/aT+MsGYwZB88Zra178kqYf8Tg3X8WxZgYHseXeZRTiNCCmNU4R8N3q2HMpyZAuXGc95xJVwGe3HnL8lU+VhNkj2Fv/7xI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Radiocarbon dating and stratigraphy", 
		"option_b": "Archaeology and written records", 
		"option_c": "Geological and biological studies", 
		"option_d": "Dendrochronology and linguistic analysis", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030110", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/OmnaBmEFqmmGEqxyMHDxV6/Da+LyxpB4JF2FzUhv53LPpravtShbq3znHVyaJrVGHUiFu+U=", 
		"answer": "24e9a579wg344oY0WxD1hfX2Jn/fEWsSonPDV7VxfmXwFgl6/JNRbfrquSv4bv9PAX4=", 
		"explanation": "25Sqa5ny1Bbm+IIpUR/+he7rIG/ZBnFRonaOErd7MGPmV6jMffns3JRlZ1SAnk904H/Foqmw8kUKgbxIpc6cZS4Xa5lq25zJ1urzhHlUPsdK2ol88J8NffdUxTKjZ5TPKOxh22mIZ1H4Ynm8CnF4jSLfmTxZrsO29DO+RtM2zFUgk4p55MYvfNGQzKaXqEysxhCDznKeXa4kAl2NsN3qLdYRNc+vklzCcTeQzCDacw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Reconstructing historical events", 
		"option_b": "Preserving ancient structures", 
		"option_c": "Identifying geological formations", 
		"option_d": "Analyzing modern cultures", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030111", 
		"question": "24GwbdHywxri9oAvXhH1zP7+OSvDF3cVuj+MVONkYnTrXbTWYf/3ytdiLkiMnht/+3DAprfjt1UdgKUb4YeMZC0Rd4huxJCa3vDy1zFIPYZQkoFmpIoNefxJ3ymiZt3YYO1n2muTZ0r2czyzRHx1lzqWtUNpl7yEyhiEa+UIjFUlno506Ig0NcSL1rqa60y0xhWLyH6CCLx2FBSavc+66kCIpZAxr8iJ8TDCtOTrlfXa/tsFdkhBq5RqYE+pha0auCs2VYi1egZC9+XTdUevlHmJglmHTgaML1riUJ7EBQ==", 
		"answer": "2725apjn0A3j+ItgQBv/xPTxJikle0DDDIcPcdc5GArf0LAO", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxzi/pY0XQz7xr3sPH/VECIQsXrDXKxgMGX6RK7Bb+Hy0Nd4KRydhV479HnUruX/8RMfnadW4ICafjZDdoptwcSIw+34yjFTNstFk45hqNoIdPFSyTy+NNzSM+ph3GeDJkmwdDCpAWM0lz7Ynn1fpsOt/DSyVtYygAYmhJJ7+d0uOcTf2KaXqEyqkg+E3XiFW/1wGVWN9d665FWVpId4vMOeuDXT4Oe5k/bH/54bYxtG/4V2dVKwnrII7CM3X9v2IiQoj9a22kWoaVA9f2ZugA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ha,bi,ta,ti,on rem,ai,ns", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030112", 
		"question": "24e5bJj80hj49YouEhrz0fTxMieQAiISsWqAW6J4MHzmQK/Naq33x9dwNV+BjF50/nnBuumw5VYDhq1IqYGRMDYLe8tQ9++26NvI+05+DPkEnoVx5YNfc/IA7zy/dtvVYK86jiajdhG5JzCzRHF6lzjThGgWp4Gx8CSvR5ojz1U2k5N9/8U1MtLfzaCW4V/4hwGHnimfNIPdI6EgdpSk9ddOeBc=", 
		"answer": "26e5bJj80Br+/pMlED+7rMx0d7VjdbkA7X5yfIw=", 
		"explanation": "24e5bJj80hj49YouEhrz0fTxMivZECIUu2+PU6p6dXWjVbSCb63zzIN5KFjJmVN65jbTt6z8/kkKnOhP4YvfYiMHd4Ruy8SAweG3wHRCMt8ElYYyx5sNfvtOjGz5NJz4caonjmeOZ0T+ZDC4CmQ0mzPcj39Cu8Ov+me+R84+zRQmk8ds5c01Lpee3q3R1Y2B1S9Ulzk1U8kKtfXgqQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ra,di,oa,ct,ive", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030113", 
		"question": "24W3ZJ3231nr+YQsSw371r32JivRDSIQsXyLU6Z7fH7kXaTDYq3qzJR5KVWYmF475n7Ht+Xj/1YLnOhX4ImXZGIMcMtnwcOd2Pb+x3BNc/l7pb9N26UgQ8t/832setCbM/ZnyHqTZ0z+Jy21ATBxmiffmHNYpYa14Wv7XN870Bw8kcdq6Ns5PcWc0a2B+w2tiAKHzmiFSbNgUUSYptro6E+VrYMssI2Mvzab4vH+n+zS5NcEbEhCvpJrZkmyhOos1FyrSPRlPoU/5NIBCjMT", 
		"answer": "25a0YZzyxRyo3xqx8JB6CzdH3B65a+Mtrw==", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHj3hXm8otgUxDzyeTsPHiQCnFRtmyGVuNgfzH2WqPHfP7qyJl1Z1SAnk904H/Foqmw9F8GgqlP7M6efiZDaI5ozcSIw+34yjFCO8dKnYVhpI4XbvtVyzXtYNzeYP9gz2KZNEzjJza7RGB7mD3ThDxErZCy8TK+R5oxzwA8ksdx44g9LtSX2K2c5EK/jwWD0DuSR7NwFEyNpoz74WmYOOWMQf6wZnwBsZA2", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Cl,im,at,e", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030114", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fn48oQsX179w73+J2jYAmcer3CES+80d3TsWKjFZ+7/xddiM0mNhF5osnfUpuX5+VcGnLhe552eci4GPop8iMSB0v23y3dHNtQEk45h7Z0XaOcAxTO5e5TPKPsuxmeTM0rifnmyAjBLqw7ptUNpl7yEyhj3FMg4wx4h2sd548x8M8OX3LrT70i3igmF1XiQRP1lAkScttq7pwOZroo5u86EvzWb++Hr2u3d9NsZcRxTsYJ2bVz8mK5J6Dg9WcGnfB1Z6KTRb1CtKCGwMwEP4Ivi2n1iw8CXQ9rQmofeLe77cfMPEPP3", 
		"answer": "24a3YZ2xiD3kqY/MLxvxi9Tco9S0Pw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH01Bbm+IIpUR/+he7rIG/ZBnFRs22MRKpwdTHqWqHNfOD/3Z5+KRyIj1Ru5jbSq6Cw/1ocm6dJ8M6QdmIQcYJjhJCb2Of81z0BMshA2o9m7J8NPPNFwzGic93YIfIuy2KFKkD+cyrxRGd8nTLeynVF6Iq25SipQNs51FU0mZU47scxLMWa0a2d7ES2gUaA02+ZCK12FFyQptqn+VrcoYw89cWEoibU5u27N/iASxLwKJ8CPvlC69hBbg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "So,il", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030115", 
		"question": "25i9b5D/2A3i5MlgURbz1/z8IW7CCngUpz+BS+NgeHTqRufDff7xyp5wM1WGgxts+2LO46fl5VoOg7sb6ICbMDQCbIJg3cPJ1vbjzXdAMNJX1sBh4YgJebRB332kesDJKfl7x2CHZ0TiZDG8AX94mzbfiX1a6IW+9DOuRt8kgAE6l5M4+MYuPcGa1eiX7Vm5jwqRnHqTR6hwUUSYptro1Hyjn70HivKyjg3ktOTrm/vH+d0OcUhTsYI/YE6wg70b+SZ4X8emZQEHsfTRc0DkIz2vJhwR4Ivq2DR9zodpeWw39x5IwpFTZcl82NjrunIZMcljFHEbeJnUQEeq8CjJ6/J4pfTx", 
		"answer": "27etepjy3VsBtxk5XgysCymEZQLKMpeq", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+1B7r+4w0Wg2yxO/6dXjEEXcSt2qRV7A0YnTvVbPHaq3qxtdzMk6AjFdosnfIp+Xy8l8Aga9S54mMPGIXdp58iN+P0eHlzX9Gc89KiYl17I4MPP1O2DLtZNXINL5s23yJJkmwdyu8B2R9lzTFyn1YrMO44CuvQcg2zFUmhIZ85Nw1M9mMleiW+129hQ+D0HeICLRqUUCRsI6M7kCfoYx4tN+IsHLU8rTQlPza8ZyJuv40w2CtRkYXLxzQmZnX", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "bu,ri,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030116", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUMWw3mhay/ImLECyI9qmyXEvE2TCxPeoofWDpCjEeFkQPDEA==", 
		"answer": "24WqZ4X8kRHj5JEvQBfxhc33NHjVQy9RgGqPRrZmdTH0XbPKLubwxoB/Z0ubhE9y/HGGobDkt0YBi61Y4J6XdTAGest8y8KAx/C7hFxUP9JN2qNn6I4KbvEA4TK4etDIbdNh22CENAXnbi21RHx1jTTEmTxErZOp8DS+Ws4+zhJyhYJu6No9MJeczKSH/V+9lUaL0juCXb5nFEeKvMGmpwO0oZA5pd2Mv3L4/eLwlvHJ8coCbQYS8rZ6cVKzk+ge8C82EeC1ehNb4eXechTmLi20ZxkP8N/q2HMpxJc9HXo35hZWlsNEZ81y35b3/Cc+O8hpHCOyplZFw9g8dxiEfae33nzl7BUabXkqc4t5tSI77CuVL1N3lGzcQSlFnI9vvsQW1RFtfmBWmWSghzGfiXeKPJzxq439j+fi4Kli4Lc0aU6GdV2YW4IJa7eCXBCAdnZp77L4HWe+6USh9g==", 
		"explanation": "24WqZ4X8nBHj5JEvQBfxhc33NHjVQyow6j+RV6VxYmKjQKiCbfjy3YJjIk/JmlJv+jbNrarn+RMYnaFP4ICYPGIPd4BqiMSB0qTfxWNAI9ZFlJM+pJgKaLRUxDjtZ9fJKe56jnyFKkT5aSr9EX5wkTLfmnRTuoa/ySmWQdYjyVgRg4ts+No5fPqQzKaX+w3wok/C1HqHTf1oEE2cp93o+UaMsocrsMOZuDzctOL4iPHc5c1LYR1eq5NtZkj8g6AI7Go+XsS4ZwVO9aTVYFflYCe3LwsPucLtlmd8xYEsTno9+xF6jKtXcMFjxpnq/BE5KcRmHCm7t01PydQ0fF7WfLy8kGmk81YtfGo/JZ5lvTl1swqRKV1wiSuJQihUl4l79tULkAAvPX9MnXXpjDjLlG2KdYGj6JXwkf3ipflq/OMzIUTAJU7XQoJRbbrTM2hgw+rbHa5dIJpbGQrpL9w08zftIZrU+iEO0c8hO37o+mrRsIS1MGusvJ7vi8c2ELYHMdjL7oujuFmHZC31KG+WJsTmGQXxRXPqkx5kpQw2iC4WqGOYBYZq+ylNinHwTkVtnGfhLH+um65Q75aLP5s/1/D+ziYRlvBxkZy32xt8Uwy+zWxKpoHfTElD2UHEG40OykkvTKQABoLY8XialGSQW3kfdsHyQ1orFqLowwHXstSCquglQIw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Proto historic Phase,Culture with known writing but undeciphered script", 
		"option_b": "Multi Culture Mounds,Mounds with layers representing several cultures in succession", 
		"option_c": "Harappan Civilization,Period when Harappans knew writing but script remains undeciphered", 
		"option_d": "Horizontal Excavation,Digging method to uncover entire or major parts of a mound", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030117", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUMWw3mhay/ImLECyI9qmyXEvE2TCxPeoofWDpCjEeFkQPDEA==", 
		"answer": "24O9eoX60hjmt6A4UR/kxOn2OmWQTiI1qniEW61zMHzmQK/Naq3qxtdkKV+Gm15psnXOsar++F8AiKFY6ILffCMae5l8iN+Pl+fiyGVUIcNX1sBA5Z4Wc/dB3j+iepT/IepnwGnAagXdYi21C3Q0mzeWjnlCrZG2/CmyWt131B031oZ/6IgzOpeQy6+S5kS7xguDyH6DQbxoAhSMpsem7AOOoYYxusyOpTvN8bT9n/vS6ZJLTw1Vvop2d1Ov1+VJ1CsqVs30ewZE/+GQckD/NSu3MhwY6ovzxHt/z4YgU250/RFVi4RedtMz35bws3IxMc5jED2u40ZV1Z19U1eGZry7xGHn5UZ/dHQvJYl4sDkgswqPZBROlWeQSSIRtY5q8skKnBcjMC90mXXojDaalWDPaJyj+JTpgfGwobdg+6YpPQGDOVXVV5kZdvPBKWMy3OycCLJdJ5ZoGWLyNcch6T7xYIab0zUI3pknPXbu+jnbXF0EXcgpSAG6/4qTBfSnGg==", 
		"explanation": "24O9eoX60hjmt6A4UR/kxOn2OmWQS0FY43aNRKx4ZnTwFKPLaer3x5AxM1PJn15t93fK47H48hMMh7pU54GTfyUKfYpjiMOMxvHyynJEc8lC2oNn6I4KbvFTjD+0NNHDI/94z3qJKUKwazikAWJn1CfTmGhfq4K3+T6HWug2xBw9lYZq78cyfPOezaGd7w3wpE/C1WjRSf1pFECRusro/0udtMItpsie8SbT8bT9n/vS6Z4EZEhAvoJ2bFq/g6Ef/Wo7UNq2ZxwLuceBNR2tNCfjIwsJ/Nnu33pshpYhWCk18xoGjYUWbdJ015btv3I9PtlvBzq7r1d8ybl5WBaafamwwyisxBx/dGguJYZsriow4RyIJ1p72niIXjlSgJV5+8NZgBdmeS9Gk2SggCqZiWSDb9+j+5Lzk+H0qbdksqopOkiHPUjLFoQScbyAJmlxw+yVGeZfJpNzAjDjLukgzDb1LJOanxgD0dU5PH70tGK42439PGmqoNLri9d5GqwUJMTG/YunsU/TISbvN3SBacX5XAbkXDz53Qolth83wSIF5HbNGohztT0fn32kQEdhgWfidTyygqtY84uAeM4h3Png2DxQn+Z5lpXklBQyBxe+iXZOt4qLXBxOw1CWDcIOyBpsBMY8F+rsdgw8jbbhxdk94A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Vertical Excavation,Digging method to uncover chronological layers of cultures", 
		"option_b": "Radiocarbon Dating,Method of determining the age of organic materials using radioactive decay", 
		"option_c": "Megaliths,Large stone structures providing insights into ancient burial practices and cultures", 
		"option_d": "Pollen Analysis,Technique to study ancient climates and vegetation through pollen grains", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030118", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMGXrUefBYePq255zMkiAglVosnnA46Ti9FsOiqdX5omGMDYMPp9nzZCaw/Hz3TFONYZFlIN74ZQLPN1OyDSsepTTKe16wXyZZ0zjJzqyFmJxlyWMtnJqptL7wyKpQNM0wRlyk5977N49KN6Q1+ia5lu3ihCHzzuVQbpjGFqe9c/o5kyJroZ4uciDtibT4/3qn7jH/54ebAtdqYNtI0+0kugK8Dg3X8e4ZxVC8uXcIUfoMT2mKQ0YucTllnd8ypY8T2wnyBF6jNEWUMF335fnvSAyMMMqETKuqkpHh4Z5Ux6TZ/233ijw6FB/cX8oZJMtsyt1gg6OKltw1zrIDC1fkMBo/95ZlAdgaH1BiHPsm3+PgXGKPJLt/4ntkOHkqbxwsqwrLUSSdUjQV4NcMuOMdzciivCeDLRPD5FbGXGmGtAh8Db+KZWV03kM3t1gLX7o+CWem870NSWpp4f9h9FlVL4SM5HA+tiyvkjOYC+hInKedsfxVA3+W2+4xwEltgomwCAV527XD4B89CFNjHujTEV2kS+sLGyzmahV7ouAeM443ebl2joEi7RxkY/4lA0uQgyynmtMoJ3fTlJLjVzfDdkI1hBszNxuMfLXCOs5R4ca1YLpUw==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12Av548UzRh/mwPD6O3+QAG0DsXqARq9tMHXmR6TQZ+/72tdnIk6dhFh6/jbDu6bx4VIbhqdVqbqXdWIQe4hgxtTJxPD20HRMNshQ2olhpJMRf/tS3jiuYJTZJf1v232FZ1fxYzCyB3Fmlj7YynhXvIq18me4VdQ5zwFyl4R7+No9KNKTwOiX6Vm9xgeMyHKAXbRwGFGK9cGk70aO4JYwtMPN5mKXpKSp2uHW8cwYIjxausZra1Kuk+ga7CssVMWxZgYL+PeQYFfuNTqiMwtd+Nij0XFmyo0uVGo1+F9HjIcWYMl82pfjtTExM415ASa+qkFTh51yWxKTcP2732bw8lw9YG4uJZ5i/Cx1ogCROEZ7km6SXyVHkcB+8NQchxd3fGFElXjnwjCNwHWdeZvq+JTzl/GwobdnsqsuOlWPJ0Waw+V6b98B7kLDXrl4DyrO2A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030119", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMGXrUefLY/3x24NwKV+MzVR9snfUoK3x8lwDgK9CqYeRMDEXa492wd6Ol+X5x3hEPdIEs4527ZsRPPxJ3ymiZs2bKe0uzWGSNUDzc2OBCkx6xXHmmHleoZCv+jWiFMgyxhAghcds4ogoNNLfya2B4UK8xgCNzjuGQLRnGRSNvcu67gOdsod4u8LNpiDS4OD8lLjA/8sZYQ1B88Zoa1KwkugB8TksXtqtKBtYsfTCaFnsMiGvPk4f+Njm0jRmyMI+T2Ag4BpIwpFTYc9h0ovYsg4+bY1eHTb6i0VSxoRsXhnWd6i0xH325RU2ZjooaoR+tSkwswqYaERslX+TASRYh5Rk7Nka1QZmfm5Vj3OgiyuYwHaMbprz/8DugOXxqbdwsrYpLUSDPEzQU58ZYfPEInRiw/2eTa1SPIhrEibhOJUh+nnuMp+A1jcK7NccISSn1TiamszwNmm1tIu5h8c2ALcFdt7L5dL3o1PScyDkYXucdIvhVwz1XW/s0gBhvhYiiCAe62vdBp0/3CMJl3++CUxtgTPvfmXt1r9Pqo6Ha4sj0uf1nSEfjeZ7moi31Q85Bwu9mXpN8pGRXVlDxFXUEshFuJvuQcR42uB6/qj4uBp3BA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEh391+/6Nn/cGiIVpnmKXKZnMGHxUa/Lffnx244xJlKNzVNy4WLJsbyw9VIciqwb5oDfYy0WbIhq25C6w+XjwXxEPdIEyMBz55kKbvVUyTG0NMfPIepr3S6UL0CwdTy8F3961DfZmDxVp42o/CO+RtM5x1UmnoI4xckuPceP2KbT61i0khOQ2TuQW/10A1uNuoOg4lCIr5Axto2+pTPP8fn8lOyTo54CcUhbsYVwcUm5lLxJ+Tl4UNq3YBNO/ujfZk2tKTvjKQEJud/r0zRmyI4wHXo74Q1Fh88WY853lpTtqDciPt9zVSC1tlZDwoc8XgWTNLy0w2ek81w4e3MtbIlssm+J7gWg9fNsVxtYbBZsNXlw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030120", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMGXrUefRZ+rwwJF4JF2Hjl47/XCGorfz/1IKgKRU7oeccS5DbI58zdGb1Oy3zX8BINJRnpl76p1fffpDxTijYJTyLvpnz2DAL0zjczavHTB9h3HVhW5ErYCvrxu1aNRmgDQglY956McwM9CGmaGAqFmwg0aR03eUCK5rBEaasI6n7QOJroY9p96ZsDzf/fr+2vnd89cObBwSloh7alqy16AA6z43Q9H4KBNYse3EIUT/Lz6qIwsOucjs22R7w4osU3o94hoGi41Fa8d7wouktTwkMI1rGT/6oldQwpdoTFeZcv2s2G2k8FQsYUYlWYQ//Bk9pE+0KUZ/inudQmxSnZZi8tkDlBBqcmEHjzb3kDafiWuIPID6+JT5iKj4oaoj8KYiJwGGIFDUT80YYLDJN2932OyfQeZONoliFi7vM9Ju+DztIZ+Y2j1N2dcmIGXq9T6QncO1OGe1poa5h8BlVK8POtjR4Mi2vBzUdTH0ImmGdM7IVzT+HDzIwQttvgsxxzMZ6yLLAZ165m0CmGq1RwRnnSnzZW+11rFaqoSBbJ043+as0jRQkOF1npXkmF0sSwW1mWwP8oWRSxxOw13bH8EUiEkvArBBF5ffsm+T1XDfXnIJP8H4QbyPxmxb1uzhi3I9sJZOWIObIg3ag9A1iBa/Bb1pWWb5rYfsLr5bim7643Brj4CSalMzxYHb", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+0Wqp4dTHiRqTKb+jxxZh2PhyAnht6/DbDsLb1+UcGjqQb+oGKYiEGPo1g2pCc2eDy1mJVMshAk451pJsRf/1FwintXdrfKf9gjmaJNFH/dSDxRHlg0yKWhHNC6Jez8GeoW9YygAY9g5V76IgQNcOay6mB8Q2riROQ336CBP1tH0eap8e4/0qTrpF09cyDtXLU4Pz8iLjX+c0Iaxhetoh6cBu/mKYd6iM6RNyxKBNYsfPVbVjRLhu3JhoY9M7twjQ7hos6HWA69xBUkIZVdoBH3p2klDMiPt16FD36sEdSzoRoHx+XZ/2233yk4lA6ezotcIZhpW0xpAyVOFx7iG6YAGxQmoQr88UanURsey9JiGWgjzqKjmyBe9Px7o39jObj4Kxt+a0oPk+8O2/MV5kZaLbOMychiuCITaVTIY1iFDamDccr9DDqNJmG1jpNw9A0KmSn/SSdl8jxeWq8p5f3ztd5GqsBP9+F78Sko1XLcmPuJz2bc8b1Vxu8D2z00gBxpFRlyS8UqGPWAYR++T5Nqna1UARlgCKgb3Osm7FS5pvOeYEk3fGs0jxQjPx934j72w05VES0iz9OvZGRW11Gw0eWH8MDhBkiDaAEFYPCsJtjXYrNKmrmmjzDqKYaiRg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030121", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMGPiUK7Nbezsy5h/Z1iImVJ19TbPsOXz+EEdiqtPs7KRTCxSPrluzNmG1OXlxn5Pc8JFjol849oNefhJyS7te9qbNPZrjmqFJETpJza7RFN1hjPZhDEH+sOv+me/Uc4y0hg7mII4+cA5fNaY3Oic7g25iAWL2XWFCLx2BV2ftM28+H+SnIxq9fmFtHLT9fj/1/Ta9ttLbQ4SnIdtYVSy2vlduCMrEZ3hPkoL6OHRc0ehYD+rLg0VucPm2mR6hoYoSWx0+x1Mh4BCcYBy1ZvxrjMkOsFzKT2GrRcA9ZV4VhiVda+632ak5FQrfHQsJYN+/CwlsQOVK1V8lm7cWCMRlY5/98EMnBBqeHwAk3rkhy3LlG2OctOyu9Cw1big4KBm87E0azXO6fv2FsVMsqsRTtH3LQA=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VyEh/xxujtNH/VD3tRsGuCRqZnMGXrUefKb+H4hJt4IVnJgl070XfUoar+ugJbz5tP6JqafScNass8iNOGxfbyx2VNKoZKlZR399oLdPEAwDSgfcDaNPdhwC6PIQXiZj20C3N1hjPZhDxSqZey+yD7QNV3wRsmn5Zt5Nw1OcTf1qSX7V/4kg6D0jvAGO0oQQTJ9det6lGP4LEstNmIvDfV4LSo2vHAsNcFYQdArYN8dxu9hOgb+S4xXsu1ehBE/6TUYEDkLi/jNQsR8M7wlntnhpYhWCkw8RxHm8NZZIBQ14rmszx9bpkmVT21twRjxoZ+UBnbJe/6zx9EWtXwOcdDiLJKCyW7OQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "2 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030122", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMGXrUefRZ+rwwJF4JF2Hjl47/XCGorfz/1IKgKRU7oeccS5DeIJhzNmH0Pe3zX8BJshAn5Jh8JsReP1Oy32setfSJfB6jkeOI0zxaXm1DWNgmyPPynVF6IC05zW+V85t/BsOmNY4zMY/NdKRzei65kmxhwjC1HKCXLJ2GFeYuY674leZs8IwtNuI8SLJ8fD2l/Hd8dAfbhESvYN6bRu5j6sI7issVMz0fQFC/+OQd1H/NCGgJgJd/NPg12Jo0osmUyk58QtOjYdFXs5P2MqkjjM0NsJpFCG4rEoAw5VoVhmRNK+93GHh8xUwezo/bY8trzk0owOZaFB7mWqFDD5QgIUr8dZZtgVxf2BO0Se0wiuEwGSMf4bx6pT5ifGwpLx397EqIE+FdUjQU80dYraAKGEyy+eYBKNSJ99oFSjjPsE9wDfFLsXU+DwC3NYnJnTm+GqKhtjxMGCp853/iNFkVLYOJdjC4d+k8FXJdSyhNXWWJsP9Shz/XWW43AgltBQsxSAE7S6YHox48DkMine/RwgkkynkLHS0m79Sp4eAaYcj3Pvh2DwE2P12i57l1R4oTgu1z+frrvF9RkU1wj2z1Ph5gvg=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+iXKB9dX/3FI7MauT/x9d5Lk+dgkly8XfK47b541Ycz6Ba/4vffi0XPpt9zdSG2u35xX9VP98EmIV36toaZPdB2jy5cdCbNe1nwGnAMUDiczC+BXw0kSnVi2pXvIq0+2e2Uc4/zxEhzcdq7Nw0OcXTmaqc/EX4kAOQyHKSSbEkEFqd9can+UqGr4wstMHNtCrY9eL4jvHc/p4GZxxasIJsI1qukugM9To0XtGxbC5FwvDRdVHgJSa3Z1xd8Nij1Xt71IcqSSkG9RtPjYBXcMJ82NjgvSY5McoqETy/sARSwphlHxiYNKmw1Sj39FQ9eX9rYY9uvTR1sw6ILRRxnCu/TT5Tm44mr4RZgQsjfGxDiWThljqHmSWKb4fq5oHogKjkqLwj86QiaU6GdV3WVYQZa6eAKGV4z+qPHppSAItmAyfrONs6vGq5KYXU3DYfwtwjOzfA8SWVncr8OmS284Htm9B/EaxAJsPK/8KztRzRYC/0IH+fY4v9Vxv5SHTswE5suQwqiDUY7SLQAZpr+j8U3nG2CUdomyrheHnt1qhZ7Yeafpo43PugnTMenLRsl5633RMoQha6jmtKvYrfTVlb2lHTEI0P0QQvAqdBFZjVsnmekDbVRWoEbcH4DK2J125bqoSe+QeFtomPW5CStEVn", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030123", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdX+J2rAE2Mf43yWXrdhYnSjXbSCbeLw2p51Ik6MiRtr4HnSrOj4/kAbgLpS6rKRTCwxe4p8x97Tl9D/wTFSMNRNipQy65xfaPxFjBWsZtXLMP9gjm2JMUz8biO8EHl7mnHEj3FXoY2otTK1UN80yQU6k5V96Yg4OcSP0LyWqEa2iRGO2X+WTf1rFxSOp8e84k2b4m4fuaBg/5Xk6tdpHGFc7M8=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt1JPjKdJ+4ucZGIGZptjyd6Iw+34yjFONYZQkoUy5YkMeeZUxTKjNngyAMd3VpX3lIvnazNfYLM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I42yXU7dxYzH3XKbWLvn2zNdZJk6InUt6/DbFtqnk4kEKz6FIqY2QfjEKeo59zdTJx/b40H4MO89Xjo9g7ZlfSPxFjC+odcfULr5+3GGWLkH1dHm8RHN7hiPTiWgWrZur+Sa1Vc4+zxtykIhqrdw0NcTTmamAqFmwg0aX0n+US7R0GVGLsMro+ECOqZIs9cKL8SbT8bTRm+rS4M4KbEhRtpB2b1KmlrwA9yR4QdqxfhdF5feQYBTrNSSvZxsT/c7xxWBoyIYgU250+xkGlotTa9Iz3pH3qD0iNs5rGXOopkdP1ZBvHU3FTcP7moh1lUpqC5gysbs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030124", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehHgzOfwO3/RDyIUu3yCRKJgeX7tFLfQYfv3zZJiZ13JjlR24mTDq6D+5FoZiuhN4IuIMC0FPp9nzZCa3vDyhHJUP9JRiIUy7ZRffbRQzS+5fdfOLP98jn6FNUz/YwWzOH5GkTDFhXIM6LW+5zOyV9s7gBAqlYZu7Nw1M9nf0KaF50GugxXC2HKWT7RqFhSY9cOn/k2Y4I49u8qZuSXS5/G5jveT5dAIbR5XrcZra178lKAb9yQ3XcezYRFK/aTDZEX4JSagIk4S/4vgw3h905AsTisiefrV8ZF9uvPc1zbMmOy/", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt1JPjKdJ+4ucZGIGZptjyd6Iw+34yjFONYZQkoUy5YkMeeZUxTKjNngyAMd3VpX3lIvnazNfYLM=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+yphjNVmKmRtT/WTPuar+41IDz61D6o+JcTYKcYUvzN+MxKT+ynVENsIEipJ98pMbebRBjD6iecTJJfZrwH2JMUCwcTC4EzB7knHXym9fvIb79jK3QM8lxVU2g5Vx4898PZeMya2Q4UuxhUaS2WmYR7koUUORvMKtq1WZspYxtsyB8TfD9/Xvm+za/9BLawZEsIppZkj8gqYK9zw9Q8G6b1Jf+eGQYlz/LyasKwEa8Mji2jR6w5M8WGc38V9JhMNVd8xnw4rhr3B1dqZW3sHkNsvNKXmCAeKe", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030125", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYB/2zPL8NHnSDGxRp36XW61zMHLiWufDbe7r25ZlIlCQzV9+5nPUrqz+8hMbh60b6ImaMC0FPoRtwtWKw/e3y31FNtQEjohz6tpOLKQMnG39NM3eIex9jnuTLkv3Jy21ATBwkTLXkzxZrsOY9DW5W9R6kUEOmLt23809L9iRg+in4Ej4jgeO2jadQbthUVuf9e2p+UGTrs9p4Y2EonKOoaKh2uHW8cwYIIWzMvPxkJOKkrXkfFFFdZs=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/PGXTDHADpnyXEpF1dHjsV6bQbOLwiZNwM1WHihty4TbIrLGw9lAMmrpa/Yvfdi0RPoRtwtWKw/e3y31FNtQEjohz6toebvtVwjntI4SXcK4+jneFJlfjJz2oATBgm3HCgnkWrIa45yK6R9M5x1Uzm4ht49x8M9Hf+qmB6kK2y1fWnHqHSbRoEFaVsI6u5FHcrYc5ptiftD/e+uC5le7W4p4fawVX/65wdF6qkrpFuD4wVIimbRNY/uqQckDsNCGtIE4J8c6j3nVlwM8lVG8xtBBAwqBXcMJ82NW16HI5LI1pGiGopkdUhU3Qepgo/cOIxJ6UAnsIDVM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030126", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdRv9yfL4PGjRDyICt2qHW6ZnMHnmWLeCe/6+3Jl1Ik6amVp19jbSq6Cw/l0birpa6pqWfyxDfI5739WM2aTky3hNIIoEioxz6o4MMLRBwjSgddjIbL5vwGrAL1D9ZjeuRH9ikSOWnnVbrb+1ySmJUdskzxto1rV56cEzP9aN26edqEm5kg+M2zuDTbFtFEfZusDo/0uZ4JEstM+BtHLf8ff4g7jB8coOIgdU/6V+cVmzmeVYrGosXoi1axFe4+XEZFj0YCymMwsP9MLt0zR9zodpXG4xtBBAwoJYYcl22IykszA6Os5+BnFi1O2qCW1Y/2iglm9u3aIq", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt1JPjKdJ+4ucZGIGZptjyd6Iw+34yjFONYZQkoUy5YkMeeZUxTKjNngyAMd3VpX3lIvnazNfYLM=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+yphjNVmKmRtc93nKrKL59FIDz7tP/IqWdTFDeoQvwd6N0uHzhHlEP9YEj5My8ZQbeeZT2DyjcJTPKPsux2CUIlfxZC20C340ljTCnXlTpsOo+i63R5Z30BkzmJNroYg9Mt6S2KSApA25iALC1G6cSbN3UVuPsNzo/0qRpcIKtMmEvjHa5vb2lLjX8coCbA8SrYNzal6v16cHuD4wVIiwbRFK6KTfZxTOITqhKABQqJ+vlnZ80sIgSXp05wtHgIpaa9RqlpH3/Dw/K41uHCG/oFBM3tRuWhuXYLi8kHzroEAxcX85dp5ssik8rwjcPFx72mKSWClDlYN/998X1QZmaXhFmXigljeOk2DPeZ/m5oXykfuyAQp3VIbzDq8BqT++WkXaIw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030127", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYQr9y/i/IW7dE24UsD+CXKc0cmPqV6yCY+LwyIRlIk6AiEg7+3iGoqvz/lYBm+hy54qWcWITbIR5wdSMl+3513hGO9JX2ol88JVfaPxFjC2sZ8CbIutnwmqJKUKwZjqpDWZ9gDjTmUBYlI2J8CaoW9RtgCczko537skuPtiRmayS/ES2gUaB3XXRSb5nBEaYocuk8gOYpZY9p8CEvzeb4Pz82vnU9Z4EZEhdvYx6YE+v16cF/C8qEdy8aRwLprScMQS9YDGmJhwOud7w33puhpYhWCkw8RxHm8NZZIBQ14rmszx9bpkoi7eBCptOwTLVmy4k544mMg==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt10Am+haqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgElYYy8JIaPPVT3zi/YN3ULryYEgLnNJiBWWyFuasFH+gL", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStz+wRqx6dTH3UarSYujtiZZ/IxyLn1J4+TbLrKvx5EcKnaFe+s6bf2IKcI9qzdTJx/b40nhFNoZNlJN745ILb7RJwimiNMTaM+ouzHuJK0H5aT79BXNgnSffnnVTu8OT+jC+Qt8ljFUmnoI4/809L9iRmbiB51uxggOGnHqTR6hwUUaYscen6EKOoo029cmMpTvV87Pq2vnQ88sZYwtL/4BwcRuzlaIM+z4rEce4bBdZsfDYYFqtd3jvd15NudLm12Z6hos6HWA69xBUkIZVdpszxY3ntHI/PcdvFiep40dByZpzS1eUcf2502vx8lQrcHYyJY5sqCgx4RqPIVp52nmdSCVel4F5/N8X1QBiaWZOmzbklzrLlGrPaJvmq4z1iOHkoa1q/a00aU6GdX/ZRI8Ta/6Rcyd2z+qaFOTm6ZDoPa1V2U+IrUjoaqcM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0gv/9IwhXl77y/vwJ2bRF2serT+HXeN3f3jtFK/Nb//62tdyKFKdjFJ1+3jB46f/41tPpqZf4I+RMCMNestpx8KM3uP5hHJOOshX2pJ38p8ecLRBzjK4YJTaLv1ny2CUZ2z+YzC8WzIFW7K4FpiQKXUNy2zBFIBB", 
		"answer": "25CgfJT9whD88sU0QB/2wL38OmXeBmEFqnCNQeNjeWXrFKHNfOj3zpkxNVmOhFR14TT90rCkyu7X+UxnVBQzL6pE", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/NmTZDSIZrH6RVrA0c37tQKbLYOTwztdYKViAjFU783jC46P/5VYGiKYb6oGWfjFDd4VrwdOIw+HkhHRZJ8NKiYlk4doLbvVEyX2ue9rVJf16x2GONAX/YXm8CnN9kT/CylVYrIq6tTCyQNJ3zwE6k5U4/807NdiRyurbY87IVrfa8FBeLIidAdjg", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Extensive trade connections with foreign regions", 
		"option_b": "he dominance of Indian coins in foreign markets", 
		"option_c": "The decline of trade in later periods", 
		"option_d": "The reliance on cowrie shells as currency", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030129", 
		"question": "25y2KJD90hDv+ZFgexD2zPyzdWPfFCIGpm2GEq5xZHDvFKTNZ+PtiYJiIljJjEg78WPUsaD+9EpPgqlf7M6Qdn1BvQxYtDdiFDY/IMgmg35fWw==", 
		"answer": "25a3eIH2w1Wq5IwsRBvgib34OmfUTyIQrXvDXqZ1dDPqZrTZF/mWj364XXnaVGF0", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Ejf8wfT+OyvTFnADpnGAS+NjcWKjWabGa63xz9d8IkiIgRc7+3jFr7D0/l0Iz6tU+Z6aYm5DbYJj3tWbm6Twy31Ff4ZFlIQy6J8eeLYSeurtHt2NEzTRx9NH4aMI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Copper and silver", 
		"option_b": "Gold and bronze", 
		"option_c": "Iron and silver", 
		"option_d": "Gold and lead", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030130", 
		"question": "25Gtepj91ln9/4wjWl7iwO/2Om+QFGcDpj+AXap6MHzsQavGfa3zyJN0Z1OPzVlu4HjS46b89kpPgqdI/c6cfy8OcYVj0ZCcxOHzmzP+yL0zXRseYu1DhO94EExj", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHYxAri9otgQhvgzPL7dxKTre506lnbDI1FvQNpLVw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hDkt4gvRxL21r3yNG/VQ20X432WQK1gMHLvVb6CeejszNd1Lk+Kgk1+4HPC7+X9+EAbz6ddqZmXeSELPplqxNGd0qTjyzFVO8MEsZVh7JsRPORF3jSicJYlpUC5cEmEZugXnmsG5RIv", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The Maurya period", 
		"option_b": "The Gupta period", 
		"option_c": "The Kushan period", 
		"option_d": "The Indo-Greek period", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030131", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxbm8sUkWxqyxvL2O3iQE24Quj+KXONgYnDtR6bBeuTxx4QxJlKNzU9p83LD/Od/ch6YKl88GKQ6rHCYCjLs", 
		"answer": "25a3YZ/gkR/r9IwsWwrz0fj7dX/CAmwConyXW6x6Yz2jQLXDauiyiZZ/IxyZjEJ293jS4Tcm8/+PeYIBlfrO6JO6eNM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hDk5MU3Vwz3hejsMG+QBW0D42mCQKp7ZWKjRLLQfuLtzIQ9Z1WHjldu9n/IpOXk5VIBnKlY/YeQfjFPPptu0d2M2fC7hHBPN4ZQiIF24dj0QTIOIPqnp/rlOL9nyiR6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Coins were only used for transactions", 
		"option_b": "Coins were used only for payment", 
		"option_c": "Coins had no role in trade", 
		"option_d": "Coins facilitated transactions, trade, and payment", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030132", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR3z+YQzRgeyzO7sIG7UQ3YZpj+PU7FzdWL3FKnXY+/729d+IRyOgld/snXJqqvjt1oBz4FV7YeeL2CSR1FBs0+n4F2qGj0FGINm", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHUxAn+9pZixoDJJRVK347fbgslLcR7nQ==", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHUxAn+9pZgWw3h0Pj7dX/YBiIdom2EV7BgMH/2WaXHfK3xz9d2KFCNzVh0+3jV46z+t3oBi6FaqzAV/WXCZhSN/QztrGeOk1k=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "The Guptas", 
		"option_b": "The Mauryas", 
		"option_c": "The Indo-Greeks", 
		"option_d": "The Kushans", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030133", 
		"question": "25a3ZJ792Bjm/pY0Eij7wOrsdSaQIG0ft22KULZgeX7tR+jhYePtzIZkIlKKiEg5jj7ECe7DzRoHVrojTI+JJA==", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjy3wqq9pZgQh/h1vTpMCvRDWZRoX6AWbR1YnWjGefoe/7qwJF4JF2dhFR1snDJseXS5VobhrtTqY2QfC0Nd4pjiMKc2+G77X9FOsdK2oNn6I4KbvEAzS7tfdrdJexnwXzAJkv0Jze4AXR9mjaWg3FGuoyt8Cq+Ws53jVUHmIN9/8U1Mt6R3uid6VmxkAPC326dXKh2EFjZpdyh70bQ4KAqvNmEojqb9ee5mfHF+dICeA1ArMZ+bV/8kqwc+yssXtqnKB1Nsc3eZV3sLjvjak4r+Mfq0nV9z40nHWYytD1Ui5dfccgz1Zfoszw5Jcx+HDy07wRwyIZoTRaPfbO/kEHq5Fw+ezo/d4tptTk8rgGPaFVt2mSeXzhQl4xu7ZANmkRzb2BHjnPzkX/GwEaacIf2+YHwxeD1p7xu/a0+aUCOMRzbWYMId7zMZTJnaHYtVyT8qidospBKpuc=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjy3wqq9pZgQh/h1vTpMCvRDWZRoX6AWbR1YnWjGefoe/7qwJF4JF2dhFR1snDJseXS5VobhrtTqY2QfC0Nd4pjiMKc2+G78HlIIIZXjoVg4ZULZeRFjCqsZ5TUJuprwC6VNED0JziuRHE0hjDCg3NYqY++tSG0RpoV0hwmn5RwrdopMNLf0KbTwUO8jwfC6HOUCLRgFFXZos+7q1eUoZZ4nMOJuDPV57Tun+rWsNAEdkhRvpZ+YVe516cPuC03R82mZhtF9qTEaVHgMy2vMQsOucrt0jR9zoc7WG875hoGjIZTZsV3lozsuXIMfc5jAzq2ql5JyZNAHVeferu0xW3q41B/enxrR5hkqCQmqU+OPVh7pmW1QihYlY4r/cUVgRFxeC9BjzbpjDmOkmyAbtPi5YS8i+31pLBt9eMuJFGSOkrdW4gScfONZ1J8zuyJAK9SOpFgVyznKdw4+Xn6NZqAyisM3JkwPX7j8WatmsTmeXW/oYHpi9diHakFdsbE+ouio1nDITfuYWidYs7mVAH+Sjzs2wsltA0p3DQC6W6YAIxt/DkMmXvwRkIkuynkZX3htKcc+o2ca5wwyvzi2nI5lvBxnpW31wgwUxGpiD9CocSWQVpK313ZDIFH0AErTJYTHYLY4WXWlnnFR3hNddvlFaGB2mxc0ub4nCFyqJ5OVpmCOAzJi9JmyRm1Qe12WW75oYX4MbwRBWkl9LN/yeidueipfOetP21qbgn3WuZP+plYcgdpAkvcCyAPZby7VZwKTvJcknrM1y5GQ3ZIC0mMtug+XAijrsXcZ2XQI74aTjzwaqcMAMa4TUjDOv+g0jHdD7CS2XO2VldlQDuPM7EZ7BH1OpvzN1OjgWd0+MbkJlRfBJcYfDHyeGK9pLeGSxIyemwHOoNTc1TdCwA2kS3GKfpiza4OMDEjRaGmWXIP1gFAjSrAD0FMvkteS62oTUAiJr9AMxsQ3nehGaVfGx/DkDMGh0yZ0DGraftFNQlkfmCGjE30lIB107iploaESvbwJKkSwYVDK7lOSJ6WHkkbj/ak++nhBSwtDmh+PLjaS+7U8Fj3EYj2p83fw1VIwL8Edlk0N3mih5vQ8QZjH6pde2JLpHoXq4r7bAKj2IYZwUJpVFz4/E7qUicgpVF8bID/a97QL4jl5F8fBjbIUKtGi+84kGzHINPFcQg+CyM9lACVe93E3nSCM6i7w6IHEQqt29X/TYN+rF5wy8uizEVOv3tijm+iHmXfZqf5515QJ3B9TL2LE1BUnBJi1DS1nl7pL4ijiacFh6pEmJwd5QX2rGFinV+IRl7HbH35nveQsybWrEYi3aNgWXXvG2dlyx4hRulr92FrUjkoR6Y0v6P5OKTWn23vJpm/yIEC608UR6nOb760s8HuKq+FDbysyY+RO2Dg6JpnA7W7LdsWJTbZdjwbrar9bYrXLQiAfGSGwa+ZESeLNmwb+nFr2kCcXQxlPmjzSMZIEjISmY9mLKoU5NrstUN3PGXXFPFrzK0djklcTFFXTrzygWJZHfVxeY+PMhhg8FIZG+FSKmy5bQoxd85J3HGxUDSm/Sz7wWQVZAH0/zPhreyRx6cZwPE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indians as passive and backward,Justification for British colonial rule", 
		"option_b": "Indian culture as inferior and needing improvement ,Undermining native cultural pride", 
		"option_c": "British as civilizers and educators of Indians,Validation of British colonization", 
		"option_d": "Portraying Indian traditions as obstacles to progress,Cultural hegemony and control", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030134", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNPjSM+ou50e8KRSwTje5DXF6h3HXmTxfpoC65Sa5WN93zxNyhYJ064UuKduameXTqA34xkbCnDvRCP0kURTZ9Y7oqwPc4MJ49Y3N8XKbtLS52riTsP9LSB1Bq495ali9g6EG9mo+Xtr0SgBC5e3DaRTuLySsKQcc9Yvxw3hs+ox7HUsm/QtPkYsWY9MzxorrsT0kOt95VTy840lPw5FuUR6Cbf253myk8Ecwcmgudpkt8W114U/caBQ+2ivcDGwRtsBZ+9kXkwtxfmpNmXj0wjCNwEeddYfq+Ii8lv3gpatq/bEuPVi8Ow+Yf4MYbLLONCd+y+qQBKhbc4tiFCroMtkh+zD6IZrU3jcJkMojJnLp4COfm861Mmu1pJ78itNzVPJAFZHw58+yolHObyrvJj26aM/9WAawTn/w2gtzshUgxjUD1GyMSLlw5zkfn2e5R0MkuynkZX2v1rJd5IWbfok0wLXtznISmfdziJrl0F09SQD7nW1Kv42LRkpKjRmWOo0k0QU6GaYAGNbV/WCfm3fEQnMDP8/4BeiEzCJcyOz9zH/aZgI1uTjkswvlPkHD6xI=", 
		"answer": "2+T1S92zg1TIu8VzHz++hamyESmKMK5oDX4xcVANnNPWx1O4", 
		"explanation": "24OxbYb63x6q3oskWx/81r3+JivZDWEQs36BXqY0f3ejR6LOaKDs3Jt0Z0ybgk1y9nPC46Sw9VIchrsb74GNMCgWbZ9mzsmA2eO35mNIJ89XksBx65YQcv1BwH2/YdjeYPx3jmqFN0zzczCzAzBdmjXfi3JF6IKotSm+Ud4+zhJyk59s6NoyPdvf3qeF7V+2hwiB2UeffLVhUVacucet7QOVrsIap8SZuCHTtOTrlfXc5NcEbEhducZybF+5haYA7DN4UMawKAJZ/uPCZEf+YDqmLgAb9tng03Ap0oosHWAw8R4GjYUWQNJ6wpH3tHIjKt1vBzq1sU1U3tR9URPWYLW92Xqk8lozcDoqdsp5tCh1pR2VPlFsiSuTSmx4moRi/5cK1QBma2pMk2bthzGfvGu7dJaj/Yn5kqj/pvlK/KcuKE+TdVDZVYYVa7SAM2JxwueUAalbOpxmG2LnM9Fu7zrwJZiA1j8E05krIXjw+C+dlci1OGy3tpa5mts2AbEEM8PI4MWy8HXJZSrgLz2SZcP9XB71Qnn2xx0lthYhiDEf+nbKCZA/1z8EinejQQR2hyvlLH2y1rBZ6YedbI8jyrXq0iBQiOZ3mInyxw4ASTS0n2tRs52WQVsP5FrSF8wJhAUvArMUFZHU4S2XhjbSSn8GaM/kBeiGzSgIyvH4g2hptoYLFZ+bPAnUmMojzFelCfg5VnLhvJPrPPBVDmsh87xw3uSuuYq0c7OwJGBqTQi+TeZK+9VTcUJ/FB3cCTFGbr/uX5MaSOdK3HrfhEdERnFOEFvL/rtIXAqu6s/GYX3SZrUbC1wK7pVfROQBAtE9oRGtcH3F", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A 1-C, 2-B, 3-A, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "B 1-D, 2-C, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"option_c": "C 1-A, 2-D, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_d": "D 1-B, 2-A, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030135", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC422GVaJmdHjtU+fWZui+25h9IhyGixt4/X/IsOX5+RMOgatS7ICLMAsNeoJuxpCB3vfjy2NYc89X2oN99ogaf+Aa8DOReoWbA/FnwC6NKFD8Yyr9CXFwkXHZjDxUvZG14We4WNsugAI3hII4/do1MdaN0KSKqFirgwLC2G6DQbNjUUCRsI6D/lCUoYx4pcifuD3fuLT4lPyT5NYOaxoSqpV+ZF78k60K9CM2VMz0ewdJ4vDRb0DkISSvPk4U94v33nEp1o06SSQT4Q9Sg8NGZ9J62ZzYsg4+bY1eHTb6oE1SxIFwXgOfe7P4326k41o2e2lraINjqCgx4QaSaEB2nyuuQyFQmsBu88AQhwEjfGNPknHzizuOwEyBeJri5cD/iuH+s/lq/OMvJkCSMU+YX4MYbLDBM2Jhiv2TCOZMIZpxFi7jM9YrvDb/YJ+ayzwf3tg0Jnjp9SbZht/0PWD6t4frh9pxVL4ONdjA59/3pFXKZDDdL0GdNYvWSwHkRm/wkxxwux1lwS9QwWzcAYg/+SgJ3mq/CVBsl2fzZXuvn7hV6YOAa84lwfTizjQVirR3mdve2hk1Rgr7jnBKvJffW1MPzlvaEsgE0AAhAqdBHZiR0H+fgXfZRTBNcs//D6Segyhd36PlgSFpt5UHR8yPPwrUidcn3B6+D71uXHPl6JLrPPgQSmUi/vJyxeCssti4cLHXZIFYIsTe2NImVTx9q4Ng", 
		"answer": "2+f4Z5//yFuwo8gtRcpR5VdHb9SvxQyG", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+CQeN3f3jtFKrNe+H62td8JliMzVR9snTTsavkt1ADjrEb/ouNdWICbZhgy9mIw+HzhGZIJ84Ejoh3pLEKb/xBwn29ccbSL/oijmCPMwXkbzz9FH9ngHzxn2xCqcOr8DWyW9538wEzgoJ16MYofITf0LvT4UO7iRSQ2XiFCL9hElWMpsvoyVGVtIsrvY2fpD7etPDwnrjf9d8PIhxd/5J3ZhuohakH6yw9Q4i7blJi/+DZYFqtIyeqKR1d7cSj9GZg0oMgUyV09gpSwopCJdMz2Jfw/CE/M8hmDHO+tkEA05s8Sx+Tfa/40Xv371Y2dG4iaoQtqyQhqU+IOlV6nyudQigRl49m89ULlgEjTntBiHPthzGfwDfPdYCj6I/ul+3ztOIj5qsiaVGSME/dWI4ZJbzGZ1V9x+iVTaVTOpF0VyPqMtsp7zD9Jda90T0E0ddgLHju+jnZm8O1MWq7oZbqzsdjE7gFJcXWqd+/tRzCeSryNXidZc60Vg6wRnLs1hxrtgwsxy8R5CLMGoh78G0Ji2y5R0MkkynjZXmvgv5I44+LbMwkPfy6m6ZFhoz8R4LqNdWz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030136", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC422GVaJmdHjtU+fWZui+zJR+KVOEhFg783jC46355EcAnaFY6ILfYysEcIJpwdOI2efyhH5Hc8dKmYl36o5fVfpExTyjNNfUKfB9jmeTZ0b/dSu4B2QuqD/qhC0WnIu+tSO+V9Y+zhByn4k4+cA5fNmK1KqW+g23gEaB03KfW/1iA1uU9dqg7gOMr5Es+OqYoSbatOT8iPHc9J4faglG/45+dV78la0M9motX821egZD9OCQaFrpKSuiMwsOucqjwXVnz4wuHWA64BpUh5BCIsl9lpbxsTsjMsx+HDCp40BV1Z1yWFeCfLyskG324WkxSXR5Jah/tTk8sgfcJ1J4k2iVTSBC08Bu+NYWhxBwPWZO3GLygzGYhmCdbprt7MDVi+z5obcj8awuJ1LAIVOYVYIQabbDM259xPrbBKgcEY1uAyPvM5Uq6SvwLpHU3DYB39cpLnun5j+Vl432NmuuoZv7m8BzVKsPdsXN7IuzuU/XZDHyKHKdJsTyGQD5XGj3wQdmthRlyTME4WTZC51stSwOjHGjWgRgmyHmaW6kmKoc6Y2bcZoj2vD/4Twslqc4q5PylBk5Vw24mXZMvMSQSRxExFrRDY0Gyg1uCL0XHZjY5mSThjbfRTwOcMf4EuiJzDgI1e39lyFtrZ8YXIiLP1nShM0vzx+lEr1wW3Pi6JTsMfkHGSNs+6Jhz+yztsS4cODkLnA+Lxu7SuAZ4J1UbBE7HQLaDTAPb7buQpUbAfBd12PLngtBSXgJF1/A8q8BUhG56sbNYmPbZaJcDxDmI6MXEs3sR0TKJrGmznDdDrrcgU6zWgbvEgmWO4QYoo5Ql8fE2hxu", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+CQeNgeHSjUKLBYuTwzNd4KRydhV47/GPLoaDit1wJz7hU+prSVzcTaoovy9+A2fe3wn5UPcIEno9399oRc+AAwjiuccfIIexnwnfANUD2azy+EDB11CbXhHVYr8Oy+zO+Rt8k1FU7mMd2+MU1L9qezaGQ+wH4hBOWnGmQXLVhAxSUvMmg/wOVroYxtsyZtHLZ5vv4nv3BsNsIbQZdso98I1qyk+gB8TksXtq9axNHsefYYFrqJTvjFBoc7c7u03p9htBpVHp09xBUkIZVdpsz9IrtqDsjN41lEzWzoE1By4c8Wx6SNKmq0Wb35lAtNVMlYYNssm02rgaSOxRqlSufQyBdkYN/998XhkRqcy9ijn/0gzaFwGGabprt7MD/iuT/rrBi/uM1PE2FeRzPXoQfbfPSInRnxv2eCeZVPd9zHyemOdw97DzrM5+b0XkC1pkoJmTz+ziQkcz5eWSop5v/j9diB/8BNcPK+tj3tFXBZybzJHOHJsj7TAbkXXX9wE5WoxkxzSwV5naYW8l25m0OkWyiTEdwyWf0ZHnhkrtM44GadoE/k/rqnTQZn+Fqmoi32xN8RAuyg2wDopaQWVVLyEeWF8MUzQ4mGKdBHZjF/S2EgHrVWW9KP8/mEa2G0S1G2ebiwiF8rNAZUICCbBjIysouzVejBPFwUm7ivZW5P/kZA2Eq6fJwxOnhp9i6duetL2A5LxWxGftR9tVUegM5L3/qEuiq6yunWBUbfkfCgQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030137", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfn6NmfZDWdRqnHDRqtxMH/2WaXHfK3xz9dhKE+dwHxu4mLH46b//l0cz65U/ICbMCsNeoJsycSMxKT2hHVEMMpNlIUy7ZRfaOZByDjtddrfYP1hw2OFNUb1Jz2oFnl6k3HCgn1C6JO+5y60UOY5/BsAk4Zr4sZmfOOX3OiF6V+xgxKbnHSXCLBhBVWVpo69+EaY4IQ3p42OvjvVtPnwlOza/tlHIgFcvIpqZ1KykOgF/Ss8HYikZwZC/6iQYlv9MC2xa04f68TtzHElhpEgUX8x5lMGg41SIsd82pyo/CE5OMNjEzq/sARBh5JwUAKEfa6w2WbjoEEtdH4uJYtjuG02rgKRLUZ9nyuVQmxFnIUr7t8KgUlOfHpShXeggzGPwEKabIfiq5D5l+H/pKohG2/D/2CRAGFqAYuMi2p6Wg==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhaqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgElYYy8JIaPPVT3zi/YN3ULrzqQuThvkUBrerE5DivBQ0s", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyjfn6NmfZDWdRqnHDRqtxMH/2WaXHfK3xz9dhKE+dwHxu4mLH46b//l0cz6FV7YeccTYGbctuiNSM1Oj+ynQBOsgEjpJz4J9fffpEjD6iedneMv1rhy6JNAXjcimtC2JgkTWWiGUWoIqo4SipXdk2zFU9lJR9/949KN6Q17vT3EW9xgWN1XWCCK5hA0Kc9c+7q0KOtIs+tM6ZonLU8rTtiPnX9Z4KbAwSuoVwbVSxnqtJ+SksWN69fAsHseXeZRTsYCymJAIU986j33op0oosVHt05A1DlIJaZ85w09jnsyc8O41jGzezoEVUwtR9HxOTd7Gx3m2k6Vt/YXIuJYt+ryI2qA6ILVA+n2iTQiNcnYMr/9MNnBJqaWZFjzbUijrLkmCOb5ztq8jqhPr5pa16sqwhaUyFIV3URc0JdrbEZ2F92KmYAq9Sc5JuGTbvM9Ju7zD+Lp+S1jwekN8sIGL1/TmRm8PyeXGospb8ztV4EP8DOdzI7Nm0tRWHZDvxLXyaaNi0TQD5XDz81g1pvhYgiCMJqHDdDoxt8CMOl3C3CVBsl2f2bW6ok6pFqo2IP4M0x/TgznIFi/F835L5lB4zTgr7gHZNpo2RSBAP2lzfHcVH1xwpC7ESAIWR5mWT1XPTRHICcsf1QbiVzD9Y3/H4mng9vp4KFYiHOhzJmdcy0Ve+B71tR2bprcb9KO4cBGNs7rp0iv2upN72WPKxPnwrLxu5Xa9+5oVFaUJrFBnUCiBcIlPWy0RCW+lOA/MwXqaPgQI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030138", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfn6JWLTF2serT+MVON/eX/kR+fDYOm+zZ5nLlKAmVJ+4TbJreXx+VAGiqZPqaeRdCsCcMtsx9mHxKTn1n5XOsJBicBk5ZYKffZMyX2kesfSJ/Z63S6JKVH/JzuyEHg0hD7ag2hfq4K3tSa1UJolxRk7kY53+Nt8PcSP3KuH+w23gEaW1H7RXLRpFGiXicCa7kKPr4xi9fmFtHLO5/G5lf6T8ssZbBwSvIp+ehu/mKEHuCc3RMSwe1Jc8PeQbFv/JWizNQsL+Mfm2GApwpc7VGcztAtOh8N9d9N715akrDciNsJuVTC1rlRB1ZF4HwOZNKmw1SjD9UUrdDo7YJhksyl3cq9bZxFvQUL4im3RrA3EVA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfcWIAcZl9zdOdl+Hv1H1APcdQk498pJUZPOBIyX2sZ8feMupnwWDC/4yutcSKElI9HNomu1oCUA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyjfn6JWLTF2serT+MVON/eX/kR+fDYOm+zZ5nLlKAmVJ+4TbWsarm/lcKnOhS552WdyoXbctmxsSGl/T4yHhVOsVFlsBz6p5fbvFMxTqke8HIYP993muDM1a5JzCuRHF3lyTEi2hT6IG+9iauR9931B031o517M85Ls7f1qbT60KxiBXC032FTbMkGFqaudus7lDcsocop8ietDzP9eDwlfbAsNENIhpHs4NtcBu9maxJ/C8xRcGxe14L4uzVZVDkLi/jKwca8d+j2XopxI09VSkg/BoGkoxaa9R61Zno/D41PslvByCyqlQAxpp4HwWTeLS/2Wfx8xUvZ3socYNuuT51rgncPFx72n+VQSkRoIhuvsIclBdscy8IiWXlwjCNwGeabp33q4PwhPGwo7Zq/OMqJlSMMU+YQYwPJb7PNWIy2vueG6dQNpFzVybzL9wg+3ntKJPU9Cwe2Ngub2fi5iOWloS1MHb6sp7qgZRiBqoFepHH/N/3uUiAcmPvLmnTYsLmXAvkQ2W4wQtptgwgzGEE5yLMAIw/9D4em2ykQEtq0hPoaTyxhLtK646LcY00k/rqnTEfkfo4kpTi2BkvBwCun3ZNtcSLR1kP5kHFFswJhBkrHr0OENbY4S2YmmKQT3Ufes3iDbHHwCNG1ObymmR5/4QBFZiGKVnShM0vzx+lEr1+VG7jrYK5O+4aByQ48rcxzuixvsmvfPyqPyUlYVq0VuZX4Nc5gY1UQwWYEYucs0fKweCl", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030139", 
		"question": "24GwbdH2yQ3v+ZYpRBuywfTsNmTGBnAI43CFEqB7eX+jWajXYuntiZpwI1nJgl078GPUrbGw9F8OluQb+Y+NZCsAa4du2tyQl+Di1nhPNIZQkoUy26UgQ8t/8wKSS5TeMv8ijBXnEFAJxdW9PtYRGI8O4lE=", 
		"answer": "256te5ny31vZ649qWTjn3qAVgaSG9clO", 
		"explanation": "256te5ny3yWot4MpRg2yxO6/IWPVQ3IQsGyCVaY0fXTtQK7NYP6+3Z90Z0ybiE16/nPIoKCw+FVPjKdS586SfzcPepgvxdGN0qT4wjFDJtRKjsBx6JsGPPBV3jSjc5TPKPsu5XuTL0T+JzyvBTBdmnHCgnkWu4a4+im/FNg7wRs52sdEr+8pLMOe5erT4V74lROLyHqTRLgkEEfZocatq1Ods5E5ssjNoiba4PHq2uzb8cpLdgBXrIM/blSpm6wauD09Q830fQFO9aTEbhTuMi2iMwtd/c73131lw4ZpWWwn/RhIkcNZbIBw2ZHqr3I0Kt9jGzT6t0xFh4B1UhLWe7v4xGDhoHIqZW4qJY50siwmtRbee3QmIIonhbqK10CdW29OgQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ku,sh,an", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030140", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hzy/pY0VxDxwL3wMyv5DWYYonHDUax9fmKjVavNYOrtwJN0Z26GgFp1snXJqqvjt1oBz6BU6JybY2IQa4xozcOdxKTjzHQBNMpLmIF+pIkcc+RFjDKrNMDJIfprjm+OIwX1ZDazC319l3HfhGhTuoK44S60Wsl3xAAgn4l/rdw0OZee16ua7UOsxhaHznKeTP1QGV2K9d6g7k2TrYc2usPNoSDU4v39n+uT9cgCZg1cvIM/bF38qJc2xxUHbveLV1JI/ureZFf5KSetNE4f/N/003FnhoYgW28x5hpIlsNGY9JnxdjrunIkN8gqAjyor0AChOLji23dLfnFsj5Xp+smcA==", 
		"answer": "27y2fJTh0hbk44wuVxDmxPG9tDglMSVV2+RZRY08fj3SGQ==", 
		"explanation": "27K0Z5Py3SWot4wzEh/i1e/wJXnZAnYU436QErd8dTHwUanWa+P9zNd1Lk+KmEho92WGt631t1EdgKlf7JzfYyEMbo4vx9bJw/b2wHQBMshA2oVx65QQcf1DjDSjYNHJIf16x2GONAXyYiCyCnQ0hjTRg3NYqY/79yiuWt420hw3hcdR44goNNLfyq2Q50O8xgSO3XWaBP1YU12Xocu66EyStIs2sMOZsD7ntrT/k+zAsN8YIgFG/4Nyc1O9hKET/Tl4Use6ZhdI5e3fb0etIi23MAsY94vn33Jvw5AsU3109xBIlopYZ85nxdSkqzo5PMUqHCD6qkpEzpd9SxKSNL+hkHzs5RUvZ384YIRuuW06p0+fJ11wiSuaXiNc1Kll+tkY1QVteS9yk3vlwjaFwG2AfYHn+MLDrVkOV/aeX0EwgaTwLNgo", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "in,te,rc,on,ti,ne,nt,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030141", 
		"question": "24GwbdH63w34/oYhRhuywfjrNGLcECIUrXiRU7VxdDHsWufDYO73zJllZ3WHiVJ6/DbFrKz+5B9Pia1a/ZuNeSwEPoBmxteam6TzzWdIPc9Qk4VhqNoecvAA3jihfdPSL+t9jn2ZKkf/ayrxRH57gHHZhHBP6Iq3+TKoQMg21BBygo99rfcDA+ig5pes13L4hxWS2XiFW/1rFxSNvcvo/0qRpcI6oNnNsD7I+7Tqn+rF9Z4KcUhEvopqYlmwkugB8TksXtq9axNHseXCdV3rISu3NEyeQpPaA6ij6fpj8dtFwn1U", 
		"answer": "27SqfJjgxRDptdZk7/5Mwsc9j/t8L8yNskE=", 
		"explanation": "27SqfJjgxRDpy8dgWw2yw/TrIWLeBCIQsD+XWqY0YHDwR6bFa63zzJllLlOHnhtv+nfS47H48hMLirxa4IKMMC0NPohgwd6al/Py1nQBNshDiIFk4Z5fa/1UxH2udcbebL58y2iMIkbkbje6RGR8kXHXmGhfu5ey9me+WN86xRsmhcd364goNNLfzaGe7Q2RiEaW1H7RW7hnHlqd9cyk6k2X7MIE986YvSbO5vX1prqT+c1LYxhCrYlvcVK9g61J+Tl4RcCxKBFE+OrDIVHgIienPk4J8c6j1WFl0pc7XGV09RFCwpFTbsl035fxr3IjNspkHDWzoEVOxJE8UBHWYLW9kG324Rl/dGlrco9hsG00sk+IIFE+imSQRThYl4FnvtQQmAFtbmZPkjb0ii2ElWKHPJfm+4n/keH/rqoj/aVnO1SMME7LFowSYfPELnF7xOCPBKNPcTZhm9M/0D8K4MQg51kC4mc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ar,ti,st,ic", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030142", 
		"question": "24asaYX23Bzk499gcwzxzfz6OmffBGsSonPDV7t3cWfiQK7NYP6+wZZnIhyNhEh4/WDDsaD0t1AAhqYb5IGKfCYQPoZuzNXJ2OK3xmRTPdIEmYxz/doPbv1NzS+keM2bJuxhwy6UL0CwTCyuDHF61CHTmHVZrM2H+xu1d9U5wxknhY5345J8CN+WyuiX4V67iRCHzmLRXbNgFEaKtsG67lDctIo99dmIsjrV+/j2nfHQ8dJLcQdCt49sd1K/lrwA9yR4Xs70aRxI+OHedRTELiyqJgBd9M7313hl05AuRCcI+iNItYtfYcgz2Z6kqDo1f8tlGT+1tE1OwNR/UBmVeKir2Wfq8xU8dHRrZ48tuD80tgHcLkZxlyuIRCkRlYJk6NVZhhBiaWpNmXj03QOFvGuuMtPX44W8rv3jqLhtsrMiO0iPMRzPV55caLLSLGJ2iuuCTbVVNJFuESvlPNs6vDj9Npea3DwA1dc0PDfu+mqJndnhPHej/a73stpUWv8hONLM7MWj8HXJZSrgLz2eY9/1VQTlXXvhkwJktBMgzGEE7WHQBoZz+ioEnX+8CVdrgi/pf2iolb9I442AMbI/7/vPk3IkkPE4j4nyxxgyRAH7gnkDsYuWQRxCwkHaGt5HzQcqBbcAAJPCsnmekDbZRmwCbdr3D6uCgyNOmvfjj2V4/5QbR4WAK1nPgttm4wKiCfx3FXfouo/2ObIpBFgi3vwx6+Oivs+1YbONImEjbhT3VOpN8pldfRB8CEvZEDZGbr/uQpUbActawX3LmUdYQm1ACl6M7KkbHRCvqczGYWbRZLgfDxLuevMWHN7wR1TbPPKo3DXNSP2uEUDKt+AMUr1jEJg9yE+I", 
		"answer": "25q2ZIiz9VtUEbyp9iOdTfOZ6tfGsAvX", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyyPjxIWLfDXFRt3eGEqd9Y3LsQqLQd63xz9dyKFWHzVZ053rCsOX99lcKz6ddqYyKYiwXPohjycnJ0fb4yTFVO8MEsZVh7JsRPORF3jSicJTSLr5v3G2IJkD/aza6DXN1mHHTkn9XvoKv/Ci1R5R39B031oR348swKcSW1qbT7F+5kQjC2mmeRf1wGV2K9ce7q1eUoZZ4ptiOuXLf/ef6le7W4tcOcUhatoF3b1K7n7xJ7CI9EdyxaxpF/ujfZl3uISTjNAEN8cLwwn1qx5YgUmd0+xkGg41Va8V9wtjNsjY5PsMqGDauokhM0oZ7RlnWVbC33m+k9F06NWo5apxkuCgx4QCMPF1xlHjQDCNfmJkr8cANnAttPUsAmH/yhzyfjHzPf5zx+YXwhPz1s/l0+7cvaVWIPE+YVYISZr/VNG59xKfZwgwqssIpyJhDOD4uCtIibw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only A", 
		"option_b": "Only B", 
		"option_c": "Only C", 
		"option_d": "Only D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030143", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhr4/pU0Egnz1r3vJ27UDG8YrX6NRq9tMGTwUaOCZ+O+xJhiMxyGixtS/HLPoumw8ksMg71f4ICYMDYLe8thx8Kd3/Py12VEIcgEioFg8NZfevtSjDSjZ9fJKe56x2GONAX0ciu0Cnc0gDnTyltDuJe6tTe+RtM4xFUzmIM46MkuMN6ay/fRKqH7dJFEYse0NrEeDqmLVg==", 
		"answer": "25eqaZn+2FsR7VT5gEoZdWHhrak9dgoq", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHRwxji+oxgQR3gzO3rdXvCBnQQqnOGVuNieWP3QabOYvS+yJt9Z1OfiEk723jCqqS8t1YXjK1L/c6ZfzBDaoNqiN6GxfD/03RSJ8NWlMBi5YgLPMBIxS7tedHaLu0u2maBMwXkbzz9F3NmnSHCymxErYe0+C61VdQjzAxyg5R96Yg6M8Xf0KaA61+xlhKL03WCCLRqUVmWptro5EXciYw8vMzB8TvV9/jsnvHd954PdxpbsYE/d1O5148c6D45EdixehtE9aTRb1CtJSmxKwcY64ejwXV6hqA7XGE5/V2mFpPylyRlNqDuJFejlCRR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Kharoshthi", 
		"option_b": "Greek", 
		"option_c": "Brahmi", 
		"option_d": "Aramaic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030144", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRHj5JEvQBfxxPG/JW7CCm0V43aNEop6dHjiFLTDea3qwZIxJFOEnVRo+2LPrKuw+FVPhqZI6pyWYDYKcYV8iNmHl/byw3hOPcdI2oxz6p0KffNF33HtedXJK/dgyS6BZ1b4bj+pRHZmmzyWnnRT6Jao8Ge0UpoH0hQ5hI5srckyOJes2KaA41+xklnAGAoUZIMPX8XJeC+WLx2uug==", 
		"answer": "24W3e4W+/Bj/5ZwhEi731/TwMSnSsBXPv7KCRCIani00tNZ9", 
		"explanation": "25y2e5Lh2An+/oouQV7wwPr+OyvEDCITpj+AXa5kf2LmUOfLYK3szJB4KFKIgRt383jBtqT38kBPhqYb/YaaMCwKcJ9niNGH06TjwX9VO4ZHn45m8YgWeecA+DWkZ5TPMv9g3WeULkr+Jz+vC300pCPXgW5fvMO6+yP7Z9s50x4gn5M4+cd8LtKY0Ked6UH4igeM226QT7h3UVuattu6+UaY4Is29dmFtHLL++ft19XS5cwSY0hCupR2bF/+E4QxjXBN1ThecYo0cGxUfA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Maurya Period", 
		"option_b": "Gupta Period", 
		"option_c": "Harappan Period", 
		"option_d": "Post-Maurya Period", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030145", 
		"question": "24GwbdH31Brj540lQBP3y+m/Om2QInEZrHSCXON9fmLgRq7SeuTxx4QxMF2azV1y4GXS46Tz/1oKma1fqYyGKmAtVUbRJGcsJcJ0beY3noLn", 
		"answer": "25+5ZZTgkSn4/oszVw6wK/v9tbuTKHMFsZYyLuD0bg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12Av548UzRx3xwO7sM37cQ2YUoHaTWqZmfXTtQOfNaK3f2p9+LF2HzVJ14XXUqrXk/lwBnOhM6J3fcSEAcYZ/xNma3+HzhHNYc+xFl4VhpKoNdfpTyS3hNNWbI/d4x2LANEDicTizEDB9mnHCgnkWrY6r+SiiFNUxgAE6k8dd7NsofP6R3aGSqG63ixaD0mLRQbMkM1GXss+kpwOVrsJp7Z7a86x9PSTIjgQ46h2lU8SdWBY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Firoz Shah Tughlaq", 
		"option_b": "British colonial officials", 
		"option_c": "James Prinsep", 
		"option_d": "Samudragupta", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030146", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiyzPPsNnnZE3YYrHHDQKZ3f2PnR+fFZ+vq2td+IRyEglV+6zqGr6T+8x9PjqZfqYGLeCcRPp1uxMWI1ejy1zFMMs9Klpky4pUNPOZFwDSqfdvOM75+23yQKFb1dGb/Kf1NhClAzjWKH7jvQVYLhg==", 
		"answer": "25G3ZpDn2A/vt7clURHgwe69Aua5XvvWlOVVGRlUvrbOhA==", 
		"explanation": "25G3ZpDn2A/vt5clURHgwe6/J27WBnBRt3DDW61nc2PqRLPLYePtiYN5JkjJnkt+8X/Aqqbx+18Wz7pe6oGNdGIEd41725CG0aT6y39EKooEmYFm8JYaMLRMzTOpOJTeNP0ijmOBLkv8fnm7C2I0hjTag3tfp5aotTeuRso40xAh2sd17Mw5fNWGmb6S+kS3kxXC1XWVQattFUGYud3o4k2frJc8vMOK8TnS+vPq1rjD4tcFYQ1B88Z+cU+1hKkH62Z4UMawKB9O4+fYYFr5M2omVZB2NMYaoHOkSsqkXXPI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Royal Edicts", 
		"option_b": "Votive Records", 
		"option_c": "Eulogistic Inscriptions", 
		"option_d": "Donative Records", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030147", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg0gvj55FgRw33wb32Oyv4AnAQs2+CXON9fmLgRq7SeuTxx4QxLk/Jj153+3PQpqGw41xPja0Bq3UIdr/kPO1lsEqXj/FnT3E=", 
		"answer": "24Wxa4X81gvr540pUVzLwJdh92LTq32sRKShvDux", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF77y+78J2LAF2serWzDRaZmdTH0Rq7WeujwiZ5/Z13JnVJ45nnBsaTg/1oMz7tY+4ePZGIKcMt4wNmK36T+wHRAIIZFlIQy65gVefdU3326ccbeYPt23nyFNFb1Y3m0CjBgnDSWjHNEpcO082erXdkj1Qc3hcdM5cEvfN6R3aGQ6Vm9lUaW1HqFCKlsFBSKttyh+1fctZE9sY2Ev3Lz9eb4iujS/p4CbBtRrY9vd1KzmbtJ7ysrEdi9awZE9vbRcVzkI2iqKU4T+N/2xHEr4cpRIKNe6uGNUysf52+V0g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Brahmi", 
		"option_b": "Kharoshthi", 
		"option_c": "Pictographic", 
		"option_d": "Sanskrit", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030148", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrp5YwwRl7lxO6/IHjVByIXrG3DRbF9ZHjtU+fjfeXxwpZ/Z1WHnlhp+2bSqqr+5BMGgehr6IWWYzYCcMtuxtTJ9uLwzHBPOtVQm44wkUGl2lDlcnvhqh9F3mpz7w==", 
		"answer": "256waYP8whH+/4xisEzgYnLt7gsILElMfWAnKg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzv/MUhXBqy5O/+OGrZACICoG2KQrdnMGbmRqKCa+DuxZhoIljJhFU75WTPt6z+8BMunKBU4o+RMCsNbYh9wcCd3uv51zFIPYZ0m4t7944ecrRBwjntVdLcKP9gx32UJku8JzuoEDBWhjDeh3UWq4y14S61Qd8zgAE91oV9rdw0OZeS2KGdqF67lA+SyDuYRv1NH1CQtI6c40bcs4EqvN2Z8SfI8fC5k/aT5NYOcQ0SrYN4alSyhOge+Tl4esC1eh1Y+fDYaBYoX4lyxMKPZ4a5QbxinDMA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Greek", 
		"option_b": "Aramaic", 
		"option_c": "Brahmi", 
		"option_d": "Kharoshthi", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030149", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw2RDv8cUzRgv23L3tMGfRF2cV42uMEqx4dDH0Rq7WZ+P5iYJiIljJhFU7+3jVoLf550cGgKZIqYeMMCECcodqzIrL0Dua2rDdRVY1HcdY2qBNjg==", 
		"answer": "24W5ZJT81gvr5405ENbBqwOC+umXLbINCs6Flng=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxQzu7sUvVF7mzfi/OmfUQ3UDqmuKXKQ0ZWLmUOfLYK33x4RyNVWZmVJ0/GWGoqv0t1wbh61JqYGTdGIRe4hg2tSal+3khHJAP8pBnsBi5ZYac/NSzS2lbZa9gcy8yrJgQQ1MeTPmn95G", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Epigraphy", 
		"option_b": "Paleography", 
		"option_c": "Hieroglyphics", 
		"option_d": "Linguistics", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030150", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17/xPTxdWfRDWUEoniGErZndXWjXamCY+Lt3dd+IRydhV4702XOrK7x+RMGgbtY+4ePZCsMcJgtdWK6rqSP3eG7xewFKO/ToA==", 
		"answer": "24WqaZrh2A2oOgYE+m3qqcuGA7F7lSJ3Sw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+3gr+t6QzWhH5xPO/PGXDAHAYs2uKXa1nMGbmRqKCa+P525ZnIljJhFU75n7D44fi9lsChuhI6pyWYDZDf4VriMSB0qTH1nBKIc9Q2oxz6p0KffNFjDSjNMDTJb56xmeSIwXzYjepEWJt1BP1yLGJE3/FIL9q+6NhLNZ6d70=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Sanskrit", 
		"option_b": "Tamil", 
		"option_c": "Prakrit", 
		"option_d": "Pali", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030151", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF77y73WO2/ZAiIComjDU+N4cWPkUefMe+D8zIUxKFrJhFVo8WTPs7H5+F0cz7pe6oGNdCcHPoRhiMSM2vT7wTFWMspIicBm69oMeeZWyX2sZ5TLJexjz2CFKVGwdTy+C2Jwh3PMRddqRihPJXy3VZ24/mn8", 
		"answer": "24a3fYX7kTDk84whEBlPqDlV4Qd9GMsgg9yfUOQ=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fn48oIpXRCyyvu/JmTFF2pRinGHW6I4MHCjWKbQaei+x4J8JVmbzVR9sn/IsKbi/kMbhqdV+s6IdTAGPplqy9+b0+HzhH5Pc9JMn8Bl5ZYTb7RPyn25cdnLLPt9jnqPZ1b1dS+4RHFn1CHTmHFXpoa14WepUdk40hEh1JqiQ5/oLCx+Pm6hvTVZYW0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "North India", 
		"option_b": "East India", 
		"option_c": "South India", 
		"option_d": "West India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030152", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl72wP72JWPVEWcV43aNQaBmeWH3XajMfa3szJtwM1mNzU90sl/Ip6zx+RMHhrtP5pyGMCMRe8tp2t+El/P/zXJJc9ZBiIl94NjWN3XWRPUg+Bj3BiCb7a8+", 
		"answer": "25i5fYPq0Fna8pcpXRqwkP1fqVW5gSF0d5kIMU5moQ==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KLj91RDr+cUoWw3myu/meSvEC2dRpn6RXqpxY2WjUKLBZ/32zIV0IxyAg0h44H/Wt6z/+UBPjrpeqa+MeC0If4Uvwd6a1Pb+1GVIPMhX1sBl7JMcdLRCyTGietObNPEu2maFZ2jxciukBTBkkSPfhXgWqY2/tSapUZowxRs3hIZ04dF8K8WWzbyW5g2xiEaW1H7Raq9lGVmQ9d2r+UqMtMI5u8nNgSDa/+bwjrjf8dAMdwlVusSWARMTSFI7skLbY97I3VkE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gupta Period", 
		"option_b": "Maurya Period", 
		"option_c": "Harappan Period", 
		"option_d": "Post-Maurya Period", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030153", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg0gvj55FgQgz3wfLyPGXRDXYduj+WQaZwMHfsRufLYP79255hM1WGg0g7+3iGrqrj4xMAiehy54qWcW5De5NsxMWN3urwhGVJNoZKlZJm7I0ab+BF3jPtZNXJNLIuynuSLkv3Jy21ATBTgSHCizxGrZGy+iP7VdQzgBAzhItx6Np8K9aMmZes13KHuTm940TTkHoDM+n6WZ1rb/Lyzrb8Fg==", 
		"answer": "25eqaZn+2FsR7VT5gEoZdWHhrak9dgoq", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHRwxji+oxgQR3gzO3rdXvCBnQQqnOGVuNieWP3QabOYvS+yJt9Z1OfiEk723jCqqS8t1YXjK1L/c6ZfzBDaoNqiN6GxfD/03RSJ8NWlMBi5YgLMLRE2S+ketObNPZrjkmVN1HxJym4Fnl7kHHXhHgWrYKp+S6+RpjWaHK7G2TOd23h7e8+V+Lz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Br,ah,mi", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030154", 
		"question": "25y2e5Lh2An+/oouQV7wwPr+OyvEDCITpj+AXa5kf2LmUOfLYK3szJB4KFKIgRt383jBtqT38kBPhqYb/YaaMB08QbRQ9++26Nu3x3RPJ9NWk4VhpoOPzDe0Ai2bLaonZ4+4FrA=", 
		"answer": "25uxZoX7kRjk88U0VxDmzb8W/nlaGYwaXnqAKPdVazN1", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63wrp5YwwRhf9y+6/N27XAmxRt3DDUKY0c37uRKjRa+m+wJkxNVmOhFR183qGr6T+8EYOiK1IqYeRMDYLe8thwd6d36T2ynUBJ8NKjogy558RaOFSxTi+Njyv8iWmvLGG/yHqTgs1L+I=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ni,nth and te,nth", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030155", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl72wP72JWPVEWcV43aNQaBmeWH3XajMfa3szJtwM1mNzU90sl/Ip6zx+RMHhrtP5pyGMCMRe8tp2t+El/D/wTF+DPl7pb9N26UgPPdFwim4Zt3eM75M7Szubn8HjWicBVW87+DIhPdl", 
		"answer": "24GwYYP3kRrv+ZE1QAey5969j4JHAQ3zB8tLL37rHITKEg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl72wP72JWPVEWcV43aNQaBmeWH3XajMfa3szJtwM1mNzU90sl/Ip6zx+RMHhrtP5pyGMCMRe8tO29iG3OX5hHhPIMVWk5Bm7ZURb7gA2zWkd9ybIvtiwWCHZ1H/Jy21ATBgnDjEjjxVrY2v4DWiFPgUglF7Gu3ROpbi9XrfzMi0Axo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Th,ird c,en,tu,ry BC", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030156", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg0gvj55FgRw33wb35OnmQFHAYt3aNVeNVY3nsX6bMLuTw2pRjLkydhFR14TbPreXA9lgGnLxa586efiZDX41owNGH3vfjxX8BJMdX2r9N26UgQ8t/8wLvJYouU0Egbw2+o/JX6p2gbA==", 
		"answer": "256waYP8whH+/4xisEzgYnLt7gsILElMfWAnKg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzv/MUhXBqy5O/+OGrZACICoG2KQrdnMGbmRqKCa+DuxZhoIljJhFU75WTPt6z+8BMunKBU4o+RMCsNbYh9wcCd3uv51zFIPYZ0m4t7944ecrRBwjntVdLcKP9gx32UJku8JzizADBgnDSWmX9EoZOvtTKoUd53yRtygo99/s18LtKY0Ked+w2vhxXC93OQWrJ3GUCRvIzXO80y+Nk+XyR8xbJO9WCw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Kh,ar,os,ht,hi", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030157", 
		"question": "24GwbdHnyAnvt4omEhf81v7tPHvECm0fsD+XWqJgMGLzUaTLaOT9yJt9PhybiFh04HKGpKz240BPgK4b5IGRdTtPPohu3MSF0qi3yHBPN4oEn5RxqNoSff1OwCTtctvJYOxrwmeHLkrldHmtEWJkmyLTmTAWqZG+tSy1W805gBQh1rhH0vcDA+ig5pfT+ki7iRSGzznUDkgDjpjDw9/NntoXH22F", 
		"answer": "25G3ZpDn2A/vtWzLylAo7TVIqDWAztNiPio=", 
		"explanation": "27G3ZpDn2A/vt5clURHgwe6/J27WBnBRt3DDW61nc2PqRLPLYePtiYN5JkjJn154/WTC46L58Uccz6ddqYOQficaMstsycSd2+G7hH1APcII2oVm59ZfcfVJwjG0NNLUMr58y2KJIEz/cir9FGVmhD7Fj28UVBydxPmXAo/V1ye17i7BOw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Do,na,ti,ve", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030158", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUMWw3mhdS/ImLECyI9qmyXEopdTH/PXbTWLsS+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWpnVFvMOS3Bu1BZoWxBoigo5344gzOpes2KaA41+xkkaDzzuQRv1hAV2ep8+440qf4I89scSYvHKWtLS52riTsJ5LIkgSnsZIal+5m7FJ7Tk9VYi9ZlJf+eGQZ1v4MjyrZw8T/Yvl33J9zsIqWGcg4Q1Ph5BqbJIz/5b3vyA5L9ljGj2p40tOh4B5Ugeacf2v0WTo8xU5emhrdY9/sSw7pAGIaEZ7mWSOSD8R2cArvpBZt0RXeGJQkHPzwj6YwHeKbJzw4pTzl+H1s/ls9OMvIFKUOk7RVYwQJbrOIWhgx+iPBKlSD5E0VwD0NMEn7zG5JJ+S2TAOxdU0Njfu+mqdl878KW2/oZv3iZRXB7cPPdDLqcK5o1/VaDP1KHKddYu5GSuwa3n72h5tsgoozS8EqGDBSKN++Cge3k6iQEp3lzegZXLhx+YPvb6AK84Y3ebvzzsAjP13kYi3xhg/SBa/hHFE8oieQVgPykbXENkUhAYgTLcOBIbU4H2alGLVWDxAP462QejH52x+2+/kj2NxutAIWp7OPw3OjscvxhDxAPN6XGLjvMb1PPIRSnc16aZ0x6+dRgPhnjYVb9Jz3ky+rnic", 
		"answer": "2+T1St2zg1TJu8VzHz++hamyESnTCFriwzgVpAvvukn2/qjS", 
		"explanation": "25S8Z4Hn2Bbkt4omEi3zy+70J2LEQ2MC436NEqZkeXbxVbfKZ+6+xJJ1LkmEzVl+8XfLpuXn/lcKg7Eb/J2adGIKcMt7wNXJ0evi1mVJc8dKnsB07ZwLdLRDyTO5YcbSJe0ijm+TZ0z+YzC+BWRxkHHfhDxCoIb75SaoR9swxVUbmJR7/8EsKN6Q17vT50P4kgOPzHeUCKplHViK9d2t+VWZ4IMr9d2Ioz/a+vH3jrjB9d0EcAxB/4dxZxu9ha1J7is0RMm2ZBcL4+HAbkfkNCexLgsOucTllnxg1ZYmT2A39RMGi41QbdJ+14ztszxwC8VvVRGoqlBJ1Jw8WRaVcbn41GHi5lw8YHY/fMpksm0xpAyVOFx7iGKSS2xwh4hk9dEX1Q1tbmxSlWb0izCFkyWacofq58DWhOX1s/lT4KopOkSQdU/NVY4ZdqDGMmt+06mfCKVVI5diBSfifcEm+TS5KZjUjmFeh5kJIWTk5iOJhsT6N3b6oZf6gcZyHbEHdt3E58/3t07GbzfyYXKdJsj7SRj1XWz00hpgpFgk2iRQ/mPUHYh9+ShNmHGiCVdwhyP5ZXKm1qpU78KPcY041vv4nT4RlvA4jILkwBgxBwW1iT9CtomWQVVc2UbXCsQIyksW9n0M3Gy5Lh9HtqNILThO", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-B, 2-C, 3-A, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-D, 2-A, 3-C, 4-B", 
		"option_c": "1-C, 2-D, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-A, 2-B, 3-D, 4-C", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030159", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kS3i8sUMWw3mhdS/ImLECyI9qmyXEopdTH/PXbTWLsS+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWyjwW6MP7tWf7FJp3gFVy1sc4rYgQNcSLmYG61EPpxjaL32+eT69lAVyQto676FGVsJZ4usvNmTPJ9eTpm/aT+dAYYRpbr5J2bFWv1+VJuGp4EYj0KFILsaSQIRStYGjjZ05dueqj82x51Ic6TmA6819PhoZXcYBy2JykszA6Os5+BnOuq1ZP0pN0Hwefd6mtwm333FttNU84YMpium0SswqZIxR/lG/cbT5QmYFi/ZAKlhZqbXtT3H/uwh6YiGqEfZ2j4o7vhvr5sK1q/a00aQzAFxzvRIQIbL3HZ0ZhwuaQDKgcOpF0FDDvLcEn8zfqYJ+anwkM29AzO3bptCuXlo3UP2KyspzwncB3GoMOZZH35sey8FPBIQHzIHWeb4vnWhr5X2i42gAllgstxyoR5iLRBpp85yQdine/R1ck32egLDzh1v4cqsLOP85xk7WsnXJQ2Nc4spr+2l0vRBaynWsDtIuND31cxVvdH8NHzQc9D6YIBILY/WOF1X/eC1UDe8f3PabTgwVFyuzjmmBzvJVOWorOIBjVjp4h2ha/Fb1wW3Tuuo/pKfUaBHdst/Ixiq3h94r7NbPkbCVqL1r3Ga8Zs9URKEI7UUudRWQPIPjuct0tVfVLy3zEkEdJSXxAAFTYu6QJUwDqud3bem/TI7ASCl7jZ74MHcfrWlXOIfimxnIkWpXTKYl3jzS1YrGf4XBk", 
		"answer": "2+T1Sd2zg1TIu8VzHz2+hamyESkbWZFqd+gJMvJVXa48A2Eh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF77y+78J2LAF2serWzDRaZmdTH0Rq7WeujwiZ5/Z13JnVJ45nnBsaTg/1oMz7tY+4ePZG5De5N/2tWaxO35wzFIN8NFicBz6p5fc/ZKyT65Z5TPKOxh22mIZ1X5ZC2oFnVn1BbEj3ld6IK18WeaRts6wRwx1pR7/8EsKMTfzq2B7Q2tlQOGnHKfCJx3GVuStMDo4k2Po5AxpdmEvjzItP332urW99cEbBsSs490ZhuMlqMA6z45X4i1ZhYL0OLXaVXjKTu3JgBdzcPmllZ7x4okVCkn9w1PkpcWdcFglozsuXI9PsRkVSC5sU1Q09R6UAXWVa6w32Pl7hU2e2kod4N9qCQ6rxzcIVo+s2WYRS0RvY54/cIQhRBqcmFT3GTlgTCZhGyBe9Pv6o74xe/iobd34eMmO0TAPFHIWZ8IZL3UZ2F92KmIGbNYKpZpEGLyNdBu/Tf6KZOay3kB0dckb2T+5z6cn430N2H6spb0h9p/B6sSN8XM5sX1Tx7YqVteMSDKMwN/h6pKHg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_c": "1-B, 2-A, 3-D, 4-C", 
		"option_d": "1-C, 2-D, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030160", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kS3i8sUMWw3mhdS/ImLECyI9qmyXEopdTH/PXbTWLsS+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWyjwW6MP7tWf7FJp3gFVyuo5r+YgVFeuRiOix+kSsjxWKnH+US7R0GVGLuMum/wOTpsIZpsWCujPVtP33ifvB+c4fawdcrMYyIxv81+hJuGp4EYj0KFILsaSQIRStAWiQIhwL8MXklnV6hpIsT2Q1+hpIlsNea9Nn2YrtvzM8f8xpFjyvrVBT+5ouHz6YZ76q2Xjw6VoxZjoka8p5uSAlrQrcP1VylnjcTT8RhoVo8cIdhkQuPS8A3Dagwn/LwCXPPNOjq8C8xaiw4PkjsuNnaQHAdRz6FqcdaLbTZ1dgw+eICLYbIN91GC7jfdwgvGihc8Go0WpN8cooIHzm+mqQnN72K2yqp5v2gMc2HbFAFMPE4ca+8F3JZWPKKXyBadj8TQD5D2/7wQd1owtlhWFQqCL7SK528zke3ni/WwR2lyvpa3Wug60c+pecb4Ei1uas3ytQjvVqlpTix101SQCym3ZHp4WTXGBBmRTyEcMG0AA4CfQTEZXe4GmF1X/eC1UDe8f3D+iPyj9c1fHoziw9/9BOFczObFmbyp5miFfxQb05FSet6Ma5fbxVSiRsuvIxiq3h94r7UbOXL3cjfw73T+5L+pRFYQ11AkvIFiFLILGgFpkXR+ZKwHDEg0daQnhAClTfuZfEnyt8S5U3ia1/ZnkfN+k=", 
		"answer": "2+T1St2zg1TLu8VzHzq+hamyFilVY6ILkPOHiVfVQO3n74k0", 
		"explanation": "25eqYYX6whGq84AjWw76wO/yMGXEQ20X416QWqx/cX+jXanRbf/32YN4KFKazUx64TbHoKb/+kMDhrtT7IrfcjtDVIpizcPJ5/b+ymJEI4ZNlMAjvMlIMLRB332gcdrPKfFgy2rALkuwczG4RGB1hyLXjXkWgY2o9jWyRM4+zxsh1oh2rdw5MceT3OiE6UG0lUaR2WmHTf1lAhSJsNyl6k2ZrpZ4vcSepT3J/ff4lrjS890EdwZGrMZ+bV/8ha0Z9zkxRcemYRdYsevWIV3jJiexKg8J8MTtllV6zo0iXGd0/RFVgZFfctR62Zb3/CU1LcgqEzyvrUAAzpo8XRiCfP2s2G2kwkc+fXciJYtjuG0eqQ6OJ0d2jmOVDD9Shol76sNV1RZme2NFn2LpjDjLlmSddZL34o/ylqj5rvlw8bEuOVXAIE/ZUYhcZLDSKHRhiu2SC6BZIZppA2L0ONIn8zfqYLKb0TgZ2c8lb2Xi9yWLlt61K2C8toC5mts2HbETNcPM+d++v1LUITfpIGnTdM73Vhr0D3vx1Rp29x4q2mEC7W7RD4Bw4D5NjmuiWUt3lzSgYX2lk/5e88KYfpw43OD/nTsenP1ulp/i1REvBcN5k2sULaBsN4wPvpMwFRs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-B, 2-A, 3-D, 4-C", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-C, 2-D, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030161", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJhFVo8WTPs7H5+F0cz6FIqY2QYjAGfZ819N612bW37X9SMNRNipR765QMPONF3jjtZMbSLf98x2KZZ1f1ZDavAHVw1D7YymtZp4e++2evVdg7xQEh1oZ26Yg+Lt6c0rvfqEy2gkaW1H6ICKphA1HZuM+h5U+F4JcrsMnNtz3JtPX9l/Hd+c0fcAlGtpB6I0uphbgG6y8rbcaIZkALxezVIUH+JWisIU4u+MXw3WZg0sIgUyk9+gxFkIpGdsl82IukvjczPsBvVSSzp0FT14Z5XhPWcKiq2WbjoEE3cDoMcJp5vW0lpB2VJ1BClFeSH2x4mpNo7NkJgQ1sc3wAjGTvlDaPhSWZfZ/26oLwgKj5rqpq9aszOgGJO0jXFoUVdqfPNW5xy+XbCLBZPYt0W2L0ONkn+zD2NYXUzysM080pLHL0uGqYnMm1OGG3upzwncBkFasJINSF5MqjpFnVcmG8vi2aHqY+aGyJhrCaIMtz", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqq+IssS1z5CJjjQYToCkb2LtWsGmEU", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQr+9pElXxv80b2udWLDQ2sfoHCRQKZ3ZDHiR+fLYP79255hM1WGg0g75XPUpuXi8lAAnaxe7c6QfmIVf5lmx8Wal+n20HRTOsdIicwy944eaPFNyTO5Z5SJYP9gyi7TZ0TiYnm8B3NhhjDCjzxlqY2o/jWyQJ0kgAUgmYpx480yP9Lf0KbT4UOrhRSLzG+YR7N3UVOLsNno71aOqYw/9dmFtHL84eTtm7jD9cwCbQwe/4dxZxu1mbsK6iMoRcG7ZgEL4fbfd13pJWi1JgII+Mnv0zRhz5E9Uns99x5KwoJYZoBy0pXtsjsjK99rATqspgRJyYd1WB+CZ/90HJ3K1tQq20PXNo8lrnsn", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030162", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJrEhz/X3HreX5+UAMnaFL/YeQfjFDd5gvy9+bxeH00E1PD8gV1MBT95IQd/VOjDSjZ9fJKe56x2GONAXnYiu4RGBmnTzXmHVascOs5y6vQN85gBw81pNw6IgXNNaN1rub/EWxxhWBznKBXIFqLVrL+46c40aPpcIxu96OozvL4P32lOuT4MwEdAFWusZ2bV2zhaUI7CM3X4i1ah1e5aTxclziKynkNE4c+sPq02Jsy4cnSXp09RFCwq5Xd9Jq19jstSEkMN9zKT2GrRcOh6B0Wlebdbe3wmHw+RUwczoKdoJityw74QaSO1dsk3uIRSNfh8B8+8Ic1QBmfmZQlHPyhzvLgnzPVpLu7pO8tfr5rqpm4uMuJwGUPVmYB9UIbfPDImlm3/uCT1Kga06/Tv4i1j0epmy3Bt0=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqq+IssS1z5CJjjQYToCkb2LtWsGmEU", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNGjTFnAQt3rDU7A0UWLrW6zDYK33x4RyNVWZmVJ0/GWGtKDi8hMfnaFW6JyWfDtDd4Uv6sKI3+n+hGJCIc9UjsBB8JsLeflFwim+NIabIfBqjj3AJlf1Jy2vEXU053H3mXRZo4K1tS61R9klyQUmn4h2/ogzOtGay+ia5l6xgQ6WzzuYRqlrUXWKvcGj6gSP4IM7vcSIpzfW8frtibjS/tpLagFBq4ltehf8lqYNuAA5XM2nKCJZ+OrDZEStJC2gLh4V/Nnm0jRkx4wwHWA65xxUi5NCa899xdjtsnIkN8gqRGuuqwRDwppoSgWPNnew3bx+DCiSe6RgRMJ+AAM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030163", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJnlhp+2bSsOXl5FYLz6FVqY+RcysGcJ8v4d6N3uX5hHhPIMVWk5Bm7ZURb7RJ332Oe8bJJf16lFKOG0uhKXmJDHU0tiPXgnFf6JC45y6rQJogwQZygo99rdguOdOQ1KGd6UOsxhWBznKBXP1xAlGd9cemq2KPqI0ztMPNuDzI9+bwiuza/9AYIglRrYlscBuVmawA+RY2bcbmJlJ/+eGQSlzsMiewLxoV8Ivw1WZg1pZpSmgntA9Ui45XcMl/z9jxrzc0f8tlB3OtsU1Uzpp7HzaFfLKz0Wak6VssdmgidZ5ksyMm4QaSaGR/kWKPWC1f1IFl+pA4kwNrfGFJj2LhjAOFvGvcMtPX44W8renioalz861nIE+TNk7RRpkVar3TZ2Zgz6mMH69IJ5ppVyvofdRu7DD6NJmTzTgd2NAjb2Tk5iOJho3hMWSu85r4nZR0EboOdsLQ6siyo0/BdC/tOD2XY8j9SQD1XXn8kXM9MvD3l+x2Oa8Z8y97rSw=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuq+IssS1zFcTLAp79rBM9JHXd+bJt+", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQr+9pElXxv80b2sdWLDQ2QQr2yGHuN1YzHLVbXDfv3/x9diJE6AnU874HPLoqz+5BMagaxe6oePeCcRe48jiMOd1vDyyXRPJ9UEy8Bz6p5fLrRB3jjtddfYNexv2mvAE031JxuvBXh5nXHFiW5fuJf74iaoFM0+xBAhhpV97Mx8OtiNmYmA4EKzhwjC1XWCS69tAUCQusC7pwOdroZ4nsWMoz3I/ODxk7jE8c1LdxtXu8Z2bRuvh60K8SwxUoimbRVC/urDIxomNdST5YcnBrNrE8PMh80=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030164", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJm1Rv+2DD47f19Fwdi7sb4IDfcSwAd45h3JCg2eD+xTFIIIZnlZJg4ZkLJshO8DP8NOLUNPd4yy6SIkb/dT2uRH11nT/akzxUrY+0+yD7QNV30hA+n4Bx4t0vfMON2Kya/ES3iBXCz26SQP1lAhS7oMqs40qPrc54n8yEvzvI+bi5m/bXsO0DYwFEtpVyX1WAmfpJzCI9Qs30ehdI/vbUchTsMi3jMxcN8Mji2nhwhoQmSGcwtBBIwpBCbc52lojtsD4xLd4qFD2+41BFyoRwWleBdbG0w1Tq3FtsNUwkcYN7uW0npAyTOlBt2mqOSWxBholm/8IQmR0jfmBOn3PyjDqPwHKGaJuj6oTxjOb5s61x87cuP0TAOF3MQogOdvPBKWMy2OaCDKocN5pkBSfjLpeDQyC8PJ7rPDxLcoa7/Qzx", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuq+IssS1zFcTLAp79rBM9JHXd+bJt+", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQr+9pElXxv80b2sdWLDQ2sfoHCRQKZ3ZD2jVbSCeOLqwIF0Z06MjlRp9mWGorf1t0MdhqVa+4eTaWIRe4dmz9mGwve7hGJVMtJBl4V88IlfLbRBwjntJpTaMvsu2nyVIgXGaC20EnU0hjTVhW5Su8O65yL7VckkzxY7l5N96YgrNcOXmbqW5ES/jwmXzzuFWrxgGECQusC7q0KSpMI5p8jNvjTP8fq5nPfG/tpLbQYSr49zb1quhOgI9i54Rc25eB5OsfPRbVj+YpG+Qro9wblLjsef5q9xVxc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030165", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJhFVo8WTPs7H5+F0cz7pe5Y+LdSZDaoQvxNGH06Tw1nBPJ9Uepo5O6stRPNhBwjntc8baLuoux2CTJFf5dy20C35n1CbTmHkWpYKy+yuiFN85xwczgIJ8rccyfNSQybiW+l20hxKHz0efdLM2XxStvcu77gOVrpE7p8SdpTvU+ue5iurc5tcPZ0hbsZV2ZFOohOgA9j43Edy8bVJH8OrUIUf0MzymKk4c98+j13Bkz4wgTn0m9QtPjY0WbcYz15bntTc+K41DGzezonhO+5ovEVe6dbO8kG/24VsrZjo8YJho/CgtogOJO11on2eFDCFQkIUr/MlZng1tenwAnXjkwi+ZiWuMeYCj7Y/uxfr1rLBk+6wyOgGQIE7IWZ4ZdvFKXBvkN2fMcg4RFuUUPXAf", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqq+IssS1z5CJjjQYToCkb2LtWsGmEU", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+QW613dTHvVanGLursyJllZ1WHnlhp+2bSqqr+5BMYirpeqYOedCdDcYUv3tGb3uvi1zFSJtRCm4N399o3c+NF2ji/OJTINP96y2OFKVHjJ2v9BX5w1GKWi25T6IK49jKpVc4ygGZymoZ26Yg7LtaRzeia5l67lA+SyHKeRq4kHlKfsNzo4k2PqYUwod7NuDzP+7T4lPva9dAfIgRTsYI/cEKvg60E62Z4UMawKAZD9PfVIVP/ISa3NE4K/Nnmlnpm0sI6UmUx+AYGj4JSZ4Bxz9j2sysxM9lzVxcnBV7BEJNGyh22b5WIm7g=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030166", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he3tMH3RD2cfoHrDXaU0QGPiX7XLeq3yyJl2Ml2OiBty/DbHrab58l0bz4FV7YeefmIKcJhs2tmZw+34ymIBJMdX2ox76ZMLefAAzTu5ccabNPZrjn2FJEr+Y3m+AX5ggSPPyl1ylI2H+xW+Vck4zk9ypYZ2/sMuNcPf3qma5ki8xhaQ03aYRrhqElHZtN3o/0uZ4JIqvMCMoyub8eTwnerS4NYCYUhfuoJ2dlb8k70b8SQ/Edy8bVJs5PTEYBT9JTqqKApf9abY9Xztt1n0G0Eone68Ng==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStz+CQeNHcX/wX7XLeqrtiYdjIkqIgV518XOGqquw/l0cjLpS+ZqWfywQPoJhy8KM1vfywDFFJtRNlIcy8JIaPNNV3CmsNMTeMvdhyi60L0CwdTy8F3961DjFympXpIq/tSaoFNMjgAUgmZFx6c0vfMOX3OiS606tlAeW2TuUUK1oEFqYocen5QOIqIMs9f6MvyHQ5v3t3euT4tcYZ0heuoI/d1T8g6AMuCYxXMGgbRYL5PfVIVvrYBixJgUP8N+j33opw5IgWns15BdPgcNCZ9hnxdo5/wxhOk5+ulP99j3sEzHg", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030167", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfn6NmLAC2cDrnqNRuN7djHLVbXDfv3/x9d4KU+Kn1Jr5n/Jrbaw/1Icz6pe7IDfYzcAfY5829ac26i31nRXNsdIk451pI4Xef1SjDGketPOKe16x23AJkv0JzqoCGRhhjDaym9fr42y8y64VdQ0xSk8qolK6MkvM9nFmZyb7Q2QhxSDzGuQRv1tH0eap8e4/0qTrpF4osiftHLM5v3tjv3dsNcFIgkSr498d1S7hakZ8CM7Edu3ehtb5aTEaVX5YCusKRgY4M7nln1tw4M6HX085hBThYsWcslwwo32uSFyWWXF+IPOZrfVEbuQqgq6dg==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/M2rcEGdd432WRuNgeHSjRqLDfeLwiZ5iZ0ibmF45Clg720YyikIsg2B1JHkzqg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/M2rcEGdRsHaNUaY0ZHnmFLfDff7/zpIxLlKNhFh65nPV47H49kdPp6lJ6J6PcSxDd4V8y8KAx/D+y39Sc9RBl4F76toKcvBFzzS9fNHJJfou5mGXIlP1dXX9EHhx1CPTi29ZpsOy5me6V9ki0hQmk8s45cE7NNuW3qCH4UO/xhKK2TuEW7gkHlLZtI644kCIr4UqtN2FuDGb5/frk+jHsNcFIiBTrYdvc1qy16EH6ykqWNigYR1F4qbqALQbvnpik9TeC3i+Fw88", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030168", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hen6NmPeCnMEpj+MVONxfnbxVbHLYOq+wJliJE6AnU9y/XjV46r+t0AbgKZeqYmNcSYWf4dj0ZCN0uf7zX9EN4ZNlMBb6p4WfbRByimoZpTPKPsu7WaSLlbkbjizRHVmlQ3YtnJkrYKo+inhFPk40AU3hJd07Nw5L5ea1K2B70i8xgeRnG+ZTf10A12UtNyxq06ZpIstuI2LviCb/frqmera4MoCbQZB/4JqcVKykOgd8C94VMmmZAsL8uHedUH/KS2wZwEbud/r0zRKzpAgTn099REGh5FXIBkZ4kn36uFA8ztFJuDdmu4=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw/kBPnL1L+YGNZCcHPol2iMSB0qTnxWJSMsFB3ZMy7ZQZc+ZNzSmke9qbIfxh23rAM031JyyuATB7knHVhWxGrZGr+SavUcl7gAI6n4t9rdw0OZeN3KmA50P4hwWByWmQXLhoCBScuc+q5FGdtIcr9cKD8SbT8bT8l/3B99sFYQ0SsIA/YFSsh60b6CY5Rc2nKBRE46TZb0fuMiGzMwcS99ihWNX/pPneccDGXaPcEardTw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030169", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd/tNGPdCiICoG2KQrc0fXDqWrPDZ+P7zdd4M0/JiVR2+3jHrab1t1IMnadI+s62fiYKf8cvzciK0vTjhHhPc9JMn8B864gLdLlXyS65ccbVYO5v3Hq8KXn+VTy8F396znHignkWvZC+tSi9FM4/xVUZnoZq4ts0KN+WmbuQ+kSokkaE02nRQbN3EkaQpdqh5E2P4JU5po2auDbe5+Trn/nXsNcFIgVdrJI/cV67nqcH62o3V4i1ZhFC9OrEIX3jJCGiZbqzynsU8AcZlYml0+P5okc=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RomzDRqtxMGHiR7TDaei+xJJ/M1WGg0g75n7D46H/+loBjqZY7M6QdmIhbIpnxdnJxOflzWFVc8NcmYVi8NoWcrRUxDjtetvJNPYj2WuTM0DiaXmtBWJg1BnZnXlArZH3tTOzUZolxRQhmYk45Nt8Ndmc1rqB7U6sykaDzzuFQLgkAVWKps+v7gOYr4cru4qZ8T/e+uDwlfaT59cPZxtCrYN+ZxuphK1J9yx4esC1eh1Y+fDYaBTkLmiuKB0Judnm0X1myJFryWf3Ml458LbkN9rjm+BmaA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030170", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfn6NmLAC2cDrnqNRuN7djHCR6/NZezwiZ5/NF+bhEtv+3nIsOXg+EAKi+haqY2XcS4Pe4VozZCNwuG30H4BJ85B2pVh4doQerRDwzC9eNHDYP9gyi6VKUPxajCxDXFm1CLVmHVGvJCH+xu1Zt820xo8zMdS7MU5L5evy6Gd+0ioxhWX33iUW65iBFiVrI6s7kCVsIo9p8iJ8TPX+LTYifDc+98FIgFcrIVtakuonqcH62oxX4igYBcLoLzEaRTuJSa3MhwEtYvx02Jsx44gU2504BdDi5EWaslgwpf2tTExM415HDS0qkJJxJVyXBLUWgj1zit2j9krm3M6G3AElQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw9lAMmrpa/YuTaWIHe5hs2tmL0ve30HlEc8VMm4x+4ZQYebRPyn2pcdfSMPZr3GeOIAXRdDGyD3F61DjYmX9EoZOv/Ci1R5ofzwI3gIJqoYgoNNLfy62S+0K2xg+RnHKfS7J2A1GaoY6p+AO2oY89po29ozvV5/Hp2vzW89cbag1AuoI/XxmxlqYQxGh4WManawBC4fDZblr+bGitKBpd+MfvmjRo1cI6SWgg8RsGi40Wdsh2lojlryExOMgox5JTdM9UfyvLC5sJKJPbNA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Material Remains to Inscriptions", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhvh0fTyNH/VByIFqnKGErNxYnjsUOfNaK3qwZIxJFOEnVJ382LPrKuw+FVPvKlV7o+SMC4Kao59ycScxeGohtif3JYtrVt3i7qhurHQm9M=", 
		"answer": "2+ToOOKggUmq1qFikiElaw8hpWzdJRbRyBUl4w==", 
		"explanation": "24a5Zpby3Fnm/pElQB/m0O/6dWLDQ2AUr3aGRKZwMGXsFK/DeOi+y5J0KRyKglZr+3rDp+Xy8kcYiq1VqZqXdWIFd5l83JCI2eC30HlIIcIEmYV88I8NdfFTjByJNiBi13T/IQ1lWyl6ekCZg5k=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1000â€“700 BC", 
		"option_b": "500â€“300 BC", 
		"option_c": "200â€“100 BC", 
		"option_d": "100â€“300 AD", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040102", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H6wlnp5YAkWwr3wb3oPH/YQ3YZpj+FW611fDHgW6rSZ+H/3Z5+KRyGixtv+nOGgrfk/1Ich6lI/ZyeMC0FPqBu3cSA2/32mzOHpl+Rm5QCC42aKcbLdWpI", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/3wxjt4pU0U17fxOjtLGqSGs29Ravm9amy8XcT7XZNmw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSww3i9pYoUw3m1/y/ImrDQ3IEtz+KXON9ZGKjUq7Mb+G+z5hjKhyNmEly/HGGt631t0cGgq0b5ojfUyoCcI99ydecx/D2hFxAJtRdm8wy5YgQafpEjCmlcZTZJflnwGCJKUKwaD/9EHhx1BLemHVFvIq6+2e+Rtt1Tez8ayduP/SamLBbVNybFQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ashoka", 
		"option_b": "Chandragupta Maurya", 
		"option_c": "Chanakya", 
		"option_d": "Bindusara", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy7PP7PGreQ3YUu2vDW7A0YGPqWabQZ+HniZR+KkyGnl5/snnA47Xi9koKnbsXqZyWZDcCcpgjiN2I0O30iDFAPcIEl5lm7JUTc/NJzzyhNMfPL+xny33fZVuutTiiKXQ0SNpqAvhtptw=", 
		"answer": "25i5YJDx2Rj49pEhEHE0UH6l8s3Sk8FQnjuNjKw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe0BHr9Y0hQB/mxL38OmbAEWsCpmzDXKxgMH7tWL6CeuX7iZlwNU6ImVJt9zbJpeXk/1ZPpKlO+4+JcW8zf4VrycaIl+f4yndNOsVQ2oJn8NoecOdPjDSjd9jOJPt9jn6SJlz1dSrxRGJ9gCTXhm8a6I668i64GJo2zhFym55s5ccwM9CW2qmfqF6siRSL2WjTk+5uN+pvF7YyGBNxqQEoyw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mahabharata", 
		"option_b": "Ramayana", 
		"option_c": "Rig Veda", 
		"option_d": "Upanishads", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040104", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7+zOn6J2rEFnAU436RV+NgeHSjfqbWb+b/2sgzXbC+hABe25SQcM7wRcomww==", 
		"answer": "25O3ZJqzxRjm8pZi354MoQ5XJWNHqtaoi+0XNg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ0A3r/IQzEh/gwL35OmfbQ3YQr3qQEqdxYHjgQK7Maa3qwZIxN06Mm1J052WGoazi41scz6ddqameZTYCc4ov6sWN0+z2hHBPN4ZLnIZ39toWcudJyzW5Z5TSLuphjnqIIgXjaDq0AWRt1DDYjjxTq4y1+iqiFNUxgBQ8lY5949x8KN6S3LvRXw8hcqJcTLuyNf1W4TLtVg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Historical chronicles", 
		"option_b": "Religious scriptures", 
		"option_c": "Philosophical treatises", 
		"option_d": "Folk tales", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy7PP7PGreQ3UesXTDW7A0c37tR67Ga//7zddwZ1GIh1RpsmXJtrfz8hMJgLob+pqKdDsKcIwvyd6K3uH50DFoPcJNm44y9JUTdeBZjDyjcJTeI/FgwWOZeAe7sBwWdENbZ2BaaF6qhCQe", 
		"answer": "25SqfJnywhHr5JEyU1wOXBekhPfVgDuDLdPcu9EN", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSww3i9pYoUw3m1/y/JXnfFWsVpmzDQKp3eDHuVbPHfOT/xdd3KE7JmVN+smXStqHpt1wJz6lV6oeafjZDV4VrwdGHl/T4yHhVKoZFlIQy4ZkQcvtN1XHte9LdJexnwGnALkvjbj61EGM0nT/ChTxFvIKv8CSpVdwjgBQ8ksd/4t45Ltme16uWqEmtlA+M2zuFQLgkPFWMp9ep5QOMpZAxusnPWSo1g8rhmQ/dG+11/yF8Ig==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ramayana", 
		"option_b": "Upanishads", 
		"option_c": "Mahabharata", 
		"option_d": "Arthashastra", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040106", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7Q0Pn7PWLDFyIFpmeXQeNjdWPmFLDQZ/nqzJkxLlLJmlNy8X6Gr6T+8EYOiK0Eq5Ba70r0Z1vCPr7qRwqjTzk=", 
		"answer": "24W5ZJixT7xFP0/a8gLgB/jEGMyvhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7Q0Pn7PWLDFyIFpmeXQeNjdWPmFLDQZ/nqzJkxLlLJvVp3+zqGouX2+EECz6ddqb6NcSkRd58v28CG3OH5hHhPc9JMn8Bf5Z0eePxBjC+oc93ULrys1j+Qgd0T6PjrXADjVY0E", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sanskrit", 
		"option_b": "Pali", 
		"option_c": "Prakrit", 
		"option_d": "Magadhi", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040107", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5EoV17EwPn+O2zRED1TcYEAjPpTaena4z0Sk1AjQw==", 
		"answer": "24ateIH/1BTv+ZEzEgr9hen3MCvmBmYQsD0Ber2cj4tlcxGxIb33AuIC", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF1B3r+YIhQV7z1/i/JmLIQ3EEs2+PV65xfmXiRr6CauTtyp5hK1WHiEg79nPQpqn/51YLz7xUqY+WdGIXdo4v28Sc0/23y3cBJ85B2rZ34JsMMLRJwj6hYdDSLvku3XuCLUDzcyr9CHl/kXHGgnNYrZey9jT3FN0lwRg/l5U0rckyOJeS1rqWqoZdLBl2JJwrnXA7yWT2nRU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ancient Indian epic poems", 
		"option_b": "Philosophical dialogues", 
		"option_c": "Supplements to the Vedas", 
		"option_d": "Historical chronicles", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040108", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy7PP7PGreQ3YUu2vDW7A0e3/sQ6mCaOLsiZR+KUiIhFVy/HGGs635+1wcgLhT4I2efGIQbo5s3dyIw+34ymIecf6qKvmYo7y9tSRApwVnEnU=", 
		"answer": "24CoaZ/6whHr85ZiJAr6r5Y5mX+WvMhlUS2DLg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwRjk/pYoUxrhhf7wO3/RCmxRs3eKXqxnf2HrXaTDYq3t2ZJyMlCImVJ0/GWGoqf/4kdPm6BeqYCeZDcRe8tgzpCb0uX7zWVYc8dKnsBh4ZYZMLRSyS2/ccfeLupnwGnAM031JzqoCH19mjDCg3NY6Iy9tRG+UNM0gAE6mZJ/5dx+/9i8ZRYfZ4sljgDRKKeAcA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Rig Veda", 
		"option_b": "Mahabharata", 
		"option_c": "Upanishads", 
		"option_d": "Ramayana", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040109", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H6wlnp+IszWxr31/j7dX/YBiIQtmuLXbE0f3ejQK/HLursyJp8Jk7Jgl07wnfIqqv5qBEp5D+j/nXpYh62ZDOXR+Ri", 
		"answer": "24W5Zpj92FtSDrtxWD5mQGpsFrLOrFil", 
		"explanation": "24W5Zpj92Fnr4pEoXQz3wb3rPW6QBHAQrnKCQON/fn70WufDfa3Ci7ZiL0iIiVNi82/P75myt1wJia1J4ICYMCsNbYJowMSal+350H4BIMlHk4Vm/dZfefdPwjKgbZibIfBqjm2VK1HldTz9AGVmnT/RynRfu8Ov/Cq+FiVBDBhBgwGzMR8C8viroi0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Valmiki", 
		"option_b": "Vyasa", 
		"option_c": "Chanakya", 
		"option_d": "Panini", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy7PP7PGreQ3YUu2vDW7A0e3/sQ6mCaOLsiZR+KUiIhFVy/HGGs635+1wcgLhT4I2efGIQbo5s3dyIw+34ymIecf6qKvmYo7y9tSRApwVnEnU=", 
		"answer": "25G9ZIXy2Bqqw4QtWxKy6/z7IClOZC4R/lMi7msyOcin1jI9", 
		"explanation": "24a5Zpby3Fnm/pElQB/m0O/6dXzRECIBsXCHR6BxdDHqWufWZui+zZJ9M12Ajhtp93HPrKvjt1wJz5xa5IeTMAwCep4jiMCb2PL+wHhPNIZNlJN745ILb7RJwimiNMDTJb58y2mJKEu3dHm8CnN9kT/Cym9Zq4q6+Wv7Udk4zho/n4Q0rckyOJeP1qSa/ES7hwrC0HKXTf+VM3sDmkd8pML3WvoskGNK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Central India", 
		"option_b": "Western India", 
		"option_c": "Northern India", 
		"option_d": "Deltaic Tamil Nadu", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040111", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hT6/okhRhf9y73wMyvjAmwWonLDXqpgdWPiQLLQa6G+yNdyKFCFiFhv+3nI46r2t2cOgqFXqZ6QdTYRZ8cvwcPJ1vDj1nhDJtJBnsBm69oLdPEA8wKSS+vkH8FR8VG/GHrPWHm+AX5ggSPfj28a6Iat8Cn7QNI41RI61pNw6Ig6Ndme1eiQ50CojwqDyHKeRv1oGF+cudfo/0yTq8IoucyOtHLS+rTtkv2T49cTdgASvINxd06ujuoWGgA2oPFxQl0l5hYShm/6", 
		"answer": "27OxeoLnkR/l4pdgcRbgzO7rPGreQVXPebkJRMv4vXB68q4wwT0=", 
		"explanation": "24a5Zpby3Fnm/pElQB/m0O/6dWLDQ2AUr3aGRKZwMGXsFK/DeOi+y5J0KRyKglZr+3rDp+X/4VYdz6kb+YuNeS0HPoRpiMSBxeHyhGVOc8BLj5Iy558RaOFSxTi+OJTMKepmjmeUNAX2bje8CDB3mzzGg3BXvIq0+2e0V9ki0gc7mIA45MZ8KN+ambua8FmwxgWH0m+EWqQmoCLwGu+GZBA6f3oNQJnhUQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fi,rs,t fo,ur Ch,ri,st,ian", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040112", 
		"question": "24GwbdHSww3i9pYoUw3m1/yzdWrEF3AYoWqXV6c0ZH6jf6bXeuTy0JY9Z0ybgk1y9nPV46Sw81YbjqFX7IrfeSwQd4xn3JCA2fD4hGVJNoZWn4F+6Ylfc/IAzTOufdHVNL5HwGqJJkvPWAaCO09Lqw7ptUNpl7yEt86lP1CHQqalVgSctG+3Ngw=", 
		"answer": "26W3ZJjnyFnr+YFgVx39y/LyLCnWc9Mci7NKwNDrf2hXR/io", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSww3i9pYoUw3m1/y/Om3WBnAC422KUas0fXD3UbXLb+G+z5hjZ0iBiBto5mPCuuX/8RMOgatS7ICLMAsNeoJuxpCZ2Oj+0GgBMshA2oVx65QQce0MjDKrctHJKfBpjmeONEz3by2uRHl6gD6WjXNArZG19Cm4UZo2zhFyk4R348cxNdSMmayG+kS2gUaW1H7RZbxxA02Yu4647lGVr4Z6hiOvvAiOaj87AB0Qmq6Lxw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "po,li,ty and E,co,no,my", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040113", 
		"question": "24GwbdHGwRjk/pYoUxrhib30O2THDSIXrG3DRqtxeWOjRLXNaOLrx5MxN1SAgVRo/WbOqqbx+xMcn61Y/IKeZCsMcJgjiNWRx+j41nQBJ85B2o5z8I8NebRPyn2/cdXXKep3jm+OIwXjYjW7RGR8hj7DjXQWuIuy+SioW8o/yRYzmsdH0vcDA+ig5pes13KHuTm9nsY5PYFcnKGSmuBJHfPdLts=", 
		"answer": "27a3ZoX23Anm9pEpXRCwd0jWqQuDHE/4SRfy4VUyYg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwRjk/pYoUxrhhfztMCvCBnQUsXqHEqV7YjH3XKLLfK36zJJhZ0yBhFd04XnWq6zz9l9PirBL5YGNcTYKcYV8iNGH06Tn1n5XOsJB2ol895MYdOBTjDSjYNubNPZrjmCBM1DiYnmyAjBmkTDag2hP6IK18WeoUdYxgAE6hIht6sB8P9iRza2e+EG5kg+U2TuVQa5nBEeKvMGm+AEzaeHrywp/D+yOvMTLF9Zm", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "co,nt,em,pl,at,ion", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040114", 
		"question": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Ejznwfn3PHjEQ3YUu2uQErRxYnSjRLXLY+zswJtoZ0ubhE9v93iGqquwx1IDhuQb6M6ZfzAOPoRpiO+26NvI+05+DPl7pb9N26VfcPVOyyisc9GbM+5hxWuOZ0z+Jy21ATBZlTbXjnRX6JG+8i60Wph5UqF9F4Ypn+q1fnahFpw3", 
		"answer": "24WqaZrh2A2oOgYE+m3qqcuGA7F7lSJ3Sw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7Q0Pn7PWLDFyIFpmeXQeNjdWPmFKTNY/3x2pJ1Z1WHzWt6/n+K46Sw81Ydhr5a/YeJdWIMeMtf2tGCxe3jhGJRPM1BlMB76toLdPEA4TyqddDTIb58y2mJKEu8Jza7AnVmnT/RynVYu4q8/TOoFNM51Bpygo99rcQ9MtCK2K+WqEy2gkaByXeFXa9hUVuf9dqg7gOIqY899xrXRr2JCn5Sc4iPFvRPe+s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pr,ak,rit,ret", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040115", 
		"question": "24GwbdHF1B3r+YIhQVKy1ujvJWfVDmcft36RS+NweWLgXbfOZ+P72tdlKByIhF87xHPCqqaw5Ecai6Fe+sLfeSwAcp5rzZCawub9wXJVIIZIk4t3pIoXc/pF2DSuZ5ibJ+xvw2OBNQmwYi2kCX94mzbPxjxEoZeu9Cv3FNcy1Ac7lZQ0rckyOJeg5pes13KHuTm940Sud4JbUzd+ZSI9335nCfCcQFdTXGM=", 
		"answer": "27SrfIP83xbn7sdpeUq3gjWmeeIrcjyAG8U6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF1B3r+YIhQV73y/7wOHvREHFRtX6RW6xhYzHnXbTBZ/3ywJl0NBDJhFV4/mPCqqv3t1Icm7pU54GSaW5DaYNmy9jJx+j23XRFc8cEmZJn55MecLRSwzGoNN3VYOtgymuSNFHxaT20Cnc0lzTaj29CoYK3tTezUdQ4zRA8l8d548x8KN6S3KOW7V2xiAHC2G6DQbNjUVWXtset5VfctIs1sN7P4BGfBEc6yQkqL+GFtzlJjw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "as,tr,on,omy,ony", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040116", 
		"question": "24W5Zpj92F75t4IyUxP/xO+zdWDeDHUf436QEp82UWLrQKbGZvT/0J49Gx7JnUl05H/Cpraw+Vwbz6dV5ZfffCsNeZ5m28SA1KT+ymJINM5QicBw8Y5fffhTw32qeN3WMO1r3S6JKVH/Jy21ATBnmzLfj2hP5MO+9ii1W9cujFUzmIM40vcDA+ig5pes13KHuTm94zueTv1sGEfZsNypqVfvnlLTacuNLUBITbOdANk=", 
		"answer": "27atZIXmwxyo/YJP4sZME40vzhutYJ94pA==", 
		"explanation": "24W5Zpj92F75t7licw360fz7PXLRGmst4T+KQeN1MH3qWqDXZ/7qwJQxKl2amV5p4n/DoKCw41sOm+hI4YubY2IPd4xn3JCG2aT212FEMNJX2oJ3/ZUReLRMzTOqYdXcJbIux2CDK1D0bje6RGR8kXHVn3BCvZG+tSa1UJogwQxymYE44cE6OZebzLqa5kr4jg+RnG+YRbgm9L7gQZOWK6sovODpp3VvDg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "cu,lt,ure,ura", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040117", 
		"question": "24GwbdHZ0A3r/IQzHl7zhf7wOWfVAHYYrHHDXaU0cX/gXaLMeq3B9qhOGGO2smREzUn5nJrPt0cOg61Ipc6QdiQGbMtmxsaI2/H2xn1Ec8FIk41i958MPP1O2DLtYNzeYO1hzWeBKwXxaT39AXN7mj7bg38Wq4y18S6vXdU501U9kMds5c01LpeP3Lqa50n6RIcKzHcxxkIFUs24h6+s9Q==", 
		"answer": "27O3ZJqxkNPALhSYamf3r7FwcWVMsQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ0A3r/IQzEh/gwL35OmfbQ3YQr3qQErd8cWWjW6HEa/++35Z9Ml2LgV47+3jVqqL440BPhqZP5s6LeCdDbYRswdGFl+L2xmNIMIZFlIQy4ZkQcvtNxT7tZtHaLPd6x2uTZ0r2Jy21ATBkkSPfhXgWvIu+7Ge/Uco+wwF+1oR349wuNdWKzaGd7w2siUaNyWnRXbNgFEaKoc+m70qSp8I3s42ZuTeb5PXqjroeAjfIGABMhQ6itGdEl9SI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "fo,lk", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040118", 
		"question": "24GwbdHA0Bft9ohgXhfmwO/+IX7CBi5Roj+XQKZ1Y2TxUefWfOLozNd+IRy9jFZy/jbWrKDk5UpDz61W7JyYdSZDeJlgxZCd3+G3+05+DPl7pb9N26UgQ8t/832/cdPSL/AuwWjAE0T9bjX9KnFwgXHXhHgWuJG04y6/Ucl3wVUln4l84t98NdmL1uiH4Ej4ig+E2TueTv1wGVHZpcun+0+Z4IYtp8SDtnLe9eb1g7jw+MwCcRxbvog/d1KxkrtLne9mWZLUBC51PHiGXtFNvg==", 
		"answer": "27G9ZIXy2BqoD/guqcp/8MsCyPjT2FwdhA==", 
		"explanation": "24a5Zpby3Fnm/pElQB/m0O/6eSvAEW0VtnyGVuN9fjH3XKKCaujy3ZZ4JBybiFxy/XjV46r2t2cOgqFXqaCedDdPPoRpztWbxKTwyHhMI9VBicB76o4QPOBIyX2hfcLeM75hyC6QIkrgazz9AGVmnT/RymhercO+9DW3TZoUyAc7hZNx7MZ8P9KRzb2B4UirykaQ2X2dTb5wGFqe9dqg7gOftY4soN+I8TPV8LTqlfva9coSIgdU/5J3ZhuonqUMumhWyRxmpuD8meqV21md9wU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "de,lt,aic,aec", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040119", 
		"question": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Ei3zy+70J2LEQ3UesXSQEqxyMFPrVbTDIq3N3JNjJleIwRtQ83rPp6Tj9h9PjqZfqayefiMBdop73NHFl/P/zX1Ec8VBloVw9psLefAAyjK/NMDTJfd8jmKJM0DiZiukRGZ1mCTTxjxXpJC0tTS+RswygBQh1rhH0vcDA+ig5pes13KHuTnC0XKDWrJ2AhSWs46840bcqIsrocKfuDHa+LT6lfbH9cYfIhxaup8/dF6ukugK9ycoXtuxbFJC/6aRjReBHomXFyROLeVlRqZm", 
		"answer": "26e9bp320g3j4YBiR+BOyvoBmTvAz0aZwEGuTw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHk3gvh5MUvVF7mzfjsMCvRDWEYpnGXEpB1fmLoRq7WLuzr3Z9+NU/JjEl+snjJt+X/+V8Wz6RS/YuNcTAaPoZu28SMxfT+wXJEIIZGj5Qy5ZYMc7RPyjuoZpTJJfhiy22ULlP1JzCzF3lznCXFynVYvIz74S++FNI+0wE9hI577MR8P9iRza2L/A23gEaW1H6YWv1nA1GYocen5QGwJhxZ8Bn38J7yjHHKdpGE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "re,fl,ec,ti,ve", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040120", 
		"question": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU1KyxvLyJWTDBmZRrn6KXK9tMH7lFJj9UdLB9qhOGGO2smREzUmGoqv0t1sWgqZIpc6Xfy4HbctoxNmEx/fy1zFIPdJL2pR64doNefhJyzSiYcebMOxvzXqJJEDjJzizADB2kT3fj3pF6Iy9tS6vR5ojyRg31IlRVmLhU0LnD/KR366ATXM=", 
		"answer": "26WqaYj2wwqoir5dBePzj+WnYaqHKSDGUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU17i1/TyNHnZD3tRoHCNQapnZGKjW6GCfv//0JJjNByIg187+m/Lrba8t1wJia1J4ICYMDQCcp5uytyMl+3513hGO9JX2ol88JVfaPxFjC+oeN3cKfF73S6QNUTzczC+AWM0lT/Syn5TpIq+8zT7RMgy1hQ+k4lsrcwpLt6R3uiH4Ej4gxSDnHKFCLJ2GFOQu8+87kfeGfjNiAUGRRiM57dNx0gHSQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "pr,ay,ers,ars", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040121", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfdHw9ZkgZ2ubhE9y/HGGrKuw9VodjKAb64+Ne2ICcI8v2NGF2qT7wXBXNtUE18AypNpfPLQAjH3tNPWbFe1ryi6JKQXTYjepFnF41BDFg30WqY2/tS61R9klyRc3ksd344gvNNKayeif7UysjgOQnHqfTP1zHludsMDo/0KerIcspvGD43L29frsifvB+c4fcU8SqYdzdl78la0P9zg9EdimYRxf+OrXIRmtYGjjZ05duYujljQphsJpHSkWtDdPhYtae4Bl15TxuTZwO9hvVSe140hBxJ88UBHWZK+x3nzt7lJ/YX8obYRisCIyuDOSexRWk2WYWWxDkYxi+dkWgBcjcWZUmWThliqZhSXCPNOjq8C8xaiw4PkjsuNnaQHAdRyYFs1cJfOAZycyiqm4TYVTPo91HjHjLpU69Dy5FpOQ3ipBkOshInb+9SSY3o3YOG27sZr4nNViFfNAN9/Bqfuiol3JYDDdLynTUM7wWAb3Tm+43BwluxEoyjJQ52SYHIF6tRsImn/wBAQk0megLDzh1v4cqsLOP85xk7WsnXJQ2NA4rI7nxBE5SgG1mWwDvYLfW1RKjWLTGsxHzQctAKEFHZjWsn2emnjVX3UObIK2E6GT1i1ElqP2nGBwspEcGcyLOADWhdIpzw79QfB8QXXkq5W1ff0bDiQt6aZjxeOuutP5TCl6PYSMr8trS/RXBR+AsQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T1Sd2zg1TIu8VzHz2+hamyESkbWZFqd+gJMvJVXa48A2Eh", 
		"explanation": "24KqYYX63x6q+ItgUBfgxvW/N2rCCCIQrXvDQqJ4fTHvUabUa/6+3pZiZ1+GgFZ0/DbPreXZ+VcGjuQb/oaWfCdDd4Uv69WHw/b2yDFgIM9F1sB/5ZQKb/dSxS25Z5TMJexrjm+MNEqwcCu0EGRxmnHZhDxFoIa+5We3UdsjyBAg1oZ26YgrM9ib3KbT/Ey6igOWz0efZbxqBEeap8e4/1DcqIc0sY2euDXV/fLwmfnd5J4dYwRHusZ9Zl2zha1J7CI9EcG6fhdF5e3fbxTiJmizNQcT7cLt0TRt04dpSWZ04BdDi5EWcMFh34z9/DM+O41+HTb6r0VCyIYxVhmCcbOr2X7hoEUtenkudpktsyt1oh2ZKUB3lGzcTyNBnYV4wt4xnApnaC9SmXrphTaElXbPcJr37pL9kf3ipflm/KAoJFGBJk/dRc0IbbaAEWJ2y/rXTZRdPp5+FizncZUD/TH4Ip6VzTgZ0ZVgLnnjtBqMgMz7OHb2853/iNFkHbEHdtjL+sKwuEjUISrvNXLTZ8X3UA3+WzzR3QpsthZlyiQc4WfeG8l++ylNnWu8XVF2lxvuWnmll7Bb65HOcJxxx/3pnT4ZlfZr35TxlAk0QkSNiHtC8pOaXVkP3kHGDsECyQwgGKdBAJ7Q5i2fm3XcXngIe47yCLuEyjxE0+30nSFxtpsLFZyGIxfentcl21vxE/RtQGbh5Mb+L/0YB2U+tvJ03vSsuMa0curobGgvewi+WvwVs5RfbEJ6Ah/PCipAbaHiFp4RT/Rd23ffgw5GQD9dChrNu6AHUQ25vs3LLn/QZ7QOHQrjbbcMHcm4QUGPIfmsiAbMAraf1VO7R1A2DNGINoQLn1IoQL/mJcmihSo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-C, 2-B, 3-A, 4-D", 
		"option_c": "1-B, 2-A, 3-D, 4-C", 
		"option_d": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040122", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfdHw9ZkgZ3+GgEty/nfSqqr+t1wJz4Va4Y+deCMRf59uiJ3Jl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLRhjB6iesDaKfB9jmCBNVfxczCrATw0kDTFiW5fuJey4yL3FNs5xFU2n4N57tw1P5eS2LyW+kS5ijqMjjuhSbNtH13epo6v+UKRrYMq9YDN8XKbtLS52riTsJ5LIkgS/8Y/Ixv81+hJuGp4EYj0KFILsaTyIWT/Lz6qIwsOucLtxX1uzpY6HWA64BAGkYxVa8Vnz9SkuTE/McJnDH/6okpEh5dpUwODZrj4326k6UEsNW4iaI9Rsn51kw6RKU1/lGrbX2xUgo9n68QQmgojMC8A3Dagwn/LwCXPPNOjq8C8xaiw4PkjsuNnaQHAFhzsRIwfYKCALnNhiuqUALZTIJZzHi3ofcEm7jbsJ57U2zAL1twyKnnztDmNk8rwKiW7vZa5jdF4AKoSP9TW1cXj8GnXYC3oMnWSYtizGRj4RnD3wAF1vxEmyS1Q+3LdC5xz9DkEkXCjCQkk0gOgT3Ovgr9V5JHObJo+wfzpznIfnrRfno7j1RA9ByauiXtLs8OMD0xdyELfEdgUhAsnHqAJB9bQ/GnWhnnTQnNAes35D6eKyi8I0+3ih2Z1q4NMaw+vn1qzyW2KSLNf4uuOcg==", 
		"answer": "2+T1S92zg1TIu8VzHzq+hamyFCnbuZ+ywCL+NkSyfnt8eEMP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hT6/okhRhf9y73wMyvEC2dRjn6LU6F8cWPiQKaCeejw3ddlL06GmFxzsmDHsaz/4kBPnLxa7ouMMCMNestpwd6I2+juhHJOPdJFk4534NoRfeZSzSmkYtGXYPpr3W2SLlXkbi+4SDB1mjWWjnVSqYCv/CT7V9U51BA8gss4/806MNKczaGd7w28jwCE2WmURqkkGV2KocG64kCdrMIosN+EvjbIyPrJm/ba/tdMcUhVrYdyblqu2+ge6iMsRc26KBNZ/vHeZRS5dXjjBS1Rudjr03B6ho4gWmEgtBBIwpBZYcl2woGo/DczMMNlGCr240VOw9R/ShuCYa+9kGzx8lwxcjojbJktqCQ4pE+LIF1ynyuVQCBEh5R5/8QQmwMjen1BkXvhljaIgWnPbobv7pPAi9z4pflR864mMECONBvLFo4TaKPPNG5mw+aVTaNKPJNxEiamMsMr7nn6JZiAyisE1cpgO3/1+z+emo3xMGO8toD8gMA2B6sBMdTWpYunolPRaCfoL3rTb8XnUA/4W2+42gBxuFg2xyIZ6W6YCYd7tS4YkmqlW0Vo0iTobXKmk61g5LaGes4Ew/Ti1CEYmfBr35j42gk9Tgr7nXdKvouMQExHxFfXEo0U1AwtGbgAAJ/e/H7WgX7RXzwJesLgBOiOzThHmuf0i3F4rdAdRYWcJQ3Oi9Jmyxi/AvhpQXStqYj9ffUbGW0r8qZihq2ztt6zcOHkOG0rYVq9TPxNs5tQehB6BQLLAGRMb7a6U5MKAyTkA0HhgmVir6qN/pfheD4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-B, 3-D, 4-A", 
		"option_b": "1-A, 2-C, 3-D, 4-B", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-B, 3-C, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-B, 2-A, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040123", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfa8gMjlkP/XCjERjx78AQVF/", 
		"answer": "24asZ4P61Aqq+INgdR/n0fzyNCvyFmYVq37EQeNkYnT1XajXfa38wIVlL0/JwBtQ/HnRreXx5BMljrxa4o+MPGIMeI1q2tmH0KT+ymJINM5QicB76o4QPOdPzzSseJTaLvouy22PKUr9bjr9B396kDjCg3NYu8/73yayWpo2zhFytJJ86cA1L8Pfza2L/F74y0ayznSHQblhUVyQptqn+UqfoY54tMOJ8SLU+P3tk/vS/J4CbA5drYt+d1KzmegG/mosWc29elJf+OnVchitBCCiNQMc6t73xHV6hoMnWSkH+Q1PlopFIo0z5orhrzEiNs9vVTevt01F1NRwXgCFNLy21Cj08lwxdnM7aY9+/Cs6s0+KKUZ3lX6PDD9el4lu6tEV1RZscWpT0DbTgzGMgWjPcJr37pL9kf3ipfkuspM1JkWVNlncFo8FJaPPInNhiuCVTadPIJpqFS7vOMZu7jzvJZeY1jcKkMovLH7m+GqckcL7NmizsNL4gNA2BLAMP8XM6sq78FDOZyaj+poV42i9DUknO5f5VR+BKA==", 
		"explanation": "24asZ4P61Aqq+INgdR/n0fzyNCvyFmYVq37EQeNkYnT1XajXfa38wIVlL0/FzVB1/WHI46Tjt3kOm6lQ6J3TMDIRcZ1mzNXJ3urkzXZJJ9UEk45m69oLdPEA3zKufdXXYP9gyi6FJEr+aDS0BzB3mz/Sg2hfp42otSi9FM4/xVUik5Vx4sx8PtKLzq2W5g2sjgPC2nKXXLUkEFqd9d2t6EySpMI7sMOZpCDCtNbapvb58dcFIglcu8Zddl+4n6Ea7GosVNCge1JE9+LVcxTlKTu3KBwU+srvlnVnwsI5UmU94BZFg48Wa8512YrpvSY5MMMqFDG1tlAA05x5VgXWYLS11XuooF06eWoia40trig2rgGPPEZrmX/cWCRU1JBk8tkNnAdicS9IlWX0jS2SwGqJPIfr7sDugO/5r7dwzq0DIUCSOF3LQ5kOZKCAJml2itqWH69IOownBzDjLtY89Tv8YJKByzAIw5VgI3bw52bZk8PxeXWoupz6h8R6EaxAMN7Xqc++tlrCcybvNT2Aacj9XBzxQzzq3AJgpFRlyy4e/HDRCpxr/CMK3mq/CUUkgTPyeX+1g6xZ7sKPcYpxwfDryD4RjPF834j41xQ5Ux2Hg0xCvIOeQhxDxEDTDMwT0RsrQPQRBpnV526TkTbZRTwMbN3zDKqLyilbmuHoznFyuoQdGcyJJQ/emZ4z21e2DfR0RXTou8b2O7wBAmFs6b1yw+yt+4q+dvyqI2gjbFb3WOFds4VeZAtvGAjcCWRDab6rFpIYAfRH1zXakghYS3oJDFSM/60ESQWjqYT8b2fXb/EyDxr3IYl7De4WbQ/kycIfZxfDW8E=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Stories of Gautama Buddha's previous births, Known as Jatakas offering insights into social and economic conditions", 
		"option_b": "Jain and Buddhist texts,Provide historical and political information of their times", 
		"option_c": "Dharmasutras and Smritis,Prescribe duties laws and principles for various societal roles", 
		"option_d": "Sangam literature,Produced by poets in assemblies, revealing social economic and political life", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040124", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfa8gMjlkP/XCjERjx78AQVF/", 
		"answer": "24exb9HF1B3rt4QuVl7+xOn6JyvmBmYYoD+XV7tgYzGuFITNYPn/wJkxN06IlF5p4TbUqrHl9l8cw+hW6ImWc2ICcI8vxcmd3+v7y3ZIMMdI2pNm64gWeecMjAi9ddrSM/Zvyn3AagXZaTqxEXRx1CHeg3BZu4yr/S64VdZ30wU3lZJ07Nw1M9mMleij6UOxiA/FzzuWWrxpHFWL9YPoxEWapZAr9cSDojvc/ODq2vHd5NFLcQdRtoNrehv8kqsG9iU1SIi1ZhYL8vHcdUH/JWTjFA8T/srulnhg0oc7XH0h5hoGz8N1bc1jxJH3uSFwLMhpAD+7sQRQyJFxTFeGZryxw2Hq5xU3cGgkYJktvSMx4QeZOlt3lG6PDpV6eA7ueJmcxNfZ/YwWB40=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU17zy/m/OWrEBnBRlXqHW6A0ZHT7QLSCa+P9xpphJk+azVo74HfIpKCw+FVPjKdV/YuRZGIKcIhj3dSA2eO31GNAKsNWicwy9pMLafVM33HtedXcKf0ijm+OIwX9fi21C3x7kzjVi3AWu5e05y6+R5Z30hA0moJ7+cEyO5eJ2Lqa51irxgeRzH6SXK4kHlLZtMCr4kaStMIRu8mEsDyb9+H1ju3B9eIFVgBX/7NvYlW1hKAI/Dl4Vc24fhcL+OrEbhT9KCGvKB0S6cPq1XVlhpE5WGoh+B5Si4xYcYwz04D0sD0iNsNtVTe/plRF1dRvTx6Efamt0WSk41oxdn87cZktvigsrgGYaFp/iHmdWCVHkZNX8OAYmw1tdChT3HHygzKGgXfDPITr4oz5xeH8rKxw5rEmPUiOMhzUV4MbcLLHIidg3+WeHuocMpN0GGL2L9o49T38M9ad0SoE19E0PDfu+j6W0tn9PCWpvJHwi8BvWP8FNd7L5sau/BzGbyehImifct7mXEj/STzw2h0loxEozR0e22PWD4hytSEEinuiSFBxgCKgb3OvhbdP/pHOcIhxwPDvyD4RirRokJ76x10oTwWvzW9Rs42MShxHyEbZG95HxQcqTLwEBpnY/GiF2TbfTXoIbcf4BuiGgztB1Of+mSF0sYQBFZiGKVnYn9Iy3QW0QfJ/FXPlrcbtNPEQSAcRJSoZ5LgF6y3yigawrTs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Rig Veda and later Vedic texts, Contain prayers rituals, magic and mythological stories", 
		"option_b": "Upanishads,Include philosophical speculations", 
		"option_c": "Panini's grammar, Offers insights into society economy and culture", 
		"option_d": "Sangam literature,Comprises secular poems praising heroes and heroines", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040125", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfdHw9ZkgZ3+GgEty/nfSqqr+t1wJz4xT6JyScTEWaplu25CI2eC393xTOtJNicA/pLtfUf1S3jK/NMDTJb59wW2JJkmwZje5RHNhmCXDmH1a6I+y8yL7W9x31B031qBt/dw9fMeay6Gc7HG21Eajzm+ZSa5sEEeNp8/o5EXci4MtocSBqDObubS52riTsJ5LIkgS/8Y/Ixv81+hJuGp4EYj0KFIL06T/Z1LoMmiqKR0U/sP3xTRgyJYmHWE95wtJkIpVY8wzxp32rz0+LIEqECW/rVBTi9R9URPWZrKh0WSk41oxYX8mdYV/vT88pBygJgc+sGqVQmxQmoQr3MUdkQxqbnsAiHP4lizLzSXPPNOjq8C8xaiw4PkjsuNnaQHAdRyYFs1cJfOAZydRitmJArBVN5p0Vy/nKdA89Tj1YJCbzXkZ2NxgPGPy8DPZncu1OGu5upf3mpRfGrsJN9+F+cS7uUjeISLvJT2WZcT6VgXpc3KskzlqpRM2iC4WqEnZBIB79D4M3jPwCQQk0megLDzh1v4cqsLOP85xk7WsnXJQ2LQ439u3lF18B0T7zVsDgpaaXF9dxFbTXsEG0xpiTLAUAJ/U4SHWlHjUC2wfdsD1CLiLxj8I3Ozjznd8rZkBQJ/OPxbYg9syyRvxE/J1UHSvfYG6qZ8YHiG1g8Q8gkwMVg==", 
		"answer": "2+T1TN2zg1TJu8VzHzy+hamyFCnzOio+gd6SJ/m5G2djDe/P", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hT6/okhRhf9y73wMyv0C2MDrn6QR7dmcWKjVanGLt7z255lLk/JiEhv83TKqrb48kBPg6lM+sLfdDcXd458hJCI2eC31GNIPcVNiox399oZc+YA2jy/fdvOM759wW2JIlHxa3mvC3xxh32WiXNYvJGy9zKvXdQwgAE91pR37sE9MJeMzbqG61mtlAPC3XWVCLJ2FVGLicDo30uZ4KMqocWMojra5+Drm7jc9p4gYx1GtopmYhf8gKAA9C94Qdq7fhtP+OrXIV3jMyGkLxoOucLtwnspx4wqVGw64F9vjIdfY84zxpfotSYpf8xkEXO/oEtOyJllE1eFca+u1Xuk4UZ/Z3MobcpgvTkwswadJBR4lXncXzhEkJlX8PoYnAojfGFE3FT1hjuDiXabPIfm85Tvxef2prxxsqopL06SOF3MX4ISJbLCKHJmiuGSHrJTIZZkFi6mLdA87zb3M9rU2i8I3s0zYzfm+i7ZgMLsOGn6sJ33mtF7BLASN8PM7Nj3v1qHdSvkKG/TcsL5XBvMQUjw1k5yuAou22Ef7iLzCYV28SwenzLwWlFnmmfhfzyql6hF65HOfoA1k/H+3D8Ri7g4kZTjlBIySx37hXBPtsSTRkhK31XEB40RxQU7CfQDAYKR82GFmjbCTnoBes3iQbyPxmxb1eD4j209vp4KFY+bIA3OmN8qiBu4B/g5UXL/oYj+fegdDyQL76Jly62xstiyevfmL1QFqJ/m/+FDcDIeD97t7A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-B, 2-A, 3-D, 4-C", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040126", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+smXPpKv58VoMjqZY7M6QdmICcIhmzd6dl835wHhAPYZQn5hm99oWb7RDwy+/cdfPesJg8mDRZ3H4YnmPDXc0ojTSizxbqYq1+T77V9U50xwhgpQ44s58LMWewK2B+w25iALCznKFXbxoAmiXicD6q3eUpcINpcyDuCHT9fDq2vnB9Z4bcAFfvpR2b0L8lKcH+y8qX82wKAVC5eyQbE35KCevKAkU+srvlmd9yZAgWHp09RFCwo5XZclw6pbYsmFwD8xkHD2z5FcAwIZ9UhqXZv2owmfy6VE6Zjoia5lkuyUhsk+VJkBx2n+USWxCm4Ni+8QA2URmfmBOk3v5zn+KjmHPf4bv/5XugKj/pvlr+7BnPUiNME+aR0EWo5C5OZtMmYibiiplrQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4Z5//yFtqIB4th9O9apMH4n7ZyUrT", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRl3eGEpF9dzHVUaPDLuD/wJl9PhyKglZr4H/Vpraw50EOlq1J+s6efiZDbIJ73dGFxKTjzHBVc9ZWlZZ74J9fdfpTxTqlYMebKfB6wS6UL0CwdTyxDXd9myTFymxEqYCv/CS+R5o4xlUmnoI4+cExOeuR6ryS/Ei1gwiWnCnRQa4kGFqauty67kCI4LYwsI24oTPV/efxm/zAsN8ZZ0hcsJI/c0m1mqkb8SYhEcu7ZhFO4+rVZRT6KTyrZwME7cPs2ntuz4EoUSkn4BBUi4ZFIsF90tjpvTU5PI1DGyCupkVEi9RoVxKPNLu30333oFoxNWojbIZiryIlqQafKVg+iXuZTzldlZRi8d4K1QVteS9EmXPwhy3Lk3WGbpr3/oHwxev/rrpm4rc0FU+zIV3MU4AZa6eAdCd72amSA6VTIY1iFDamDdQg9TfwZ4XU2CsM3dQhPTun4yKQnsi1MGm2poHtnNViHbEHdt3E58yisVvCITH0LXiAKovwVg3jD3L3x05rshsg2zIR+mvUEclv5yIbl3q1CUBtgCLjeDyomK1V7YqabM443eHjnSYYnbRrkJj+0QklC0S+jnBNvYmGAxxOw1CWHdgL0Bw8CfQOEtbZ+37WgX/dTm9PGCB+YyE5nGLZ2ZTitXe/Fg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040127", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+smXPpKv58VoMjqZY7M6QdmICcIhmzd6dl835wHhAPYZQn5hm99oWb7RDwy+/cdfPesJg8mDRZ3H4YnmPBX11jTDYizxZrsON9Cu2XdE+gAIzhcd74sUsM8Sa3eia5g2sjgPC2nKXXLUkElGXodu68gO9hL42icPf8QbT8bTMivnd+c0DYwxB/4VwbU+9nqZJ6CIxXcenZwJD+OfRbRT+MC2gMgIc7cLs2GdVyL4nDikE9RFPjIoRcYB0xJnpsTMif8tlFiapplcA1JtwWhuPNLK2kHjs71s6YXModshTrFdqoLGWh/XfadDnwxfQ", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+3WqY0QnDuVb7DYOy+xpExEV2FgFJw+zbRoraw+Vwbz6tU5J6QYycHPoJhiMSB0qTxzXdVO4ZHn45m8YgGPNVkgH2vYcCbKep9jm2PKlX/dDCpDX961DPTjX1Y6Iq1tTOzUZoxyRMmnsd76MYoKcWGmYqwqEy2gkaV2XWFCKlsA1uMssbo5laQtIsoucjNoiba8/Hqpvbg5N8fZwVXsZI/MRu1hOgK9zgqVMugKCZD9KTlcVXjKTurJgoOucLt0nFswsIqUmcg9RZIwpNEbcZ8w5bg/CI4NsFlBjyqq01Dxpg8TAeTd6i00Xzt71ssSXQYcYt5uSAwrxvcexR3iSuVQi9ehpJu/cRZpQVtdGFJ22WghS2KjWiObtPg5Jb5l/uwtrhx+6wyOgGBJkzdVZkPJbzGZ2tzxO6ODKFZf99uGSHqKNEn8j65LpmAnzMYw81gP3/o+i+Nm87meWevp9L4gsd5VLgSN9zI6Nn78E7SbSbybT2SaM+0VQH+SGnxwBpstFg23DMF63bNGow9EdoL5WFLGgT6jrUvW9eebA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040128", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snXJrbHi/lEam6FU553ffyRDVop9ycCZ1uq3x3hXOspNgIFm7ZURPP1TjD6iZsbeI+o08mC8KRSwUzG4RFh1hjDGmn1Yu8O/8DG+WNUnxRFyl4k47MwqPdmc3KzT/1+xkg+M2zuCUa5wFFnZocap/wOVs8IrocSBvXLO5/H92uzc9N8SXgZusdQ/S1qulrgZ+SR4UNq3YBtf9OfEdEboYCGtJAII/c7nlnFlx4AmT2gg8V9Sh45GbsVglpnquHIgPsFrFjapn0p8ycc8ax+TNJW5wmn08FQxZjoudp5sviE8sgeZLBR/2miTQTxdkZgr68IblAojbWNBknjpjDjLk3ycaJbuq5f1keCwt7xv/u4oO0aBO1XCU4lcdqfSImJm2amaA6IcN41mHiznOtBsBP0Tf3I1qQTTU4guuC/3wg==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+3WqY0WHDxVbfSb+PtiZN4IxyNiE1+/nnW46Sw5FAdhrhPpc6dZTZDd598iNSM1O3nzHRTPsNKjsB799oMaP1MwH2sNMfOIvRrzXrAKEOwdTyuAXFmlzmWi3JS6Ie+9yavUZZ3wRs21o5srcEvfNmQzeia5g27kxSQ2XWFCKh3FGiXhtqp/0aRpYws9Z/NuCGb/fr6lerB9d0fIiBTrYdvc1qy16kb+yIxRc23fAdZ9KTUaFCtLie3ZwcT+sf20nEpw44oX2Ym9QtDwpdTb9B/04ukvTw0f91rGTK5plcbh4Z9Sx+TZvH42Xyk6UZ/dnIqd4tuqCgnqBWZLBR8gyuLSSBd2ZBn/94XkAAjfmZUlXPzwiiClG3Pb4fi5YT9l+z5urxnsqE1IEKLdV/XWJ4Id6bDM259xNWVPrJdJ5pqEizyfYZu9Sq5I5mGzTwOxJkUJ3Kn3CuLk93lOGup85Pri5R9GrAXOJHD5tn3pFTCaDGhIHmFZ8X3XAywWm760gAlpxQkxi8Z5mWUSIBx9iEYmne+TgRzlyvsIXOzkb9S45iLe84ix+fp2CYD2PV2m9v22l05QQKyjnZGvJDfS05OxFrXGchH1xA9GLEMVlQGEiYIBW6rCBEOq9hBOP0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040129", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+sn/Ls6Tz4xMAiehz6JyeYDICcMtswcaA2+3txWVIPMgEk5Myx5UNbvFD2GeReujVcb5Gz3yBN1XxaXm+DWZ9mDjMi2hfp437/Sa/FNQ4gBw8kItt6MY/OZeQ1+iH4Ej4iwmG2WmfCKprA1idicCU5RHclIo99dmIsjrV/eXsn+uT/9hLSglAvpZvYlX8h6cd7C8qSIW5aRlC/+OQaVX7JWihIgsTucfsxWApyZQsTykg/RJDvo1qbJMz4pDh/CciPcxkVSO2okpOzpp7HxiQNJW5wmn08FQxNXkicYNor209oBzcIVptimKOSSgRmY9v+8IX1RFxf25O3HLllDqHj3WCeZ33q5T0gOfiqbxwsIHqiBAaO5IaZLl/b8Ep/3Y=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+rU7F1YGHiWufBZ/v3xZ5rJkiAglU79n/C463x4VZPjqYb4IOPcSEXPoRhiMSB0qT6y3VEIcgEjY9g6J5TPPVTjDi7fdDeLv1ryi6CPgXkbzz9F2VmgjjAi3AWp4X79iKpQNs+zlUzhIRw5Nw5P8OKy6mfqEy2gkaS0HqfRrRqFhSJp8em6EqMrIcricO+pTPP8fn8lOyTop4CcUhRsJRtZlio158B8SY9Edu7ZRcL5eHTaVrkMT2mNE4S/4vL12Zo1pIoUykk+wtSh5FPL81y3ZHqu3I4PttvVTG/pkoAy5tvS1vWe6mw1Xr3oF0+Y39rdp9/qiQjpAvcKVp62mqOSWxCnY1i8tEL1RBsPXtFn37uiy6ehXbPaYDm78DoiuzxuYVtwbcmPUSNMFLMFt5cbKCAJGhg2OyYGeZoO5onAjDkPNtu7DX4Lpid0T5N399gB3b19TqJk8O1OmyuupfqwpRhHasIdsXN7MKl8EvCbS+sLm+UZ8X9Qw30D2/swQtgowtlyS8UqGbKCYBx9CoI3m2pWlBhnzSsLHSghf5V5IaLeopx2vv/zTsCnfA4kpTz0Q8yBxGpj35N8oCaWVlDwkTbG8MThB0mCbsTHZPCsCEHmTb+4fQazzhBqAitjRk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040130", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+sn7PsLH/5VoMjqQb4ICLdTATbI57ycSA2OrkhH5Hc8dKmYl36o5fVfpExTyjNNnaLut9zXyJN1HjJzCuRHN7hiPTiWgMlI2H+3b7ddQ0yRA8gsdL7MYvN8WWzeie6UOtlQWQ1WuFW/1lA1HZpdyh5kKOqY4h9cuCpDzftP332tbc4soDIiFcu49+X1WAmfpJzCI9Ef6xbBNF9uXDIVX/JWiwMh4N9c7u03p9x5AwHX0x7AtVwpdZItR709jSuTYxLI1rGzf6oEtWwoY8TAKUfri7xHuk80A8fToqdspqriw4rA6OaFVwniudXzhDm45k88klmzhtLi90lHOgsD6GgXyOcpKj5Ia8s+n8rbBo++MyJ0WFJ0vdWJlcaKbMM25ixuzbHrJdNJp0Vy3gfdYh8Sn2M5+A1jYDkNguKzfw9TnZlMT7OGm2qtL6gdlmHbMFMpHM54ujuFmHZyrnNXXTZc76TR3iVjzZ90zb0WHLjVtY7SLrf0gv5AmW", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+iXKB9dX/3FJTDYP71255lZ1GIg05o8WTPs7Hjt1Idiuhd5puRdGICcocvx8aMxaTeynVIMooElI9mpJAKb+AAxTPtWtvJNPYu52CELkTMaQqpBWRxmTTYnjwE6IqotSS0RsgywwFyoo99rf45ONaR3qmAqEyqg0aL0n+UTbkkAkGJpcKt5kaStIMqrI2ZtCrP57TtlbjH+NtLVA1WvpUzI1qyk+gd8C8hEcu7fhdZsffFY17oIzywZwIU8s6j0WZoy48oTyl84gZHiYJEY85yn9SkvSEkLcJkGj6j4wxK3ptoVgSedfT0kGnq5BUwYXIud5lRsh4hoBuZJVFwjivPDCVC1IFo/cULlBBmPVtImTbSgzKKmWSBfdPs7cDKhOT9qbJqsqcuLQGVO1jdRIoTJb7VK3N72uWeTbVIMphiBGLpO5Ut8zTpL4WdyzAC3pVgLWLztCON0tr0KiW0vIa5jdt7BLYMM9WF4MX3pFTCISXoJ2mbJsjxVxzlXWW48io+9xExiCkR7CLRHJo/9ygKl3C+QEpjgWfpYjy1nrsc7IuIa4Zx0PDiyScCgbRavNv22hl8VwWonnpH8pCXXVNaylyWCMwVzQY7H/QSAJfW937Wl3PWRG4IP8zzCKaAgypB1OL9h3t4u9JeEDXtCPgcUyjT/ttNosTY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040131", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hc/2MivmBmYQ42+RW651YnjvTefBYePtwIRlNByGixtr4Hffprfjt1IBi+hJ4JqKcS4QQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBB85B2rJ749opefBBjDS+NNvVJb5hyC6UL0CwaDW5AWNg1CXTkmhF6Iq1tQ61UNM2zlU6n5Rs4tolfNaR3eiV506tlQORnHSfCK9hHV2evMG9+AOMsoM7ocSOtCGb9fr92vDK/dAYIgxXu498Yk+5k+gd92ouUNq9ZwdYseDVaEDkJTvhRUEmhWsa06YWn4ta0Vhwzw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RomzDRqtxMEPqU+f0a+n/iZ5/I1mMiRtr4H/Lorf5+0pPjKdV+oeMZDFDcY0vwMmE2fe7hGFTMt9BiJM+pJsReLRSxSm4ddjIYPprymeDJlH1Y3mpCzBilSPfhWlF6Ie+/DOyUcl39B031pV97NszMpeWyuiS5F63xhKQyX7RSbNgUUecp9it+AOds8IsvcjNsj3J5vH6jrjW6M4HYwZTq49wbRf8lrtJ7CI9Efq9b1J99ODRIV3+YCetIk4S/4v33nEpyY4tWHogtA1DjopRa89mxdjwuSokLI1rGzf6qlBTh5dzUQOTeqn42Xuk41AxYX85YI4tvT86tAGYaEZ7lmKbRSNEh8B77NEagQ1geHwCpTwTXcac3QJX7U9/bveInQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040132", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hcjvNGXZEGoQp2zDUax6ZHDqWufSfOL4xoJ/IxyZhVJ3/WXJs6359FIDz7tL7I2KfCMXd4Rh2+yH6+rFwXBSPMge2rR64doqbPVOxS6lddDIYOlr3GvAJEr9dzauAXQ0lSKWhH1EuoKv/DG+R5o4xlU/j5Nw4sQzO96c2KTT+1m3lA+HzzuQRrkkFEKcu9q7qUnA0cOM1kD6bLIZ/CmFXdk=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RomzDRqtxMETzVanLfeX/zYQxLlKNiF5/snXJrbHx/l1Pn7pU74GKfiZDboNmxN+a2PT/zXJAP4ZXioVx8ZYeaP1Pwi7hNNHDMPJh3GeOIAXzaDe+AWBgh3HEj3BXvIa/tTO0FMgywRk7gp40rcszMsSc0KeG+0O9lRXOnHqfTP1wGVHZu8+8/lGZ4I0+9ciVuCHP8fr6n7j7/8kOdA1A88Zra178ha0I6yU2EcGnKBRK/ffVLRTsM2i3LwtdzNvi2H16zoMtTikj8Q1Dwo1ZdoBw2ZX0syE1O41rBnO0olZSxoB1SRKFNLK+kGX99F0weXUsbIlssG0mtQCOIVFt2mqSSGxUgoVl6sNC1RZiaWdFjjqgljeOmSWJc5D2+MDzi6jgqLBv/bAoOUmJNl3UFpkZZLDILml12aus8tbnWFUp4REB+jAgttMe", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040133", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYh/8zPP2cniQBHAQrnKCQONkYn71XaPHfa33x4R4IFSdnhty/GLJ47H48hMcgKtS7JqGPGIGfYRhx92Qm6T2ynUBMNNIjpVg4doQerRIxS7tYN3WJe1SwFKOFUDxdDazXjBElT/fhHURu8O85ya2WdslgBwh1oY47scwMNKczaGc5g23gEaPxW+ZR7FrFl2atMLo+FeTsos9po2Mvzab+PH+n/bX454NcAdf/4dxYFK5mbxJ0SQ8WMn2MKrwupJDIk1FcSVnSrQyKw==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RomzDYqJ6eX/qE7SCaf//xJpwNRyNgl5osmbUrLP581ZPhqZI4ImXZDFDd4V7x5Cd3+G3135COsNQg8wy4ZkQcvtN1XHtddrfYP17wnqVNUCwaD/9DHln1CXfh3lF6Jez5yiuU9J31B031otx488pNcSL0KvT7UG9iwOMyGjRQLgkFV2Kttu7+EaY4Ko3osibtCCXtODxn7jB9d8YbQYStpU/ZVqwhK1FuCsrEfi1ZhtF+KPDIVP/ISWuJhxd8Nij2Ht9hoNpXmY4+BpFlopZbIB80NjppSY4MMFlEjq5okgA1IBzTR6TZ/253myk7FA4cHQvdtEttTl1qBzcKRR9lWaMXilZkY5498Yc1RBxeG5UlWXlwjCFwFaOcoDo+Ynoxe/iobRu87FlsdkTMrXd+i32+u21A7rbgg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040134", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hc/+OGrJAmwQ43CFEpV1fHzqX66CeeztiZR+KkyGnl5/sn/I47H48hMbmK1X75qXMCEGcJ962snJ9sDLyk1PAcNFiY98vtordPEA/jygdc3aLv8ux33AJgXzaDWxAXNgnT7YynNQ6Iuy5jO0RtM0wRlyk5F949wvfNGN1qXT/EW9xiGXzG+QCJhpAV2LsIyoi+XinDxnUbxYuKyhLbOb", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RomzDRqtxMEPiWabbb+P/iZh3Z2qIgVZy+X+GtKTjt1AAgrhU+oubMCcCbIdmzcLFl+Xly2RPN4ZQkoUy4pMZaPwAzzijYMHJOb5M7SLAJkv0JzeyEDB9mnHCgnkWvJS++SGvXJo0xRsmg5VhrekYfP+Qzq2F7V/0xhKK2TuDTbx3HlrZvN3o7UKQs4d09cye8SbT8bTLm/XS6d8FY0hbrMZ+bRu5h6EKuDo3VMX0fBpK5aTTblr5ISGtNE4Q4N/r2XhmwYsqXGV09RFCwotTcM961djqvSAiPtljAzap7wROyIA8Vx6FYLKq2Wvl7BU6Y38lcZktuj86rE+daEdun2iVSiVS1IVm7tkLkEZNtNhuEq9jUxXsfmPQkCxj", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040135", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hc7+O2zRDiIdqmuGQKJgZWPmFLfQYfv3zZJiZ0qIgU568HrD46z+5FoIh7xIqYeRZC1DaoNqiMOG1O32yD0BNsVLlI9/7ZlTPPVOyH29e9jSNPdtz2LAK0z2YnmyAjB1mjLfj3JC6Le6+C63FPQ2xAAOmLt23809L9iRg+in4Ej4tQeM23qcCLFtBVGLtNq9+UbcqZF4tI2Ovj7X8fftk/fdsNENIj5Xu498I1OlmqYauCs2VYimYQZe8OjDI0fCaQW8lfSy/OOrBOVfhBg=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RomzDRqtxMELiWqDDY63ywIN0NV2dmEl+snLJpraw50EAmaFf7M6JcS4Wf4ljzZCA2ff+w3lVIIZNlJR9pI4XebRTwz6kddiXYPttwWCPKkzzK3m8CnQ0hD7ag2hfq4K3tSuyUt93zxNyl4l75M0yKJer2KWa5A2WhwKXnG+ZWrJxFlzZvNq7q1OTpZYxto2Ovj/L++fwjvHc/s1LSgdFupB6cRf8g6AMuDg9UNu7ZlJC4qTWYFj+JWTjJh1d7cPmlkdoyIUoUCk4/QtDkIJCd9J2lpH3/Dw/K41rVTC1r0hFxIB1UBnWe7v45m3g6VZ/fWMma5ktvSMx4R2VPEF/lnjHDCVF1INk8MMQhhBwPWBG3GXlgSqHgXfPbJzm/5Llxen+pPlv+7ciO0CUIE7dFIL/WEigOUEMx2tZdjsK6OA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040136", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H63w/r84AkEjf8wfT+dWLeQzFD9T+hceN1fnWjXbSCY+jw3Z5+KVmNzVJ1slHUpqD7t1IMjKdO55qMMCMQPoovy9+Hw+H61H5TMtRd2o90pLsTeexBwjmoZpTPKPsu6XyFJlGvJUTf9VzXJtVHYJFNiLCAxLU=", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/3wxjt4pU0U17fxOjtLGqSGs29Ravm9amy8XcT7XZNmw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzv/MU3QBfmwO/sdWbVDXYYrHHDYaJ6dGPsX6jWeuzthdd4I1mHmVJ9+3PC46Tjt3AHjqZf+4+YZTIXf8tCycWbzuW7hGZJPIZNlJZz4J8bPN1OyDSsNN3VYK08mC6iBAXxaT39E3Fn1DCWiXNYvIa25SipVcgugBo01qZ06NA9MtOay+iH4Ej4oRSH3W/TXowKnmEM4Sh8ZgU/JHALWQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ashoka the Great", 
		"option_b": "Chandragupta Maurya", 
		"option_c": "Harsha", 
		"option_d": "Fa-hsien", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040137", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy0vLtPivAEW0HqnuGQeNicX32VaXOa633x5F+NVGImVJ0/DbHoarl4xMijr1J8I/fcSYOd4Vm28Sb1vD+y38Nc9VLmYlz6NoccPVT3zi+OJTaLvouy22PKUr9bjr9BXNgnSffnnVTu8O/4DWyWt131B031qp5+NolPZeP3Lqa50n0xgKHz2uYXLgkEluXoc+h5UqSp8I9uciAtDzP57T2nLjQ4tsPdwRbq58/YlW4160R+S0/VNq1fBtE/7uSzi7CLk87wPMxZwSOpSUXHA==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHa3x3j/IRgXRiy6Pj4NHjEC2cfpmzBiTVkKyQ2JR5V0CG/W4D3Rg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3j/IRgXRiy6Pj4NHjEC2cfpmzDQrF7ZnjnUbSCeOzy3JZzK1nJhFV9/WTLorH5+F1PjqpU/JrfXSMWbJJuiNGN2u35zWJVIcdQk498qNoMc/dJzTHtd9jaM+1r3SLAJkv0Jzy+C357mTjVyn1VvIqt/DOyUcl3xAAgn4l/rdw0OZey2L2B8Uz4lgOQ1XSVBP1gFEeJvNqtq0CTrpY5vMOEvzWb8fj8l/3d5M1LbQ4SvJR6Z06wnrwQuCs2VYixcBNM9uHCYEDkLybh+P9vQkdFSzvbCa/NqJrIfw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The Indika of Megasthenes", 
		"option_b": "Pliny's Naturalis Historia", 
		"option_c": "The Periplus of the Erythrean Sea", 
		"option_d": "Kosmos Indikopleustes' Christian Topography", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040138", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy0vLtPnicQ3UDqmuXV600eX+jc7XHa+ayiYdjKEqAiV475HfKtqTy+1ZPi6lP6M6ZfzBDaoNqiMOdwuDuhH5Hc8dKmYl36o5fe/FPyy+sZNzCYP9gyi6DKEj9Yiu+ATw0nT/VhmlSoY28tS61UtUlzRQmn4h2rck+M8KLmbyB6Um9xgSHyGyUTbMkOFqdvM/o6k2Y4JYwsI2/vj/a+rTcl+ja4ttUIC6AeDG7OVdFzl26/wnLk8c=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHD1Avj54k1QV79w73rPW6QJnAIt3eRV6J6MELmVefDYOm++YN+K1mElBxoslHDrKLi9kMHlupV8G0zbSP34w6gg9Cm8T21", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD1Avj54k1QV79w73rPW6QJnAIt3eRV6J6MELmVefDYOm++YN+K1mElBxoslHDrKLi9kMHluQb64GLeGIUbIJ73NWHl+35hFZTNsNP1sBi9pUJdfBFjCuseMHaIvJrjmqBM0SwYTavRGR8kXHFnmlSscO082e6Wtk+xRsm1oB94s8uPceXwOiS5kn4hQmP0X6DS7goUV2XtsK970qSp8Ixu8uCoz/a4P32lLjS8tEedkhGrYd7Zhu+krwe/S82EeG6bBtKseXeZRT5KC3jFQEQ+MWj83l5z5AsH99ErxbUHWNSG3wNFqvN7qo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pliny's Naturalis Historia and Ptolemy's Geography", 
		"option_b": "The Periplus of the Erythrean Sea and The Indika of Megasthenes", 
		"option_c": "The Periplus of the Erythrean Sea and Ptolemy's Geography", 
		"option_d": "The Indika of Megasthenes and Kosmos Indikopleustes' Christian Topography", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040139", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hk0Aqq440lEhLz1um/EnnRBmEe7k2MX6J6MGLgXKjOb/++3ZgxME6AmV4783TJtrGw3l0LhqkXqYOafjYKcYVmxtfJ9OzlzWJVOsdKicB76to2cvBJzX2setCbE+xnjkKBKU7xJzizADBmkTfTmG5fpoT74Sj7XNUl0xBygpV56c1jfv+04J7hI3uKtRgwS/DoX2I=", 
		"answer": "2563e5z8wlnD+YEpWRHiyfjqJn/VECDEWLn1OMIt7dxfwMRDh4aH", 
		"explanation": "2563e5z8wlnD+YEpWRHiyfjqJn/VEC5Roj+kQKJxc36uZqjPb+O+2pR5KFCInxc75WTJt6Cw41sKz4tT+4eMZCsCcMtbx8CG0Pb21HlYf4ZTkolx7NoSefpUxTKjZ5T4KOxn3XqJJkvjJzCzRFl6kDjXyn1YrMOI5y77eNs5yxRyl4l8rckwL9jfy62V7V+rxhKNnHOeWq5hUUCLtMqtqWmGd0zI0wu6JSgkAtR4yIM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Megasthenes", 
		"option_b": "Kosmos Indikopleustes", 
		"option_c": "Fa-hsien", 
		"option_d": "Hsuan Tsang", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040140", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTri/oslQRuy0e/+I27cBnBRp3qQUbF9cnTnFLPKa63txpR4JlDFzUl+/n/Bqqrl5B9PjqZfqYucfywMc4JsiNOG2eD+0HhOPdUEk44yzZQbdfUAyCi/fdrcYOpmyy6BIECwaD/9EHhx1BbDmmhXu8/79Cm/FM0/xRtyko58rdw0Oc7fz6GA4Vn4rwiG1XrOCjuSwWhVpbuH+eXgPO4Sr3w=", 
		"answer": "25O5JZng2Bzkt4wuEgr6wL35PG3ECyISpnGXR7FtMuZ6a2UKQQ4ehfuMWXR48IU=", 
		"explanation": "25O5JZng2Bzku8UhEj36zPP6Jm6QF3AQtXqPV7E4MHLiWaKCeuK+4Jl1Ll3JhFU75n7D46f18FoBgaFV7s6QdmIXdo4vztmPw+y3x3RPJ9NWg8Bz6p5fePFTzy+kdtHfYOpmyy6TKEb5ZjXxRGJxmDjRg3NDu8/79Cm/FN80zxs9m457rcszMtOWzaGc5l74jwjC9XWVQbwkFUGLvMCvq1eUpcI5ssjNvjSb4Pz82t/G4MoKcUqr5+O7rS/TMrzhWsEbgJum", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Fa-hsien in the fifth century", 
		"option_b": "Hsuan Tsang in the seventh century", 
		"option_c": "Fa-hsien in the fourth century", 
		"option_d": "Hsuan Tsang in the sixth century", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040141", 
		"question": "24GwbdHUwxzv/MU3QBfmwO/sdWbVDXYYrHHDYaJ6dGPsX6jWeuzthddmL1PJhEg7+3LDrbH58VoKi+hM4JqXMB08QbRQ9++26NvI+05+DPkI2oEy55URaPFN3DK/dcbCYPFojk+MIl3xaT24FjBgnDSWrW5TqZf3tSa1UJo+zgMzkoJ8reEyON6emaGdqB7q0Eag/zkKK+My7IPQJo25ZJFLmQss", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/3wxjt4pU0U17fxOjtLGqSGs29Ravm9amy8XcT7XZNmw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzv/MU3QBfmwO/sdWbVDXYYrHHDYaJ6dGPsX6jWeuzthddmL1PJhEg7+3LDrbH58VoKi+hM4JqXMAELf4Vr2tGOwvTjxTFsMtNWg4E+pJtff/tO2DigZNvJIex3jmGGZ2T8YiG8CnRxhnHCgnkWj5G+9DP3FNs5xFU7mJF56c04fP6R3aGSqES2xlXQijuza/+cn5zvBndzZ7XGBD1Nvs0e", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ch,an,dr,ag,up,ta ma,ur,ya", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040142", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSHN+sLACivfBSI8pniCQbd8dX/mR+fSfOLowJN0NByfjFdu83TKpuX5+VUAnaVa/YeQfmICfIR63JCk1vHl3XABMsJJk457944NfeBJwzPhNMfUI/dvwi6DK0TjdDyuSDB1mjWWj39Zpoy2/CT7VdkjyQM7go59/og4KcWW16/T/EW9xiuDyWmISf10FEaQusrkq0eZs5IxocjNsj3V4PXwlPHd954Obg1fuohrcBuzkegK6i88RMS9fAsL8OrUIVH1IS+kIhwc7cLs2DZhZDVmSEoztevhWkogp/sJ", 
		"answer": "25y2bJj40Fsp+sSEw8kkIJR4VPMbuTRo", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3j/IRgXRiy6Pj4NHjEC2cfpmzDQrF7ZnjnUbSCeOzy3JZzK1nJhFV9/WTLorH5+F1PjqpU/JrfXSMWbJJuiNGN2u35zWJVIcdQk498qNoMc/dJzTHtd9jaM+1r3SLAJkv0Jzy+C357mTjVyn1VvIqt/DOyUcl3xAAgn4l/rdw0OZey2L2B8Uz4lgOQ1XSVBP1gFEeJvNqtq0CTrpY5vMOEvzWb8fj8l/3d5M1LbQ4SvJR6Z06wnrwQuCs2VYixcBNM9uHCYEDkLybh+P9vQkdFSzvbCa/NqJrIfw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "In,di,ka", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040143", 
		"question": "24GwbdHD1Avj54k1QV79w73rPW6QJnAIt3eRV6J6MELmVefDYOm+9qhOGGO2smREzUn5nJq8t1EAm6Ab/pyWZDYGcMtmxpCuxeHyzz0BI9RLjIl24doJffhVzT+hcZTfIepvjmiPNQXkbzz9F2RhkCiWhXoWqY24/CK1QJowxRo1hIZo5dF8Pdmbmauc5UC9lAWHkDuYRr5oBFCQu8no4k2ar5A1tNmEvjyb9fb2j+yT5MwKZg0SvYNrdF65megg9i4xUIi1ZhYL5ezVIWbiLSmtZysQ6cLx0zbt4wMKmNJKfn8lfUhXg+qa", 
		"answer": "24WsZ5323ACt5MUHVxH11/zvPXKSYvV3AXMvsOfJziH646IZsg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD1Avj54k1QV79w73rPW6QJnAIt3eRV6J6MELmVefDYOm++YN+K1mElBxoslHDrKLi9kMHluQb64GLeGIUbIJ73NWHl+35hFZTNsNP1sBi9pUJdfBFjCuseMHaIvJrjmqBM0SwYTavRGR8kXHFnmlSscO082e6Wtk+xRsm1oB94s8uPceXwOiS5kn4hQmP0X6DS7goUV2XtsK970qSp8Ixu8uCoz/a4P32lLjS8tEedkhGrYd7Zhu+krwe/S82EeG6bBtKseXeZRT5KC3jFQEQ+MWj83l5z5AsH99ErxbUHWNSG3wNFqvN7qo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pt,ol,em,y's Ge,og,ra,ph,y", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040144", 
		"question": "2563e5z8wlnD+YEpWRHiyfjqJn/VEC5Roj+kQKJxc36uZqjPb+O+2pR5KFCInxc75WTJt6Cw41sKz4tT+4eMZCsCcMtbx8CG0Pb21HlYf4ZTkolx7NoSefpUxTKjZ5T4KOxn3XqJJkvjJzCzRFl6kDjXyn1YrMOI5y77eNs5yxRyl4l8rckwL9jfy62V7V+rxhKNnESud4JbLmumivGX1Hyj4mjxZhHVSigYRqPI5sbG4H4=", 
		"answer": "2723eoL2kQ349oElEJqIX/tXuTodHt8xh2g3A94=", 
		"explanation": "2563e5z8wlnD+YEpWRHiyfjqJn/VEC5Roj+kQKJxc36uZqjPb+O+2pR5KFCInxc75WTJt6Cw41sKz4tT+4eMZCsCcMtbx8CG0Pb21HlYf4ZTkolx7NoSefpUxTKjZ5T4KOxn3XqJJkvjJzCzRFl6kDjXyn1YrMOI5y77eNs5yxRyl4l8rckwL9jfy62V7V+rxhKNnHOeWq5hUUCLtMqtqWmGd0zI0wu6JSgkAtR4yIM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ho,rs,e t,ra,de", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040145", 
		"question": "25O5JZng2Bzku8UhEj36zPP6Jm6QF3AQtXqPV7E4MHLiWaKCeuK+4Jl1Ll3JhFU75n7D46f18FoBgaFV7s6QdmIXdo4vztmPw+y3x3RPJ9NWg8Bz6p5fePFTzy+kdtHfYOpmyy6TKEb5ZjXxRGJxmDjRg3NDu8/79Cm/FN80zxs9m457rcszMtOWzaGc5l74jwjC9XWVQbwkFUGLvMCvq1eUpcI5ssjNvjSb4Pz82sfsz+E0XTdtgLlAXGSD1aKOPDalIEQmnyr2e4Fdk+I=", 
		"answer": "25KteIXywlvF3l8HAo312rc7As7Hf1cX", 
		"explanation": "25O5JZng2Bzku8UhEj36zPP6Jm6QF3AQtXqPV7E4MHLiWaKCeuK+4Jl1Ll3JhFU75n7D46f18FoBgaFV7s6QdmIXdo4vztmPw+y3x3RPJ9NWg8Bz6p5fePFTzy+kdtHfYOpmyy6TKEb5ZjXxRGJxmDjRg3NDu8/79Cm/FN80zxs9m457rcszMtOWzaGc5l74jwjC9XWVQbwkFUGLvMCvq1eUpcI5ssjNvjSb4Pz82t/G4MoKcUqr5+O7rS/TMrzhWsEbgJum", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gu,pt,as", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040146", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Raq5YAsWx3hhfL5dWjfDm8ErX6PErB8cWPqWqCCZ+O+z5JwNEiawRt992XSqrPx+0BDz6lV7c6PZSgCbct9zcaM1ui3xXNOJtIEm45x7Z8RaLRU3jSvddibM/Ftx2uUPhqypAYGHdLKXXKCPb5ulV6sog==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYizwQvl4YwkV177y+72MmPEECIYrWuMErd8dTHmU6bOZ/n/255wKRyHjE9u4HOGrKOw9l0Mhq1V/c6LYisBf4cv29+K3uHj3TPF59rtuGGAIQ+a1LDqRQzk", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1BXj9JZgXRiyxvLyOH7eAm5RsHeCQKp6dzHqWufEa+zt3YQ9Z1qMnk9y5HfKsOmw9l0Lz7hO44+MMDEWeYxq28TJw+z20DFAPcVNn45mpI4NdfZBwH2+e9fSJepny33AN1fxZC20B3Vw1DCWjHNEpcO082e+U9s7yQEzhI5548EvMZvfzqCW+kj4hQmP0W6fSbEkEFeNvNih/0qZs8IvsN+I8THe+uDrm/ST5NFLdgBXtpQ/cFS/nqkFuCw5U9q9a1J/+e3DIVfiLjyxJh0J6ov032Bhho4oSWwmtBxHkZdTL8JyxZ3g/Do5Ot9rBzCyqkFTh5VyW1eferipxWno6UE2cGlpDxxfHWl+qnh/DsvUYbC9pQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "They highlight the dominance of high caste people", 
		"option_b": "They indicate the absence of loyalty within clans", 
		"option_c": "They provide insights into the egalitarian nature of ancient tribal society", 
		"option_d": "They suggest the decline of ancient sects and institutions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040147", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2BT69oY0Ehr7wb33PGzYQ2EQsGuGErNxf2HvUeDRLuzq3Z5lMliMzU905XfUp+X99l0ajqQb5Y+dfzBDdop5zZCG2aTky3JINtJdxcJ+2FPUVh5k25pfpmN4oKH9", 
		"answer": "25ysKIHh3hTl44AkEgv80fLqNmPRAWsdqmuaEqJ6dDH3XKKCauTtzZZ4KRyPgkk7/3fItqT8t18OjadJq+uF1oKifnWzcdY9e3v0PzU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4glXAr7yvPsdX/YAnZRq3aEWuN3cWL3UefSa+LuxZI2NByKglVv93vWt+X2+EFPgqlV/I+TMC4CfIR9iNOG2fDlzXNUJ8NA2pR9pI4XebRQ3jKge8DSL/AuwWjAMkvkaCy+DHF2nT3fnmUWqY2/tSb7R9850xBymYE4/t0sOcWW1rqa/FT0xgqH3X+YRrokBVvZpsGr4kKQ4Is2sNyYsD7S4P38ibjS/tpLYQlBq4M/c0m5nb0N8Sk9QopuGs4YeW0ec7hKNjI0dUMi", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It led to the abolishment of untouchability", 
		"option_b": "It reinforced social equality among castes", 
		"option_c": "It promoted untouchability and the disdain for manual labor", 
		"option_d": "It strengthened the relationship between man and woman", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040148", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17i1/jpNGfVDWEU43CFErd8dTHwVbPLLv7n2oN0Khycg09y/jbSq6Cwpgpc37sb4ICbeSECao4witj7cX33F8GyEpmdtG2sUjk=", 
		"answer": "24W9eoL6wg3v+YYlEhH0he7wNmLRDyIYrXqSR6J4eWXqUbSCaujt2Z5lIhycg1Jt92TVoqmw5EYJibpa7ovdJqKwDDWKM3xvKSN63no3rg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w73rPW6QEGMFqj+QS7BgdXyjQanWZ+G+3Z90Zw3Q3gtosn/I47fl5VIDz7ha+5qMMC0FPqlmwNGbl+35wHhCMtJBicBm7JsLPPBF3y2kYNGbIf1mx2uWLkv3JyyzDWZxhiLXhjxFvYW95ya8UZZ3xBA3hspq4scoOdPfyqeQ4Uy0xg+M2WqESbFtBV2cpo6p5Ufcr5Iop8ieojvN8bTpiPnQ5NcIZxsSr4NtcFKvg60NuCM2EcuxegZK+OqQc1HqKSetNE4S/4vK2HBgx8Biv68ZAbOyfKcY7NNMdmY5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Literay sources to village study", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A decline in the influence of Dharmashastra rules", 
		"option_b": "The prevalence of communal sharing in rural societies", 
		"option_c": "A lack of loyalty within clans and castes", 
		"option_d": "Persistence of social inequalities despite universal suffrage", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050101", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17n0fTzPHHRF2serT+MVONnf3LqVauCfe73zJlyIk/Ji1RpsmTDoKr+5EcdmqtP4ICYMCMNfYJqxsTJ/urzzXBPc85NiZR99oNff/tNwTijd9GEYhYeRyuH2fRMZ6N3UI2QBug=", 
		"answer": "25S6Z4TnkQ3i/pc0S17rwPztJivRBG1TnX7daXhTIITS//rVOcftJw==", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHmxRDm/p8hRhf9y73wMyvWCmwVqnGEQeNyYn7uFLTNbeT/xddiJFWMg1h+4TbArLew9FwBnLxJ/I2LeSwEPp9nzZCB3vfjy2NIMMdI2o5z9ogeaP1WyX2icpTaLv1ny2CUZ2z+YzC8RHJxkzDYyn1GuJG07S62Vc4yzAxygo9x/9wlfM6a2LqAqEy/iUQ/1TyhyIN2VL8iKJnwFXjE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Around a century ago", 
		"option_b": "Approximately fifty years ago", 
		"option_c": "About thirty years ago", 
		"option_d": "Within the last decade", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2BT69oY0Ehbz0/i/O2rEFnAQrz+QUapxfnLmR+fKb+m+xpkxM1SMzUhv53Lf46r2t1IBjKFe55rfWSwHd4owioGlVolWyhcN8qW+07MjlRg=", 
		"answer": "25CuYZX23xrvt4MyXROyxvX6OGLDF3AI7z+EV6x4f3b6GOfDYOm+y55+K1OOlBtz82WGsaDz8l0bg7Eb64ucfy8GPptq2sSA2eH50DFVPIZRlIR39okLffpExTOqNNXVI/drwHrADkv0bjj/Q6LCFV/QgpmGmPhFHYXTPw==", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHmwhyq+INgVwj7wfjxNm6QBXAerj+NU7dhYnDvFLTBZ+jwypJiZ1CAhl478X7Drqzj40EWw+hc7IGTfyUaMstuxtTJ1e34yH5GKoZMm5My5p8cc/lFjC+oeNHNIfB6jnqPZ1H4YnmuEGVwjXHZjDxXpoCy8CmvFPM5xBwz2sdr+M87OcSL0KaUqEz4lAOB2XWFCLh8AVWXpsen5QOVrsIsvcjNojHU5PG5lf6T+dAfZxpWtpV8akuwnqYI6jN4Q82nbRNZ8uySXz716wDHhREhOdUhJRMGUg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Natural sciences have remained irrelevant to the study of ancient India", 
		"option_b": "Chemistry, geology, and biology have been used to study modern India", 
		"option_c": "Evidence from chemistry, geology, and biology has recently become pertinent to understanding ancient India", 
		"option_d": "Natural sciences have replaced social sciences in the study of ancient India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5EoV170yujtdWrXBnFRrnqNRqp7fnTnFK7MLvn2zNdBMk6Ig1posmLOorGw81YfhqtPqYOQYiMPPophzJCa2Of+xX0BN8NDn4539psLdftOjDK7ccabNPdjyzHC8CspfkO+S0FXRsOdUKctNQ==", 
		"answer": "256qYYXynVne5YA0U1Ky4ev+JWrCAi5RiH6PW+FMtIPWclDiBjPFnAvXS7aT", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDxAvr+YQzEhP3y+n2OmWQBW0EsT+CVaZnMHLiWKvHaq3V255lJhDJuUl+5neK44Hm9kMOnakXqY+RdGIof4dmiPWI1Oy312RCMMNBnol849oee/EAxS7tcNHLKf16y2rAJlawcDavF3U0gDnXhDxCoIb75TW+V98zyRs11oh26IR8K96L0eie51+5ikaU3XeETa4kEFqd9d2n6EqdrMIxu96ZuCbO4P32lOuT9NsMZwZXrYdralW716cf/Th4RcG5bVBGxfYcQNZWlm9eT8tjTRC+", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Krita, Treta, Dwarka, Kali", 
		"option_b": "Vedic, Gupta, Maurya, Mughal", 
		"option_c": "Golden, Silver, Bronze, Iron", 
		"option_d": "Krita, Treta, Dvapara, Kali", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRHj5JEvQBfxxPG/ImTCCCIGsXaXRqZ6MHjtFLPKa63q3pJ9IUiBzVh+/GLTsbyw50EAmaFf7J3fcWIQaplmxtfJ2OK3xnhONNRFioh74Ylfc/IA2DWoNN/SLvl9jmGGZ27xdDGwDWI0lT/SymxZu5C+5jS+R5o0yBQgl4Rs6No1L8OW2rvT50v4iwmG2WmfCLVtAkCWp8er6k/ct5AxocSDtm2Zn7UaVv/M1JEIJvO12Fs6pA==", 
		"answer": "24e5YpDn0Avr+YIpXBewL1g9NX51hA3W5jzMO/NZhw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH72Ar++JcpUR/+herwJ2CQPyAjonWCRqJmcX/kXanLUq++3oV4M0iMgxt56zbtoqn49l0Oz6FVqZqXdWIXaY5jzsSBl+fyymVUId8Ek5My5doMaOZJwjrte9KbIvdhyXyBN035Yir9C3Y0gDnTyndfpoSotSi9FPE20x0/n5U47MY4fN6Mmauc5l6xggOQ2X/RXLVhUVKQp928q1STsol4osSZuXLI8eL8iPnfsN0DYxpTvJJ6cVKvg6EK62o3V4i8YQFf/vbZYlXhYD+xLhoU98yj12cp04wtWHsn4BBJhsNCbcRyz9pUDzFgmCi4Oe7RdBqXnDcc", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ramacharita", 
		"option_b": "Rajatarangini", 
		"option_c": "Harshacharita", 
		"option_d": "Mushika Vamsha", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQv/+4AyFQ2yzPPsNnnZE3YYrHGQEqVmf3yjQK/HLvn2wIV1Z1+Mg09u4G+GgYaw81YCgKZI/ZyeZCdDf8t8wdeH3uL+x3BPJ4ZMk5Nm64gWf/VMjC6oesfeYPx3jnyFJEriYzCzAzBxgjTYnm8Wp5W+52e2QdYjyQU+k8dq6M8yPdvfwK2S+l7nxCjRCLdgBGQC0/C7HHAQuco=", 
		"answer": "25SrYJ740Fvy5z7da3XrRxoMu0yRACAp", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwhHl/IQuEhf81v7tPHvECm0fsD+FQKx5MGXrUefWZuTszddyIlKdmElislTl46H1+lwBnLxJ6JqaMCEMcJhmzNWb1ub7wTFJOtVQlZJ755sTPOdFwi6oNNbCYOxrzWGSI0z+YHm4EnV6gCKWnnRXvMOz9DerUdQyxFU9gIJqrcUpMMOWyaSWqF+9gQiD0DuITbx2AhSWs46J+EuTq4N/po2ftDvc+ri5iurc5tcPawZV/49xcFK7n7wauCM2Rcf0fBpOsezZckDiMiGgJgJd+sTtwnFx0sImWykg/B5Swpdfb8Ux2U5ciDAmp+8PAKNi1LHyhA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chandragupta Maurya", 
		"option_b": "Harsha", 
		"option_c": "Ashoka", 
		"option_d": "Vikramaditya VI", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1A/v+ZFgWw2yy/ztJ2rEBmZRqnHDYaJ6dHn6VazDfOy+55Z/I1XOnhtHsETHrqTz/1Idhrxa1czAMg36llT0jYeowtzdhC8fY+M=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHw3hfs+4wjRl7wwOnoMG7eQ3IUomyCXLdnMHDtUOfDLv3swJlyIhyAgxtQ83rPraLxtTUFrFIchyF6lYfLeJiu5Eo=", 
		"explanation": "24a5ZpX7yBjh9pchEjDzy/n2cniQPyAjonKCUat1Ynj3VZuALuP/24VwM1mazU9z9zbVt6ri7hMAiehP4Yvfcy0NeIdmy8TJ1eHj03REPYZQkoUyz5sWavVS2DztZNHaM/9g2n3AJkv0Jy21ATBElT3XymxEoY248GeJVdc20BQ+l8s4/80vKduL0KaUqES2xhKK2TuBWrRqElHepo6+4kCIr5Ah93GoacsPfpCDTeH8YIC9EF4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The conflict between peasants and a prince in Kalinga", 
		"option_b": "The achievements of a Chalukya king of Kalyan", 
		"option_c": "The rise of the Mushika dynasty in Kerala", 
		"option_d": "The court life of Harsha", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050107", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0Whuy+b/XNHnDC2MSq36RW7d1TDOjVr6CTOzwyJV5JkidjBt/92XFsazy8h9Pi61I+YeLdWIBe4Jhz5CB3uP/yGgBNt5FnYd39psLefAfjvJyxYqgl0W5I5tmXxebfrs=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdH20Avm7sUjUwz3wO+/Om2QK2MDsHeCRKJmdHniWqaAlAIrCZVNBevvH3sPRULqFQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHPkzHr5ZYoUx36xO/2IWrsQSITuj+hU611cnniQLPDLun72pRjLl6Mnhtv+nOGpqTi+0pPjKlJ7IuNMC0FPqNu2sOB1vL21nVJMshF1sBi9pUJdfBJwjrtfdrIKflm2n3ALkvkaHm+C2VmgHHag3pT6Ja18SKpFPI20gY6l8d548x8KN+ambuc60S5ikaD0n/RWrhoGFOQutu7q0KPsIc7od7NvjSb/P3q2vnU9ZJLdgBdqoF3I1Ko16EauCE2Xt+6KAZEsebVIVzkJyCvPk4Y4crk0XF7x5YsWSvyKTCIy0An047e+QV3dXj/", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "The dynasty of the Mushikas", 
		"option_b": "The achievements of Vikramaditya VI", 
		"option_c": "The early career of Harshavardhana", 
		"option_d": "The court life under Harsha", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050108", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSGy1u36NGCQDGRRpXCWQON1d3TwDufpfOTqyNsxE06MmVo3slLQorXx5VJDz4Na5YfTMCcCfYMvy9iIxeX00HRTOtxBnsBw/doePPBFzzGketGbKfAuw2GSJkmwcTixEXVn1DDYjjxFp4Cy9Cv7XdQk1Bwmg5Nx4sYvfoK5/UQxr2uXmQAPiaFOIbY=", 
		"answer": "24WtepD90AqoZoADW0dXMbjom6JJZXh3Lw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDxAvr+YQzEhr31v7tPGnVQ2Qetm3DU6RxYzHiR+fpfOTqyNsxE06MmVo3slLQorXx5VJDz6lV7c60cS4KMst4wcSBl+H2x3kBMsFB2oR39JMcaPFEjDy+NMPUMu1rjnqIJkuwczG4RGBmkSffhWlF6Iy18GeyWpojxQc/hcd364gxM8We1eiF6UGtgxXC3XWVCK5rEl2YuY6h5VCIqZYtocSCvyGZy1JfeK0GDfVQCYi6Ki0tgQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Pu,ra,nas,nes", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050109", 
		"question": "24GwbdH72Ar++JcpUR/+herwJ2CQPyAjonWCRqJmcX/kXanLUq++3oV4M0iMgxt56zbtoqn49l0Oz6FVqZqXdWIXaY5jzsSBl+fyymVUId8EipJ98pMbeecAzX2+YMbSLvkuwWjAJUz/YCu8FHh9kSKWhXoWvIu+tSyyWt0kgBo01rhH0vcDA+ig5pfRedA0VnqlgJ+Mj6AkfY6eHg==", 
		"answer": "2565e5n+2AuoJAIjQ9GZHjfUB0Atq5wYCw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHPkyvr/YQ0Uwzzy/r2O2LsQSIYsD+CEqt9Y2XsRq7Bb+G+3phjLBydhVpvsmbUprb1+Uccz6pS5omNcTILd458iN+Pl/D/wTFKOshDicB94to0fedIwTS/NNXVJL5n3S6DKEvjbj24FnVw1CXZymxZu5C+5jT7V9I20hQxgoJq5NsoNdSMmaeVqEC3ggOQ0juZQa5wHkaQts+kq1SOqZYxu8rPf81bhvapSRh0a0MMx9drEg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ka,sh,mir,mer", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050110", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSHNhfTxJmjCCnIFqnCNQeNyYn7uFLPKa63qwZ5jIxyKiFVv52Tf44fTt1cKgqdV+pqNcTYGPoov2tWE1vb8xXNNNoZMk5Nm64gWf/VMjC6oesfeYPx3jnyFJEriYzCzAzBxgjTYnm8WvIu64WeoRNs5gBgnmpNx/cQ5fMWa3qaS5A2hgweQzzlTZ369kEn7ox7z+lm74XYJ", 
		"answer": "25SrYJ740Beo8zQI3ThxXoFeiB0xx6P4iw==", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHSwhHl/IQuEhf81v7tPHvECm0fsD+FQKx5MGXrUefWZuTszddyIlKdmElislTl7+Xn/1oMh+hf7IOQfjEXbIp7zZCIl/f+w39INc9Hm45mpJIWb+BP3jSuddibM/tg3WvAJVywdTy+C2JwnT/RynlArY2v5mevXNsjgBoxlZJq/804fNiJ3LrT+0iugxSD0DuDTbpqEFjZrMup+VDcr4R4lN6Fvjnas+e5iO3f9Zx5dfp3XejGEEi5CV3Fp3L6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "As,ho,ka,n", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050111", 
		"question": "24a5ZpX7yBjh9pchEjDzy/n2cniQPyAjonKCUat1Ynj3VZuALuP/24VwM1mazU9z9zbVt6ri7hMAiehP4Yvfcy0NeIdmy8TJ1eHj03REPYZQkoUy26UgQ8t/8wKSS5TLJf99z2CUNAXxaT39EHhx1AHXhn0WuJGy+yS+FOg2zRQil4t5rwzEeHOg8PTGTsfRmuVdsMQ=", 
		"answer": "2565YYfyww3rtaOmJ9TTV0zDRfua4SqDP0U=", 
		"explanation": "26GwaYWz4hjk8405UxXz1/y/G2reB2tWsD+/EJF1fXDgXKbQZ/n/9dUxM1mFgUg75n7D47Hx+1ZPgK4b/YaaMCEMcI1jwdOdl+by0GZENsgEjoh3pLEedeJB3imsNMTeIe1vwHqTZ0T+Y3mpDHU0pDDaizxGuoq19iL7Zts6wQUzmoY6awnCxGlFWjp3+7mdr7pmQA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ka,iv,ar,ta", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050112", 
		"question": "24GwbdHPkzHr5ZYoUx36xO/2IWrsQSITuj+hU611cnniQLPDLv3sxoF4I1mazVp1snfFoKrl+UdPgK4b/YaaMCcCbId2iNOIxeHy1jFONYZ7pb9N26UgQ8t/gH2ictLeMvdgyS6JKVb5YDGpFzB9miXZyn9ZvZGvtSuyUt931Rs2k5U4xckuL9+emamd7A2sjgPCz3SSQbxoUVWXsY667k+Vp4s3oN7NsCHL8fftibjc9p4DaxsSvoF6IQ7n7zR4lGdgmF4SD3UIY18=", 
		"answer": "2525eoL70A/r5YEoUxDzh4NDG4x7OL5MU4A8wAqVG7M=", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHPkzHr5ZYoUx36xO/2IWrsQSITuj+hU611cnniQLPDLun72pRjLl6Mnhtv+nOGpqTi+0pPjKlJ7IuNMC0FPqNu2sOB1vL21nVJMshF2oF84NoQevJF3i7tfdrIKflm2n3ALkvkaHmpDHU0lz7DmGgWpIq98Ge6Wt530xoxn4Js7MR8PcSP3KuH+w23gEaW1H7RXLRpFBbRIV1K6MDuJZ9vstgWI/bq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ha,rs,ha,va,rd,ha,na", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050113", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPqdm28TJ/s3LyiABBc9PiIF/5dosfflWzSnhNOfTIfVvjl2BKlPxc3nwRDA01HGWyjwW6MOavGeOWt4y0hg7mI526ogyPcOWz63T61i0khOQ3XfRWK9tFVHZtMCsq0mJs5Yxs9SEvzWb1ubwjvHA+J4PbQVbsYdxYF6AmbgI6zkxR830aRxPsebRYl/6ITqnGwBPue3sw2Ypx4UsTjN03w1PloIaIvRh04zl8HIUKcx6FCG77wRrxph1H1rWVvT4kELx80E2c2Mia40tnj88tQaPIBR9lWeTQiVLlZRi8d5ZlApnPWxPkmLyjTPLj3OKbtPK5YT1hNT+r78j260jIECOJmDWBc0/ar/PKW5zxqmLArRIIZ5+Fi6mMtNu1Tf9KZeazHlNnZlgbzentGrZ0o21eSX687GwzvFlAL4COtjW4cK5txzGISXzIHCWccTmUkj2QG641w9xvhYiiCkZ+3bXGoB89CFNm2i1R1B3rinHeWy1l/5Z+IOycdpx8eflyTsDkLR5jNv03Qs1Sw2hiG1Q8oWRSxxKyUHVH9kI1hpuQfRBVNaRsi3WsT+Qb3kdds3iCKaAgy0I3ubygmhzutAHW8yDIwvahp4wyRukBO45VGnp6JX2PvUUBiQl9KFlw/m0o8O0e+DkI3MvfVqjUOJcsdYjddmrixAvsuC3QqjMXTE=", 
		"answer": "2+T1S92zg1TOu8VzHz++hamyFykwF/U8rsfWz4mCtMYaNQBK", 
		"explanation": "24OxY4Py3BiqxIQtRB/mib3MPWrbAiIionKVU7c4MFb2RLPDLujsyNd5IlCZiF8792XSoqf8/kAHz6kb75yefScUcZlkiNaGxaTzxWVIPcEEkolh8JUNdfdBwH2oYtHVNO1SwFqIIgXzaDe+AWBg1D7QynpZvZH79CC+R64c0hwml8s42do5KNbTmYyF6V25lAfOqHKcWLFtFEfZtI6s7kCQqYw99cSD8T/U5vX12u7S/MsOcUhTsYI/cFS/nqkFuCM2Qty9fAdf+OvechTiNi2xZxoU9M7f2EBhw8IqUmU7+hZHjsNGbdJnxJn9vT5wMMsqPD2+qkVO1NR9TFeGda6r2X7hoFQxcTopZIlmqywnpUPcKV1zn2/cWCMRgY5v+8IUnApmPWFBiH/2h3+IlWmbaYHi58Dsl+H0pfli/KdnI1STIVXeT80+d7rULnR6iu2UAK9SMpFkEh7oCd0rvBvrKYKdzDFKw5kwKmXk8TqNm8L7eWq884bxi9llEbMWM8KF6Nj3s1XRaC/oO3iBdYv1VwywSnjt0A9xuAo2iC4WqEvWDIB++z5A3n2/R1B2myX1eHml1qpTqoibbJo41ezl0zVQuuZxi5Lk3F0/SAi0g3ZZs5CWQFIPzFrSXs4Iyh08A7hBG4DU4C2/m3LZSj5uLdHfpjA0J7SyIKKSjXrQ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-D, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"option_b": "1-A, 2- C, 3-D, 4-B", 
		"option_c": "1-C, 2-D, 3-B, 4- A", 
		"option_d": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050114", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc6zeTEXPqJG9N7Yl8/lzWVAf4ZwiIVm5dZfWOJB3Dy/dZibC/9ixy7NZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWyjwW6KLytRW+RMgy0xA8goZs5McyfNiZmaub6UO/jwiFnHaeWrxoUUKYudut+AOdroZ4psKOuDPXtPD8mfTa/ts3bFoSjYd1Yk+9hakH/yM2WIi2cVJg8OjYYFrsYGXjZ05duYujljQphsJpHSl0tF9ky8NzY9J/z9jstSEkMN9jFjK241NP1Z88SB6CfP272Gn24VYrcGgidp5kvz51rgncJVt6n3mSDCRYh5Rk7NkalAgjan1JiH/uhQOF0yXPXYDr5Iv9i6j5rqpg4Ko3PUiPO0+YG81cJfOAZycyiqnbTeYcc98nV2KmfZVuvHm5A9/Unx0I3dYuPGP19T6QnMq1MWypp53rh9d3GP8TM9/W7Iu1qRzVZCDuM3maaMy0XB71QWjrkwFzsgpl2iQX5mPUSJB69D8eonDkCXdlnCPodX2ql6xdqqyPcYo4lOas4XAimfl5nJP2xhQoRjj5zVsK8qqeXU5O2V3ZEI0IwkktA7oHGJ/S5i2UkGLHTnkDP97zALuGzThbmuL/iiF8/4AcXIKNKVuDgGA91VbBg4Hkl+YdNjsh", 
		"answer": "2+T1Sd2zg1TIu8VzHz2+hamyESkbWZFqd+gJMvJVXa48A2Eh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1Aj/8osjV179w73+Mm7DQ2sf41aNVqp1fjHrXbTWYf/nvbxjLkiIwRtP4HPSoumw00UOn6lJ6MLfWyMPd8sb2tWZxeHkwX9VIIZHkoF845MRe7RNwy+seJTNIfJ7y33AJkv0JyqyB3l1mHHSj39aoY2+tRu1YNIygB07hZN3/8E/PdvfzqeB4w2ExDSD1nqFSa9lH1OQu8eUqQOeucITtMGFsDzatLm5k+uT89EFcQFWupR6Zxuon61J/SsqXcGxewYL5uvCahT6KTyrZw0V+Nni1WBs1Is6SWA3519JhMNbbcR2xJaktDsjK8J4HDC7rwRX1Z1oVhmRNIG25GDhoHQsfXUgZIQttSMmoh2VOEB3lWWPDGERkIVm8d4KgRZiaWoAlH/zljCZiWaOcNPw7o7vgKjyuflx96AoO0WJO1uYU5sZa6fTZ2hkz/vbH6NbPZ5rVzvjPMc9vHGqaaqa7DgD1NE5Lnzm5ivZvMz7PWz9oNLFzOZ3Gb4DPtDX4N+2jB6HLGPvIG+BZ9/xSkjkR3m40AFrsRQsyzVQ6mfMH4x6+20dm3+jSEpwgWfhYnjhl/5M+IuAfItxm6Gln5kw7eumCljhrimJpqqgsvE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-D, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"option_b": "1-A, 2- C, 3-D, 4-B", 
		"option_c": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_d": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050115", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd5Lk+dgkly8XfK47b1+UAKz6FVqY+RcysGcJ8v4d6N3uW3zWIBEMlWiIVx8MAjcshOnXOZfNGbEOt8z2CBNAXgdTarDXRx1DXPhH1FvIq4tS+yR8440gxyg5c4+cd8KN+amaqW70S2iA+M2zueTv1wGVHZktu4/0Lcspc0sPGDjTyJusDxn7jj5cwKbAlB/4t6bU+1mKZJ/Tw9X9ynKBtFsfDYZBT9ITu3ZxoY99jmmjR7w4QlWGog/RFBwpdeZ8lhlorhvz0iO8RkEnO2rEpHh5V6SxKENKmw1Sjh9lAxYWlrcYVit20lrQ6fLWhwpmXPAhhZkcBi88AWhxBic2xF3HnmwiuCjWDPfZ3nq5DwhOv14LBtsqsuOlWPJ0WYX55ca7zUZ2J/2uGaHq9GNpsnHiymKd0rvAnsMpea3ipPNzAW6KBv/mGEa04CVv+BGw==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfz8Nn7CAnYU+D+XWqY0QGTxVanDfa3u25hnLliMzV9i/HfVt6zzt1sGnLxU+5ffZTJDaoQv3NiMl+byw3hPPc9KncB94toLdPEA6yi9YNWbMutiyy6zM0TkYjS4CmQ0xnHfmTxXpJC0tSS0RsgywwFp1pNw6IgsPcSM2K+WqEC9iBKL03WCCKlsEEDZptqp/0aRpYwspo2Msz3O4LT8jP3d5M1LawYSq456I2uphakH+Tl4UNqxKB9K9eGQaFqtNCCmZwgI7d7x0zR9w4w6WCkw8QxWi5dTIsJ235bj/CA1PMJ4ETa+40lVxJw8UxaCca/443zl9FAycHQ/JdkttT51qAGfJ0Zsn2iIF2xFnIUr7tEKhgVkeC9JknLpgT6fhXbPaJvmq4nxlefitLht8aZnJkfAIVXVU80da7eAN2tzyezbBKgcO5Z0Ay30JJeJt26cPOC+1+jRGc95rFUT", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050116", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddQNFSGhlp1sn/IsKbi/kMbhqdV+s6WY2IAcZl9zdOdjdj5+H8QfedXko955d0MPP1O3z6/fcTPKfFg3S6SIkb/dT39AWZxmiXFynpEp4774S++FNw+0gYm1pN3rdw0OZeT2LuHqF+9gQiD0DuITbx2UVuf9cah+AOOtY49icOxv2CVwPz82tnA+NEAYwYStohsYEm1h7wA9yQrEdimZwRC9eGQaFr+KS+rMx1d8MX32TRhz5E9Uns99x5KwoZAZ85nxdjgqSA5McoqHTqp41ZFzpNyYxmqeu729X7h7kEsNWguaYt5tSMy4RuTaFtwlnLcQiVfkcB5+9cXlAgjZGpBjmWggy2OwGOAaZ3nq4nyxfz4pflC4asoIkCOdVXWRY4ObKPULmh82amfBLVfPIliBSfifcYhvD/4MtRiIq/KG9yRZPq5mBPATxjZ", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStyTDRqtxMGHiR7TDaei+xJJ/M1WGg0g75n7Ht+XR5FsAhKkc+s6WfjEAbIJ/3NmG2fe31nRCPNRA2oVk4ZQLb7RG3jKgNMDTJb5rx2mIM02wczb9EHhx1CXBj3JCsc6o8DG+Ws4/gAc3kYl54YglOdaNleid51n4hQmU2WmYRrokBVyc9cum/0qOpcIqsMSKv3Lo4PXtn/XW/spLMEhbrMZ8bEmukqsdo2osWc30SQFD/u/RbxTkLjugNQcN7cLs2Gcp1pAmS2Aw8V9PjJBfZchnxdjtsiY/f8VjBie1sU1Dxpg8WgGTeqmrkGzx8lwxcjojbJktrig8pgHcG0B/jm6RSSJF1NMr98NZlAdgaH1BiHO7wiuDhSWffYDw6of5xfvkoa1m4eMzIUCUdVnOU4MIdvPSImtz3uCVCuZIPN9oGS7/fdsn8jy5MpOT0TgBkMAlLmX0tCuLl43zNnC0t9LwgJRiHLpAMtjW6sShtU7CZWPAMnWcbcr6GQH+XH/q2h5xvhcr221Q5GfZHoBx8m0fkXG9CUJrgGfmeWi0hLsc7oudfIEn1ufl2CFSmRk4Y35isg/LQKKnzzslkg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050117", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd5Lk+dgkly8XfK47Li/kcGga9IqYeRMCMNfYJqxsTJ/urzzXABOtUEmY9g9p8caK58wgGjJZrvKPsu/nuSJkvxdHm5AWB9lyWWizxaoY2+9DX7RMg4xwc3hZRx4sZ8M9Hf1KeB6UH4kAeOyX6CCLxqFRSKus2h6k/cqYwrocSZpCbS+/rq2vnQ4tEYcUhUsJNtI1q7krtTuAEqWNy1JFJ/4+HEYBitBD6iNw8P+Iej/XVlz74nYWdmuitOh8Nea9Nn2YrtvzM8f9plBzj6nwZyxp59SxaEdbO/2Wbt3Bd/d2NrTothtCw7oE+VOxR9lWWPRShUhoVvvsQRkERmfH1MlXPzln+cj3eEPIfsq5Dzlvv1s6oj4aYxLFOBORzbXowOZLDUInV72f2SDrUcPJknGi3iOMcgvDHwM4KbzTAO0dVgOGXu4COXlfH7BWvp/abxi5RXB7cPPdDLqcK5o1/VaDP1KHKddYv5WAH+Q2W41QFmogtlxy9Q+mfbB5t7/CMK3nuzRkprny7jLGizl7BP64GadoE/wLXt0zZQjOZ5m5630AguTgq8zV5QuouUThtcjUbDEshFfZxMYu5eZH0Bej8mYLWgeg==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfz8Nn7CAnYU+D+XWqY0QGTxVanDfa36zIRyNVWLiBt9/WPU46T38kBPjrsbwpyWZCNPPr99zcSIm6TT0nBRMtRF1sBz6p5fV/VMxXHtZtHLMvt9y2CULkv3JzSyFnF41DXTiXBfpob7+jG+RpojyRg31rRs7Nw5MdKRzejBqESrxgeOz3TRS7J2A1GaoZXo1wGuoYg5ocyfsDzc/frwprqT8sdLSQlet4dxYhu1hOgK9yQrWMyxehdPsfDYZBToITqvLgsO7Yv02WZihpUgSWF09xdHkIJVdsVh34vwtTEjf8JsVT61p0FSydR0VgSCe6+x02nooEItfG4ia40tjzk0tQqRLVpq2jjcRT8RnY5o8cILkAd3Ji9UlHOgoyyDj26OctPq5ZP/l+HgtLBs/LBnL06DIE+YWYNcd7bMLmB7xfyITadSN99qGDDnMZUj+SrqIZGRzHVN3tY0b3Lk+ySWn8T2eXGospzqj9diHbAOJZHK+4ujol3DZGGXcz8SUPf3CoPr0WGrmFr5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050118", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddzLlOOn1pr+n/Foqmw4EEGm6FV7p3feSxDf4VswdWHw6TeynVIMoZNicBx64gNefdUlgGjSNqKbsIs5m+SNE3xZDG8FnlglQ2Uyn5P6KG6+ya5XNsj1BRyhpV3+8E4OcTf0KaA4UqwkhXC1XWFR/1wGVHZsM+651rco4MqsMif8T3dtNz4iOvb8cgKcAxavoh+I1qyk+ga9ykxVNytKBZe4+3eZhTlKTvjMwcQ/Pft6no7iLEoU2087R5Ng5FXIu5y2JztxSFwA49YFD67oExB1Z1oXivUNLO5wnrl9FAsNW4jYMp+qCInuE+TLhRqkm7cTyNfkoxi/cRZlwF3ampFkjb0ijrLsGSDfdPz+Ynyhu2wkrhu87MmJUDANFLcFpkUYPPrJm5ky/uPDOZMNp50FizyLukgwDeqbqrW6TAGwtgtLnns9S6chMz2MWSouob4spY2FqZAFNjJ4cq5sRzVZCDuNHOHdYvgUQ2wTn/w2gtzshUgxjUDqG3eSL92/j8Mk3+0QFB9k2fWRTDhgrZZqqGGfoIk2OztnTkZlvM4kJ23/xwwXgW1zwx6zml9gqUpHaoJANpuACk=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfz8Nn7CAnYU+D+/EIt1YmLrVaTKb//33ZZNZRyLlBtZ83jHoa3x40cOz7hJ5piWdCcQPoJh29mO3/DkhHhPJ8kEsoFg95IeavVSyDWsetWcM75rz3yMPgXzZiu4AWI0lT/Sym9Zq4q+4T77UM8lyRs11o9x/ogoNdqamZuH6Vm9iwOMyDvDCLR3UV2XtsG6+UaftNl4vNnNpjPItMf4lPzb6d8AYxpT/6h+bV+17rtJxGgKUMW1axpK4+3EYGivYDyrJhpd98rxxHV9w5FpSWExtBxJjIVaa8NnlprhqCU1OsMqATu/429BzoJ9TQOXNK290Xvl7kEsNXslYcp5tCh1kQ6QKRRuiGKSTykRpoFm/8AYmQUjTntBiHPthzGfwDbPdYCj6ozviqjxo7p24KIzLBrACR7uX4YOZL7BKWxzzuyNDKVUMo1uAyPaf5Us5XnbKZqc3jcMkMslLHjy+j6K0tn9PCW7sJrwi8JzGboOIsKF5s33hlXMcyLsIHmactL1GT7ZAzzs2wsllBAkxDQb8WOYA4Bx8m0CmD6bSEh9kymikYGV1Lhe5Nj89aZSG3UiUA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050119", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf7wO2jVE3ZRrHnDVKxhYjHiU6LRGsbswINwaxy9n15v8zqGh7Px51IdjuQb6ICbMAkCcoIbwcPJ0+HnzXJVNsIEk44y8JIaPMRV3jyjdcebNPEux2KMMlbkdTipATBgnDSWjnlVpIq18GeyWpo6zwczmsdu7MQpOcTf2KaXqF63hQ+D0DuYRq5wGECMocen5VDcr5Q9p42ZuD/eyPrFlMrW8c0EbFISi456I0iplKsM6zkxR830aRVO4qTRc1GtJC2wJBwU+87nlnV6hpUmT3oxtAtOg40Wdsh2loj2uTE1O8RkEnO1rUEMh4d0UACferr40Sjg5VI6e385ZJ5ksyN1qAHcO1t9k26ITSARl49l+tkNnAttbi34vF4mKJ8f12X0FAF3CyOC", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefDbe7r25ZlIhy9hV474nfVsKT38hMCiqZP4IGRY2IXdop7iNWI1Oy312RCMMNBnol849oee/EAxTPtYNzeYP1hwG2FN1GwaD/9An9hhnHXjXlF6IqotSO+RNM01BA21oZrrd8zLsSambyb6UP4kg6HnGuDTb5hFV2Xso6n5UbQ4IM2sY2ZuTvItP31lu3A5MwKdg1B/5J3Zhu4kqsF8SQ9EcG6KB9E4+XcIULsLD2mNE4c98+jxXtqz4MlHWA65wtPlpZCa899xdjQtDdwLchrBjy041RSyIJ1WxKFNLz4xmno6VF/cGI7aYtjvTk8rgHcLlts2n+USWxQh5Nu7MQQmgoh4deXqxEPEPNQiJngrQcZBg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050120", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfX2Jn/fEWsSonPDRaxmezHfFpXDZOzqyIVwKVuAg1JHsDbEuuXb9l8HjqZaqYeMMCEMcJhmzNWb0uC30H4BI8lXiYVh99oMeeJF3jyhNNfTIexvzXqFNUzjczC+FzB7knHbhXhTuo37/S6oQNUlyRYzmsdv/8EoNdmY5aav5n+9hxWN0iHRdP9WEF6Yoc+66k2bqYwxiY/NpjPItOPrk+zH9dBLawYSvog/bEmylrwMuDksSMSxKBNF9aTWblf4My2wZwsF+sf2xX1/w44wHWY6tAtOh8NUa890xJn0tDs1LI1lE3OxqkpH1NbN57yR1jW9sbOvJQGNbWgT", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6eSvSFnZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufLfa34yJtiIh6GB1b7ea+qyNYC6T5cLpBo", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBjlRnz2xU6l1ZHDxVanFZ+P39dUxJUXJplp3+nfIouX55BMMgKZI4IqaYicHPp9giMCGxPfy12IBIMNSn5Jz6NocdPVSzT65ccbSM+pnzX3AKEOwaja5AWJ61DnfmWhZuoq49Cv7Q8g+1Bw8kcdQ4t85KtKNleiH4Ej4lAODz3SfCLR3UVKYud2tsAOg4rA5v8yZsCDa+vPwlPHvsp4CcUhcsJI/ZkO/m70a8Tw9XdH0bh1I5PfVZRTiLmihLgEa68rz3n1s1cImWyk//RFBkcN/doB6xdjl/CEkLcRkEnO1pQRCzpt7TRaGfLS9wyjr5hUrfX9rboNjuz51rgncA1VtkmaVXmARlpV/vtkN1QVvbmAAlXjjjiqPhXbPdJrw/4/ujOvxrPlt87E1KFWJI1nLFowSYfPFMWJ83vrbD6NFPJFjVyDvMtI8/SnxKZOHnQIm5qQ/8JvtJ6ZLUqLJuMo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050121", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd/tPH/ZEGpRoHCPXa19cX2jQq7Hea3xz9dYKViAjFVosnfV47Xx5EAGma0b6ICbMCACfYB4ycKNl/fy1mdEN4ZFicBzpJgeb/1TjDuiZpTRNe16x2iZLkv3JxuvDWR9hzmWiXNap42y9Cv7Rs87xSk8qolK6MkvM9nFmYqB4VmxlQ7C33SdR7NtEFiQptq7q1OZsoE9vNuItXLy+vDwm/aT88sHdh1AusZ+cBuvgrgM6iM3Q4i1ZhYL/+HVZV3jJ2izNQEJ/Mj333tnhoQ7UmR0+wpSkYpSZ4B62J7oqTc+PMh5V/9R0wc43Jnyw111AC/2Zmc=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjJ1721ktgw/yfEcV3+ayWaI=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5Ihyrn1Jv+2XO46b/+1wBhqlXqZiWdTVDcY0v4d6N3uX51zFAIIZUm5Nh7YwaPPVOyH2vddfQN/98yi6ELkGwdDyvEnU0lSKWizxUqZCy5me9W8h3ygAhgo5+9MEyO5e9y6GH4V6wxgWN0HSfQbxoUUaMucvow0yLpZQ9p4HNpTretOb8m+vc/p4bcAdEtoJ6Zxu1hOgH9z54RcCxKBFE4/bVYkCtJTCzKw8T+N/q2Xop5JAgSWAn/F9FjY9ZbMly2pH3qCFwL8h4FjaztUFEh71yWx6Xev27xWTw9Uc6NXs4JYNjuignqACOZBRwlX/cXzlBkZJi8cJV1QVteS9CmXrphymOhCWGaNPt7oX4gOywqbRz4KwxLEyFO0iYQ4MYYKGABXV73uCIBeZVPZlrAifoPtBsrIFjYTEE3vZr0YInkoU0uQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050122", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdzsPWTbAmxRqnGQUbF9YGXqW6nRLv3swJpwNVWFlBt9/XXTsOX/+RMKjKdV5oOWc2IXbIph29GKw+34ymIBMshA2pRg5Z4aPPBV3jSjc5T6M/ZhxW/HNAXiYjC6Ckx6qD/kj31Fp43htQaoXNU8wVUgg4t96Yg6M8Xf2OiA4EKqkkaS2WmYR7kkHlLZocel7g/coYw89cWEonLS+uf6iPHD5NcEbBsSsod2bVel16wG+z81VMagKBpC4qTRZVnkLiGwMxwc7cL10zR7w4QmT2Qntt1JjWH6D0FTfHMj3EPpeQo=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6eSvSFnZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufLfa34yJtiIh6GB1b7ea+qyNYC6T5cLpBo", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBjlRt3eGEoJneH7oVamCZ+PtyoV4N0iAglVosnLJ46v/4xMfnaFW6JyWfDtDeIRs3cPJ2Oq3wXJOPclJk4My8IgecudBzymke9rIYP9gyi6UNUT0YnmUCmNgkTDSxjxCoIaitSq6XdQ72VUxmYlu6NF8HcSX1qOSr174lAOO1XyYR6h3UVWXsY6l5FGdrMI1sN6esDXe57TNkv2T4tsKcQdc/49sI129m7sMo2oZQsC7YxML4/HcZFCtJiexZw9d9cTt0TR5w5AgUm10+xkGlopbZ4wz15bg/Do5LI1jGyC5sU1Q051zUQTWd7Ku1Xqk4RUofH4uJZhssiow4QCaaEBximKfX2ARnY5o8sUdnApkPX1FkH/nizCekyWOcpej6oTxjOb5s61x87cuP0TAOF3MQogOdvHXX7+u7ckzc5Bj0z7+2M5r", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050123", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0An65YohURayzO6/Jn7XBGcCt3qHErd7MHLsWbfQa+X7x5MxNFOKhFp3snPQrKnl41oAgehS586efiEKe4V7iPmH0+32mzP+P7pS+lXB7x5lRAaqY+VU", 
		"answer": "252xe4X8wxDp9olgUwzxzfz6OmffBHtTk+oMui2HXmXnrAxGgJ81xw==", 
		"explanation": "27C1eJnywhDw8pZgRxD2wO/sIWreB2sfpD+QXaB9cX2jUbHNYvjqwJh/Z0iBn1Ru9X6Gq6zj41wdhqta5c6eYiELf45gxN+Ozqi3x35PIM9An5J76p1fbOZFxDS+YNvJKf0uz2CEZ1XiaC2yDHlngD7Eg38Wu4qv8DT5C4De3rXm0bBj81QVoSurXQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Historical archaeology", 
		"option_b": "Textual archaeology", 
		"option_c": "Religious archaeology", 
		"option_d": "Urban archaeology", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050124", 
		"question": "26KwcdH6wlnp+IszRgznxun2O2yQAmwSqnqNRuNdfnXqVamCZuTt3ZhjPhyagld+/m+Gpbf/+hMDhrxe+4+NaWIQcZ59y9Wal+j+yXhVNsIb2Hx90l2hi3bh0Xba6asj/vo=", 
		"answer": "25y2aZX2wAzr44BgURH81vT7MHnRF2serT+MVON1YnLrVaLNYuL5wJRwKxyMm1J/93jFpudkB310XxlkpVuf7nYkJ5TZ", 
		"explanation": "272xb5n/2B7i45ZgRhb3hfP6MG+QF21RoHCOUKp6dTHvXbPHfOzs0NdiKEmbjl5osmHPt62w9kEMh6le5oKQdysAf4cvzcaA0+H5x3QDOe5g/ssS6gvCrJZff+KClw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Lack of detailed information", 
		"option_b": "Overemphasis on coins and inscriptions", 
		"option_c": "Bias towards foreign texts", 
		"option_d": "Inadequate consideration of archaeological evidence", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050125", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQEW0dpj+MVON3f3jtR+fLYK3t3YJ1PlWHiht6/HXPpqvkt3oBi6Fa586XeTEXcZl2l5KzK33Bg8kKilxeRaQlnmEC", 
		"answer": "24e9bp320g3j+YJgQRHxzPzzdWreByIUoHCNXa59czH3RqLMav68ER0sMowL8Px9YRtJVbUHag==", 
		"explanation": "27u3fJTgkRrl/oszFV7hzPrxPG3ZAGMfoHrDW600ZX/nUbXReuzwzZ5/IBydn1p/9zqGtrfy9l1Pg6Fd7MLfcSwHPphgy9mMw/21o8sKzynZLmY44lcaxm5VqQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Providing accurate chronological data", 
		"option_b": "Confirming details from ancient texts", 
		"option_c": "Validating religious narratives", 
		"option_d": "Reflecting social and economic trends", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050126", 
		"question": "24KwcdHg2Rb/+4FgRhb3hfT7MGrDQ20X436NEqZkeXKjVaDHLu//2pJ1Z1OHzU9z9zb0oqjx7lIBjuha54rfZCoGPqZuwNGL3+XlxWVAc8RB2oR795kebvBFyGLvI16jHVIyd54F1ZBz0hr8Tw==", 
		"answer": "25m5a5qz3h+q9pcjWh/3yvHwMmLTAm5RpmmKVqZ6c3ShYH5xqK0oGoqstRq7NmuNng==", 
		"explanation": "26GwbdHywxri9oAvXhH1zP7+OSvVFWsVpnGAV+N3f3/3RqbGZ+7q2tdlL1nJiEty8TbHpKCw9FwBjK1L/cxp9cijcrhuvt1EvsSOblUE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Lack of archaeological evidence", 
		"option_b": "Inaccurate depiction of social evolution", 
		"option_c": "Conflicting family tree information", 
		"option_d": "Overemphasis on historical inscriptions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050127", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hjkt4wuQR3gzO3rPGTeECIDpmmGU680cXPsQbOCb+P9wJJ/Mxygg19y83iGq6zj41wdlvcZKfmnj1MJuWmbWXFig7qT8A==", 
		"answer": "25G9fpT/3gnn8os0EhH0he3wOWLEGi5RsHCAW6ZgaT2jUaTNYOLz0NsxJlKNzUl+/n/Bqqr+tWlquh7QeYM7W1il6b18f18=", 
		"explanation": "25y2e5Lh2An+/oouQV7i1/LpPG/VQ2sfsHaEWrdnMHjtQKiCeOzswJhkNByInkt+8WLV46r2t1sGnLxU+5ffcicacYVriMCG2+3jzXJSc8dKnsBg4ZYWe/1Pwn8zsdB9x3QmIzB3OsnkgyAC", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Political alliances", 
		"option_b": "Religious rituals", 
		"option_c": "Social hierarchies", 
		"option_d": "Development of polity, society, economy, and religion", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050128", 
		"question": "24KwcdHywxyqx4QuWxD7hfzxMSvgAnYQrXWCXqozYzHkRqbPY+zqwJRwKxyegklw4TbPrrX/5UcOgbwb4IDfeCsQaoR9wdOI26TlwWJEMtRHkt8wgnMYgG4AQ6VLyxZ5ZIUJww==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz0Avvt4MyVxuyw+/wOCvdGnYZsD+CXKc0fHTkUanGfa/janXCbGm3v9yi0o/dX1PM", 
		"explanation": "26GwbZjhkR/j74AkEhrz0fjsdWreByIDpnOKU6F9fHj3TefBYeDuyIV0Ixydght262LO7qnx81YBz7xe8ZqMMisuAEDT0ZBJ0U8gwo6jpCc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They provide accurate dates for historical events", 
		"option_b": "They contain detailed descriptions of ancient urban life", 
		"option_c": "They are free from myths and legends", 
		"option_d": "They support the narratives of the Puranas", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050129", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1A/j84AuURuyzO6/OGTCBiIDpnOKU6F4dTH3XKbMLt3r25Z/Ll/JmUl69n/Sqqr+5BMJgLob4YeMZC0Rd4huxJCP1ufj1y4DXk0QUiiI2NmIMnlKDA/xZA==", 
		"answer": "25a3YZ/gkRjk88UpXA3x1/TvIWLfDXFTl7cdoNDaAGjeNguGHCZpNQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYWz2Bf59JcpQgr7yvPsdWrCBiIcrG2GErFxfHjiVqvHLuvx29d5Lk+dgkly8XfK46z+8VwdgqlP4IGRMt8e5dcLiuBS4CSv7WnEgA8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Literary texts", 
		"option_b": "Mythological narratives", 
		"option_c": "Coins and inscriptions", 
		"option_d": "Linguistic analysis", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050130", 
		"question": "2523f9Hywxyq8pUpVQzz1fX2NivcAmwV43iRU61gYzH2R6LGLuvx29d5Lk+dgkly8XfK47f19FwBnLxJ/I2LeS0NIckwpfPSLFfenDhQErpe8vGq", 
		"answer": "24G3KIT91Rz45JEhXBqy1vL8PG7EAm5RoHeCXKRxYzHiWqOCfOTtzNd+IRyHiEw74WLHt6DjtTfHjexl0wzDKnGXA5poByU=", 
		"explanation": "25CoYZbh0Ani/oZgVQzzy+nsdXvCDHQYp3rDW61neXbrQLSCZ+PqxtdiKF+AjFc78X7HraL15BMOgawb54uIMDEXf59qiNaGxen20HhOPdUGcg8fjFuh1813SvW9AtaG2A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To establish family trees of rulers", 
		"option_b": "To determine the extent of conquests", 
		"option_c": "To understand societal changes and rise of new states", 
		"option_d": "To validate religious practices", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050131", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEh/7yL3wMyvRQ2Eerm+CQKJgeWfmFLHLa/q+xpExJlKKhF515jbVrKb58kcGirsEqyWiE/hAYg3RS5qNIg+K1Wo=", 
		"answer": "25y8bZ/n2B/zt5EyVxD21r3sPWrCBmZRtHaXWuN7ZHnmRufDYO73zJllZ0+GjlJ+5n/DsOdBPIKobxtMPvDiYWsghfgY", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZYHywxD5+ItgQBvkwPzzJivDC2MDpnvDRrFxfnXwFKbPYeP5iZZ/JFWMg0874XnFqqDk/lYczY/KX3jx6e/uPo94lhqcVIk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Highlight unique aspects of ancient India", 
		"option_b": "Disregard developments in other countries", 
		"option_c": "Emphasize the role of mythologies", 
		"option_d": "Identify trends shared with other ancient societies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050132", 
		"question": "2523f9Hw0Beq/5AtUxCywvjxMH/ZACIDpmyGU7F3eDHgW6nWfOT83IN0Z0iGzU519nPUsLHx+VcGga8b6ICceScNastGxtSA1uq3zHhSJ8lWg98wpPF8XxO1mPFdy0N7b6TqJA==", 
		"answer": "24WqZ4f61Ryq/oszWxn60e6/PGXEDCIUt3eNW6A0fXj7QLLQa63/x5MxJEmFmU5p83qGp6zj5FYChqZa/YeQfmBTLWBQnGZWdeToa2NY2XdP", 
		"explanation": "25K9ZpTn2Bqq5YAzVx/gxvW/J27GBmMdsD+GRqt6eXKjWa7aevjszNdwKVjJjk535mPUoqmw81ocnK1W4ICeZCsMcMmc8Sp6xBaYbHelb66sv/Gd", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Determine exact dates of ancient events", 
		"option_b": "Explain the origins of mythological figures", 
		"option_c": "Provide insights into ethnic mixture and cultural dissemination", 
		"option_d": "Confirm the accuracy of family trees in Puranas", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050133", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Rzut5EvEhb71unwJ2LTAm5RpnGRW6B8fXTtQOfGa/7uwIN0Z1WHjlR14X/Vt6D+9FoKnOhZ7JqIdScNPo1mxtSA2ePkhHBPN4ZQn5hm98VdnoNqwBk9J1EHkMl73jmQ6g==", 
		"answer": "25itZIX6wRXvt4AkWwr7yvPsdWTWQ2MfoHaGXLc0ZHT7QLSABIP9oyuQw5rR/oMRkJOwTA==", 
		"explanation": "25itZIX6wRXvt4AkWwr7yvPsdWTWQ3YUu2uQEqZ6YnjgXKLGLuX32oN+NVWKjFc7+3jArLf99kcGgKYb7YuMYCsXe8trwcOKxeHnxX9COsNX2pd78JJfev1OyDSjc8eZ2WGsY9zjjBAQ1JWwBfM+ow==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Foreign textual references", 
		"option_b": "Multiple editions of ancient texts", 
		"option_c": "Extensive explorations in urban areas", 
		"option_d": "Overemphasis on brahmanical sites", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRj49I0hVxH+yvr2NmrcQ2EEr2uWQKY0eWKjR67FYOT4wJRwKUjJi1RpsmPIp6Di5EcOgaxS54nfZCoGPopozZCG0aTjzHQBAc9D2rZ34JtAPtz6yAuVxzZXA6BVQABUNcA=", 
		"answer": "25K5ZpX70Avrt4IyUwj3hf7qOX/FEWdTClJFOd/hC1x5X5kGlXWOJQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU0Bfu/4QyU1711/zpMCvTFm4Ftm2GEqpnMGPmWKLUb+PqiZF+NRydhV47wH/B45P181JInOha7ovdyTBnhNtemDPvrTl538J4hA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Harappan civilization", 
		"option_b": "Gandhara grave culture", 
		"option_c": "Megalithic culture", 
		"option_d": "Northern Black Polished Ware culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050135", 
		"question": "24KwcdHg2Rb/+4FgWxr3xO6/Om2QAmxRpm+KUeN1d3SjVqbRa+m+xpkxM1SMzWl6/3ffoqvxt1EKz6xS+o2eYiYGetQt4XHwbw7bVzpY0G9D4MiqRQ==", 
		"answer": "25u3Ztzy3RDt+YglXAqy0vTrPSvbDW0GrT+LW7Bgf2PqV6bOLv37255+I0/LNkOGcTsv7eDFyKzavnes8Q==", 
		"explanation": "25Sqa5ny1Bbm+IIpUR/+hfv2O2/ZDWUC43yMXLdmcXXqV7OCeuX7iZ51Il3Jgl0783iGprX59BMOiK0b64+MdSZDcYUv3NiMl9b2yXBYMshF2GfG5fnLmgdkSDj5VDno2Nk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Lack of historical inscriptions", 
		"option_b": "Absence of literary evidence", 
		"option_c": "Inconclusive archaeological findings", 
		"option_d": "Non-alignment with known historical periods", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050136", 
		"question": "24KwcdHywxyqx4QuWxD7hfzxMSvgAnYQrXWCXqozYzHkRqbPY+zqwJRwKxyegklw4TbPrrX/5UcOgbwb74GNMCoKbZ9g2snWlZ7QgAgFoXfUsm9TH0jIr4I=", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz0Avvt4MyVxuyw+/wOCvdGnYZsD+CXKc0fHTkUanGfa/janXCbGm3v9yi0o/dX1PM", 
		"explanation": "24GwbZjhkR/j74AkEhrz0fjsdWreByIDpnOKU6F9fHj3TefPb+b7iYN5IlHJhFZr/WTSoqvkt1UAnehT4J2LfzAaPMnfPvrGWNQYM1/cdaTRlfU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Detailed descriptions of ancient rituals", 
		"option_b": "Accuracy in dating ancient texts", 
		"option_c": "They are free from myths and legends", 
		"option_d": "They support the narratives of the Puranas", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUhEh39yO3+J2rECnQU42mKV7Q0f3ejVanBZ+jw3ddiKF+AiE9y92WGoqb4/lYZivcZF35T3uBDznOXAaKf6vPyNg==", 
		"answer": "25y8bZ/n2B/zt5EyVxD21r3sPWrCBmZRtHaXWuN7ZHnmRufDYO73zJllZ0+GjlJ+5n/DsOdBPIKobxtMPvDiYWsghfgY", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZYHywxD5+ItgWhf1zfH2MmPEECIFsXqNVrA0Y3niRqLGLuzzxpl2Z12HjlJ+/GKGsKrz/lYbhq1Iq5BHY+vz9TxI8KKZCvcAC68=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Highlight unique aspects of ancient India", 
		"option_b": "Disregard developments in other countries", 
		"option_c": "Emphasize the role of mythologies", 
		"option_d": "Identify trends shared with other ancient societies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050138", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSHNhfL5dWjVEXYQqnHDQapgdWKjXamCfOjyyIN4KFLJmVQ74HPKqqL5+EYcz6BS+pqQYjtDbYNg3dyNl+X7134BMsVHlZV88NoZc+YA3zKufdXXYP9gyi6FJEr+aDS0BzBylTLChW5F6vL5+xDvf5Blhg3jE5QjAWc=", 
		"answer": "26axb5/61xDp9osjV1z8BOmY8CVEuJexJkA5GIZH", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63Anl5ZEhXB33hfL5dXnVD2sWqnCWQeNneWXmR+fRZuLrxZMxJVnJmFV/92TVt6r/8xMYhrxT4IDfZCoGPohgxsSMz/C3y3cBIMlHk4F+pJsReLRFzzKje9nSI75qy3iFK0rgajyzEGM2EXZaXPmzaThf0WRsKqm+jQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "si,gn,if,ic,an,ce", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050139", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSHNhfjtNCvYAnFRoXqGXONkYnjuVbXLYvS+yph/NEibmFhv93KGoaTj8ldPgKYb5YeLdTACbJIv29+cxefy1z0BMclQksB064gadfNOjDyjcJTSLvpnyWuOKFDjJYpkWLJYhlDN3C4D7RhH40M=", 
		"answer": "27S2a5j23w2q/4wzRhHgzP7+OSmqoNkTy1d4xJCj56ELsfuh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Ehb71unwJ2LTAm5Rpm2CFbA0YnTgW6nRev/ryoN4KFLJn153+3PV46319kUGg7Eb5oDffCsXe5lu2snJxOvi1nJEIIQ1q/s1eKTtEeOtdRw1mBd0", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "an,ci,en,t hi,st,or,ic,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050140", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg2B7k/oMpUR/8xvi/Om2QBmMDr2bDbZxLT07ca5j9Ua3twIN0NByBjEg78HPDreX4/lQHg6Fc4ZqadG5De4Z/wNGa3v7+ynYBJ85B2o534Z5faPsAzzKjetHYNL58y2KJIEz/cir9DHlngD7EkzxBoZeztSWpW9szxQdygpV948wvfj1M9PLNiV7r2wcyK382bcQ=", 
		"answer": "25etbJX72Ar+tQ6XUA66HO2C7YVe0daM8PE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63Anl5ZEhXB33hfL5dUnFB2YZqmyXErB9ZHTwFKbMaq3qwZJ4NRybiFd+5HfIoKCw41xPmqZf7JyMZCMNeoJhz5Cb0uj+w3hOJtUEkolh8JUNZbRJwn2sNNjaMvlr3C6DKEvkYiGpRg/Ezx2pKd4YQSlZMm/fKEU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bu,dd,hi,st", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050141", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh1BXj9ocpXhfm3L3wMyvZDXESsXaTRqp7fmKjXbSCeOzy3JJ1Z1iMnkty5nOGrKbz9kAGgKZa5c6gTx08QbRQ9++2m6T21zFVO8Nd2pBg64wWePEAwTK/cZTaI/173G+UIgX4biqpC2J9lzDaynVYroyp+CavXdU5gAE6l4k47s0uKNaW1+iH+ky8jxKL03WCCrY2e5OonESUliFUbeVJ1aQ=", 
		"answer": "27CgaZb01Avr44wvXA2wBAer0hPzwIIEh52CDcmW6g==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63wrp5YwwRhf9y+6/OGrJQ2EerWuCW600dWniU6DHfOzqwJh/NByLmE8782TD47bk/l8Dz6VU+4vfdCcTe4VrydKF0qTjzHBPc8VBiJRz7ZRfaOZByDS5fdvVIfIuwG+SNUTkbi+4FzI4htP1Rq0pixZWIzW2VoyK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "ex,ag,ge,ra,ti,on,s", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050142", 
		"question": "25a3YZ/gnVnj+ZYjQBfi0fTwO3icQ2Mfpz+CQKB8cXTsWKjFZ+7/xdd3LlKNhFV84TbVprfm8hMOnOhW5pyaMDEWfJh7yd6d3uX7hHRXOsJBlIN3pI4XffoA2DWoNOvkH8FR8VG/GHqwbjf9BX53nTTYnjxCrZuv5mX7J8S6uGcW0DNrU8VTX+RX", 
		"answer": "27ihfJn83Rbt/oAzEPQnptKswO2suzHdEzlE20A=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hDk5MlgWxDhxu/2JX/ZDGwC7z+CXKc0cWPgXKbHYeHxzp5yJlDJi1J19n/IpLaw9kEKz6VU+4vfYicPd4ptxNXJw+z2yjFVO8MEl5lm7JUTc/NJzzyhNNHXJfNrwHqTZ0P/cje5RHl61DDYiXVTppf74SKjQMl1f4vrqRLRd7Q9+9i9LmmNBg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "my,th,ol,og,ie,s", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050143", 
		"question": "24GwbdHnwxju/pEpXRC/x/zsMG+QB2MFpmzDXaU0c3TxQKbLYK32wIRlKE6Ajlp3snDPpLDi8kBPg6FQ7M6pcTAHdopiyd6Il8n2zHBXOtRF2oF84No4feFUzTCsNPbOJPpmzy6OIkD0Jyu4B396hzjSj25XvIq0+2e/Qd931Bpyko5r7to5LNaR2qGW+w2vjxKKnESud4JbLmumivHo7lWVpIc2tsjPZxzB6K+Wkhv51Zmp0tViQQ==", 
		"answer": "27Sqa5ny1Bbm+IIpUR/+h7dn5kOMX0gpX2nH4X3GuSA=", 
		"explanation": "25Sqa5ny1Bbm+IIpUR/+hfjpPG/VDWEU43aQErd8dTHzXL7RZ+7/xddjIlGIhFVosnnA47H48hMfjrtPpc6MZSELPop8iNKG2eHkiDFVPMlIicwy5ZQbPPZVxTGpfdrcM75H2i6DJkuwZTz9EWNxkHHChTxSqZe+tS+yR8440hwxl4s46N45MsOMmamd7A2+jwGXzn6CdLNQGVHZodyp70qIqY02tMHNtTPP8ee5nPfBsOgKcAxavot+bVr8uqkB+TwxQ8n0aRxPscPRdEDsLSnjBRsZ/cPilnV7w8IrXHox8F9JjMNCasUzwYrtqDs+ON4qGjX6t0xFzoY8WRiaeLKv1Xr3rBUrfX9rT4tksj51oAGYaHZrnm+URT9Fh8Bf9tUKkER0b2ZUlXjnkX+KkmDPcpz3q4Hwkunps/lx968uKEOMMBCYV4MYJafIIn4yyeiVTaRZc5ZpFC3oLtw96Dz3NNaD1i0FkNwhLH+n+z6Rl9+3R/wlKwOvh3ox6oDiSidc4A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ar,ch,ae,ol,og,ic,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050144", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfbfCx6t/dhy8nl47/XCGorfz/1IKgKRU7oeccS5De51mzNWH1OG30H4BIcNNlJR39ooNeeAAzTOufdHVNL5HwGqJJkuwbzCuEH9mjXGbyjwWicOJ8CaoR98k0xw8kcds/8k4NcOW1qaS5A2wjxWW02mYS7xoUVqYp9yp/0qKpZEEu5/NlTfL/fftk/fdsNENIiFcu49+bRu/gqQd7Tg9EcmnKBtF9+HCaFv/YCmtI04U94vt03Ftho0vHXsx8hBUj8MbIoAzltik/HJwf40qVXOY425V1IB1WR6Vdamx32ak5lotNXkkaYVjtSw54QaSPFFsjG6SWCVemrxlrZA7hw13dHxI3GbvkCuZgXyOcNPi+MDxiuz1srdq6KY1OgGBO1iYU4kJZrLUKHVhiuadTY9SN5ZmGTGmcJVuvHm5YNbUn3lNkJlgbzentGq60vj7PWCovpv3h9pxVLEBItjT7Iu0pVDTdDHgLT2QacXyUAz1QX/97wAx9yg3zTIV5nbRBo4/3CMJl3++CVB2kyPpeHWumK0c65HOd4c/1+ft0zEVi7RskNvnxhI7VQGonj8O8sTfDxwPjRSWXo1HhEluTPRBVNaRsi3W1VKQfX0Bdsr3FaGJxGxqyOrlh3J1/5MBWYOAJRjXyswzxBLzQHuOmyBgnGClHZ8bt0ewOA==", 
		"answer": "2+T1St2zg1TJu8VzHzq+hamyFCmCgWs4DmTa4x9QWOFcQbhl", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHmwhyq+INgUwzxzfz6OmffBGsSonPDV7V9dHTtV6KCeuK+25J4KUiMn0tp92KGoqvz/lYBm+hy54qWcSxDdoJ83N+bzqT0zHBNP8NKnYV2pI4NffBJ2DSietXXYPBv3HyBM0zmYir9BX5w1DDahnNBrYf78yipFNt3zRogk8d57sspLtaL3OiG5km9lBWW3XWVQbNjUVuf9dqg7gOMoZEsicOptCLS9+DwlP+T2dAPawlc/4Vqb0+pha1J+Tl4WMaybQBC/vaQYFrpYCGtZwAY/M+j2XIp1IcvUns5tB5Pj4ZSItR8lo3quDciMsRkEHO0olBJ0ZE8XAKaYKiq0WSk41oxc3MvYIRuuWF1rA6XIVp52mKIDClQh4lu7JAfmhYjaWdF3FTyiyuCk23PaJyj7pPohOr8qaprsrcvLEiSdV/NWpkJd7LMZ2N9x+CVDKhfNqNpJy30Kccv5TD3J9aA1zxN8sspO370/GqYgY34NmG/oZzwlNFkB/8BONWF7M+is13TbjHyYXKVJuL6XQHxQW+4wAt3oR0hiDUfqHTZBIB79DkI3lyiQFBtgS+gb3OtmbBV647ObZs91rXuxHIAl+dxi5L42hQyQESvhXpO8oWMD15Kw1HAEcECyh1uDbMEGoLCsmKQ1WbCRHsfet3lPaa30Slb3+3lh296/7kAUYWPIlnPmN8iwQO4DvNqFWb+6I7wM/gHC2ov/6Ex3uLhp9i0cuGhP3ZqZQ+kTeZf+pBVKCBpGB/UFiwPaba6U48IRO5b23rE1xNHB21MFlLN661IdAquo8XGLnnRYLgZGgeiYrAGHNz8R0nIdeWmiBLbD6uVhk/+VkAgTzaObfAY6RP5d43mIR+q02Jx6tXsNEhSSoRXKC/2fXn5pqyPBAgzfiBlOp9LfwVj3I7b89XY9PvA1KOxOwPH", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-D, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"option_b": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_c": "1-B, 2-C, 3-D, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-D, 2-A, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050145", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfbe8z4yGH3hQGJtixvGARq3utA==", 
		"answer": "25qubYP23Ani9pYpQV79y73zPH/VEWMDuj+XV7tgYzHlW7WCfOj9xpliM06cjk9y/HGGoqvz/lYBm+hT4J2LfzAaPsYv5NmE3vDywDFAPcIEmIlz958bPORF3i69cdfPKehrgi61NECwaD/9B399miKWi3JS6Iq15iSpXcojyRo8hcds4ogpMtOay7uH6UO8xgeM33KURqkkAluavMu84kaP4M94kMOFsDzY8fC5iP3f+d8JawRbq58/YlW416wA7i8qQs30YRxY+OPYdUehYAyqNAMU6tji2jRmwMIgU3o35hZWlopZbNMz0o3h/CY/f91vBzC/qlJFw9RwXhSdNLK+kGDt80EwZ3MoZIYtqiw5tArcZRRQn2yQSS9FnY5svsYYmRFif2NF3GXvgTaEzWCMc53s5on/xeH+s7Bk+rc0ZQGtLEjQWYETYrrDJmsyxOiJH6dIOoliBGL1NdQ+9Tf+YIWb3DAIxNgsb3no5ieK0sz7PSWssp7si8c2Wf8zI8HV5tmj8FrIc2PiNHGHc9n1VUjxQXi4wAFmvhkpiC8f+m/LSg6bVRkwucgdZEtvRRlXvxw=", 
		"explanation": "25qubYP23Ani9pYpQV79y73zPH/VEWMDuj+XV7tgYzHgVamCYuj/zddlKByIzVdy/3/SpqGw9l0Lz6pS6J2adGITe5l82NWKw+3hwTFONYZFlIN74ZQLPPxJ3ymiZs2XYP99jmKJM0DiZiukRGRxjCXFyn1ErcO08zO+Wpog0hwmgoJ2rcolfNKT0LyW+w25iALC0XqICLNrBRSLsMik7kCI4JYwsI2IqSLe5v38lPvW454EZEhdrYJ2bVqujugZ/SUoXc2IZiZD9KTFclGtLy7jJAEU99ij13pthosnTmom/Q9Si4xYcYBw15akrCA/KcRuEHO/rUxByZd5W1eEcbGx0Wrt7FwrbDoqa44tuCQjpB2PLRR3lHiVSyRFh8Bi8MQW1QVtfmZFkmKgkTCIiWCbdZbwp8D9lqjkqLx6sqI1LAGMME/LFoEVbrbMPidmxamZCOZeOp50EiamMsdu+DDqNJmGyzwJkNguKzfk9STZgt/6L2y+ttLwgNJ5BrIBItjK54u2slPSdWPgYWqaYs7mGRrxQXv9kwFj9wwq2CgT+17WLIBs+CQejXe+TgRtnDTjfnWxgrdT5JHOe5s0k+HjnSYYnf1q34vyxh45ThK+iT9Ps4eUD1NJjVzfDdkI1gAtDbhBApfd52jWlnfeC3AIfsq2FafHzSlP1ubymmhzuNAYVICbLRvXj541xxS4DrB8Vmjjp4vwPrwcBHcl/bpl2aHhttn7fP23L3cjfw6+VuFKs5ZQZkJrAwTLDCBKILGgUJIMTOFb23rE1wZKSGpdRU7E/ugNXgukpcnRIirNbLIVCwr7L/MEHcq4TVLDIeS7zXDGAP+dm0S3WkoxDimSIrkI8Q71abD8CQqnm2do9sbsMVBXBI0WLjXyYGKvoLDDCAc0Pz8tKZpCOlTaSBkhgD/PZ/don6oTMBkjReixGFwDkwID3z/BTkxNtVVeXKSjAFAoJL9AORsFxTL1E6UTVRnMlXoLgFLc1S3+Jf5dOEw0aCSciQz0k5cmj/rmkoKESsPqIv0YwIgCPLNfBI7eGlZegl7Yn+fc3pXPME7TjaHYXQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Overemphasis on literary texts for reconstructing ancient history,Limited and biased perspective", 
		"option_b": "Use of coins and inscriptions to understand ancient societies, Enhanced reliability and diverse insights", 
		"option_c": "Dismissal of inscriptions due to perceived lack of historical value,Neglecting valuable socio-economic insights", 
		"option_d": "Mythological narratives shaping societal norms and values,Support for cultural and social norms", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050146", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDXRDm1/T9IH/ZDGwC7FyMXLBxYWTmWqTHfbe8z4yGH3hQGJtixvGARq3utA==", 
		"answer": "24W3eoXh0ADj+YJgUxDxzPjxISv5DWYYonGQEqJnMGHiR7TLeOi+yJl1Z16IjlBs82TCsOW9t3kanLxS74eccTYKcYUvzt+bl8blzWVIIM4EmY9+65QWffgA3iihcZibBPt+x22ULkv3JxCzAHl1mnHVn3BCvZG+tSaoFNM5xhAgn4hqrckyOJeW1+id7Ui8xgmEnHKcWK9rB1GUsMC8qw7clYw8sN+AuDzS+vO5lPnH+cgOIhtXs4AyYFSykaEN/SQ7VISEehdY9OrEaFrqYAqxLhoU6sOj12cpy40tWHs6/QVDkJAWY853lp3gqTExK8J4BnO1pQRpyZB1XhmFNPD44m3t7lMwZ3kia40tvyI5rgGVKVg+m36IRCNDnZRysvkXgQFxbX1FiH/uhX+ijmGGfZ2j/5L9geHkqbZt4eMmOgGPN0/MV44QYKCAM2gy2vuUCrRZIIwnWmLQPNkn+DjtKZmanzYLkPsyJmPu5yLZkcL5NmuzqZPth9t4VhTecs/MjLcfMbM7+NfanEA=", 
		"explanation": "24W3eoXh0ADj+YJgUxDxzPjxISv5DWYYonGQEqJnMGHiR7TLeOi+yJl1Z16IjlBs82TCsOXj4kMfgLpP7IrfZCoGPoF628SA0e30xWVIPMgEnI9gpLgNdeBJ3zXtd9vXL/Bnz2LANVD8Ynm/HTBwkSHfiWhfpoT73Cm/Xds501Uzhcdx44gyOdKbmaeVqEigkgOQ0nqdCLprB1GLu8+m6EagrqY9pcSOpTvV87TQlPza8dBLYR1eq5NtZhu9hOgA9iw9Q8G7elJK/+CQaFqtLi2mI04S/4vq22R7yZQsUGw64F9Hi45TZoBn2djxsjY1LcBjGzb6rUVUzoJ5HwSTeLv102fq5lw7cHQoYMpssil1tw6QIVB/jm7cbj5YgIl49pAagAh3aH1BkDbkjTKCjmSBf5bf5bDugPv1rq1q/KRnC1OJIVXLXs0ddvPNKGN32OeSF6NOIN9mGSamONE7/zjtL4SHnzYLkPAuK37m+jnZgdjlKWqop5f9zsB+Ef8JMtTEqcSx8H7VaDfoMnXTZcT4Vgb5TnC4wRtpslgk22ERqGHRHoBz/DcEkHnwRE13gS7vYkCvv7BI75CebYsl2vvrnRsenP15kdvjxhw4ThCygnFQ8oWMD1NN3kDXHcEC10k6A/QRBpnW4GiFhjbGSnAEe8/iBKzH4T5BzurihiF+sJwBW4WULQ3ShdBmyg7xB+94WG7jr8btNfkcGCQp/LR+2Pmy9960NeGhP20rfx/3cOFd+pRfKBF0EgLYET0PYavuV90QRONKwWbDgx4IQXBbRVvI7akGXgGnr8rcLGxTTl0ircNWNkFjySYZepk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Portraying ancient Indians as passive and backwards,Justification for British colonial rule", 
		"option_b": "Depicting Indian culture as inferior and in need of improvement,Undermining native self-confidence", 
		"option_c": "Presenting British as modernizers and educators of Indians,Reinforcing colonial authority", 
		"option_d": "Interpreting Indian traditions as obstacles to progress,Validation of British colonization", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050147", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVR42yXU7dxfXTtQLSCfOj5yIV1LlKOzU9z9zbPrbH15UMdirxa/YeQfmIMeMtnwcOd2Pb+x3BNc9VLj5Jx4YlfdfoAzTOufdHVNL5HwGqJJkuwbzCuEH9mjXHfmTxVp5Gp8CSvDuY5/Btj1rNw6IgpL9Lf1q7T6V+7jgeH03eeT7RnEFjZsNih70aSo4d4vcye8SDe5/z4iv3XsMoZYwxbq49wbVqw16AA6z43Q8G3aR4L/+XCc1X5KT6mNE4f4IvzxHt/z4YgU250+hpRwopYccl03oz3/Ds+K8IqFD25qkFO09RVUROfdbP4w2fn6VArfH84WYRRsn91hQqMIVdqk2SSDCNX1Kll+tkYm0RgaGNUiWTlwj6YwGyBepbx4o/uxen+pPlq/OMpLESEdVPeFp8ZY7zSKidxxeePH69eJotiE2LyMpU69Dy5M4KG2jcKxNElIX7p82qWlI37OHGzpZe5jcF6AKoSN92F+dm+tFmHYC3lYXSXY8XgUBzpc3LE3V0lhwog2yQe/GvWD8lr/ShNvGy5XU13mmfhfzysmbpZ+IyHZYsjwLXt0zZQnfBtnJrj2w8vBwu9zVZNto2eQU8P2lXFXswOyQwqTLUVVJXZ82GakHjXQnIKP9r+BOiRwiBB3urllyFyudAsR4WaJQrTyt0pxBi/CPx1FXX4pIO5PPIRSm046fJ4x/2gtN6oNfyqbEwkaxO2V69K/JZYbRZiU2/Oc0cUGLgM+tW+mdqo7wE=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzH3RrLHLtn2zNdkNFnJgl0782TFq6T1+F8AiKFY6ILfdTQKeo5hy9XJ3+XkhHhPN8NBnsB+4Z5faPsAzX2/cdHNIfJ7z3qJKEuwaD/9EGJ1kDjCg3NYqY/7/S6oQNUlyRYzmsd27NouPcOWz62ApA2olAmU1X+YRrokH1GO9cem7UyOrYMsvMKD8TPV8LTpn+rA4NsIdgFEupU/YlmzgrxJ+SQ7WM26fFJi/+DZYFqtMyegLgsJ8M7w6npa0oM9WGQx+gsG0NkWVsh6xdj3qDMkOsBvGyf6qlcAwZVwTBLWULio2Wvw6Vs4NVMlYYNssm02tAOIPUZ72mqPDCVfkoV5998L1QVteS9JkjbuhzqPwGqJPIHm7Y/uiKjnoaoj9qwpLAGUOhzNWIkZd77JKWIyxOiPBLBZc5xyGzbzL9QivCnrKZKRnzgD1JkqOmTz/SyA0u/nMHGzoJq5jcF6AKoSN92F7cS6uVLGbyDkbT2dad+0TQewXGjq1gBioxAgxmEZ/F7WO51+4SgAm3CkCRc+0hPoZW/hhapd/oeDeoAlk/z/nSYCjfE4r4nyxxgyUw21ij9XuoHfbU5G2V3FFo0G10kjA7AEBpjY6GiEhjbRRXhNesrjAqmTzD5bmuz3zkhzu5kPW5/OOxjIyt9m2wOjAOl8Un6tvIm5K/0ZA2At7rcx6P+oo8OofbOnI2klYRO2Va9L5plUKABiURvSFzBdYaGnWJpeSPQP02aKlkdYSGxAEVPa/ugOUhapr4TcZmvKI7MOAQvla6dFA9z3SVXKJuLpyT7NRruZg0KyUFQoSzSJYaQCpS7+foXzZrjesMs83Io+v5NJVnUe/Js=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050148", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+smbJsbHi9koOg+hU7862fiYKf4Uv3MKI0+3jzX5PIIZAj5J76p1ff/tMwzOkddibMutiyy6JNAXzaCuvAXNgzg3YtnIH6KC0+Si1Xds7gAU9gYJq/ogqNdKI3KzTwUO8jweMnG+DSbltBV2Wu93o6lDcr4ArocyOvTfItOD22ujB/9kZZxtB88Z1dkionq4Q8SQ/Edy8bRtZse3edVH/Ni2tMwcS94vi2HApx5Y9WGQk4AwGg5cWYdV/wo32vT5wK99rGyC8rFZNxoB1UBmqeoG2gijQ6FB/dnUnaoRkvSF1tAGYLUZtjmqSSCVfk8Bk+JAwmwBqfGEAiGThhjafiWqBb9Ps7ZT5i6jxqbRm9uMmPQGSME/IU44IbL3HZ2Z8zqmLH6NPNo1xHizhfdkh/zj1YJWBzC0C3cpgLnnjtDqLk87hMGa/oK73stolVJ0SP8XM+sP3s1PLbi3oIHHTdN74XEj4Tni43wdxoxQgiCgd+GPbHMlw+20FkWnwYEpgmybuLGizl7pV/ouBcZ1xxPD+2HIAneZ7mpLh0Rl8Rgq/zW1GopaaXFlB2VHSXskS1gAgC/QVHJOR5mSbkDSn6cEnx0wlJkkIUxw6SQ8S", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzH3RrLHLs7xxZh/Ll2FzUt05XPUsOX/8UcKgehf7J6WczYGestGxtSA1uq30GNAN89Qk49899oeb7RIxTOpZtXVI/t9jnqPZ1XiaD6vAWNn1CXZynZDu5ey8z77QNIyyQdyk4F+4tooL5eL1uiB7V6whxaHnFKfTLRlHxSKus2h7leF4IM7tsKftTvV87TtlbjH+NsCcEhdqIg/al+5lqQaxCQLRcmgbR9O//CQMw6tFCCqNE4O7cr303lsyJZpVHp04A1Th8Nhasl/09jwtDciOo19ECG/401O1IB9URSTZ/231ijn71kwe3Mqacpouis6sxuPaEBx2nmZXzxUl5Qr/94d1RRxeHxFjmDlwjOEg2SDPJD2+JTziPu84K1r+7BnPkCTdVLXQs0IbbaAN3V3zuaWBKhdPYsnFjL2L9ov/zG5IZiQnz0IwNwuK3LjtCWX0tv0K2y1poG5iNV1ALASJe3L2t+2pFnKZC31YS7JJv/8UBuwXGj5xwtoshYxiCgDqGTZBJp6tQ8fl2q5WkwkkSjsY3Kol7Ic+JeCes4i2vLi1DQZm/V2i5fulBQxVwW4mXpH8oyQWBxmw1DfH8NH0BsvCL0VHZnf4S2BkGTVC2wIbc3zCL6Cx2xJ1OexnGRtrZUdUIKaKR2XytEg3BK/QfF8VGPkpoG5KfNVCXEg7qdjy+Hho9i6e+CiI3cnbg6+VuEZ8ptVKBB+GAXJADZfcr26V4kXTu4Ngx/QoFAyT6OSktuGXWrHpg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050149", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC422GVaJmdHjtU+fWZui+2phkNV+Mnht09DbOqrbk+EEGjKlXqYWRfzUPe49ozYq12dj5lTFtOtJBiIFg/doLeexU332sZtGbNPZrjn6SLkjxdSD9F39hhjLTynpZusOu+yO+RskjwRs2n4l/rckyP96a17zTwUO8jweMnHOYW6lrA03V9dmh/0vcr5YwsN/Noj3O5vf8ibjR9dcFZUhducZsZlizmawI6jN4WMWkZwBf8OrTZGjjHCbxZy8P+sPi03tlyYUgXmg4tBpQi4dTbMN2lpfiujciLI1jGyCzpExU1NR1UQOZNLy202Hh7kF/ZnUobI95tSgm7U+LIF19kiufTSIRh49m+8QQmAFwPWxPkmLygzuCg3HPaJvmq479l/rxtLB197BnL06VO1iYX4NcabrUInVz2PDbGaNEJ4xbGR7obpUN8zD3M9aV0T1N2dczLGXu5D6QncPmeWSottLvj9hjFb0MM5HD5tn3pVLDZDHyNXydYsL6XkjkR3m4wwFpvgwsyyAcqGrRG51w5zRNkXjwSEpnmyLueDyImLpV68KMappxw+fjyzsUnbR0lpb+wBg4Bw21nnZEupCMD1VB2VuWDcIEzQgiTLUPENbU8WKYmnvZSDwMbN7zAryUgX2EWGcdM/I1YbbV6K/LcQY=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzHlVavRa63JwZ59IhyFhE9+4HfUuuXk8ksbnOha+4vfeS8TcZl7yd6dm6Ti13hPNIZF2pZz9pMaaO0AwzvtZ9vOMv1r3S6JKUb8cj20Cnc0lSPVgn1Tp4+08i64VdZ3xQM7koJ27s1wfNSQ0KaApA25iALC1XWCS69tAUCQusC7q0qP4IcrpsiDpTva+LT/leqT8Z4IbQVCrYN3ZlWvnr4MuD82Vc2mewZK/+DZb1OtLy7jJgAe8M7twjRAyIYgXGd0/BZVloxEe/x95YzlqDc9OsN+VWHg43BIzoc8TAOXYLi11WbwoFwsNW45cI8tnT82qQ6ZJ1hxnWKfTSARkZZi+tUXlgEjfm5O3GbyjSmChGDPcpb0q5D5l/vgpbp3+7UiOgGBO1iYRYIRYKfJKmJhiuqTDKpQNpFgEmLyNdBu8jjrMpeA1i8Iw5kwPXL08SSNl8m1MGv6v5vti8Z3BqZAItTd/diLvm/TYDfkLHidcounA0jER3Xrkx1xtgwgxSQe/CLRG8lr5zgI3km4QEhh0iTvZXKy1r9S7sKHcZ0ywfz8yTsfluc4nonylAs9SxG6j3NG8oKQXRxaw1DTDN4TxQcqBboGVIbe/mSCnHXRRzwFdt3iDrqej2xc0ubozmBxrJ9ORZ6BOhDfj54vxgS4BvVtRifkppL2ff0GGmEv7qExyOi4uMS/NeOrIGw+ZhmkFa9K5pZZKANoURjSBi1KdKHiFpgdTu5A32yG1wZGQz9bAFbF/KEHU0ZXoWQjByFHYUreZ72qrYYU", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050150", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJjlR3/XjPoqmw51YdnLhe6pqWZicQPoRhiPmH0+32ymIBOtUEmY9g9p8caK58wgGjJZT4L/JhwGeBKwXxci21C2J9gDjTmTxZrpe++2e/Uco+wwE3ksd548s1OdmLmYGd7ES5iBXC3WjRWLx3Al2PsI6p5UfcooM7vtqMozbIuLTrn/Hd9tEZYQFcuMZra178nqwM+WosWcmgKAZD9P2Qc1H8NSGxIgpd/NP302Znx45pXmY64A1Jjr9YXs4hlqzsuXIgMN9+BzKjokgAyJI8dhmSfby2kGvx7EEqZ39rZJkttSMzpB2VJ0Y+m2WYDCVf1I5u+9RZmgIjdGJQjnn2hzKOjnHPfZru7oS8keewpbRz/bQiOwGpO1jRV4MPJbHZZ2Z0zOCJAK9SNN9zHyfvL5Ut6TXtNYSV03kF1cspO3bg8RaXrsOmeVOztoXwgNM2ALcFdvPX4N++o1SHYDChLHKXY9n6UBL1XW+40gBh9x0h3SIR/G3KG8lw820kkHq5SEp30i/lYGykkv5Q74WHa4c82u/pnSYYnf1q34vl0Q45SQe+zXZN8q2RS1VOjVXYGo0TzAwnHvQEEpDe4HmF1XfEC28CfMf3DeiT0S1GyeX+nGx8q5kBW87UN3kE7/o/B8b66ZMKfozk", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzH3RrLHLs7xxZh/Ll2FzVpu5n7Jsazk/lYcz6dd/YuRMDIMbJ99ycmM06T2ynJINshQ2ql84JMecucAzS7tZNXIM/d4yy6BKUGwZTi+D2d1hjXFymhZ6Imu5jOyUsN31B031ol96Mx8OtiNmYqB4VmxlQ7C1XWFTa9yFFqNvMGmq0KSpMI7usOZoz3XyPrKjvnH9dMObBwS7dw/V1O1hOga7CssVMWxZgYL+PeQZ1XhMy3jEwYYudvsxGB7x5soUSk78l9vjIdfY84z1Y3oqCciOo1rBnOzrUJF1Z1zTVeBda740WHp5VF/dG5rb59+qCQzuAaSLxRciGKIRT9Z1IN+8sQMhwVvPWtPkX/ugzGIhSWOcpej6I/ykfr/rPUj/KwzaUSNJVPPU58Va7SADml2w+iVHppSAItmAyfrONs6vGqjYKKc1ipNw80hO3Lq8SSN0sTmeXGoppe5qtFmHbwUP9/Cqd+/tRzlcyr1KG6bJsrnGQX/S3nq3Qd/sgo2iCAe7CLdDJx89DkCjG3wRkIkuynkZX2vhf5U746eeopx3/Dr1CYZlf1imtvj3Bg1VUS4gnNMvI2eQxxd2FjTXs8ehA88DbkIGpGR+3nWlGWQSjwPesDzF6eLxiJcmu74nXJ0sJ5OQYPOLgvShNlm2AW+Bu98RnStvIm5FPIRA2VuQ9wCbInhZslyEbfCUVhRIA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050151", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddlL1nJn1R39zbJpeXx5VAHjq1U5YGYeSECcstq3tmN0ur0wTFIPYZMk5Nm64gWf/VMjDSjYNHJMOxr2m+ULkr+JzCuRHN7hiPTiWgMlI2H+3b7dcg0yBQ3mYt36sE/Pdvf36Gd7ES2gRXC3WmUCLJiBVGX9cem6EySs4srociDpXLM/eDx2uzb9Z4IbQZGuohrcBuzkegI9ikxVMagKB5C5eHCYEb0YDymPxoOtYv03n1qzsItVGQ9+hZVioZFItR705H2/D0mOt9rGT/6tUVM0pFAUSuYJv2Zwmvs4VAweXUsfMp9riIjqAuZOxR3lHiVSyRFh8B77NkUlBZqcXYAlXj0jX+bj2mGaJrg6oy8jeHjtLZx6+9nPkmJOVmYVYIVa6CAJml2iuCVHqVOOo9zHi3oLpUv7jy5LZmG2nkE3t8vPXrm4COPl430O2qvp9Lqgdd/FbNAN9/Bqc60v1LIbCriYXyAds73TRvMQUD2gE5Rvx1l3TIVqG3eSIht9iUMm3G8RkNtkSbsLHm3n7pZ5IGLP4YwwLXg2DZQjPs4ntvl0RgqRgiujGtKvYrfQFoP2UbXGsQTzQYgDbhBHJ/C5mKEnHXRRzwDftzkALyO1SlblqP0gHN0vJgHW4vOIwzJyssozBKjEul4W2PkpoG5MvpVC2ov87d/3q2Iuc6ydP3kP2opZh+jUOpKsfNFs41embb2vonJmUT3hUY=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzHlVavRa63JwZ59IhydhV5p9zbFoquw9VZPhqZY5oCMeTEXe4VswdWal+by0GZENsgEm5Jx7Jsac/hPyzSuddibJehnymuOJECwZje5RHx9gDTEi25P6Je+7TOoGJojyBAhk8d85M46OcWa16uW+w2olAmU1X+UCLxqUVuJpcG6/1aSqZYh9dmC8TXa/fq5m7je/8wOIgtdspZtZlO5mbsA7i94RMawbQBY5eXeZV3jJ2isIU4V8Nj32WZw+owaSWgg8RJDjJcWMJoz4pDtr3IjK8x+ED6/rVAAzoc8WRaaZ7j48Xrn6FQ6enYkYpMtrD86twaYLUc+k2WPRStZgJMr994NmkR1fH1Jk2Pzwj6YkGCMaICj5Ia8hObzqbxt5uM0JkKJMEjRU55QJbrOJGtnzuCVCuZPPJxuFi6qfdAt8zf2LZ+Xk3kf1dUpKH7o4TnV0sz7PSW5pp7tm8Z3GP8FOtTI7MWjoxCHazbyNT2fb8DxGQv/RnLrkw9rs1gsxjIT+mvIHIBw+z4xkE2kSFBhnyLueDzyzP5o4oudP50l0uHp0DcejLRxjNvjxgg5BzCziD9WoYHfQFoPzEbVFswCywUhC70CFZqR93ufkXPeSHlNd8/lQaGJxylN3qP9i2U9q59OVMycKRzNi9IzyQO4DvM5WmGtvJT4OfUBA2si+74xwuSyo8WpfPClICUkbgilWPtQ5ZBCJEJ+HxnUBixGbr/uWYgMAfVB1nDYhBNJSXtAC12M9K5IXAqpo8HGeir3bbUVDxCicLwGGsvsR0Lcd72zge7RaqoJYba9VL0O4Nc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050152", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddlL1nJhFV9/mPDrab1t1wJz4pJ4JqWYypDfYRjx96A1ui31mRNNoZLlMB67YkLc+ZJzzyhNN3VNPt83nyFM0TkbjazFzB9h3HVhW5ErYCvrxu1aNRmgDcgn5Nx/sB8P9iT1qaa6UH4hxOW1HSDQaltFEfZtsGm+EqPtIc2ocGU8SfL/PH1nrjS/tpLchpdsolrZl/8makd8Tw9EeG6bBtK/6TTdFj5NTqiK04N68rgwn1qw5FpXGcwtAtUg4dfdsl82IvYsg4+bY1eHTb6p0FQzpdoVhiYNLK+kEHq5Fw+ezoocIZ5qT8w4Q6PaF1wnG6ORSND1JNu7MYckUR3ci9MmXHpljaGiX+KPLHx4pT1luCwo7Zt5rEoJQGBO1iYVZgQcabSJmsyzuaWBKhdPZxiKyzaM4ZuyDH8YIabzS0f0cAhIzfo8mq7gMThMHay85Pqztl5ELoSONjf7Nmk8F3JZWPkJWiQZ9/7SxuwTnX11goloxdlyykR5G7dBo56tTkFmz65TUFl0jPobWjhlbFQ5YyHfoJxweDg2HIHmec4nZ750Rs1RA26gT9FvZbfZlJLxFWRDY0X1gYpHrESB9TpmirMRNutx0l8fbFcVzbL", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzHlVavRa63c255lLk+BzVh0/nnIqqT8t1Iam6BU+4eLeScQPoRp3NWHl/f40XZJJ4ZQlcBn6p4abvlJwjjtetXPKehrjkeOI0zxaXm+EXxggSPXhjxGuoK44S64Ucl31BpykJJq+cA5LpeL0a2a+g23kQjC3XyURrllLVqqoc+87k6ZrpZ455fNhTrS57TqjvnH9dMObBwStpU/d0mpkugt/ToxUty9ZhUL2OrUaFXjYCu2KxoI686j12cpz4wvWHs9+w0GkYZEdMV3lozr/D41OMR+HD6zuUEA5YZ1Sx6FfP2732bw8lozNXslYcpuqSEhtB2dJBR6lWaVQi1fl4UnvsAWhg13dGBOlXjnwiuDhSWtbpr34pP0xenj4Kp24qY1IE6SdV3WUs0eYL3FMWh+z+ePTadbNpFzBGLpO5Ut9Dj3J5Oo0QoZ0c0lInLp4GrKyI3BMWyp84Htj8BzGboOIpHM+oujoknCIRfpJD2DadngSwnpTnC43AgloxAgiAMC4XbRG4E/9D5Nk3G0TFZqmz3lfm/hl7BYqoeKao0wx/r+znIRkfl9m9vj210/TwW3gXpNtYHfW1RKjV3SG8xH0AEvGPQCG5re/GSXmTbCXnAIP9n3EuiFxiJN3Oryh2Bx/5YBR8ynIh3Si5k1iAejDvprUHT+5MbpL/kGD2o487x2iuS198uoNfLkPGo5Zg6+T+oZ9ZpDawc7FwTPRSBKdr2iWY0TRO5bkD7GBHpdCLCLEwsYsSa3BJQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050153", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he/6PGXEBnABsXqXU7d9f3+jW6GCb+P9wJJ/Mxygg19y83iGq6zj41wdluhS+s6RdSEGbZhm3NGd0uC3xmgBJ85B2o534Z5faPsAzzKjZ93fJewuzy6XLkH1Jyu8Cndx1D7Qym9ZvZG48DT7Vt8uzxs21otx+c0uPcWGmbyW8Fmrugi+0kmUSa5rHw7Zmce87lGdspt4ociVpSGb+/Ltn/aT4MwOcQ1cq8Z+I1e1mqEd/S54Qc2mewJO8vDZd1GtLybjJgAe8M7twjRAyIYgXGd05xBFi4ZCe4wzwZDtsDdwMNliECH6sEtV1Zd5TFeafba9kGn2410+cHUnao10/Cw7pU+VJkd9iGKMWCVempMr8dYfkBYjeWZWmWTzh3+CjnaGe5v3+MIiHBo6qqFCVrTWaaBvPeLR", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIQsD+RV6p6ZHTxRLXHeuTwztdwKV+AiFVvsl/Ip6zx+RMHhrtP5pyGMDAGb55m2tWal+W3zH5NOtVQk4My5YoPbvtBzzXtfdrNL/J4x2CHZ0jlay20FHxx1CLZn25VrZD7wS++FMgywQY9mMdx/og9MMSQmbyB/Uj4hxXC0HKFTa9lA03Zocuw/1Dcr4QssMPNoSDU4v39n7jSsNAKcBpdqMZpal6rh6cA9j50Ed+8YR5OsevEaVH/YDusMhwe/Nij1Xtn0pAgX3wg8V9Ci5VTcNN2lojhriEgOs5+HCW/sARUz5VoHwGXeLS80XzhoEE3cDoqdplorjk8rgHeQ3OjsXelBuIooFIPOSvdOQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050154", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he72MmXZBWsSonGAV+N7djHiRqTKb+jxxZh2Ll+IgRt+5H/Cpqvz8hMGgehT4J2LfzAKfYpjiMKM1Ov512VTJsVQk498pJMMPPxJyzWhfdPTNPtqjmyZZ0zkdHm8Bnl4nSXPymhZ6ICz9Cu3UdQwxVUzmIM46MYuNdSXmbyB6Umxkg+N0nqdCLNlA0aYoce+7lCgrr42h8iMoj3VrrTYiPvb8dsEbgdVtoV+bxu6nqYN8SQ/Qoi7bgZO/6TGYFjkJCm3Ik4J8c6j1Xtn0ocnSXp0+xkGjopCZ9JyxIGkqDcoK94qFyr6oEtOwZ1uUh6Yc/2s2G2k4VY8YGgqZpMtsyt1tQeZIUY+nm6PTz5YhJRi8d4K19w41gSxvYT1+sxWhY4fycs=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIQsD+CQKB8cXTsWKjFZ+7/xdd0MVWNiFV49zbPraH18ldPjKBa5YKafiUGbctuxtTJ0urlzXJJNtUEjpJz4JMLdftOzTHtetXJMv96x3iFNAXYaC64EnVm2HHCgnkWuoa65ii1FNMkgBMzmpR9rekuP9+e3Kef50qxhQeOnH2YRrltH1OK9cOp8gOKoY4xscyZtHLI+/n82vnA4NsIdhsSsIA/b1KokroI6jN4Rc2sfAEL8/HEIVfsLmiiKx0Sudvx02dsyJZpWWAn9w1DkoJYYcl2xdjlsjZwL99lAzq+pgROwoM8VhmFfbqwxHuk9F0+YTomZJMtsiIh4Q6QIVNw2nyVWCQRgIhuvsQcjRBwP8Kkw8y40l2qWPsddwpVDAU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050155", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcRH7y+6zdWLeEGEDqm+XW6x6Yz2jVanGLuzsyp9wIlOFglxy8XfK46Dm/lcKgateqY+NdWIOcZlqiMKM2+32xn1Ec8BLiMB67YkLc+ZJzzyhNMbeI/Fg3XqSMkbkbjazRHN7mSHXmHlS6Je0tSqiQNI4zBo1n4Jrrc4zKdmbmaGdqEiojwWRnHqfTP1UBEaYu8+7102grrA9tN6Cv2ib2e3tkvff/9kCZxsSvpR6I0upha0F4WoxXMmzYRxK5e3GZBTjITqxJhoU787wlmNg0oppU2Z09h5Vi5AWa84z3pH3qD0iNs5rGXOopkVMzoBlE1eBfLS01Sjr9F06Zzo4ap9/vygm4R+OJ0J3nm7cSi1SgJVq8pAQmwJsb2JBiH/vjH+KgmqaaNPw5IP1gPz5paoj860jaUSWMFLMRc/iCFdLdEkJlV+Lm2HiUZNR", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIQsD+AXap6Yz2jXanRbf/32YN4KFKawRt6/HKGorfz/1IKgKRU7oeccS5De51mzNWH1OG3xWNEc8RFiYV2pJURPPJBzym4ddibJP96zy6BKUGwdyuyEnlwkXHbhW5T6JG++S66VtYygB07hZN3/8E/Pdvf0KaV51+1hxKL03XRS7JpAVWLsMro/0zcrZssvcKBvjXS8ee5rvDWsMwOYxtdscZ2cBu9m7sGuD4qRM30aQEL/P3EaVvhLy+qIh1d+Nnmlntv0ocnHXs7+wtDhsNfbIB625njtTwxK8R8EHO7rUAA1I1xXRiafb743mn28lQrfGwudsp/vTk9pB3cPFx/lCuURT9Fm5Ji/dEV1RZmfGNJiG+ii1CxffiNtwmdcybDNnFnDw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050156", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf7weHnVD2MFqnCNEqxyMHDxV6/Da+LyxpB4JF2FzV1y/HLPraLjt0QGm6Ab4YeMZC0Rd4huxJCd0vzj1zFCPMhQiIlw8Y4ab7RUw32sNNnUMvsuwHuBKUb1Y3moCnRxhiLCi3JSoY28tSi9FNs5wxw3mJM4xMY4NdaRmaCa+1m3lB++0keferhlAluX746J+UCUoYc3ucKKuDHa+LT8jPHX9dAIZ0hduZJ6bRu4nroM+z40SIi3ZxxN+PbdchT5KC3jNB4Y+sLl33cpw5QsU30ntBtDkYBEa8J20tjtsnI4Nt5+GiGzoEVMh4B5RwOFNhJWKG6sWrOAh1AL+Qh85sM=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw/1oIh6RS7oaLY2IXdo4vwd2Z2PbjxX9CNoZLnMBx65cddfpJwjrtdcbYKP9rwWKPIEzzZjX9Anl6kDjYjW8Wv4qv/WezXckjzwc7lYZ0rdw5JMOMma6c+g25xgWN0WuDTbVhH0eQo8vo/k2YpZArocyDtTvV87TRle/W5tsZLkhGt4M/cV69hKcHuCMrEca7fFJO//DZc1HhOWigKBwP/Mj3lkNhz44sHXo7+RoGg5FVasF22ZTruzszPsEqECWzp0FOxJE8Uh6RfKn40WTt51t/YnM/bcpltT4hrh2VK1Vy2m6KSSJFh8wr6tgcjERncmEHiDbhjiiKmXbPeJrx7oPoifGwo7Zt9Ko1JAGTJVnbX4sVZvPFMWJ83vrbCaNPMI1uFSfifdwgvC38OIKHnWv28FWZd1FSfrIY0joJIh4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "050157", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gexDhxu/2JX/ZDGwC42+RXbV9dHSjXanRZ+r23YQxKVOdzVR1/m+Gqqvk+BMfgKRS/YeccS5DdoJ83N+bzqT10WUBMspXlcB76o4QPOJB3jSiYcebIe1+y22UNAX/YXm8CnN9kT/CylVYrIq6+2eoW9k+xQE7k5RE4/QyDtKeyqedsg2RiBWBznKBXLRrH0fZpdyh5kKOqY4h9d6IoyTetPXq2urW89EZZhsSsIA/c1SwnrwA+ys0Ec2ibRxf4qTRb1CtMie6JgJd/s7t03VlyYUgWHp2QaIysIYpES/BR1zkiZ2Azw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7ib5/NF+bhEtv+3nIsOX5+VcKiqwb+ZyQZisHe8tmxsOA0Ozj1zFIPdJL2pZz9pMQaecAzS69cdfPM75hyC6BKUb5YjepRGN7lzjTnnVTu8O58D60Wt530Bo+n5Nx7skwfN+Wyryc+lT4rgmV2W2UWvEkBVyc9dyt6lCTrsIxpo2Dviab8frtk+rW/MdLYQdArYN8dxu9hOgA9jk7Q8GkfBtE//eQaVX7JWiiZwwP9srn02Yp1pc7TWYn8V9SioJYIspmxYykrjczMN9uHD2941RPy51oVhSXeP29xm3q9EZzNXsndoUtuSM2rgKMKUdtk2WbDC1ChIVo6sNZmQ1oeC9Tk3XphyuSzCWKf5zt5I3lyajxrr0j4KYrIEaJOlKa581akXJRVH/Bi4SFi3kihg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Nature of Sources and Historical Construction >> Natural Sciences to Constructing History", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060101", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17by/n2NGWQEHcToHCNRqp6dX/3FKXHbeLzzNdwZ0+MnVpp82LD46L1+FQdjrhT4I2efGIWcIJ7l5LJovEPRr9YUDF+4jwdRAd9", 
		"answer": "2+HoKJz63RXj+ItgSxvz1+6/NGzfQfnLxngNn+dZ6PZM3/P45V8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3j9otgQQvwxvLxIWLeBmwF43qOV7FzdXWjVbSCb636wIRlLlKKmRt893nBsaTg/1oMjqQb/ICWZGICbIR6xtTJg7S3yXhNP89LlMBr4ZsNb7RByzLtY9zeLr5n2i6TIlXxdTipAXQ0kiPZhzxCoIb75iiuQNIy0htyhZJo6NpxP9iRzaGd7UOsxgWD0HeUTP1DHlqdos+m6k+droZ6n6zAJqrmlqxLL/qJVA/OXw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "40 million years ago", 
		"option_b": "225 million years ago", 
		"option_c": "58 million years ago", 
		"option_d": "2 million years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuy0erwdXjFE2cD7nyMXLd9fnTtQLSCeuX/3dd0P1WamV5/snTDpari8hMbh60bwICbeSMNPph6ytOG2fD+ynRPJ4ZGn4Nz6Z9fb/FQzS+sYNGEYqlyRUMpxGnOBRPUWphkDt4=", 
		"answer": "25K3ZpXk0Bfr+4QuVl7zy/m/GWrFEWsCqn7B9hfqWsjZxnwR7j8CB8c++A==", 
		"explanation": "25e9bp7h1Fn+/4BgexD2zPzxdXjFAWEerWuKXKZ6ZDHhUaTDY+i+2pJhJk6ImV43sn/S47Lx5BMfjrpPqYGZMDYLe8t8x8Wd3+HlyjFSJtZBiM1x65QLdfpFwintU9vVJOlvwG+MJkv0K3mqDHl3nH2WnnNRrZez8DX7Q9MjyFUmnoI448cuKN+ay6bT+1iogxTP33SfXLRqFFqN9eKp/lGVs4s5+Y2LviDW8fC5m7jA+dAMbg0Ss4dxZxuxlrsauCk5XcSxbFJ78OrXYFHsYvLrT9y2lQWKcyyXdvwvY/I=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gondwanaland and Pangaea", 
		"option_b": "Gondwanaland and Laurisia", 
		"option_c": "Pangaea and Laurisia", 
		"option_d": "Gondwanaland and Eurasia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060103", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut6wuVhfzhffwPGWQF2oU41qWQKJneXDtFKTNYPn3x5J/MwPL84jGa5RPZAHyHOsccsVMcA==", 
		"answer": "2+bvKJz63RXj+ItgSxvz1+6/NGzfQX8lp5ubT6AVVFe61fKzNP4=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjykRTl4YAkEhD91+n3dX/fQ2geqnHDRqtxMFT2RqbRZ+zwiZR+KUiAg1515jbVrKj141oCiuhZ7JqIdScNPt43iNGH06SkkzFMOspIk498pIMafeZTjDyqe5ibLf9lx2CHZ0zkdHmVDX11mDDPi3IWqoyu+yO6RsN30hA+l5Nx+80wJZeG1r2d7w2xiEaF2XSdR7ptElWV9dqt+U6P4hI0vnpv7wk5jGvrDKHOR0Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "58 million years ago", 
		"option_b": "2 million years ago", 
		"option_c": "37 million years ago", 
		"option_d": "12000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060104", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl+4onWx3zyb3vJ2TTBnEC43yMXLdmeXP2QKLGLvnxiYN5IhyPgkl282LPrKuw+FVPm6BeqaeRdC1OWYphz9Wd3ue31H1AOshXxcK7iAHacxif5XHiHk4zg+QO", 
		"answer": "24exfpThkQrv84wtVxDmhfn6JWTDCnYYrHHB+7HBKjJzcG7oDJPkzcbWPQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3luqIhXBn30fT8dXvcAmsfsD+UV7FxMHfsRqrHaq380NdlL1nJiV5r/WXPt6z/+RMAieha5YKKZisCcst8zdSA2uH50GIBMdRLj4d68Nobc+NOjD+0NMbSNvt83S6GNUr9Jy21ATBcnTzXhn1PqZD3tSb7RMg4wxAhhcds5ckofMOQ1qPT+EG5hQPC022UWv1pGFiVvMGm+AOTpsIhsMyfonB6vylnQq/E8/GKqCjHV4f3", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Glacial erosion", 
		"option_b": "Glacial erosion", 
		"option_c": "Volcanic activity", 
		"option_d": "River sediment deposition", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRz6+IYoEgn70fP6JnjVByIFq3rDVKp6cX2jQbfOZ+vqiZh3Z0iBiBtT+3vHr6Tp9kBQzRL9kiN+PA2YpaqLc7rB9Ok=", 
		"answer": "24W0bZjgxRbp8oslEhviyv73d3bBXPQW+4ZxTRwW0KVtSEg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/0Ar+t4QuVl70zPP+OSvFE24YpWvDXaU0ZHnmFI/LY+zyyI5wNByGjlhu4GTDp+X5+RMbh60b2YKaeTEXcYhqxtXJ0vT4x3kNc8dUipJ9/JMSfeBFwCTtcsbULb48jmOJK0n5aDf9HXV1hiKWi3tZ6Je0tXbpBIpngDcR2sdq6NspMMOW16/T4UP4kg6HnH2eWrBlBV2Wu46n7QOIqIcrsI2AsDje5+Dwmbje/8sFdglbsZU9mM90+pWzTatHoqBpeg/IdQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Jurassic epoch", 
		"option_b": "Cretaceous epoch", 
		"option_c": "Pleistocene epoch", 
		"option_d": "Holocene epoch", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060106", 
		"question": "24GwbdHa3x3j9otgQQvwxvLxIWLeBmwF5GzDQaZkcWPiQK7NYK3425h8Z3uGg19s83jHr6T+8xMAjKtO+5yadGICbpt9x8iA2uXjwX1Yc/l7pb9N26UgQ8sAwTSheN3ULr53y2+SNAXxYDbxRHxxlTXfhHsWvIz7/DOoFN86xQc1k4l76Ig9L5eemaya+1mxiAWWnHyUR7p2EESRvM2p5wOJross98ckwGstlFv+5yTVnkH/+v4=", 
		"answer": "2+HoZZj/3RDl+ccXGav89WEdgDHZ/dDrQI0r", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqy1/j5MHnDQ3Ye42uLV+NkYn7gUbTRLvr2zJkxM1SMzXJ19n/HreXj4lEMgKZP4ICafjZDbY5/ycKIw+HzhHdTPMsEjoh3pIkQaeBIyS+jNMfOMPt8g22PKVH5aTyzEDBTmz/SnX1YqY+6+yP3FNslzwA8kscsvYgxNduT0KedqFS9hxSRnHqWR/1QGV2K9d2t+0KOoZYxusPNvDPJ//H92uzb9Z4JZw9bsYh2bVz8mK5J8T4rEcy9ewZC/+fEIV3pJSa3LhoEuxpE7F8tZKczAx6qgMpBix4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "40, mi,ll,io,n,50", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060107", 
		"question": "24GwbdH13gvn9pEpXRCyyvu/IWPVQ0sfp3DOdaJ6d3T3XaSCfuH/wJliZ0uInhtr4H/Lorf5+0pPi7pS/4uRMCAaPp9nzZC26NvI+05+DPl72oR39JUMdeBJwzPte9KbM/tqx2OFKVGwZDivFnlxkHHUkzxEoZW+5zT7W8g+xxw8l5Nx4898OsWQ1OiH4Ej4rg+P3XeQUbx3U21YMU0B83mEtKO6nd5zJbQ=", 
		"answer": "27S0ZITl2Bjmtc9ZKzZ+yLMUxdVswaPZTkk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3luqIhXBn30fT8dXvcAmsfsD+MRaY0ZHnmXbWCaOLsxJZlLlOHzU90smLOpuXx9FAagr1X6JqWfyxDcY0vydyFwvL+xX0BIMNAk4136o4MMLRXxDSufJTMJexrjnqSJkvjdzavEHVw1DDYjjxSrZO05i6vUd53wgxyhI5u6NovfNiN0K+a5kysjwiFnH2DR7AkBVyc9eah5kKQoZs5u42AvifV4PXwlOuT/8gOcEhTscZ6e0+5mawM/GooVNq9ZxYL/uKQdV3gJWoNeq7+CHfaveAJvOzUEm6b", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "al,lu,vi,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060108", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb2BTr+4Q5Uw2+hfLxMCvfBSIFq3rDRaxmfHWkR+fPYf7qiZpwLVmamVJ4snvJtqvk9loBz7pa54maY25De5N/zcKA0ur0wXUBOtJX2oZ76psTPOFQwDSrYJTfNexnwGnAM031JwaCO09Lqw7ptUMWrZO09i/3FMk/wQU7mIA4+cA5fNue16yA60yog0aV2TuCTbgkBVudtNfqbX2jqHXav47hNmiF+eoDVQ==", 
		"answer": "24W0bZjgxRbp8oslEL7vMUvAmyWCRBwFgcppveM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb2BTr+4Q5Uw2y0PP7MHnHBmwF42uLV6pmMH3iR7OCb+P6iZp+NEjJnlJ8/H/Aqqbx+UdPmrhX4IiLMCYWbIJhz5Cd3+G39H1EOtVQlYN36p9feeRPzzXhNMPTKf1mjmGDJFDidTy5RGJ7gTbehmUWrpG0+GfpFNc+zBk7mYk49M09LsTf2K+cqFm3xlfQjCvBCJ9HUWCRvN3o/lOQqYQs9d2BsCve8LT42vvB5d0CYwQSrYlzZhu1megd8C94V8emZRNf+OveIVvrYDyrIk4Q9s/mxHop7oskXGU17R5Iwo5Zd85n15Hq/CAxMcpvVTK0pwRJ04c8VhqGdb6skGfqoEE3cDo4cJh/szg7pQaSLxRsn2yVQyJC1pd9ceTnz7q9lmecHhjbXIs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pl,ei,st,oc,en,e", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060109", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQF2cDrmzZEJtlk0Sm8//1dSnpkF3CTUo=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHa3x3j9otgQQvwxvLxIWLeBmwF5GzDRqxgcX2jVbXHb62zibR+KkyIn1p5/nOGt6qw0kYdgLheqZmWZCoMa58v+sWaxO32iDFlOtBNiYl96toQerRUxDjtZ8HZI/Fg2meOIkvkJzCzEH80kjjAjzxVp5a14TWyUcl3jVUUmZV17Nw1M9nf1q7T4UO8jxCL2G6QRP1qEECQusC7pwO1roYxtIqe8SLU5OH1m+za/9BLL0h8uodtb0L8mKYMuCgxXcS9ZxwL4eHfcVjobGiNMgMf/Nmj2XIp1ZYoSWwntB5IhsNDbMl82NjwuSAiNtllBzq/sARJydRVUROfdf31kFzz5VsrbDcubI1lqG0mtQ6ILUc+m2WYDD9UgoVlvsUXnAttPXtFjmTpljCZiWCcPmXVDAT2VZg2TEPeWu+LAv0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3j9otgQQvwxvLxIWLeBmwF5GzDRqxgcX2jVbXHb6332tdyKFGZjEl68HrD47H/t3YanadL7M6IeTYLcZ57iOKcxPf+xT0BO89Dkox745ILdfpHjDS5Z5TNIe16jmmFKELiZim1DXN1mHHTkmhTppeH+xOzUZozyQM7hY5344gzOpeL0a3T+1i6hQmMyHKfTbNwUV2XocHo7UqKpcI7utiDpSDS8ee5lv3XsMoEIhxausZ5bEmxlrwA9yR4Xs70YRxP+PLZZUHsLGitJhoU9sXwlnhgzYdpdGcw/R4KwqFXbMd/15zhrzp8f+NvBTK27wRiz4FoXhnaNLy21CjU4V42Zm4qa7ZjlSMxqA7bOxRulXuJQC1FnY9lvtkK1QpmfH1MhTbvjDrLgmyDcJrs5cDsgOfgrLwvsq4mIkiOMhzRQs0Ta7aAKGEy3uGeTatTIIsnBy32KNkh6Sq5I5mB0S0f2dwzb37ptD6Rl43iNne2t673p9pyHb5ANd7I+dm+o1nUITf2JHOHf4bxUA/4Wzzrxw9xsgtlyS8UqHHdHoxxtTgDl3G+CVBhgDXpeHOzn7tPpsKHcY09xvHl0zVQjPx937X2wBQzSQW3zVxCoo2LTlAP+VHEDMQTyxs3TLsHVLLU/mWf1xmtYr5AN2RGt0yo32XsEKM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The Indian subcontinent's total area,Comparable to Europe without Russia", 
		"option_b": "Division of the subcontinent into five countries,Formation of individual nations", 
		"option_c": "India's population,Nearly one billion people", 
		"option_d": "Number of states and union territories in India,Twenty-eight states and seven union territories", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060110", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snHDrKn/8FoMjqQb4YeMZC0RZ8tgzpCd3+G37X9FOsdK2pNn5pkQcuBJwjijYJTSM75twXySIkbkPQWzOH4l1AXejzx/poey9Cn7R881wxo8go526MYofNKS3LqU7Un4hxXC3TuCTa1lA1WNsI6v7kybsoMovcSOsD6b4frwjrjS4tEebAwS69Y/blKwm6EG9mohVMmme1JK9uuQZUHoYDysZxoY+t/s2H1qho8mS2w58RFSkb9YXs4hlr/rsjYnPsNrGTK0pwRByZA8cxaDZrSr2Wmk91AtcDoka4lo/D00sxvcJ1I+myuPRSJWmIUr8tEXkQlibnwAn3fsjjqPwFWOcpTi7oG8h+32r6tmsrcvLFjAJlnIV58dcbbEG2lOxLrbOa5Zc4p3GyvgKZUh+nntKJPU9zAA0dUhNnb0tD6Wnca1KWm7sJe5h9o2ALcFdvnK5cS0tVLCISbxLn6bKov1SwflQXi4gU5ovhQpwS4eqHbXSNgtuX1dzj6SagZIU1Q/Kt0NjqxF2d8zRi++", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRl3eGErN1Y2LiU6KCffn/3ZJiZ0iBjE875n7D44z+81oOgehI/IycfywXd4VqxsTJ0uny1nZEN4ZFicBzpIkabPVSzSmoNNPeL/l8z36ILkbxa3moCnlg1CLZh3kW/NP7+C63WNM4zlUrk4Zq/og9O9jf3b2WqFm3xhKH32+eRrRnUVmWo8ul7k2Is742htmMpTfW8frt2qqT+c1LYQdArYN8dxuIn61J6CsrQsmzbVJG9OrEaFvjM2i3Lw8Juezs2HB+x4woUWg68F9HjIcWTsFmxJH3tTNwKMh4EHOqolZUh5t6HxbWZ7S212ThoFk+e34mZJl+/C40rQOZLBROm2WbTSlQ1IJu+N8LkER3dWpZ3GXlkj6ZgXGKeK/t2JT9ke39pbd3svBnIFLAPFLbWZ8OYLDUZ1N6z6mLDLVPMphiVzHyPMEr73ntKJeAny0F1Zk1P3vu8j7Zncu1LW2/87rwg9V6FaYBJZHR5sS88EzLYCDkYXSdJt/8XEjAQ3nxwBpqtB0rzWEV+G3bAMU/+yIZ3mq4TARMnSvvb3mvk/5Z+o2Nd8wUA2Se/YBUXBTTDWEMCP+a", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060111", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdTxMWLRDSICtn2AXa1geX/mWrOFfa3zxoF0KlmHmRt6/HKGpKD/+1wIhqta5c6ceCMNeY58iNiIweG31H1AKsNA2oEy95MYcv1GxT6sesCbMvFiyy6JKQXjbzitDX5z1DjCmTxVvZGp8CmvFN0yzxIgl5dw5Ms9MJeZ3KmH/V+9lTqM4HWjTbx3HlrD9fqt6FeTros79cCCpzfW8frtibST+dAIbh1Wtoh4I0+0kuga/To5Q8mgYR1FseLCblmtByetIxkc98rv13pthoMnWSkg/BoGkZZUccViw53qqHIzMMFmHCCzrEoA0J1oV1eCfLj49X324UY2dHRrZoVjqCQ7pAGIZBRyn2/cWCMRgIhuvtYWhwliaWZPkjbvhH+fiGDPVZ3n4oHyxfvlorps/LcuJ0SOIRzZWIlccbvFZ3JixuCdGeZTNd9zHyemFdwj/TX4OZeHnbbCR9yimJTkDEAHUK9phes=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIlq3rDQrF7ZnjnUaOCfuzt2pZ2IhyNiEh44H/Epraw/1wYz7xT7M62fiYKf4Uv28WL1Ov50HhPNshQ2oV/4YgYefAAyCioNMDUYOprzXqPKUzzJzSyEnV5kT/CmTAWqY2/tS6vR5o6zwM3m4J2+Yg9MtPf2qef5ESrjwmMnGyYXLUkBVyc9eu9+UKPqYM29c6CvybS+vH3jrjf9dpLdgcSq456I12zhaUI7CM3X4i7blJf+eGQSV3gISSiPg8OxcXf2EBhw8I7WGgn+xEGi5AWdsh2lpvrriA1PNkqECuqr0VOxoB1UBnWe7v4xGDhoFQsZn85cYNism0BqQrcOFVtiWqbSWxUjJBn99MQgQh6PXxUnWLlkX+fiGSbPIfr7sDogOvkr7dq8eMqJleFOFnWQp5QJbrOJGtnzuCVCuZPNo9mBSPyNNogvDj3JNaX0DUB2copIHmrtDicgdj5LWC+85v3zsB+Ef8FO9TX7s65s1mHbiWhNXWWJuL6XQHxQTzrxgxmuBYxwS8V5naYCYd7tTkFmz6lWUhtlDOgY3rhgrZZqqqHco890uztznAIANZuiCssJRNtpuIHARsz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060112", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQEW0dpj+MVONgeHSjR6jXeuWz3pJiMxyEglVo/XnI46z+t3oBi6Farp3feCsQaoR90Y/LGm2GAF0a2T40PKAl5CVYvw==", 
		"answer": "25a3ZoXh2Bv/44wuVV7myr3rPW6QAHcdt3aVU7d9f3+jW6GCZeX/2553Z1+bgktosOKNOg0/ikioGuHL5fBE8Yw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg3gz+/8g3Vw3mhfDwO3jfDGxRs3OCS6ZwMHCjV7XXbeT/xddjKFCMzVJ1snfIoKz1+UdPm6FW7J3fcjtDbplg3tmN3urwhGVJNoZKn4N394kebu0A3jykepTdL+wu2maFZ0blay20EnFgnT7YynNQ6Iiz9DWyUpo00hoihcdx44gyM8WL0ei65kmxh0S+p7dDQIwUzkllEEseCzfv", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bringing winter rains to northern India", 
		"option_b": "Facilitating trade with Southeast Asia", 
		"option_c": "Contributing to the cultivation of kharif crops", 
		"option_d": "Supporting the growth of wheat and barley", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTl+ZYvXRCyzO6/J27DE20fsHaBXqY0dn7xFKXQZ+P5wJl2Z1GIh1RpsmTHqqv29l8Dz7xUqZqXdWIAcYp83NGFl+XlwXBSc8lC2rRz6ZMTPNpByCjyNhLNqMCE6FH4GDh7fY6qxKo=", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nBzr5JFgXxH81vLwOynptrtMSUE7GdsFpYfgu4bX", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hj544QsEh/gwPzsdWTWQ1YQrnaPEo11dGSjRqLBa+TozNdlL1mAnxt283zJseXi9loBialX5c6ZYi0OPp9nzZCH2PbjzDxEMtVQ2o196okQc/oAyi+ieZTWKfoj4W2UKEf1dXmpCzB5nTWbrnlVrY658DX5kjhxUnMOKj4wEVo25nMmtQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "South-west monsoon", 
		"option_b": "North-east monsoon", 
		"option_c": "Western disturbances", 
		"option_d": "Winter monsoon", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060114", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEhr71v7wI27CGiIepT+XWqY0fX7tR6jNYK33xIdwJEjJpFV/+3eBsOXk5VILiuha54rfczcPap59ydzJ1Ov50HBCJ9Ub2OqHayPieEf55/I/hrlqc9w=", 
		"answer": "25ysKJfy0hDm/pEhRhv2hentNG/VQ2Mfpz+AR69gZWPiWOfBYePqyJRlNByehE9zsnvTr7H5518Kz7pe7oeQfjFBOCMROi/mCVaVybHZeRei7g==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/IWPVQ28erWyMXa00cX3vW7DHaq3q25Z1Ik6azU90smXHqqmw4Fobh+hP4YvfYy0WaoMi39Waw6T6y39SPMlK2pR9pLMReP1BjDyjcJToL+t6xmuBNFGwRiq0BTw0lT/Sym5TvJap+2esXc4/gAE6k8d24tooNJqa2LuHqEC3iBWN03XdCKlsBEfZsMCp6U+VroV4od+MtTeb9fr92vvG/MoecAle/4VwbU+9lLwauD0xRcD0fxdY5eHCbxTMMyGia04J8c6j+3Ftz5YsT3s1+hpHjMNXcMVymtjlsjZwDMJ/ATu/oldUh7VvVhbUpCIQ7TgwzodydC2Jt9LzMw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It led to the decline of trade with Southeast Asia", 
		"option_b": "It restricted India's cultural interactions to western Asia", 
		"option_c": "It facilitated trade and cultural contacts with multiple regions", 
		"option_d": "It caused a decrease in trade along the Mediterranean", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060115", 
		"question": "25y2KJD90hDv+ZFgRhf/wO6zdX/YBiIaq36RW6U0c2PsROfLYK3wxoVlLxygg19y8zbOpqTm/l8Wz6xe+YuRdCcHPoRhiMSB0qTI+05+DPl7pb9N26UgQ8t/jvsQG4B6/EUxrQxBdU4d+fw=", 
		"answer": "26a3fYX7nA7v5JFgXxH81vLwOykIy31DKZTTgzbZOHTQCrwr", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH42Rj4/oNgUQz91b32OyveDHAFqz+qXKd9cTHrUabUZ+HniZN0N1mHiV5/snnI47H48hMCgKZI5oGRMDACd4V8iOSB0qT6y39SPMlK2pJz7ZQMPPVSyX2+cdXIL/Bvwi6SJkz+dHmpDHFg1D7ViWlE6Iq1tQ61UNM2gBEnhI526ogoNNLfyr2e5UiqxguN0m+ZW/1QGVGA9c+67gOZs5E9u9mEsD6b8vvr2vnU4tcIdwRGqpR6I1Ky14EH/CM5HYi1e1Jf+eHJIUT/Lz6qIwtd7cPmlmNo0oc7HWcx8RtDhsNQbdIz1YrrrCFwK8IqEiG1tAY2LY7tfqxsMl2ea1eK4Myg", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "sou,th-,we,st mo,ns,oon", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060116", 
		"question": "24GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/IWPVQ10unEC8bZxLTzHiWKvNeej6ib5/I1WIzU90snPVt6Ty+1och+hY/IKLZTACcstsx96d1ufj1zFAPcIEjpJz4J9fa/1UxH26ccfPJexgjk+TLkS8Jy21ATBZkTXfnnlEuoK18Ca1FNslxRR+1oZ26YgPM8KL0a2S+1n4pxWL3TlVA2rNvVp4WplwvMeI3fF7", 
		"answer": "25i3ZoL83heq4IwuVg2wR4KDbsdDwZ020ZmconA6hA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+3hf5+IouEgn7y/nsdWrCBiICpn6QXa11fDH0XanGfa3qwZZlZ16Fgkw79GTJruXk/1ZPpqZf4I+RMA0Ae4phiMSGl/D/wTFgIM9FlMBx65QLdfpFwintddrfYPxvzWXAJkLxbjf9MHhxjXHXmHkWq4Ku5iK/FNgugAE6k8d85M46OcWa16uWqES2xhKH0WuUWrxwBEac9cyt/1SZpYx4ocWI8T7a+vC5m/bXsMoDZ0hdvIN+bRuVmegd8C94Qt25ZRdZvaTEaVGtLCmtI04V/Mr3xTR81sIoU2104BdDwoJfcIBy1JfyuXI5K414HCC/sAR0z51vHxSEcbys1Xuk4RUzem1mdZhorz4gswrcKUZ7myuTWilD1JRj+5AVlApnMS9BknKgljeOwHKGcpfwq4buiuWwtLFmsqwkLECOdU7NRYVcbL2AM2gyzOCXAeZVJ99OGWLyNdBu6zD3NJOGk3kZ2NxgI3bp8GqancL5KiW+vIX3ztV4EP8UPtSF6MKl8F3FbjXkYXSHJtj9VwPjD0jw2h0ltAogyTUV+yLZSIF28iVAjmy1WldxgCKgbW6kl/5T/IecP5o51rXg3DwU1LR5kZ+3wBU5BxOyg3tQ8oKNQFEP2VzTXsIEwQggTKYUB56R/XiC17PX6Dx5Vfz0mQ+MVVrc8ZA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mo,ns,oon wi,nds", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060117", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snvJrbb/+F1InOhT4J2LfzAKfYpjiMOA0Or+wnhCMshHn8B76to2cvBJzX2kZ5TYL+x8y22UfXn+WzfsRER8kXHFhWlCoM6s8DSvFNc4zgY9mYk479o1MtCMmbqS4UP4kgnC0XqbR68kAVWLod3o5EXciYw8vMzNszfP4/H8lLj55dAOIglcu8ZQYE+zla0bxCQEX5r0XBpOserfc0DlbS2iNBpd9MTtxXtmyMI5UWgt519HwoBEd8N615Skrj08Oo1jG3OzsVZJwJVoVhmRNLO3wnzs5UcxNVMlYYNs+z51oh2TOEc+k2XcWyVfgIV5wt4lm1cjSWdF3HLpkTyElmCdZdPs7cDoje2wrbZt4awoJwGFO13aWogYJafSJmN3iuiVCeZfJpNzAjDnMZUt8zftIZWAzHkP1c03KnLptAOXlsT0eWS0t9Lcm8Z5BLpC5Tppwj03elh/6Ll5z8ZeQQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRl3eGErN1Y2LiU6KCffn/3ZJiZ0iBjE875n7D47b/4kcHwr9e+prffS0NbYRgxpCF1vfj1zFDNtJTn4V8pLAKcvEAzTOpNPvYNPFsy3zAJkv0JzuvDX5zh3HEi3VY6Je0tSq6XtUlgAUzhJNrrcc6fP6R3aGSqEmtlA+M2zuFQLR3UUScp8en73+Sk5Y5ociAtDzPtKa5k+uT89EZcA1Rq8ZLa178h6ka6ys/VIi5bRxf+OvechT5KCm3ZwcTudzq2GBs1M5pSWExtAhDkZdTcM4z0pH3qCciPcxkFjap40ZSzpp7HwWXfbOrkHzroFswZ24jYJhj/AQ7pQadaEN2n3mZDC9Dm5B4vtwQngEjamdFnWKggzGPwGeObp/m8sD7l+fnnLdQ5qIzLEyFO0iYBc0VdvPJKWR92PueDrIcB5diVzLnLsYv+zy5JJ+H3Cwew9wzb3/o42qNmsi1PWypsJ3vi8ZvVLAGdsXN7Iu6v1LUbizvYXidZ8n4XAywW2751wslthYhiCIF5HbNGohztS4CkGqxSlB30jDpeHThgbtP/oeccc4QwPztkXIEkPE4sp7z3Qk5VRa6g3pCvMSeXVlOgRTXEMlH9wY7GLwEFYXFskyFnHecC3ICa47TFLqI0ykKXxAZkznd+5IQqY74GpsbNQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060118", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfDwO3jfDGxRq36QErN4cWjmUOfDLu7s3JR4JlDJn1R39zbPreXj/1IfhqZcqaeRdCsCOZgvwNmaw+vlzXJAP4ZFlIQy5Z0NdfdVwCm4ZtXXYPpr2GuMKFX9YjepOH5ImgPTi29Zptn7wS++FMk41QE625B9/tx8MdiRyqec5g26lAmX23OFCLh3AlGXocep5wOOoYs29cuCo3LQ/PXrk/6T88wEchsStog/YlW/nq0H7GosWMWxe14L5uzZbVGtNCCmZwAS69/rm3Fo1ZZpUGY65xBJjMNFd9Bj2YrwuTZwPsp4HDCvr1BV1ZE8VhnWerKqxGDh8lt/XHQvbIstuDgnqAGbaEB2nyuLRSJFkZIr7dUYhgttP3G8d5bJXYl5Uj54+9OGrqI=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIlq3rDQqJnY3DkUefKZ+r2xZ52L0iazU9z9zbVqqL+/lUGjKlV/c6Nfy4GPoRpiMSB0qT6y39SPMlK2ol8pLMReP1Biy7tfN3INPF81y6BKUGwZj6vDXNhmCXDmHka6Ia25S+6R9MtyRs11o5s/og1MceQy7yS5k69xgCNzjuSWrJ0AhSYu8ro/1GdpIcEu/GDhTretOb8m+vc/p4CcUhGt4M/YFSuha0K7Go9Sdi4aRxK5e3fbxTiJmi3Lwtd+Njw02Z9z40nHV088V9Wg5BFY8d2lpvouTMiM9QqBie7t0FTh4B0XgPWYLW9kHvr9UE3OG0udp4tsSI7sgCTJhRulmqFSSgRlcBo7MUanAVvPX1PkHOgizHLgWuMdZbt/8DojOX1s/lh6+M3O06WPFjRWIpcd7LJKSd0xfvbBq5dIZZhVyH0MsU9sHn4LpLUyzEIkNcvPWPvuS+Ygdm1NGq0oJ32gJR1G7EUJNjH/N+ytBzTbmPgJm+aZd74TR3iSjzx3U5ruAoxwCQC5iLxBo129G0Ji2y5R0Mkhi/lLGuomKpZ+MKdeo8i3Pus6ToV2OZ9noj42l04Tha+jmtPq8SMWkxfwkbCDY0TzAxuDacSEYTF+2KY14zLM62QWvRkGQ8Jj2knw+Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060119", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdW3VAnYEsXrDQrF7ZHTgQLSCR+P6wJYxIU6GgBt4/XrC46Ti9EcGjOhM4ICbY2ICcI8vy9+Hw/b+xmRVNtUEjo8y5doNefhB2DS7cdjCYOlv3GPAJEn5ajipATB9mnHYhW5CoIap+2eSWt4+wUpwwqeg0AsokbsMeh9Gih0xoQ==", 
		"answer": "252xZZD/0ADr5McjRnrLxAQVQP6UgWuyZEAh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb2BTr+4Q5Uw2y1e/wIW7TFyI4rXuKU+NyYn7uFKTNYum+yIVyM1WKzUxy/HLV7+X99loBm6lS54eRd2ICPo1uwcKFzqTgxWNMc8VIk41z8J9fdfoAwjK/YNzeMvAu52CELkSwYyy4RGR71CXej3VE6JCz/CK3UNM5x1U3kIF97tx+jnyXe46HsFft/qy2m9KFWQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Thar Desert", 
		"option_b": "Western Ghats", 
		"option_c": "Himalayas", 
		"option_d": "Ganges River", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060120", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTl4os0Uxf8he3+JnjVECIQr3OMRaZwMGX0W+rVb/S+3YVwIVqAjht592LRpqD+t3oBi6FaqY+RdGIge4V72tGFl8XkzXABNdRLl8Bz6pkWefpUjCmkedHIf7y3eamRv+2iADw9vTHtIrce", 
		"answer": "256wcZP2w1na9pYzEGOgivKa0q+qcS9OS7eWL4s=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHY2QDo8pdgYh/h1rG/NGbfDWVRrGuLV7FnPDHlVaTLYuTqyIN0Ixydn1p/9zbHraGw9EYDm71J6ILfeSwXe5luy8SA2OrkhHNEJ9FBn44yzZQbdfUAzTOpNPfeLup8z2LABlb5Znm7Fn951CHEj3Rfu5e05y64FM4+zRAh1oh2+skuOMTdTUl3nAK1Q3Ngw5p11Z/ObQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Suez Pass", 
		"option_b": "Khyber Pass", 
		"option_c": "Appenine Pass", 
		"option_d": "Bosphorus Pass", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060121", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxbm8sUkWxqy0fX6dVvRDmsD42+PU7dxcWSjRKvDd633x9dlIk6Enht09DbSsaT+5F4Gm7xS54nfUjcHeoNm293WlVmufCLXuOEzUEfFBPaNaFo=", 
		"answer": "24WqZ5z8xRzut5EoV17h1e/6NG+QDGRRgWqHVqt9Y3yjQKiCTejw3YVwKxyonlJ6sI5uub/u8W+Vhh/vLhDHAmE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD0BTj5cUwXh/mwPzqdXjVEXQUpz+CQeN1MGXxVanRY+Tt2p5+KRyKiFVv92SGparit3Eai6xT4J2SMDYMPoprwtGK0urjhHBTNsdX2o90pLkacuBSzTHtVcfSIbxMORpt03+X11rv5CWYMUOo", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Served as a military outpost", 
		"option_b": "Acted as a barrier to trade", 
		"option_c": "Promoted the spread of Buddhism to Central Asia", 
		"option_d": "Encouraged nomadic migrations", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060122", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ/r+4klSw2yx/j8NGbVQ2EUrWuGQLA0dn7xFLPKa6393JtlLkqImVJ0/DbJpeXD9l0chLpS/c6efiZDbI5/x8OAw+vlzXRSc8lC2rNz6okUbv1UjDCsesHII+xn3nqTeAcG+7oPuiuVfXv0rNdKkpiL", 
		"answer": "2565e5n+2AuqwYQsXhvrh/SAHrz/FXv5aZoI0+0GruI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHY0Ari+owyEijzyfH6LCvRDWZRjXqTU680RnDvWKLbLu/7ypZ8IhybiEt04X/SrLf58kBPgK4b/YaaMC4CbIxq28TJ2fH6xnRTc8lC2rNz6okUbv1UjDCsesHII+xn3nqTZQ4at+VIgq7iNGxYemaQ5xE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indus Valley", 
		"option_b": "Nile Valley", 
		"option_c": "Kashmir Valley", 
		"option_d": "Yangtze Valley", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060123", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdWrUFWMft36EV+NweXWjQK/HLuvxxoN5LlCFnht09DbSq6Cw31oCjqRa8I+MMC0FeI59iNaGxaTyxWNNKoZXn5Rm6J8SefpUjDyjcJTPMv9qyy6SKFDkYiriRgPGPhxetV1hEeDh/Jn/D58=", 
		"answer": "25C5e5j2w1np+4AhQB/8xvi/NGXUQ2wQsW2MRaZmMGPqQqLQfa+pNSyl8I6HwvYhaListTdA", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13hb+/4wsXg2yyvu/IWPVQ0oYrn6PU7p1YzH0UbXHLuj/2p50NRydght4/nPHseXx+VdPgK5d7JyadGINf5l9x8eMxaTlzWdEIdUI2o1z75MRe7RUxDigNNfULvp7zWeWIgX2aCv9AXFmmCiWmXlCvI+++CK1QMl3wRs21pNq7Mw5fMWQzLyW+w8yZZ2tUbNC8fnMr4xWwHqj", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Rich alluvial soil", 
		"option_b": "Dense forests", 
		"option_c": "Wider rivers", 
		"option_d": "Easier clearance and narrower rivers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060124", 
		"question": "24GwbdG+nFSnushtH17hzfT6OW+QKmwVqn7DU6R1eX/wQOfBYeH6iZZjJEiAjhts+3jCsOXx+VdPn7pU/4ebdWICPplqxNGd3vLyyGgBJMdWl8Bx6JMSfeBFjDSjNNrUMupmy3yOZ2z+YzC8RHRhkXHChTxCoIay52erRtUjxRYmn5F9rc06OtKczeqovYm/eEVFLgEmNm9YljVz", 
		"answer": "252xZZD/0ADr5McjRnrLxAQVQP6UgWuyZEAh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb2BTr+4Q5Uw2yxP7rdWrDQ2NRoX6RQKpxYjH3W+fBYeH6iZZjJEiAjhts+3jCsOmw9EEKjrxS54nfcWITbIR7zdOd3vLyhGJJOsNInsBm7JsLPP9FyS2+NMDTJb5twmeNJlH1Jza7RH57hiXej25Y6Kq18S66FMgyzBQmn5F94dF8K9aN1OiH4F+3kwGK026FCKlsFBSAsM+6qdOqZIOejHrI6uRY1xKYSAE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hi,ma,la,yas", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060125", 
		"question": "24GwbdG+nFSnushtH1O/hfzzOWTHBmZRoHCNRqp6ZX72R+fWfOz6zNdwKVjJjk535mPUoqmw/l0birpa6pqWfywQPolq3MeM0uq37X9FOscEm452pLkacuBSzTHtVcfSIb5o3GGNZ1XiYjG0F2R7hjjVymhfpYaotz4RGVNHNOxcZyBQy3C+4ho=", 
		"answer": "256wcZP2w1na9pYzEGOgivKa0q+qcS9OS7eWL4s=", 
		"explanation": "2729KLr7yBvv5cUQUw3hib3oPWLTCyIYsD+TU7FgMH7lFLPKa63N3JtwLlGIgxt2/WPIt6T5+RMdjqZc7J3TMCQCfYJjwcSIw+HzhGVTMsJB2oF84NoWcuBF3jyuYN3ULu0uzGuUMED1aXmUCnR9lXHXhHgWi4a14TW6WJoW0xwz1pRx48s5fNaR2qGW5ln4kg+P2WjdCLxoHVuOvMCvq1eUpcI1utuIvDfV4LT2nLjD9dEbbg0e/4FwbF+v2+gI9i54Ut24fAdZ9KZYtYIXZoCmxeBR9xMZAWqE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Kh,yb,er Pa,ss", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060126", 
		"question": "24GwbdG+nFSnushtH17iyfzmMG+QAiISsWqAW6J4MGPsWKKCZ+O+2odjIl2NhFV8slTTp6H4/kACz7xUqZqXdWINe4p9ysnJxeHwzX5PIIZLnMBR4ZQLbvVMjBy+fdWZNymmi1ZLiMh/Pq4osMf6Wg==", 
		"answer": "24W5ZZjhkQnm9pElUwuwVlaK8uhxluC3HnhpWQlr+A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD0BTj5cUwXh/mwPzqdXjVEXQUpz+CQeN1MGXxVanRY+Tt2p5+KRyKiFVv92SGparit3Eai6xT4J2SPGILe4d/wd6Ol/D4hGJRIcNFnsBm7J9fbvFMxTqke9qbNPEuz2qKJkb1aS39BWJxlSKWhXoWi4a14TW6WJoW0xwz1pNw/8cpO9/f2r2f/FiqhwrC3XWVCKl2EFCc9c2n5U2Zo5YxusOe8/7mG7TfsmKmmtwV7IggSOc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pa,mi,r pl,at,eau", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060127", 
		"question": "24GwbdHl0BXm8pwzEhH0hdb+JmPdCnBRonGHEo1xYHDvFLTHfPv7zddwNBybiEt04X/SrLf58kBPgK4b6M6TcTAEe8th3d2L0va3y3cBAMdKiYtg7Y5fcfVO2S6uZt3LNO0uz2CEZ0b1aS24FmM0kj7EyjEb5c72uGr55bfx7BV69dy/AQkPcuNe8w==", 
		"answer": "24a5ZoL4wxD+t4Y1Xgr70/zrPGTeQT2oCfqrvdrZYL90Et2j3WU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHl0BXm8pwzEhH0hdb+JmPdCnBRonGHEo1xYHDvFLfQa/7724F0IxyIzUhy9XjPpazz9l0bz6ZO5IyaYmIMeMtcyd6a3Pb+0DFMMshRiYNg7YoLb7RBwjntdtHYIfNrjmaVJVawYTavRGR8kXHVn3BCoZW64S60Wpo2zhFykoJu6MQzLNqa17zT50v4tQeMz3CDQakkHV2NsNyp/1aOpcI5u8nNsifX4OHrn7p00DJyQEiEFpcUYRq2lS03", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sa,ns,kr,it cu,lt,iv,at,io,n", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060128", 
		"question": "24GwbdH13hb+/4wsXg2yyvu/IWPVTi9c7jLOH+45MGbmRqKCa+ztwJJjZ0iGzVh393fU46T+8xMHjqwb54+NYi0Ue5kv2tmf0vbkiDFMMs1NlIcy8JIacbRJyDiseJTdL+wuy2+SK1ywdDypEHxxmTTYnm8WqY2/tTOzUZozxQM3moho4M0yKJeQ3+iH+ky8g0aQ026FTa4mRIe3PRiRW1l5teVyQTl07Q==", 
		"answer": "252xZZD/0ADr5McjRnrLxAQVQP6UgWuyZEAh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13hb+/4wsXg2yyvu/IWPVQ0oYrn6PU7p1YzH0UbXHLuDx25IxJl+KiEho+3TKpuX2+EFPjKRe6JyWfiVDeIR9zcOdxKT2ynUBPMBCn5J34NoRfeZSwyqoZpTJKehr3H3MZ1L4bjq1RH11kDSWnnRTu4b79DW+Vcl30wA7goZ64c18OtiNma2S+kGhxg6X0XqfCK5hBUCVsMOt5VeP4IM2sY2ZuTeb8eftm/rf+c0Dbw1cq8ZwZRuohakN/WoqXt2gbQEJY0Yi8/3d2p73s+nmRmX8vQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hi,ma,la,ya,s", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060129", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCLq2+ibt4NEjJpHJH/CeGiK3p9VYdz5ha+p3fPWJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc+cN2rRg5ZQMcf1T3zSiepTYJfB6y3zAKEOwRSy5AHh9hzyWnnMWqYex9CS+Ws53wQc3l5Q44s58H9KRzbqS5A2ZlQ+D4HXDCI1lHF2L9f6k6leZoZd4+I3N8XKbtLS52riTsJ4pKyZTq5NtYlf8lakb6iM9Q4i2bQZc9OHeIX3jJCGiZw8T/YvA03p91IMlHUgn/R4KwoVXYcl/34zlqDs+OI1+BzK+pnhOlNRXXgSeebSqkF7l7Fk6bDpmJcot/G114U/caHc32lmZXCNCnZRk7MlZmgIjfC9MnWTnh3+FlWiNeYGj5Ia8hObzqbxt5uMzLFmUJhzRWM01a7fJJlt8nqmoDKhPOI1uA2LLPNs77zrrKYaAzHlAkP1pb1Di+y2Lk939MGa7v9L/i9ViAa0FdsHX5t+ys0jObyShCHOXb8q0Xxr/Qjz73AJh9xk3yzUZ6yLPAYd75m+ZB8dYV+4/JCKyhkiu7GXu", 
		"answer": "2+T1St2zg1TLu8VzHz2+hamyESnwEIz1JSJkTR5zNgBcSWyf", 
		"explanation": "256wcZP2w1na9pYzCF7GzfTsdXvREHFRsHqRRKZwMHDwFKaCfOLr3ZIxIVObzVh0/GLPrbD/4kBPm7pa7YvfcSwHPoh6xMScxeX7hHhPJ8NWm4Nm7ZURb7RCySm6cdHVYNdgymeBZ0T+Y3meAX5ghjDayl1FoYL3tSa4QNM5x1Uzhcd5rcY9KMKN2KTT6kyqlA+HzjuTTalzFFGX9dqg7gOIt414p8iKuD3V58j3qvne+cxLUgRTq4N+dgH8o6AMuBo5XMGmKCJH8PDVYEGtMCSiPgsZucqjxX1uyIsvVGo1+gsGkIxaZ4B62NjwtDdwK99rGyC3qldTzptyHxiQNJ+t1Gzs6UYyNW4kJYRovT83uE+OLVN3lWWPDCNX1KNu8MQLlAgjXHxJnTbklzrLlGrPdYfwq5Pol+nkpb5q8eMrJkKBIVXXWM0da7eAJHJ+3vyJDKocMJBpGSflKdwh8irFLr2VzDEA2ctgGXbr+C+AyI3BMWD6pZP1gtFvVLAGdvrE+sO6uU6HYybiIHCWJsq0Sw3gQG/xxwF3rlgqzmERqG7ZGo56tSMYk3y1WwRrlGfTbXKynaxV/sKDfoAkwPb+1CIEi7g4j4nyxxguUQ21ij9CvIeWSlJbjUDTBtkUhAggCPQKGpnG/miSknPsRU8Mcd39E6GTgwFJ1PbijXN0r4QdD8y5JBDXj54ywB6iQfRqFWb+u4n6NP0BD2Bs7btlwq21v8/7XvK3JGgjfVqBWONV9owdKAtvVhidEitddLDuWJIKSO5IkmHClhMIU3dMRWrN9qEaHTSmq9DNb3+eYr8YTjXqerEAAY7IT1TcdfCl2z+JAL6fnEu3S0UxSz7dNbgIpQLoeYTzKhS202diucLwPkVOVoIbfCb9cCuroK+KDA81aj9lIYRBdVXYSgQtmzCPZ/BpjqsVdBEjRuizEVVWggNOkS3fB0tWuUMQH6qrAHEyLq1NKUgcjTa7FeAeUh/DgzQezkKZ2jb/axwOaMo89zLi9EdHnG1zkes=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-A, 2-D, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_b": "1-B, 2-A, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"option_d": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060130", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUGXRL+yur2O2yKP2wtrS7Deqp5cX3iTabRLqC+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPqomiPaI1O37zWVAJ8NA2pRg5Z4aPPVOyH2uYdjPNexvwi6DKEvkZjqpFzB2kSXBj3lY6Kq18S66GJoUxRsmhIZ0rekvNdbTmamd7A2PgxWWnFqCQbxYHwbZhtuk6kqRoYx4mMKYvyba/fq5qPnd99sYIkUSnc8/RVqqmLoM/Go+Xtr0bRNZ/f2QYFP/KSu2KxoI68rvlmds0pYlWGQx+gtVwodDZ4Bn2djhvSE5Ot8qFj+/olZByZd5HxaYcP220Xr270J/Z3M9YJh+gCNm4SSdO1xzk3ncei1dmIVyvp1Z1UQjPS8A3Dagwn/LwCXPPNOjq6O1xdjir69q9qYjaVGSOkjdVZkVar2AJmBzw+eIGeZfPJNjVyP0PsEn/3nuKZiQzHkM3t1gLnTz8S7Zk961OCW4soDrh9FkVLkSOdyF/cOy8FLIczfpHXPHJuz1Vw/1W3X7kz5pthEr22FdqCKYSMk/tW1N3j7wCQQk0megLDyF3/5475SLc4Eh1vGs1CYD2Ptvkdvg1QR8SAL7gXZFt8jfXEld31vDEMkCwEksFfQJHZHZsmCZgHjESnUDbIwQMwWEB6GD8gXd+9K8Per4", 
		"answer": "2+T1S92zg1TLu8VzHzq+hamyFymGqjIYkf4N6Sh16nGaAWr2", 
		"explanation": "252xZZD/0ADr5N9gZhb31vi/OGTFDXYQqnGQErNmf2fqUKLGLv3sxoN0JEiAglU783HHqqvj4xMMgKRfqY+NczYKfct4wd6NxKT2ynUBMsVQn4Qy5YlffbRCzS+/fdHJYP9pz2eONFGwbjerBWN9mz/FynpEp4774S++FNQ40gE6qolL+MQ9Ndqe1+i+51i2kgeL0jujSbNjFEfD9fqg7lCZ4JA5u8qIonLd9ffwlvHH8coOZkhGrYd7Zhu9maxJ+z80Rd2maR4L8uvedVXuNDvjJQsJ7s7m2DRAyIYgXCk1+hsGkIZRa899xdjotTk1f+5vGyeookgA5od1XleXern452339BUeZnMqWYRGvT49rAaOaGJ/lmeZVXYRoIhi7ZALkANqcmEAmHP2hzOEkGCLPJr3+MDzkuawpLBw5qopKlWJI1mYQYwFJbzGZ2t7zOzXTbVJIY1oAiziONFu/iC5KJ+T13kA38wuO3bu+jmlnOr0N2K/p5v6zuR6FbYOJYuF3cOy8FrIbjfpKHGfdYv7X0jkR3m4+wdothQk0SADqHXdGow/8ywbkWy1TQRinTWgaX2zmqcc64Wcdo0k3+H5zzMc2Od9i4/70RA5SRCozXtWt8SLQBxbxVHfDI0CxRonCaZBF5rU83+Xm3XVC30De474ALqVzDtNyKPjh3d4rYNOVoODPBjJj9pm3BjxFfV8FW34poH1OO9VBWJs7rp0iv2ttsO1ZrE9uy/Bj36HuPGkYQhCgDvw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-B, 2-C, 3-D, 4-A", 
		"option_b": "1-C, 2-D, 3-A, 4-B", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-C, 2-A, 3-D, 4-B", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060131", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddlL1nJil509WTHs6359FIDz65e6JqKYicQPoRpiPmH0+32hHhSc8VLiJJ3545FQPp8wmztQNzeYNZnw2+MJlzxdHmtFn9gkTLCylVYrIq6tSa8VdM50wFygo99rcszMNPf2LqQ/ES7xhGL0n+CCLt2HlnZhseq7lGVoc54uMyEvyba/frwlP+T8Z4cYxpf/4Vzala9g61J8SR4X8emfBpO4+qQSFrpKSmfKTITq4vX3nEp9ZclXGA59REGj4xDbNRy35akrjM+OMh5WXO740dPyYB1UQKXYLS33ijr5hUrfX9rTYNgvSE0uA6PZBR4m2iVQCVFlZRu+pAamgp3dGFVk2PzwiucjyiYfYqj/5L9g+75o/lh97cwLESOdXXWUoQdJbLOIydRz+ePH6dQc750HiPaM+kgr3nNKJPU6zEMwpkEKmTi5j7ZkcL7LXezsYfti8c2ALBAItnAqca4vk/Ibi2hM3yaaNi0UAawW3T9kydrsxEkxmED/WDbB4dr/CMIkGryBCvgyAYqK5bYwFmdKB6QXA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRomzDRqtxMFnqWabOb/T/2tdiL1WMgV8723jCqqSw8UEAguhY5oKbMCMRfZ9my5Ce3urz1z0BP8NFnol849oLc7RBjC+oeNXPKehrwnfAMETianm+CHl5lSXTynVY6Jez8Ge1W8gjyBAgmMdo7NoofNiZmbyb7Q27iROMyGmICI5wEECcuMum/wPO4Isr9cyBoj2b9ff6j+rS5NtLYxsSq456I2ipm6kA9Ss2EcW7fRxf8O3eIUbsLi+mNEJd7sPq1Xwpx5AsHWh05xBTlotBY9J3lpvrsiY5MdhrATq1rQRPwdRoVxLWXLS10WTl+VQsOToia45ouSl1pw6fIVh3jmqISSgRgJJq+tVZlApnPWZOiHPygzyfiWqBb9Ph7pTrgO3+4JBt9qomaUCOMRz7U4MId7LMZ0Zhw+jbPrJdJ5pqEizyfYZu9Sq5KZiX0Csf1do0b3b0tD6Rl43BMWSo87b8ndFkAP8EOdTW54yj8FjOcybiNXGKJsj7VxziRn7txwsloxdlxS4e+23XBslt9CQDjSXwREtqgSjvYm/hl6xZqpKcdoMwwfzgxHIZlvJ0ip751xg4BwaizXBAt4WRRl8Py1XVCsIV10sK0zHIJK1xoHxt8iCzqo/D", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060132", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddlL1nJiF1993XSsOX/8RMIiqdc+4+PeCsAf4cvztWIw/HlwWIBPMgEmYlk7ZYWZvVUxTKjZ5TSM75twXySIkbkPQWzOH4l1AXejzx+oY66+SaiVdR30BQhhYJrrc49P96T0LyS/Ei8xhKQ3X+UCLxqFRSaoMK8/lGdrMI7usOZsDHP57T7n+zE9dsFIiFcu49+LxufkqYd6is0EemnYRMHseXeZRTaJTu3Zy8O8Mrf2EhnlMIdVWx04h5KjoZPIs91lrPlrzo9Nt8tBnOtqkpUwoY8XBibZLi03G3goFwrZjoia4JsviQhoAGIOxRqlSuRRStDlZRuvsQW1RBreC9QkHfpjCzHwGSBeNPq/5O8lv39rbxxsqIzPVOBNkjdUs0PbbbQL2JgzvrbC7RTPt9zHyemLdkv9TfqHJio0WpN5NElb0fm+SOL0t35OHG/soe5ndFkAroEdtDWqcr3sl3VcyrkMz2DdM7iXAbkRnL/kxptslg22DMV6WaYB48/1zgJmna5WkkkhiigbXirl71Z5JbOfpw00uas0jRQu/F2i4n22F0dVA26z+H1YmphLIirgtGbv9JIBpU=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZd436QErd8dTHzVbTRa/6+wJkxM1SMzXNy/3fKorzx5BMGgaxe7IrfdiMAd4dm3NGd0uC30GNAN8MEm452pJkKcOBV3jyhNN3VNPt8z22ULkr+dHm/AWRjkTTYylVYrIq6tSa1UJolxRI7mYlrrcQ1N9Lf+q2d/F+5ikajz3KQCLxqFRSusN28q2KPqYN4htmMpTfW8frt2qqT+c1LYwRBsMZ8bEmukqsdtGo5QoigYBcL5+XcbVH0YCelZyUc6sPu32Yu1cIqUWA59QtPgcNVbc5334ztszwjf8FvEXOurARTwpVvUBmXeP212W/24UE2enQ4JYtjuG08rxuZOlV9jmKTQj8Rg4l/9pANnQEjbWNBlXjzxX+YiGCfdJbx75O8tvzxtLxu960zaRLAPE+YX4MfaqHSImRmkamPBaMcI550BCPhOJUq8zzqLtGAnzQI3s0pIHmn4CKc0v30NGyo84L1j8BzFapAN8KF6Iu1sU7VaCbzYXyUZ8L6ShywW3T9kx11pR0kzGEf7iL6HY17/SQekzLwS1Fw0jXheHSkhP5d+cKPP5oj0vv/0DsDi/13kdv00RMoQhb7i3BR8qaKS1hHxEfbXtkIhAgqBrUCEZjFsmyEkHfDC3MLP+3zD7yVwiAI+/D4jyMuez5+DNRw73GHZ7Oz4nMw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "3 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060133", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddlL1nJhFZr83XS46r2t1QKgK9J6J6XeSECcstpzdGdwvby1zFOPYZMk5Nm64gWf/VMjDmoYtHXL+5jy2CUNAX5dHm+C2JmkTLC0EBYlI3qtROzUZoE1Rkzn4p544gxM8KRzama5g2qhwiF2WjRTrxnGFiQoc+87kfctJU3+NqMqHLP5vX/nPHQsNwOdh9Xuog/SlW4nqlJ+SQ8EeuxZgZZ8OiQQEfkIWinMgtd7cSjwnxsz5BpVWAz/F9DjoZAY9R62ZbYsg4+bY1eHTb6tUVMy5FlTFeZcv2T0Xvs7VwtNXslYcpDuT00rU+eLVd/l27cXilBm5Ni6t8LnAFwPWBG3HegkTaMjmyJdZDi5ZS8i/39orxxsqwhaXKBO0/TRIQIJb7BKXJhyfuSHbJPD5FbGXGmCd0rvD/2L4Kc1jUBw5kvKTfz/C/ZusT4OGm7qpPqzsNzBrpAMtjD78K0pVDTITfuYX6fY8rmGQn+SzzswQ9zsgo2zW1Q4GvWDIxt/CMK3nuxW0h90ibnfnWig7JI/5CPc84i1uH40TcdnfpsjNmvP/VjmEd+niJFKD/pJYgp", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStyTDRat9fHSjQK/HLt7rxZZ4Kl2HzVZ053jSoqz+t0EOga9e+s6beSZDeIpswdyAw+XjwTFVIcdAn8Bz6p5fdfpUyS+sd8DSL/B9jmyFM1L1Yjf9LX5wnTCWi3JS6KC++zOpVdZ34QY7l8s4+cA5NcXf3KSW/kysjwmMnHKCCLNrBRSNvcvo+1GVrYMqrI2ftDPI+/q5qezS5NsGZwZG/9Q/akj8lKcb6i87RYT0aQEL5ezVIUTsMzuiIAtd9M7twn1myJFpSWE14F9EjZdeItR709jyvT48OtR5VTy8429B1JxxVgXWdbO8kEbh8FQzNXguZotguW0npB+TO11qlXmVST8Rm4Yr8MUUkBZsaHwAr3fukTSZiXHPcZLt/pP/l+HgtKojwbcmPUSNMFLMFt5cbKCALmlxxfuJCKVIaN9zHyemLdQ97zj+JdaHyj4K1co0PDfz/CuN0tn9PCW8vJ3tht16GKxAOdeF/cOy8HTObCLtIGSSdYvjXBr1D3n5wAdgpVgxx2ET5GfZGsl++ylNimyxX0F2gSKgb3Oshr9O74bOa4Fxx/3pnTYVlud935Hi2howQhf7gnkDpoyaD11DwUHAF8wLhBkiDb0PB9Q+zL67f6c0RB4+YdGarS6g", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "3 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "1 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060134", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hc7qOWrZDmMf43KMR61gcXjtFLXDYOr72td3Jl+AgVJv82LDp+X4/kAbgLpS6o+TMDYUccZ4ycnJw/b2wndIMIZGn5Rl4Z8RPN1OyDSsNNXVJL5Ny2CUNUT8JxiuDXFImg3YuHlXu4y1r2ePXN8kxVUgl4l/6Nt8OtiN1K2XqEz4iAeWyWmQRP1mEEaLvMu6q0KboYs2ptnNuDzN9efwlfbAsNgZbQUSq456I1WzhbwBurEhRTj5ltfroFB0V24Z2gE=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+yphjNVmKmRc783jC47H48hMdiqlI5oDfeTFDf8tsx8Kb0ufjhHRZI8pFlIFm7ZURPPtGjCmlcZTaM+1r3HqJKEuy6ZMCXLSIUD5z+4dnQqJcJw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHAxBXr/oghXF7/yujxIWrZDSIDonGEV7A0dHjnFK7Mauj7zdd3Jl+AgVJv82LD47Hi9lcKz6lV7c6WfjYGbIps3NmG2fe3xnRVJMNBlMBb6p4WfbRBwjntV9HVNOxvwi6hNEzxJy21Fn9hkzmWmn1Fu4aotSuyX9936x0rlIJqoYgeM9ue1+TT6UO8xiGN0XqdCK1lAkecpo6c40bcoZErsN+ZuD3VtP3q2uvG4M4EcBxXu8Z9ehu0nrsd9zgxUsm4KBdd+ODVb1foYByrIk4P/Mrw2Xopx446Uikx7A9Kg4pYcYBk3oGkqDo1LMgqBzK0pEFTh4N5TRLWfbCo33rw4VsrOToqdsp5tCgs4Q6fPFF62mqPDC0RloF57Nkch0Riem5JkmX0wjuCkmCMaNPq5Zb9luH/rqoj9LEoJAGUPVmYWIIOcbuCTgihE3FDE1J1w9RHvej+Ow==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are correct, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is correct, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is incorrect, but the reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060135", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hev+OWfVGnFRrHnDeaJneHzqRufDYOm+55JhJlDJiV5t93rJs6D0t0YBhrlO7M6IcTsQPoRpiNyA0eG3wGREc9JL2pR64ZMNPP1TwzGsYN3ULr5nwC6UL0CwTzCwBXx1jTDFtnJqprG+9DS0WoB39B031oNx6841P8KTzeiH7V+qhw+MnHqfTP1sGFOR9cOn/k2IoYs2po2epCDJ++H3nvHd954fag1BusZpYlewkrEauCc5Vc30ax1G/PHeaFfsNCGsKU4K8N/rlmBhw8I5UWg9+gwGgYtXbsx22J/tsjVyaqb17/qOAT4lWCNk46t32w==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStzPDULZgMGXrUefQa+ztxpkxLk/Jg1RvsneGoKri5VYMm+he8Z6TcSwCaoJgxpCG0aTjzHQBMtVXn5Jm7ZURPlDTA7rnLRtdBr7S/IfM3EQ=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUhQQ331+n2OmWQCnFRonyAR7F1ZHSvFLPKa63szJZiKFLJnUl05H/CpqGw81wKnKYc/c6ecyEWbIp7zdyQl+Hv1H1AOsgEjoh3pJMMc/hB2DSiepTaLvou22CJNlD1Jy68HWM0mzeWhnVQrcOy+2evXN931hQ+moJh/ogzOpe02Lub5USqxgeM2Du/Ta1lHRStvcvo4lCTrIMsvMKD8SXa57T9j/2T5NFLdgBX/4F6bFyulrgB8Sk5XYiybRNf5PbVchitIj23ZxoV/Ivx03V6yYxpUn8x5gxPj5Naa8Z604ukqDo1f85lGD6vrU1DxoB1UBnWd7W53GTh7lI6Zjoqa44tuCIwsgHbPBR6k3mZTzhdjcBo8d4XkAd3PXtP3GLoh3+Kk3aKbofq5I6+mzYvMeHciSdyzixDbkvAZw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are correct, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is correct, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is incorrect, but the reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060136", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfvwOn/YCm4dsD+MVONgeHSjfK7Pb+H/0JZiZ0uMn1474mTDpaDi5VYLz65U+86acTAPZ8t8zcSd2+H6wX9VIIZFlIQy8IgeePEA3jK4YNHIYPp7yy6UKAXkbzy0FjBykSPCg3BT6IK3+TKtXds7gAY9n4tE4/QyDtKeyqedsg2MjgPC3XedXattEFjZpsGh5wOLoZF4sMyeuDfJtOD22vvG/MoCdAlGusZ+bV/8h7oG7iM8VMz0aR9b/eGQc1H+Lz2xJAsOuc3sxDR605E9WGc1+hxDwFJPC15/W5AIDYMFNuFTxfs=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStzPDULZgMGXrUefQa+ztxpkxLk/Jg1RvsneGoKri5VYMm+he8Z6TcSwCaoJgxpCG0aTjzHQBMtVXn5Jm7ZURPlDTA7rnLRtdBr7S/IfM3EQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+QRqJgdWKjQK/Deq3qwZIxIVOGmVNy/nrV46r2t0cHiuhz4IOefCMaf5gv39Wb0qTn1nRHNtRWn4Qy4pUNPOdF2CmhcdneLup9jm+OIwXkdTi5ATBmmyTCj28WgIys8DG+RpZ31B031pV97NszMpeW16uc+l+9hRKOxTuQXKl2GFaMocu7q1eUqZF4pd+ItzfJ8fr6n7jH/54NZxpGtop6I1qwm70f8Ss0Edu7YR4HsfPYZFqtKSbjIQ8e7YejwnxshpAsXHo7+l9Ki4ZFIsl9lozsuXI1Pt5jECH6oEhFxoZ9URSTNLK+kG7r8lAsYWlrZIRp/Dk9pE+SKUZslXyZXmxGnYR/9pAWk0RxdHlFjmWswjGElCWBeZDm+JP9l+H8ufl3+qZnPViQMBzXUM0ParrMZeextamjOtUfGq9DR6/uhd4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are correct, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is correct, but the reason is not a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is incorrect, but the reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdW3VAnYEsXrDVqpieXXmUOfWZui+4Jl1Ll2HzUt+/H/IsLD89hMGgbxUqYqWYzYKcIh7iNOc2/Di1nBNc8dKnsBi65YWaP1DzTHtZtHcKfFg3THCkn/S4AzqgkIgJ5afQRY44Q==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHE1Ar+8pcuEjn6xOnsd0MXkYmpHvLX83r857EIik8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE1Ar+8pcuEjn6xOnsdWrTF2cV436QEqI0d3TsU7XDfuX3ypZ9Z16GmFV/82Tf47H49kdPi6FN4IqadGIXdo4v4d6N3uX5hGFEPc9KiZV+5doWcuBPjDmkZ8DSLv16jnyFIEz/aSr9E3lgnHHSg3pQrZG++zP7V8871AAgk5Q47MY4fMeQ1aGH4U65ikaH0m+YXLRhAhYO2CkUkReTl7XyLM2CDAgJ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The Western Ghats", 
		"option_b": "The Aravalli Mountains", 
		"option_c": "The Brahmaputra River", 
		"option_d": "The Thar Desert", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060138", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqyxvTpPGfZGWMFqnCNEqV4f2TxXbTKa+m+wJkxM1SMzXJ19mPV45Px+18KluhJ7ImWfyxcPPtDe1ETC292jFe8SGA1O0E=", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjktShYVvswbDI9MPpoC3x6YoE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVQ20DqniKXKJgdXWjVanGLuvyxoJjLk+BiF87+3iGt631t3oBi71IqbiefC4GZ8t9zdeA2Oq12iegnL2YsbIBeIQCJiZ+4Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Vedic", 
		"option_b": "Harappan", 
		"option_c": "Mauryan", 
		"option_d": "Gupta", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060139", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEg3r1un6OCvTD20CpmyXErd7MFziXKbMb+n3iZZ/IxydhV471XnCorPx5VpPnaFN7JyML2BA5L3U+zazbOhCCwT+43u2", 
		"answer": "256qYYL73xioEkanYozuU+e76H8KPpuV5A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYP2kRD5t4svEgz70/jtdXjJEHYUrj+QW7dhcWXmUOfAa/npzJJ/Z0iBiBtW837HraT0/hMOgawb/YaaMAUMeop5ycKAl/b+0nRTIPpKpo5G7J9fUfVIzTOscN2bMvd4y3zALlawZnmwBXp7hnHEg2pTusOy+2e4UdQj0hQ+1q526cE9fP6LmaeB4UqxiAeW2WjRQbMkBVyc9e2g40yIocIWtMqdpCCbxPj4jv3S5Z4KbAwSuYpwdEj8g6Ab9z8/WYigYBcL4vDRdVH+YCelZy0V8cr3wn16wYM7VSV02xtPkYtXLoBy2JyknTw0N99rVQOookBF1Jw8ax+TNJq31Gny4Uc2NWgic49//CQm4Q6QO1s+myuRTSZehsB598Ych0Rqcy9pknLpg3+ilCWAbprk4o79ke3j4LBtsrcvLAG3ME/MU58SJZTIJnNhiuiVCeZaP5BwBGLyNcch6T7xYIKc2nkexNg0KmSn+yzZv8z9OHe7oJrtnNU6VIsFOtDL7sq5sRCHQC3lKW+SJvvmWAz1XHS0kw9rs1gOyTMe6XbZA4hD+xEDqna1CVBznWfyZWqkhK0c65CLP4I+0PT42DZQkfo4m5Lx0hguQgqvzW9CoJCMD1NJjX3YGsQGhAggCPQFG9bf/XnWnHjETm4ees3iQZyPxmxL1uzii3Jp/4IHQ4mcbArCmcojxVelDr1tXWKthYfxPPIUDm1s6Ltnz//hvtn7YfuhbE44Zgm/V+4Z4ZxHbRA3URzVDCdHILG9FpERQuFb13GKgwgIU3dMRUnD7rwAHTCir4TLYmXNZqIITgzrdbYXU93hXVPKOLG9x3DdDrrcski6XlIkXDPdM7kb4BWwc5+yMBu200N28NLtPFAbVooBOTW/NHyxrKCLSw8pPyAqK4tTf0OVXx9kgDbGZ+5inrNCQA5fiZJj8qoVa836d9STSA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ganga", 
		"option_b": "Yamuna", 
		"option_c": "Krishna", 
		"option_d": "Kaveri", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060140", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdW3VAnYEsXrDX6JwdTHrQarDYK3tzINlK1mEiFVv4TbPreXk/1ZPu6Ba+86bdTEGbJ8vzNmP0e300X1Vc89K2oF855MacuAA2DSgcceEYpdvpFe8Ctb49c60eeD7Yzg=", 
		"answer": "25SqaYfy3RXjt6gvRxDmxPTxJind2Bxy+fiM/Jra+CrG4p3F", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzrt5IlQQqyyvu/IWPVQ0MDommCXq99YzHqR+fBYfv725J1Z16QzU9z9zbyq6Tit1cKnK1J/cLfcSwHPp9nzZCf1vfjhHRZI8dKiYUy65xfaPxFjDmoZ9HJNL5jz2qFZ03lajizRGNxgCXaj3FTppeotS62RNUk0xwwmoI45MZ8Pdmc0K2d/A2sjwuHzzmA7yDZttk191dpEJk2TwlL", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Aravalli Mountains", 
		"option_b": "Indus River", 
		"option_c": "Eastern Ghats", 
		"option_d": "Western Ghats", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060141", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElEhbz1r33PHjEDHAYoH6PXro0cnTmWufEb+Dx3IQxIVObzVh082XSoqmw9l0Lz65U+4uWdyxDapluzNXJ0/HyhGVOc89QicB65Ygdc+ZTk3/fpOSto10zeSiORxwYj4qf", 
		"answer": "25KtYpDh0A2oJmc+FesUksdysJmyuevhaQ==", 
		"explanation": "25KtYpDh0A2mt5YpXB33hfzxNmLVDXZRt3aOV7A4MHniR+fAa+jwiZFwKlOcnht9/WSGqrHjt1AAjrtP6ILfcSwHPo1g2tWA0Oq30GNAN8MEnpV3pI4QPP1U332+Yd3PIfxiyy6IJlfyaCuuRHF6kHHThGhTupOp/DSyWt131AczkoJq/ooHnCWBvHge0mYDLqvSkgOJ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Maharashtra", 
		"option_b": "Madhya Pradesh", 
		"option_c": "Gujarat", 
		"option_d": "Rajasthan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060142", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsXaVV7FnMGHvVb7Haq3/iYR4IFKAi1J483jS47f/+1ZPhqYb+oaeYCsNect7wNXJx+v7zWVIMMdI2oJ98ZQbfeZJyS7te9KbIfBtx2uOMwXZaT20BX40hjTRg3NYu9z51w9+0sWkmT9wabG4wUWocQ==", 
		"answer": "25K3bJDl0AvjtRT1JKDXsODEvhJiG9NVdq4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzrt44uXQn8hfzsdUreB2oDoj+zQKJwdWLrFKvDfOr7xY4xK12QzVl+5mHDpquw41sKz49U7Y+JcTAKPp9giMSB0qT5y2NVO4ZFlIQy8JIaPN9SxS6letWbNPEu2maFZ1b/ci21SDBwkTzXmH9XvIq18mevXN930hA1n4h2qtt8LNiT0Lya60y0xgSNyXWVSa9tFEfbtsLHRci7cUpLqDtYoekhLw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ganges", 
		"option_b": "Yamuna", 
		"option_c": "Godavari", 
		"option_d": "Tungabhadra", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060143", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xr35MGrEFnAU43eKXKdxYnTnFKTNY+Drx55yJkiAglU78HPStKD1+RMbh60bxI+TcSACbMtsx9Gaw6T2ynUBMsJOlYl87ZQYPPVSyTy+NN3VYP9gzWeFKVGwczCwAWMr1rsSSo5NcvZKowzq1p6Bd+U=", 
		"answer": "24K9e4X2wxeq0I0hRg2wMYnA29Q7qBdoTk5kPQ2krQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE1Ar+8pcuEjn6xOnsdXzZF2pRp3aFVKp3ZX33FLfDff772td8JliMzVh0/3vTrazz9kcGgKYb64uLZycGcMt7wNXJ+uX7xXNAIYZHlYFh8NoecvAAzTmne93VKfBpjm+SIkTjJzW0D3U0uTDei25Xu4uv5yb3FPE20hszgoZz7IR8PdmbmYOW+ky0h0aB1HqdRLhqFl2XsoywGoYFRsWE25kxdIAZTs5t", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Thar Desert", 
		"option_b": "Aravalli Mountains", 
		"option_c": "Western Ghats", 
		"option_d": "Eastern Ghats", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060144", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF77y73SNG/YGmNRk22CVqZneDHhUaTDY+i+wZ5iM1ObhFh6/nrf46z951wdm6lV/c6bZTAKcIwv3NiMl8Pi1GVAc9ZBiIl94MVdDfB1CaNo2EA5B14abL8eUQ==", 
		"answer": "25C5e4X2wxeq2rVi9AIam6AduJIUQW/gpRet3Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Ar+8pcuEg7z1+m/Om2QLmMVq2aCEpNmcXXmR6+OLu7x35JjIljJj0I75n7D45P5+VcHlqlIpc6YcSsNe48vwNmaw+vlzXJAP4ZNl5B99o4ecvdFjDm4Zt3VJ756xmvAAFDgczj9FHVmnT7SynVY6Jez8Ge9W88l1B1yl4l8rc41OsOXmauW5lmtlA+HzzmrHuZczpeExEN2UO5PENLd", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Western MP", 
		"option_b": "Eastern MP", 
		"option_c": "Malwa", 
		"option_d": "Chambal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060145", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEg3r1un6OCvdAnAapnvDRqtxMH/sRrPKa//wiZV+MlKNjElisnnA47H48hMOna1aqYWRfzUNPop8iPuI2+35w3AecSm7UK6RUVpSm3i7cQRkZU0=", 
		"answer": "25i5YJD90B3jta7rtqPhZtxsPPIjHPcZJCo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzrt44uXQn8hfzsdUDRD2sfpH7DRaJnMGLqQLLDeuj6iZV0M0uMiFU75n7D44jx/1IBjqxSqZqQMDYLe8thx8Kd36T2ynUBJ85B2qd94JsJfeZJjCmiNMDTJb59wXuULwdjBw/DpFSflDYXBdIfebfp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mahanadi", 
		"option_b": "Krishna", 
		"option_c": "Godavari", 
		"option_d": "Ganges", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060146", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdW3VAnYEsXrDQaZmZnTnFKbRLuy+x5ZlMk6IgRt94HnIt6z15RMNirxM7IuRMDUCbJlmxtfJx+vgwWNSc89K2oF855MacuAA5TOpfdWEYv3aR1myusQQyf4gj9cKezM=", 
		"answer": "24OxZpX7yBiq2oo1XArzzPPsd4gzL4aHcFnWi/22aKlghWs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxBft9ocoUxrgxL3NPH3VESICpm2VV6c0cWKjVefMb/nr25Z9Z1qbglVv+3PU46f140QKiqYb/o+NYisNect/x8eMxfe30H4BOtJX2o599o4XPPVOyH2+e8HPKLIuynuFZ1H/JzCpFzB4mzLXnnVZpsOy+2evXN930hA1n4h2rcszKtKN3KzT6lT4kg6HnE2YRrlsCFXZmMG95VedqYwr9zXSZ+acZNIyW8ZwNEKdYNY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Aravalli Mountains", 
		"option_b": "Thar Desert", 
		"option_c": "Vindhya Mountains", 
		"option_d": "Eastern Ghats", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060147", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4IlXRngxO33PGjRDyIDpniKXa00dHjnFLPKa63uxoRlamqMiVJ4snXTr7Hl5VZPm6BJ4JiaMDIRd4Zu2tmFzru1OvuE5V2Z3g6UO70iFDiMEw==", 
		"answer": "25ixbNzU0Bft8pEpUV7wxO72Oynkdsjmli7UaHruMUFF2a3V", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj3gr+urMlVhfxhf7qOX/FEWdd43KCW614aTHhVbTHaq3xx9dlL1nJmEh+snnA46zi+F1Dz7xT+4eJdSZDd4Uv3NiMl+n+wDxmMshDn5R759odfedJwn8iacvE9azC+yO+xS/iP9R2", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Indus Valley", 
		"option_b": "Western Gangetic basin", 
		"option_c": "Mid-Gangetic basin", 
		"option_d": "Brahmaputra valley", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060148", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF71wPL4J2rAC2sSonPDRqZmYnDqWufBZuzsyJRlIk6Al15/smLOpuXz+FIcm6lXqY+NdSNDcY0v5dGB1vb213lVIccb2BHOQTNy4lnaecdGkSgJ9Oc=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJT9xRzutXleZ9pYJILO1Ttq/oT/kXM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hj544QsEh/gwPy/Om2QLmMZom2CQatgYnCjXbSCaOz325toZ1WHiV515nPC7+X99lgGga8b4JrfYzcKaoptxNXJ0evlhGVJNoZBiZRz5pYWb/xNyTO5NNvdYO1r2GuSJkmwbzivBn9mh3M6msZ1CLtH05HxM27HoAS4", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hilly", 
		"option_b": "Flat", 
		"option_c": "Rugged", 
		"option_d": "Indented", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060149", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3xj+4pchXl70wPzrIHnVQ2MSt3qHEqJnMHCjVqjXYOn/244xJVmdml5+/DbSq6Cw2Vwdm6AW3ouMZGIlbIRh3NmMxaTH1n5XOshHn8Bz6p5fTOFOxjyvOJTdL+16y3yJKUKwczG4RHdmmybCgjxZrsON8COyV5o01Rkmg5V9sopVeLNasIpBM4qzZjvtXLTM", 
		"answer": "24K9e4X2wxeq0IQuVRvmzP6/N2rDCmxT5eco/haF0WIqW5Ys0W9Puw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF1B3j9MUjRxLm0O/6dWTCCmUYrX6XV6c0eX+jQK/HLsPx24N5amuMnk871GTJrbH58kFPv7pU/4eRcydDf4VriMSB0qTH0X9LMsQI2oF84NoZcPtV3jS+fNHfYPdgjnqIIgXnYiqpAWJ61BbXhHtTvIq4tSW6R9M5giFWFJesAijmVKXdmfJf3zY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Western Gangetic basin", 
		"option_b": "Indus Valley", 
		"option_c": "Brahmaputra valley", 
		"option_d": "Indo-Gangetic divide", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060150", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEhPz1/b6MSvEC2dRsHCWRqtxYn+jVqjXYOn/244xKFrJmVN+snfUpqSw/F0AmKYb6J3fWyMPd4VoyY/LSxUozC/g9eRmwlSvELUrtg==", 
		"answer": "25K3bJDl0AvjtRT1JKDXsODEvhJiG9NVdq4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzrt44uXQn8hfzsdUDRD2sfpH7DRaJnMGLqQLLDeuj6iZV0M0uMiFU75n7D44jx/1IBjqxSqZqQMDYLe8thx8Kd36T2ynUBJ85B2qd94JsJfeZJjCmiNMDTJb59wXuULwdjBw/DpFSflDYXBdIfebfp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mahanadi", 
		"option_b": "Ganges", 
		"option_c": "Krishna", 
		"option_d": "Godavari", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060151", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXFnhhfn6I27cDHIcpnGXEqB1fXSjXanWYa34xpRkNByNmEly/HGGt631t1IIiuhU786LeCdDWZ5/3NGaiKbopIUqtigurHUkiLWpuNQT", 
		"answer": "25m3f5ThkT7r+YIlRhfxhev+OWfVGiIQrXvDXKxmZHmjdqLMaezyi+E1IEOnAvN4EjdMrgTzrJw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/3g7v5cUHUxD1wOn2NivGAm4dpmbDU61wMH/sRrPKLs/7x5BwKxyKjFZ+sn/It6qw8VwMmrsb4IDfZCoGPopozZCG0aTjzHQBFNNUjoFhpqFJcSylDb9DkJfrxCnkaTI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Upper Gangetic valley", 
		"option_b": "Western Gangetic basin", 
		"option_c": "Lower Gangetic valley and north Bengal", 
		"option_d": "Brahmaputra valley", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060152", 
		"question": "24GwbdH71Bj448UvVF76zO7rOnnZAGMd41aNVqp1MGbiR+fRZuzuzJMxJUXJhE9osn/Ls6ri41IBm+gWpMPSPW9OM8Yiils+PbcGAtTuqOZaHbJukMI=", 
		"answer": "26exfpThwlnr+YFgXxH81vLwOyvCAmsfsD0RS7/EXxAZAm02Q1EUiGCt", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH61Rzrt5EoUwqy0fX6dWjVDXYDonPDU7BkdXL3FKjELuX32oN+NVWKjFc723jCqqSw4FIcz65U+4OadGIBZ8tm3MPJ1Pbix3hAP4ZWk5Z39olTPONIxT6lNMPeMvsux2CGK1D1aTq4ADB2jXHCgnkWpYy15ii0WpolwRw8hcXsyrdxh92DnfY4nQlFAkfH", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ri,ve,rs a,nd m,on,so,on r,ai,n,s", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060153", 
		"question": "24GwbdHa3x3/5MUWUxL+wOS/NGXUQ3UUsGuGQK00V3DtU6LWZ+6+2ZtwLlKazUx+4HOGoLD841oZjrxe7c6KYysNecsihZ3Emqm6iTwBOstUloV/4ZQLb7Z2K6U0avXd8M+XIxNWK3Xb", 
		"answer": "26asZ5/2kRjk88UjXQ7iwO+9Kxk1/oeA1bP+Lsb2GYPalQ==", 
		"explanation": "2723f9Hn2Rz58sUyVxn7yvPsdXzZF2pRr3CUV7E0YnDqWqHDYuG+yphkK1jJj1478XrDorf18xMJgLob6puTZCsVf59mx97Jwvf+ynYBMcdXk4My8JUQcOcAwDSmcZTINPFgyy6BKUGwZDatFHVm1DjbmnBTpYa14TT5/KIMK5DpHtehgXEKrmKfzg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "st,on,e an,d co,pp,er", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060154", 
		"question": "24GwbdHgxRj6+4BgVhf30b32Oyv3FmgQsX6XEqJ6dDHwW7LWZq3xz9dlL1nJu1J19n7foraw9VYMjqVeqcPSPW9BXlfeOOYFXl9dSWUFSGagzQ==", 
		"answer": "26exa5Sx+aaDFo50ufXza3S6i+ZLhw==", 
		"explanation": "24exa5Sz0xzp9oglEgr6wL3vJ2LdAnAI43mMXac0Y372RqTHLuTwibBkLV2bjE8783jC47f18FoAgbsb/YHfZCoGPphg3cSBl+vxhGVJNoZyk4527IMeb7Y+DG18M0F6LgxrKD6/4bTk", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ri,ce,gra,ins", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060155", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVQ20DqniKXKJgdXWjXamCeuX7ido8ahHEwBnOL25nr957pMEbvtK6aVSb", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgkS/r+4klS1xWXIUYb4kff+0qsqn67P4i", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYWzxRHvt60hQB/i1fzxdWjFD3YEsXrDWqJwMHj3R+fNfOT5wJliZ12HiRt9/nnTsazj/1YLz6FVqZqXdWIqcI9625C/1uj7wWgD9YAn9KwCYUj6jZH4YU+Y9w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "In,du,s Va,ll,ey", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060156", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh2A/v5ZZgQRvg0/j7dWrDQ2MDt3qRW6ZnMH7lFOqPI6CzhNo8ahHEwBty/DbHrab58l0bz4FV7YeeMhOoVOrLRFIWrr5uHsbpPvE=", 
		"answer": "27a3ZZz2wxrvt4QuVl7xyvDyIGXZAGMFqnCNQeGF1+T+l7i2lDWMb8QVippB", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh2A/v5ZZgQRvg0/j7dWrDQ2MDt3qRW6ZnMH7lFKTNY+Drx55yJkiAglU783jC46b/+l4KnateqYeRMCMNfYJqxsTJ/urzzXB9PfpKqIlk4YgMPONF3jjtYNzeYPNvx2DAKkDxaSr9C3Y0gCPXhG9Gp5Gv9DOyW9R3yRtyv4l85Ml8OtiNmauW5lmtlA+HzzulQLh9UUOcp8vo/lCZpMIsuo2ZozPV5+T2iOyT99EEZhse/5Z6bEuwkuRJ+SQ8EcmmZRtO4qTkaVGtLim1Lgkc+8fmlmZg0Ic7Tik78l9vjIdfY4Bk04rh/DM8LMIqHD6qrFZUxppoHxGZZv2swmng5RUofG4jJYV5tCgn4QyTPVpqiGKZXxBfqI5f9tVZhw11eH1T3GHlkDrLgWmcc9Pq5pDzl/zxrq0j9Kw1aUKPOFHNWIQfZKfJKGky/uGeFOZLNo1iVzf1ONFu6Da5M5Oa23kA1cozLnDi52qYnMm1N2CtoN65j9pyVKsIM8iF/s6ltRzGbTDuYWiAY8+0XwfiD2793wdivhcw22EA4W7fGoBy9CoIjUK+dUpQmiKgZXGxmaxI64yNes4+1bX+1CQViuc4noi31Q8oQhayiGwDvYLfTFNCwEHYF84G0AAhAvQAGpKR8WKbmHPCSHlNe8v1DaGJxigIzerlhiFpt5VOUYmYKRXUmtMjxgPxDvs5R2bkpJH4JO9VC2oouqB+y+my9+K0YvayKXdmLwi+T+pL4NVQegc7Ah/UCSgPabW+WY8KQO5bknPFhUdcVX5HFkrD6bwJSQ2lpITJYG6eYL4RAwvsarAEB8f3QAfGO7GAxjTAB/+ImkO/RgYUsle7PR3JGu6VOQ0nCBCe", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "com,me,rce an,d co,mm,un,ica,tio,ns", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060157", 
		"question": "24GwbdHe0BHr+YQkW17zy/m/EmTUAnQQsXbDQKpidWPwFKPHY+zsypZlIljJmVN+snfUpqSw/F0AmKYb6J3fPW9OM8Ytc/tSpI1xSmD0mUIFoBWe3Q==", 
		"answer": "2565ZJj91hio9tlyfEHyWCnyLpTNw4v4ig==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQvj4YAyQV7x1/j+IW7UQ2wQt2qRU680cn72WqPDfOT72td3KE7JmVN+snfUpqSw/F0AmKYb6J3fWyMPd4VoyZKrf3bYGHMbphSfwddlPyn8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ka,li,nga", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060158", 
		"question": "24GwbdHywxzrt4YvRBvgwPm/N3KQKGMDrX6XU6h1MGbiR+fRZ/nryIN0IxyLiE9s93PI47H48hMth6FW6M6efiZDaoNqiMWZx+HlhGNENM9LlJMy65xfaPxFjHDgOZmWbbN8x3iFNVayruTKNF25yZ195irb9kjlKg==", 
		"answer": "256qYYL73xiq9oskEirny/r+N2PRB3AQ4VGYkmRRmdSNCcKsfxy24LE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR2RDn9slgeQz71vXxNCeQAmwV40uWXKR1cnniULXDLv/335JjNByIn147+3vWrLfk9l0bz69e5omNcTILd4huxJCP0uXj0WNEIIZNlMBm7J9fVfpExTyjNMfOIv1hwHqJKUD+c3X9BX5w1CXej3VE6I6++zOyW9R3yBA+hpQ4+Nt8Kdmb3LqA/Ey2gkaK02zRY7x2H1WNtMWprFDcrIM2sd6OsCLetOP4ibjA5MweYRxHrYN7I1Ky17oM9CssWMe6KAZEsfDYZEfoYDqqMQsP6omnOv7lGg8LPzn+15flsTZh", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Kr,is,hn,a an,d Tu,ng,ab,ha,dr,a", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060159", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH2Rj4t4ElQRvg0b3yNG/VQy9c7jLOErBxZGXvUarHYPntiZ58N1OanlJ5/nOGqquw9l0Mhq1V/c6LeS8GbckTJUp6dPK81juuGgctTyJk", 
		"answer": "252tZZD9k58/aTpN+JWeKkZuErciovk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHl0Ar+t7EoUwyywfjsMHnEQ3IDpmmGXLdxdDHrQarDYK3tzINlK1mEiFVv4TbCtqCw41xPhrxIqY2XcS4Pe4Vowd6Ol+f4ynVIJ89LlJMwrm0P66ns8xuDW+jlnv3Dew==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Hu,man,an,ma,ls", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060160", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hj544QsEh/gwPy/Om2QJHcbom2CRuN8cWKjVqLHYK31x5hmKRyPgkk7+2LV47Hi9lcKzQ8Vo+BcxJSQtkq6lCKgqko=", 
		"answer": "27a3aYLn0BWq9oskEhj91/j2MmWS21a0yPhsGu2PdQCvrJW8Pg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYWz9gzg9pchRlnhhf7wNHjEAm5RsXqEW6x6MGbiR+fQa+7xzpl4PVmNzV104DbPt7aw9lAbhr5eqY2QcTEXf4cvyd6Nl+L41nRINMgEjpJz4JMRe7RBzymkYt3PKft9jATl05miZizY0piT5rhxi90=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "co,as,ta,l an,d fo,re,ig,n", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060161", 
		"question": "25i5ZIbykQrv5ZMlVl7z1r3+OyvZDnIesWuCXLc0eHjtQKLQYuzwzdd3KE7JmVN+vzuL7ui9tdRrmviK35sZunMN1iwJE3A=", 
		"answer": "25KtYpDh0A2q54oyRg2w0LgvQwzEVqWtnNA7Q9Wi/A==", 
		"explanation": "25i5ZIbykQnm9pwlVl7zhe72MmXZBWsSonGXErF7fHSjVbSCb+O+wJl9JlKNzUl+9X/JreXj4kMfgLpP4ICYMDYLe8t/x8KdxKT4wjFmJsxFiIFmpvCrMuDVs79xZrJ2CAkYgf8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gu,ja,ra,t po,rt,s", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060162", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQF2cDrmzZEJtlk0Sm8//1dSnpkF3CTUo=", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgkQrz5JElX17zy/m/Im7DF2cDrT+kU61zdWXqV+fSYuz3x4QxahyiiEI782TDouX2+EFPh6FI/YGNeSECcstsx96P2+300GINc+tNnoR+4doecvAAwDK6ccabB/9gyWuULkawdzW8DX5n1HyWuHVVrcO44CuvXcw21Bw9mMd548x8NN6Y0eiS5kOthwrCznqYRrtlHVjV9ey66kuRoZItod+M8STa+Pj8g7iesOwCYQ0SvJNzd1KqlrwA9yR4UMawKBpC9uyQYFrjNSmvZxwc8MXl13hlisIdVWgmtBtDkYZEdoA+lr7hriY5M8gqGjKpplcAxpp4HxSXebi0kGv270YsfHQsdsidRKNEEMtXH+Zhzymjixhg", 
		"explanation": "25y2bITgkQrz5JElX17zy/m/Im7DF2cDrT+kU61zdWXqV+fSYuz3x4QrZ2iBiEh+snfUpqTjt0EKjK1S/4ubMCMNcJ5uxJCb1u35wnBNP4ZDiIF28ZsTcO0AxTOuZtHaM/dgyS6GNUr9J2voRHN51CXZynNArZH7p3LrFNk6gCE6k8dv6NsoOcWRmY+S5kq9kg+BnGudSbRqAhSVtNyv7k+F4JIqusmYsjfftOPxn/nHsN8FZkhQvpRzZkLw178B8SY9Edy8bVJi/+DFchTbISSvIhdd6t7zxnt70octHXs99xcGgZFZctNP2LXtuDY8Oo1rGzf6r0tXwoY8eBaYc7is2Wuk8Fk+fHQ4P8pZtCgmpE+OLVN3lWWPDCRQkMB5/9kXkwVvcS9SnXjnizGMwGOdc56jvdC8keew8uwzsqAqaW2PIlnKFqoda7TFM25xivmXDK9SIN9rFjDhONk3vCnrL5KB3DwJkMspLHKn9SSd0sjtKWCoupf3jdFyVLcJJcXK+8K0sVCHYizvJ3GaZd/nGQzlSjzs3E5xvx0s2mED/HDZHIx4/C5Nl3OgRlZwkynjaUCvtKxd4o+Pb5slwfSsyzMclPFhxdvD3BQvBwWpiH4DoIGcSlVZyFCWDMwOyg8vALhBFpPF5WiTmzaBGSlNa8G2U/3Xgy9FmsrlzmN4vJEDUMyHIQnUmMonxgPxCPM5UGb/pJ+5MPkRA2E6+74x3uSsstn3NfKqKCU+Zx/3e/1Y+5hQeBdvAwqdFy1ZZaruVZIQVfJG0GDekgMIU3AJDE7fu64NTxCjps3cd1bQV7kdHF7mZqAAAdqiDnTGIeSo3DXNRqiZhlP+UEJlWjKYYZEf5BHxdoD7ZB68hmZw+MjrIR0bUIsSfBP7dXn5oaaQDhQuPy8qJp5Gc0nQT1AikSzXLvVizagBYx0+AampHRABlwIPjCvbGllHvEleWaq/AFAmJ6xJYFgDwiSmGK4YT1zOkz9Kmlncyzb/aexKIl1jfnyDjkLzntJPi7/+g53BDt3kK7QYx4EXaLBUVtreClYdlLP36vX0HWk0A2NjPbSIXPfF8EzzENz1q82ayl1YzK1IIVopIHmYjIvN/D9pb6xBL3FEvnocot6Sdg+n3JsbbUyGFGLjIPZcCCDqGiIGNg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indus system and western Gangetic plains,Key area for historical conflicts", 
		"option_b": "Middle and lower Gangetic plains,Rice cultivation and high annual rainfall", 
		"option_c": "Brahmaputra valley,Rice cultivation and high annual rainfall", 
		"option_d": "Thar desert,Fertile oases and camel crossings", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060163", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCQuTt3ddYDmCH3BtT82THs7Xx+RMMmqRP/JyaMG9DPssv6ZnJ8+v6zX9AJ8NA2pR64do0feJF3jTtYtXXLPt38mDSZ3P1YzC+RHNhmCXDmHkW5cP7tWf7FJp3gFUQ38dM5do1KtKbmaGdqFmwg0aP1X/cb7xqFlGNvM3o6UKPqYwEu57NgT3I4LnPn/za854IdwRGqpR6Ixb814tAuAw0Xt2mYQFD9OCQaFqtNCCmZxkY6t/mxHop4YMnWmwg/RwGgIJFa85P2Myknzo/M8wqBTytplYAitQ8H1fWNP34kCikxBx/WmgiYoNjvTkwpU+VJhRqkm7cZSJVgZMryNEVmQF6P2houAP0tvmnhZWIjeENJ1E=", 
		"answer": "2+T1TN2zg1TJu8VzHzy+hamyFCnzOio+gd6SJ/m5G2djDe/P", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRjkt4Y1Xgrn1/ildV/YBiI5om2CQrN1fjHgQavWe//7iZhjLluAg1pv93KGqquw41sKz4FV7ZuMMBQCcodq0eyH4eHzzXIBMNNIjpVg4cBfSPxFjAuocN3YYP17wnqVNUCwYTWyEWJ9hznTjjxfpsOv/SL7Q98k1BAgmMdf7MY7OcOW2uiR6V6xiDqM7HSCXPBSFFCQto6r/k+ItZA97425uTeb5PvqjrXl9doCYUhRqoprdkm517wB6iMuVMz0YRwL5ezVIVnkJGWEJgAa/N/q1TRrx5EgU1U61xdJjoIWcs9k04q+/AY4Oo1JHTy2ogRQyIN5TVeSe7Cx3mnw5VF/YXIuJaFsqignqE+KKVhyn3Lesbh8E2n9ryHazgL18lOsIQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-B, 3-D, 4-A", 
		"option_b": "1-D, 2-A, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-B, 2-C, 3-D, 4-A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060164", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDHPXbTWLsTXidcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz5RVuM60cS4KcIxuiJ3Jl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypLtfWvFS2DShcZTLLP9nwH3ALlfibj68EHVw1DPPylJXuo668Sb3FO420Bx+1qp55cFwfNaR3eig6U+5lAuDyHKtRu8kMFqdvdypq3OOoYY9psXN/HL5tNf2m+vH8dJLYA1eq8Z9Zk+rkq0HuAc5Wcm6aRZCseXeZRTKLyyiMQ8P8PfthTREx4ooT2gn/AtUg8MbIoAzltikn3ISMNhkETa+40ZZh7d0XhqUdbH0kFvr7hl/Q3MlYYJ0vWF1oAGYaHp/iGadSC1tmtQr2cUTlBZiaS8N3Dagwn/LwCXPPNOjq8DYxcD5s61s4KokKE3APFHIWZ8IZL3DIidz2amaTa5VPYtiBS7nM9Fu+jbrYLGB1Tgf0c1gP3j14DnbewTRUEojSdQ+AJHUE+DLHQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T1St2zg1TLu8VzHz2+hamyESnwEIz1JSJkTR5zNgBcSWyf", 
		"explanation": "2565ZJj91hiwt64hXhf8wvy/PHiQF2oU43yMU7BgcX2jVqLOeq38zINmIlmHzU9z9zbroq3x+VILhuha54rfVy0Hf51u2tnJxe3hwWNSD8hllIR69ptfTOZByDi+fI6bFPZn3S6SIkL5aDf9B396hzjFnm8Wp4X78yKpQNM7xVUimoZx49t8NcWN0K+S/Ei8xgSbnG+ZTf1KEEaUtMqppwOooZIx+Y2gsDrSuLT4lPyTw98JYxpfvpJ2I0m1ga0b6xY2fMm8aQBK4uzEc1W3YAG3ZwcOucnsw3ptw4ZpX3B04BdDwqBeY81x15SkvTw0f/5lG3OoqlJF1Yc8SxjWYLW9kH/h80F/dHQvJZ5luW0DqAGYIE1/2mqSSGx/lZJm/9QY1RZqa2pSjzb0jX+fiGDPb5z2/4jAi8/lqrhx87d9aXWIPE+YRIgbbLzOZ29z2amTBLVIPI1uFCPqfdwj7DbrNJea3DxN0cpgLjfv/SSNl9/5OGu+85T2nJRRAbUBJNDRqdu4okjUI1lOXGPKvh8rBIC90R4BkDc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-B, 3-D, 4-A", 
		"option_b": "1-D, 2-A, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-B, 2-A, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060165", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCQuTt3ddYDmCH3Bte82XSprf+t3QHjrxIqcPfMGJDPssviPHAl8z+ynVTMshHn8Bm69occ/lN2TOkd9XPKfFgjmyFM1L1Yjf9B391hyXXhjxXuoa65me6Wt537RQ6l5V5/sAoLtbTmYOS+kO5kgeJ3TfRY7h2EFiYicD6q3SZs5Y9p8PNljra4Oe517iTsJ5LIkhw9sY/QFS9hLwI9Go5Q821KAVC5eyQclH7JTqiK04V+Nnh2WF71cIoU2105BBUlpBqbJMz9Zf2sz8xMclvGXO5rEVT09QxHzTfNJu00Wbv5VF/d2Nrdp5orD51tgaIIBRsk32ZXmxehIVl994ehjhtKS9tnXrhgD6ZwGaAfYD3q828xaiw4PkjsoduaWWJI1XcU55ccbvFZ2Jz2f2eH6gcMJBmBDamO8ch8Xn2NJ6RzXkd0cs0PDfo8mq4nMn9K2T6spz9zuB3GbYMdv/E7d71dShBFeaU4k7oTfstyzCDVA==", 
		"answer": "2+T1S92zg1TLu8VzHzy+hamyESlZpBN0GGl4bM9fVr6pK3XT", 
		"explanation": "25C5e4X2wxeq0I0hRg2ohcn3MHjVQ0UZomuQEqJmdTHlWKbMZej6iZVoZ0+diEtosmHPt62w5VoZirob5p6afisNeZhTxueMxPDy1n8BFM5FjpMopK4XebR3yS65ccbVYNlmz3qTZ0TiYnm8RHh9mjXEi3JVrcOv+me4W9c61Rs7lYZs5McyfNWazb+W7UP4hQmDz2+QRP1lA1GYpo6p5UfcjYMwtN+MojrP5vW12tPS4tAKdglZvso/YlW414MM6is0UPS6Sx1Z/unRb1DoLGigKA8O7ZGj4nxg1cIqUmgn4B5KwoJEZ8Ez3pn3/CE1Kch4FD/6q0VSxZtpTQTWdbO8kHjr8kEsSXQGZIZsviwn4QyTKUdqwCuoRCkRuYFn/9IYh0Rgcm5TiDbkiymChGCcPIfr7sD5hPvkpattsqAoKFKUdVrKWYBcaqfIInUy2uiJGbUcPJknNiziNccvvDj3JNag3jQE3JkOLnPytrewNKGLlgcOZ5HKZUD3x7E=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-A, 3-B, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-D, 2-A, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-B, 2-A, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060166", 
		"question": "25mxe4Wz+Fmqt8VgEl6yhb2/dSuQQyJR4z/DEuM0MDGjFOeCLsH32oMxDnW1gwo71XfIpKDk/lBPjalI4IDfPWJDPssviJDJ9q237XxRPNRQm45mpJMRPPFB3jG0NNneJPdr2G+MZ1H5ajyuOH4m1BjYjmlF6LW6+Su+TZp6gFVy1sc4rYh8fJff++HT3kyrkkaDznKVCLh8AVWXpsvo/EqIqMI3tN6Iog7Vp7TNkvnBsNoOcQ1Aq8YyIxv81+hJuGp4EYj0KFJouKT2ZEb5KSSmZw8T/Yvx33dhhosnHXs99xoGgZZadsll14ztszwMMZkqNyG7q0lB14FoTRbWYry03G39oBh/UTNrJahkrjk9sQOdK1E+lW3cZC1DlZB7/95ZlhFvaXpSmTSAXKQE+0rsagV3d4oYeoCk", 
		"answer": "2+T1KLK/kUun08lgAVPQib2reCvxQZpvdu6xb0bSDCzhE82P7uk=", 
		"explanation": "25K5Zpb2xRDpt4chQRf8n73UO2THDSIXrG3DW7dnMHfmRrPLYuTq0NdwKVjJn1J4+njDsLaw/l1PnaFY7M6cZS4Xd51u3NmG2dj57X9FJtUErIF+6J8GJrRixS+5fMTXIf1rjmGGZ1H4YnmVBWJ1hCHXhDxVvY+v4DW+aNQDyBQg1oN9/s0uKI3f+qCS+ky7kgOQ1WGUTP1mCBSQod3o/UKPtMI5p8SJ8TfD5PX3if2T59cfakhdvIV+cFKzmakFuCU5Qs2nVBxp4+XYbFX9NTyxJk4L+Mfv020zhqUoVGcx8F9Pj5NZcNRy2Jvh/Ds+f8hrBz+j40lFw515SRaaNKmx3W33os2IxX8IbSP7SebBU9Dbs0A=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1-C, 2-A, 3-B, 4-D", 
		"option_b": "1-D, 2-A, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1- C, 2-D, 3-B, 4- A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060167", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snHDrKLi9kMHhqta5c6ZdSMXa5lq25CG0aT/zWJVPNRNmYF+pLMReP1BjDyjcJTPKPtn3C6JKlXxZC2uRHln1DLZmG5Tq5fhySmHWot39B031q526d0vfNaR3eiH4Ej4kQORyH6DRv1DEFqesNqh6AOMrIMxu97NpjfJ8bTqj/HH8dwHZ0hUsJQ/YE6wg6Ef+T4xXsb0fxtf+aTDdVvjJWiiKQpd+sTzxnF7hoskTWUx+RpIlpAWZtV2lozr/CY4OsR4VT+1tEFSh5VyUQKXeP2q0WHq5lQzeUYlWYQ//Bk9pE++OlV2l2qMWThDlcB9/9wVkB0jem5JknPkwi+Zj2iGcpbt6IW8gf3iqbdksrcvLAGoNE7ZRp0da/PDMmtm3/ueMahgPcwnIyrjfeEm/Su5JJOH2isZkN8hLH7r/T6YhsjxeWC7oIu5hsF7FbFAJdTR/ceyvVnJdTChKHPTZ8X3UA3+Wzzs2gNgpFgh3SRQ/G2YAZ1stSsIjGq5RU1wi2VJT/lMnF5aAHF1fBxBKxZc", 
		"answer": "2+T4Z5//yFtqIB4th9O9apMH4n7ZyUrT", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYWz0Avv9pZgXhf5wL3rPW6QKmwVtmzDU61wMGXrUefVa/7qzIV/Z3uIg1x+5n/F47X89loBnOQb/oeLeGIPcZxq2pCI2erixX0BIcdNlIZz6JZTPPdP2TGpNNbeYP1iy2+SIkGwYTavRHNhmCXfnH1CoYy1tTKoXdQwgAYmmYl9rckyOJec1riD7V/4jwuS0H6cTbNwAhStvcvo5FeUpZB4ptmMpTfW8frtibjS4ttLbAdG/5Vqc0uzhbwM/Go6SIigYBcL4eXDclXqJWp7WuPdjm5sIT8VcuvFYiyZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 and 1", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060168", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+sn/Ls6Tz40BPgK4b4YeMZC0Rd4huxJCg2eD+xTZSc8FBlYdg5YoXZbRJ332ue8bJJf16lFKOG0uhJwu0EnVmh3HGhn1PrYf79GeoXd05yRM7lYZ2+YguM9uamaGdqEy2hQ+H0m/RYbNgGFWX9c2n5k6Jros7tNmEvjyb9fr92vvc/dMOcAtX/4JqZhuomOgd8C94VcGybhtI5OjEeBTiJmihMgcR/cLt0TR7yYMtTlU6yBEUwrdeZ4B104rwtT41f91mFDq0sARPwdRRXh+XZryr2Hz24RUocGguJZp/tSA0swaQMRR3iHmVSy1FkYQr/MlZgQxmPURSlWXojD7LgWuLPKf25Yf9h+DxpKtisrEuP0SSJmDWaoNPUbvFZ0pzxuiZDLQcMJBmBDahLpUt8zT0NZid3DgZ2dYub2Du4CLZk8n/Nmy0upz+ztVkEb4TdsbE+ou/uVLDZDHkJT2Rf4vgUQ2wan3rxwt3uVgCwCAE+yB8LHp8BjoRtul0C4UvWYik", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "2523f9Hh2A/v5ZZgQRvg0/j7dWrDQ2scs3CRRqJ6ZDHxW7LWa/6+z5hjZ1+GgFZu/H/ForH5+F1PjqZfqY2QfS8GbIhqiNSc0qTjyzFVO8MEmYhz6JYacvNFjDKrNNfULu163HuDM0z+YHmvC3Fwh3H/njxXpJC0tSq+Ws4+zxsh1pNw7Nx8P9iS1L2d4U65kg+N0mjRSrhwBlGcu46840bcjYM0tM+Mo3LY+/XqjrjS/tpLYxpXvpU/b1K3kugk+SI5Q8mnYAZZ8KTHZEboYCWiIwtd/cLl0H1q0449HWsttAtOh8NGcMVg05bnuXI/OY1+HTb6lEFT05FuUVexfLyswySk7lorNW4jYMpIvT4hpB2SaHN2m3+PDB9FlZRu89UXgUQxPWZT3H/ugTCZkmCMaNHGwqTdtMh2GpZOEdn26Tdz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060169", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snHDrKLi9kMHhqta5c6QYisEd4V8iN+Pl+z+12VOIc9Hm4wy548TaOFSyS7tfcebI/F83GuDMx/MaQWzVTBAnDSWvHlSoYD79jK3QM8lxVU9hI5/5MY9KNKbmaGdqFmwg0ar0n+EW/1SEFiVsNeU5X+S8sIMvcjNmTPJ9eTpm/aT88sHdh1AusZwcVK7nqYI7C88EcG6KAZD9KT+bkb5KGWUIh0Jue3x2Xp9z4c7HVkm+wlPjIBTXs5P2MukiDo1f+5iGj+741RP0JFuHxiEfbqx3mnw5VF/fHRrcYJo/AY0twqOIRRom2eQSTUTv0yFS5K+y5SYtNxNbn6E3A==", 
		"answer": "25u3ZpSz3h+q440lEg3mxOn6OG7eF3FRom2GEqB7YmPmV7OAJCnGPfNll0TFHXc9P/MQVA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF1B3j9MUjRxLm0O/6dWTCCmUYrX6XV6c0eX+jQK/HLsPx24N5amuMnk871GTJrbH58kFPv7pU/4eRcydPPp9nzZCh1vb21GFAPYZHj4xm8YgaPPtSxTqketXPJfoux2DAM031JxCzAGVn1AfXhnBTsc/79Cm/FM4/xVURnoh07IgsM8Cay+iX50CxiAeW2X/RXLVhUX+Yo8u64gOKoY40sNTNhTre5vH/lerWvJ4FbQZX/4l5I0+0kugO8Tw9X4infBNf9OnVb0D+YCmxIk4e9tnx03d9hPeVPQcD/39nDdb3v4QJWDM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "None of the statements are correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060170", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snDJsajx41oAgehU786Pfy4KaoJsydzJ1eviynVAIc9BicB76toXdedUwy+kd9XXYNdgymeBZ0zjJzqyFmJxlyWMtnJqptL7wS++FPslwQMzmotxrcUzKdmL2KGd+w28jxCL2H6VCKlsFBSctN287lGS4IM2sY2atCHP8eb32ujS4soYIgdU/69xZ1K9q6Y19nh4ZcCxKCZD8PaQZVH+JTq3Zw0P/Mr303Apx8InXH0h5h5KwoFZd85314r9/DA1K9pvED36t0xFh71yWwKFNLy21CjD4Vs4cG4iZsp+pT4hpAKPFFpClDjceCRU1Kt598MRmwUjb2ZWmWSggzyfhWHPfYCj6sD7gOf3srhz+qokKE3AN1PNWIkdd6qAJWJm3eyeA+ZxMpdmBSP1NcE8/Xn4LpLU9Dgf3tg0Lnzmtov6L/q/umDTGi6ZoAnJzJc=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwxj89oksW17/yujxIWrZDXFRp3aHEq17ZDHnXbHLaui+3Z90Z1mInk9+4HiGoqv0t0QKnLxe+4DfYCMRapgvx9bJ/urzzXABB85B2qFg5YwecPhJjDCiYdrPIfdg3S6SMkuwdTaoA3h4jXHGi25XpI+++WevW5ojyBBylYh5/tx8M9Hf/r2Z6V+5kkaD0n/RerxuEEeNvc+mq0qS4JU9ptmIozyb3fr9k/mTxNYOe0hTrYM/bVSo16sG9j4xX927fQEHseXeZRT5KC26ZwoSucXswjRvyZAkHWh0+h5Sl5FXboBx2Y3quDMiJo1oECetpkFOh4B0WleTda6s1XrqoFQxcTo8YJl5uT874R+dOkBt2mSaDAVfkIlqwt4tnQEjSWdBjjbkhyyOknHPeJrnq4PugOnkpflisq0mPVSSNFCYVIIJa7fBNX4yyOyPGqNZPd9zHyemFNsq6Sq5IZiQnx4M3t4lO37ktDmAgdnwNHb6h5r8zuB+Fa1AMtTW7Nmj8FXUIS/uInyHY8+0UAawQXPqxwZysgsxzTMeqEvWDIB+tSwDmj6ASE9tgTPhYjyIgv5V+cKPP4IwwfLpkXIRiv1834ny0xQzSUSvhX5X8o2MD09K3VXEH9kCwEkoHrsMVILZ9y2/m3LFWDwMccq2JqmJxClc0+CxnGhruoJORpWdOBzWmZ4k0VelCfg5dHXsvof1MfVVB2s59KZww+Oy9/6zcLOQJGQ4Lx6ySupL59VZaRE7Ag7PEyFLILm9FpxeT+Fbx2fLm0dKSGpHAVve4ugKWBC9r8HGLn7WZvEIGRGicboTFty4XV7cIfSk23DPCa3clkKwS1E3Rz+OHb457QKwUZ77Nxu9kih28NfgIBFfTYdXPSTnNGqq5aLDDAM1eD4kOIJOeUbZCxIrgTDHJut+zaUFZA8oRKbnNFEelwNOjDbGHFkFsUIaH46sUl0mPqhOIRslxTL1OrIWTxTEh3oYh0CZ0GLlOrpHPkoib2GXz0Xu25Fjkev7g4LBI9rmJLxb+5lDLrpUU4mWC1MOlebj56H0GWl5FXl2Ov3bHu3X8GL3Csnmo9DS0U5Khf4jN001JC2Kgp6VsDtjK+VuYXRCr3JZnNjTZgO50cht3VUoe0fl5knqQCczvwd2fNPja86cOZ635lVbViXUF7gDn/l32j7lJdfYZxszR2E6hAmUd8DThzaGKbv+xaNJKBmq1ovKVoJ5/kk5z9K2g2dBuTV0m33pCjbcbfWt6xtaNmlqQrGMWCAiDvcUvEgfT1y4fqMYV4M=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the statements are correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060171", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+smTDr6Tk/lwBnKBS+c6ddTYUe45hiMKAweHl1zFAPcIEm45x7Z8RaLRTySm5eNHWJfB63S6JNAXzaCuvAXNgzg3YtnIH6Kq25SipQNs51FUmmZB2/og9MtPf2qmD4Vm5ihXOnHeYQ7gkOVWKocem6lOJssI5u8nNgSDa7fX+1rjE9cwOIhtbq5N+d16416ke+TN4V9q7ZVJf+eGQY1XjKzvjKAhd7cPmlmZg0Ic7TlU6yBEUwrFfdMVhxdjzuSA1f854ADCzokgAwZtuHwSDZK20yWHq5xUodG4ud8p5s202oAGdJEc+mH6IDChYkMBl8cRZlgV2bmoAjHPyizCPiWbPep/s5IT1i+/MroVtoeMOJwGQJ1mVX4MYcKDUNW5zxqmPBKtZINMnAy3xM8Zu6zzrJdab2S0I3pksIHTm4C+d0sL7eXezpZfrztZ3GrQTdtDL7Yu9pVLEdSruL27TYt7xGRz/D2jq0gB2pxc33CAE4W3WSIh74ywDin+3TFcm2bTLiUYACHFnZopwM3q7Xw==", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "25y1eJ7hxRjk48U0XQn81r3+O2+QAGMBqmuCXrA4MH3qX6KCRuzt3Z5/Jkycnxt6/HKGk7fx7lIIw+hM7JyaMDEKap5u3NWNl+XgxWgBNdRLl8Bm7J9ffvVOxy7te9KbNPZrjnyJMUDidHmJDHln1CLCi2hTpYa14WeyR5o+zhY9hJV97tx8FdqP1rqH6UOsxhKNy3WCCLxqFRSatN6h/0KQs8Ixu42MvzHS8frt2tHd9NcKIh9XrYM/bF2okqZJ9CU7UNyxbFJE/6TEaVGtIimtLB1d9s2jxH1/w5A6HV08/QwGi5AWYMVw1433uXIiNttvByD6s1ZP0Z14WhPWdf2r333241B/enxrcot5uT954Q7cJVF/lHjcQyoRgJJq8MMJmhZ3fHtJk3iswj6FhCWOPJ3i/5XuhOSwpLxl9600LAGBMl3RWJ4IJbLUM2Zxwam9ArQcNodmGjLqOJlu6DH8YJWdyyBN399gB3b04COXk93gKyWtsoG5gtt1FasFMpHK54ujuFmHYyLvKm7Tac20TQD1D1v53QlgpFg3wTcV+i6YCYd7tTkFmz6zQFB90ijmLEyzl6dd7cKZfp1x3/rv3CYVnLR5i9vj3Bh8RAu1i3NWt4qcShxAyxTCFshH4wggC7ESVJff9i2vlHvFRX1NbcfgBLqU/yJ60/X0nHI9qJUcUMyNPgzYg98qiBG+E71qQHf9pJ/wM/tVHWU4/6Ax3uLhtMu1dP+3bGc/e1qzUOsZ/ZpFKAF6BBjYRTRKcrGhUpQdAeZD3XrOnglPB0tBDEmM6LwJSQGnr8rcLmPNI6EdHArrYr8JCo77QVXdMPK9iALAELqOhgepWlYgDjOTJbUI4UfzaJnxLRK/025r64H2J0FLSJoeMiCzY2qtoLHDHwl6fC0rKYZUOm/aXBUykSyPZ+tum6ISY1gsTbuoWVMXgwJKm37CC0pMv0gXXOWrTFwoLqBLJxslxT6mUaYTUxPOjzQNzlWT1y7oafhOcU0maHCBmk/0koRj07/rl5rBA8CiLrIO3olDKbpIS9rUGhsen/3h6ejjGG01Rmt4PLjJWfDYs1r6Ft3mp4P8yk4LzKYJO083IHXLnZfcsDxhIKpLZn5N/Xwf7N7aZ0aD14xMxhB6WUPp5wHgRHcupRhna5eredTQPtux+FFLVinGU7wDjPR9nT/rPNORYh8tE2o5lDueX9yK1yaGcKX1xLgaEQqr1pWLUYNg6Vs1jsi91EJT6yxwnXmiBHDOZ+mt5BFXI2h9T/SQFB1PjwEnx3qz313jLs+riaJJhKVP26Ea7gLk4iVjih6YQAracXLkzeaRpXLHqk4ux+piWHCiVWdsyQk3BMQj+2ouUzkgXaR5ubjhbLjX3mKgPI69zphNzFgUVrXPYrS1ucDvMbHMLqmszYmOKmGtsYdmE/u8ZckAMnONazsLobC0bovHbB2WOCuL3PuKGz2LN2BZ73dliSKPWhwsJ3W9SN1UEThB0IBzILgEt8ukpEJgb2+AFr5r2LUAlFVKTEdcWPmhkXxdF+p2OICIMkt//lgPGeAHfmyjYEV4J9RT2XD0cS657juvw6p8C8HikRF9aArayiGJd2ac5+00Pj6kUdHVzYWNAxGrr/pgR15Cta9dnQCeRn0fciV0phnUgOQjGFiCalA+N+gX1ZwfXtf0ogwBmNJnEQgIbDnIETu6HouEQN0OGJLi1Lcor4lezj5GR4ELd5yOQlbOnHuDHi5QeQJHfkeWkR7x6Js/pu75bQdDxn+Ti1X473Tz3g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the statements are correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060172", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdTxMX7DQ1QQr3OGS+NjcWKjR7LLeuz8xZIxIVObzVhu/mLPtaTk/lwBz79S/YbfYzYMcI4vyd6Nl+f41GFEIYZNl5B+4ZcacuBT8DOReubeIe1hwDTAE031JxCzAGVn1AfXhnBTscOp8CS+XcwyxFU6n4Bw6Np8LtaW166S5EH4hQmPzHqDTbkkBVvZocatq2SdroU9ocSO8TDa5/332IPlQNiaqMWNMuwVG/L2beU=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHjtV6jQfOj93dUQgC3NJ0H/k1gNqikK24fP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3/5MU2Vxn30fzrPGTeQ2Mfpz+TXbBneXPvTefWZui+3pJiM1mbgxtc83jBprH59BMZiq9e/Y+LeS0NPohg3dyNl+byhHJNNsdWn4Qy4pUNPPdVwCmkYtXPKfFgjnuTLkv3JyqpC35x1DDYjjxVp5Or8DX7XdcnzBA/k4ls/ogUM8Caz62BpA2sjgPC7n6QW7JqUV2XtsG6+UaftI4h9d6ZsCbe57TtkvnHsMoDZ0h7sYJqcBuKlqQF/TN4Q823bRtd9OCQaV3qKC2xZxwc8MXl13hlhKiEHgK8SUfS+vQZDVfLyTQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060173", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYBfkwO/sdXzVEWdRs22KX6JmeX36FLLRa+m+z5hjZ1GAgVJv82Tf47Hi9l0cn6dJ/c6efiZDcIR7iNaGxaT0y3xMNtRHn8B76toecvdJyTO5NMDSLft98mC8KXf1ZiqyCio0oDnTym5fvoaptTW0Qc4y01Uhk5Vu6Mx8PcTf0KWD51+shwiWnHieRbBxH12atNqh5E3coZAssN+EtCGb8OH82uzcsMoDZ0hWtoB5alipm7wQuCU+EcqhYR5P+OrXIUbiISywZZsjfmC4ZzbgQArnszlD0g8=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV77y/7wJ3nVAHZd432WRuNGdXDwW6mCZ/6+yphjNVmKmRnP7LdkhVlMSIQqZcTyPI9j", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB1Bj5+ItgWw2yxvLtJ27TFyIQsD+XWqY0YHDwR6bFa63zzJllLlOHnhtv+nfS47f54VYdz7pU/JqaY2IUe5lqiMWa0uC3wn5Tc8RLjogy6ZMTdeBB3iTtddrfYP1hw2OFNUb5ZjX9EGJ1miLGhW5C6Ieu8GevW5ojyBByko5+68E/KduLwOic7g26kw+O2HKfT/12HlWdpo6A5FSZtocq+Y2ZuTeb1efqn+rH+dEFIgFcvIltcV6/g6QQuDksUNyxe1Jf+eXEIUbkNi2xNE4K/NnmlmR7z48oT2A47V9TkYZSIsZ8xNjptT45K8x4DHOusUVO1IRzTQPWe7O0ySpGEZZ6JfRtO9dKJzGA0LQt", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect, but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060174", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd/tNGPdAnIEt22CErV1fH3mTefVb/6+2pJlM1CMiRt+82TKuuX5+RMOgatS7ICLMDYKc458iNSc0qTjyzFIJ9UEnIVg8JMTebRTwzShNNXVJL5oz3iPNUTyazz9B3x9mTDCj0BYlI2J8CaoW9RtgCE6k8da/8k0MdaPzLyB6Q2uhwqO2WLRX7x3UUeQodup/0aY4IA9odqItDyb4Pz82tXS+N8FYwxb/4dxZxuon61J3yU8UN61ehsL4+3GZEb+YoZDD96oqQ8jhFlI7ZqZPEA=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6eSvSFnZRt3eGEpFxcWLsWufLfa34yJtiIhyIg1879nnDsOX++EdPjKdJ+4ucZC4aPo532NyI3uq30HlEc+dXiYVg8JMQcra5CvSolDMXW3o39tIdzFvw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStz+3WqY0UmPiXKrDfvjq25YxMV2FgV5isn/V46n/9FIbiqwb4IDfZCoGPoVg2sSB0uXk0HRTPYZUm5JmpJUZPN1OyDSsOJTaLvoux3rALlawaDe4RH9y1CXejzxbp5CvtSG+Rs4+zBByhIJ/5McyL5eW1+iH4Ej4hQmX0m+DUf1QGVHZo8+k50aF4Isr9cyBoj2b//r2jfaT9tEZIgFGrMZyale416sF8Sc5Rc34KAVD+OfYIV3+YCusKQoI+sL10zR9ycIoWns99wpKlpZEZ/x96pbQtDdwLchrBjy0401Th51yXBiEZri7xCjQ6FB/V2gqbYdsrDghsw7cPlVylm6FDCVC1I5k6pAKnBB2fHtFmDbihyuchWCBPIfr7sDRhODxrrhn++MmJ0XAIVTdFqoTYbLWJnV7ivuSG6NOIN9THyemENQm/Tf4JJ/UzTAb1ctgJmSn+CWak9nwPSWzvdL6i9piBr4MdvjL7cK2/BzGbyehNXWWJuz7XQnmTm7xkxxsoR03iCgDqG7XC4hr8ClNl3DwWktxhi/lfnLhv7BY44POS4Y0k9f+3DodmeRti4n2lA81UQGpzXZQ8oiQTF1byFCWF8NH0AErTLoOBoLZ92yFgXPCRTwdftziQaeBgwVG3urwwiF8sZROXJjOJQqbhNEyiBS+D/N8VnPorMbtMrwBAmFs17N5y+Ogs8P7euHkC2oubgy2S+YZ4ZxHbRBoU3OmSJTJS7YdE8nSyh7yrZ0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false and does not correctly explain the Assertion", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060175", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hcn3NHmQB2cCpm2XEqV1c3jvXbPDeuj6iZ9kKl2HzUh+5mLKpqj1+Uccz6xO7M6Lf2IKapgvztWbw+37wTFOMtVBibx82JQtefVTwzP3NODTJb5axm+SZ0H1dDyvEDBjlSKWhnNVqZe+8We5Uc4gxRA81pNw6IgVMtOKyuiS5kn4oQeM236FQb4kAk2Kocul+AH75L9UXB9Yijgn/4/UUSXh", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV77y/7wJ3nVAHZd432WRuNGdXDwW6mCZ/6+yphjNVmKmRnP7LdkhVlMSIQqZcTyPI9j", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYOz1Rz58pc0EhPzwfi/PX7dAmxRsHqXRq9xfXTtQLSCZ+DuxoRiLl6FiBty/DbHrab58l0bz7xS5IuMMAoMaY55zcLFl/D/wTFzNsdXlY4y7Ylff/tS3jiuYJTaM756xmvAN0TjdDi6ATBngDDCj28WvIu64WevXN93wQc3l8d66NwrOdKRmbyb7Q2RiAKXzzuQRrkkNlWXssu84kDcs5srociAonLS57T9k+7a9NsPIgpL/5J3Zhudhakf+SY0WIi5ZwdF5eXZb0ehYCmtI04J8c6j4nxo1MItWHox5gsGi5AWbs9w14zhuHI5MY1+HTqp41ZFwJ1zUVVwtEpQgp/Uf3huLADbJl6Q", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect, but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "060176", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfTyJWTCF2MfoHrDXaU0Ynj1UbXRLuvx29dyKFGEmFVy8XfSqqr+t1IBi+hY5oOSdTAAe8tsx96d3uriwXUBPMhIg8Bn6o4WcLRUxDjtcNXCM75hyC6UL0CwQjiuEDBdmjXfizx1p46r9CmiaNQLzic3l5R345J8CN+amaGd/ki2kg+N0jueTv1wGVHZptqt6k7cpYw/vMOI8T7e8LTtlbjH+NtLZg1Rs49xZhuzkegb8Tw9Q4igehNF4vTfc0CveHhvEiAp8uwzfK5RRH8fOg==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7xyu/tMGjETyITtmvDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuTwyphjNVmKmRn5LTdgcDgk+ptIIVXowem3", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyzO6/O2TEQ2cft3aRV69tMHLsRrXHbfm+y5JyJkmaiBtp+2DDsbaw9kEKz7tP4IKTMCsOboR93NGHw6Txy2MBMMlJl5V87ZkeaP1Pwn2setCbI/Fjw2uSJECwbjf9LX5wnTCWnnNSqZr71CuvXNUixx1yhIZx4d89JcTf2KaXqF6sgwePz3OYWK4kEEac9cOn+UbcpYQ+vM6EtDzPuLTtkv3KsN8ZZ0hcsJI/YlerlrEauCsuUMG4aRBH9KTfcxTsJi6sNQoc+8fmlkZg0Ic7Tik15hoGkZdfbswzw4vhuHIkMI1+BzK0sFRP1YA8WBiZcK740WbgoEU6emonYMpksm0npAKTPFE+m3mZTT8d1IFl+pANnQF6PW5SmTbhjiyEwHCceZej7Y/uxfz/tatq4a5lxHybkLA09tSus70o3vhqnA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Emergence of India to Rivers", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1xjp44oyEh39y+ntPGnFF2cV42uMErd8dTHkRqjVeuW+xpExI1WamVJ18WKGoLD840YdjqQb/ICWZDFDd4UvzNmP0eHlwX9Vc9RBnYl96olfc/IA5TOpfdWEYmXxAffn29NnrnvqQItxm0g=", 
		"answer": "25a3ZZz831nm/osnRxfh0fT8dXnfDHYC4Z7jJJt9unGKXDZ/LmjhCM4=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJ/8ww3i8pcuEh/8wb3oMHjEBnAf41aNVqp1PDHuW7TWLuH/x5BkJluMnhts92TD46H15VoZiqwb75yQfWIXdo4v29GE0qTeynVOfudWg4F8pIkLc/dLgH2hcdXfKfBpjnqPZ1H4Ynm6Fn9jgDmWhXoWrIqo4S61V853wwA+gpJq7MR8KdmWzbvT/0SsjkaB03acR7MkHV2Xstuh+FeVo8I9uciAtDzP57bMdukIr+OSJBm8McnbG3qp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Foreign invasions and conquests", 
		"option_b": "Trade with neighboring countries", 
		"option_c": "Common linguistic roots", 
		"option_d": "Defensibility of natural frontiers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l54onQB/izfT8NGeQB2ccom2AU7d9f3+jR6LQeOjtiZZiZ0iBiBt/93rPraDx41oBiOhd+4GRZCsGbMt8zdeb0uP20HhPNIZQkoUy6pUNaPxF3jPtddrfYO1h23qIIlf+Jyu4A3l7miKWhXoWvIu+tQ61UNM2zlUhg4V74sYoNdma17zMqs6UjUQyOmNUIw5BFOBVVU8=", 
		"answer": "24OxZpX7yBiq+oo1XArzzPPsd1Mg8zwBbu0UoCJgGPHgJvk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF2Bfu/5whEhP90PPrNGLeECIStmvDQKpzeGWjVaTQYf7tib5/I1WIzVp19jbArLf98ldPjuhZ5puRdCMRZ8ttzcSe0uH5hH9OIdJM2oF84NoMc+FUxH2EetDSIbxt7az7yexpxg+ubkGvIBXr", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Himalayan mountains", 
		"option_b": "Aravalli mountains", 
		"option_c": "Western Ghats", 
		"option_d": "Vindhya mountains", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwRXr7oAkEh+y1vT4O2LWCmEQrWvDQKx4dTHqWufEb+73xZ5lJkiAg1w78WPKt7Di9l9PirBY4Y+RdydDfI5739WM2aT5y2NVO4ZFlIQy95UKaPwA5TOpfdWEYoysUfW9SLghTkmkxCA68Cw=", 
		"answer": "25i3fpT+1Bf+t4omEg73yu3zMCvRDWZRt22CVqZmYzO/ygPrElK1FHoKGUFwcXfO", 
		"explanation": "25Gxbpf60gzm44wlQV79w738OmbdFmwYoH6XW6x6PDHzUajSYui+xJhnIljJi0l0/zbIrLfk/xMbgOhI5puLeGICcI8v3tmK0qThwWNSMooEloVz4JMRe7RUw32uYdjPNexvwi6FP0b4Zje6ATJlVx4bccBvwrH86EypQ8Tm", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Frequent foreign invasions", 
		"option_b": "Flourishing agricultural practices", 
		"option_c": "Movement of people and traders", 
		"option_d": "Natural barriers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXA2yyvu/HGXUCmNRtHqRV+N/fn70WufEYf++zJl2JluAg1w7+3iGpan/4kEGnKBS54nfdi0Re4JoxpCdxeXzwS4DX5evTmJdmNnkZwFSgJ2wew==", 
		"answer": "25a3aYLn0BWq9pclUw2yxPHwO2yQF2oU41qCQbdxYn+jVanGLtr72oN0NVLJqlN65mWEzo4PVPx6IkCbOIaQ2y477w==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hj544QsEh/gwPzsdWrcDGwW42uLV+NRcWL3UbXMLuzwzddGIk+diEl1slHOorHjt1Ibm7pa6pqadGIQe597xNWbxKT2ynUBJ9RFnoVg99oecvAA2zi/cZTeLvlvyWuEZ0z+Jz+xC2VmnSLeg3JR6IW05yKyU9R31AczkoI6Owt1PAHCHju4YZbED7f16Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Northern and western India", 
		"option_b": "Coastal areas along the Eastern and Western Ghats", 
		"option_c": "Central plateau regions", 
		"option_d": "Himalayan foothills", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070105", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxz5+JAyURuyxu/6NH/VByIQ43GGRrR7YnqjW6GCZ+PqzIVyKFKHiFhv+3nI46f140QKiqYb7YeZdicRe4V7iMKM0O34ymIBPMAEs4527ZtAPmK3oEBb4HglHh9pGrCJsmA=", 
		"answer": "25i9fJD/wlnr+YFgXQr6wO+/J27DDHcDoHqQEE5lqTbFS8MzMDgIVrCS2+0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hTn+ItgXBv3wb35OnmQDmcFonOQEqJ6dDHsQK/HfK3szIR+Mk6KiEg74mTJp7Dz8ldPjuhV7JqIfzAIPoRpiNmHw+Hlx35PPcNHjol96todeeBXyTijNNDSJvhr3GuOMwXiYj60C35n1D7QymhercO4+jK1QMgugg1cdYcZfpY4MeWyuCIckRY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Precious gemstones", 
		"option_b": "Timber and wood products", 
		"option_c": "Metals and other resources", 
		"option_d": "Agricultural produce", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17gyvH6dWTWQ3YZpj+1W61weGjiFLXHaeTxx4QxLlLJjFV4+3PIt+Xk/l4KnPcZaIZNptAmaM+ht+nCzCAwQw==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz1xjp/okpRh/mwPm/OGTGBm8UrWvDUKZgZ3TmWufMYf/qwddwKVjJnlRu5n6Giqv0/lJNz5tQdp1HaXGauhH/4BqJnw==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnc/oskWgfzhe/6MmLfDXFd43uGQbN9ZHSjUK7EaOT93JtlLlmazVR9snXJrqjl+VoMjrxS5oCMPGITe4R/xNXJ2uvhwXUBNdRLl8B864gLdLRUw32+e8HPKL5vwGrAMUzzYnmrAWJnlX2WiXNYvJGy9zKvXdQwgAE91oRt4dwpLtaTma2L60W5iAGHnpRs9/fRvRkyuLT9gzfTH6I=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "They were the heartland of agriculture", 
		"option_b": "They served as trade hubs", 
		"option_c": "They formed a barrier between tribal communities", 
		"option_d": "They facilitated movement between north and south India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070107", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbSGyyPLqO3/RCmwC42yGQLVxdDHiR+fDLu/x3Jl1Jk6QzVl+5mHDpquw+Vwdm6AXqY+RdGIQcZ57wJCg2eD+xTM93BqOr5eoBX8B+MTkGJU6", 
		"answer": "24OxZpX7yBiq+oo1XArzzPPsd1Mg8zwBbu0UoCJgGPHgJvk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF2Bfu/5whEizzy/r6dXjVEXQUpz+CQeN1MHPsQanGb//niZV0M0uMiFU7/HnUt62w9l0Lz7tU/JqXMAsNeoJuiPmdl+3khHABPslRlJRz7ZRfbvVOyzjtYNzaNL5822CTZ1H4dTaoA3g0gDnTyn9Tppe+52e0UpoezhE7l8s469ozMZeL0a3TyV+5kAeO0HLRerxqFlHZvMDo/0uZ4JU9ptnNpT2b4Pz82tvb/8oKIiZTuJZqcRuMm6kd/SstEcG6KAZD9KTVYEf5YByrIk4r8MXn3m1ohrAoU24xtBZVwo1ZdoBl04r9/Do5OMUmVSSzt0wA05x5Hx+fc7W9w3yk8FA+fjo5YItutCQ7pk+TJlhn2jzQHHwB1IZu+8RZvQt0eHlFjjqgiyvLiXbPfdPu6orzl6j/oqp386ArLAGUOhzMRIwKYL+MZ2Z8zqmSGeZUMownHyv1Kdo89Tr4LJqNnyoIws8lKzfm52qY0s/6LGu+soDgztZzAKgFM9+F/cOy8F/SbTf0M3iAJsTyGQb/XWjwkw9rs1g2xzQE4CLxBo129G/zGjANRepKCXHcvqOZQxjz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Vi,nd,hy,a Mo,un,ta,in", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070108", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hj544QsEh/gwPzsdWrcDGwW42uLV+NRcWL3UbXMLuzwzddGIk+diEl1slHOorHjt0QKna0b7ICYcSUGestmxpC26NvI+05+DPl7pb9N29oZc+ZFxTqjNMDJIfprjH4iRqop4Jte86U7xbWz3Io=", 
		"answer": "27O0Z4Th2Ari/osnEPYMmNZU95HjMxQa1vmlU1A=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hj544QsEh/gwPzsdWrcDGwW42uLV+NRcWL3UbXMLuzwzddGIk+diEl1slHOorHjt1Ibm7pa6pqadGIQe597xNWbxKT2ynUBJ9RFnoVg99oecvAA2zi/cZTeLvlvyWuEZ0z+Jz+xC2VmnSLeg3JR6IW05yKyU9R31AczkoI6Owt1PAHCHju4YZbED7f16Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fl,ou,ri,sh,in,g", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070109", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+3g/v+oAuRl79w73vMGTAD2dRonGHErdmcXXmRrSCbOjq3pJ0KRyHgklv+jbHraGw5Fwam6AbwICbeSNDeIpswdyAw+XjwXUBMNNIjpVg5ZZfQ8t/8wKSS+vkH8FR8VHCqiM3vToUFHAFi8vCLDpVQg==", 
		"answer": "27Cga5ny3x7vtRecl5tsb6/wzFHEH2mzplQ=", 
		"explanation": "25G9e4H6xRyq84wmVBfx0PHrPG7DQ20X43yMX65hfnjgVbPLYeOyiYd0KEyFiBt2/WDDp+X25VwCz6ZU+5qXMDYMPphg3cSBl+X5wDFXOsVB2pZ39okeMLRMyTypfdrcYOphjm2VK1HldTixRHVslznXhHtT6lzROeYMD0SLOJFMjRKmYn0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ex,ch,an,ge", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070110", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hTn+ItgXBv3wb35OnmQPF0unEC8bZxLT07ca5iCb+P6iZhlL1mbzUl+4XnTsab15BMMna1a/YubMCNDcI5739+b3KT4wjFIPdJBiIN96pQaf+BJwzPtdtHPN/trwC6ELkP2Yiu4CmQ0hjTRg3NYu8O082eSWt4+wVdl1lztV3lB6Er0jwCScquA", 
		"answer": "27i9fJD/wluAzqa5vviMkoV8mXSodKE/", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hTn+ItgXBv3wb35OnmQDmcFonOQEqJ6dDHsQK/HfK3szIR+Mk6KiEg74mTJp7Dz8ldPjuhV7JqIfzAIPoRpiNmHw+Hlx35PPcNHjol96todeeBXyTijNNDSJvhr3GuOMwXiYj60C35n1D7QymhercO4+jK1QMgugg1cdYcZfpY4MeWyuCIckRY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "me,ta,ls", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070111", 
		"question": "24GwbdHgwRzr/IAyQV79w73rPW6QJ3AQtXaHW6J6MH3iWqDXb+r72td9LkqMiRtEzUn5nJrPyGwwsJdk1s6QdmIXdo4v/tmH0+zuxWIDMyFxRe54o623VKOyCI2Slw==", 
		"answer": "26a3fYX7kwDZfRrm8gp8gJemIY3SzVc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF2Bfu/5whEhP90PPrNGLeECIStmvDQKpzeGWjVaTQYf7tib5/I1WIzV1p/XuGtKDj4xMbgOhe6J2LMCMNestpx8KE0uC3xTFDPNNKnoFg/dodeeBXyTijNNrUMupmjm+OIwXjaCypDDBdmjXfizxioIb75je+VdEy0gZymYE4+cA5fPON2L6a7ES5iEaO3XWWXbxjFEfZuce+7kfcs40tocXNvjSb4Pz82s7a/toDewlB/X70hADqXj7/HsXtKV1Ya1k=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "so,uth,rth", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070112", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snXTr7Hl5VIDz6xC54+SeSEQPoRpiNGH1O3yymUBGshAk4Ey7Ylff/tS3jiuYI7nLsJgny6nIkr3dTitDHl3lT2WjHlXvJap8DT7R880yFUzhcdq5N45LsTTmaWc/UOshw+MzzfRSbNgUVqYodu66k/coo0tu8mMozve57T6lfbH4tcJdxxXu8ZrbBuon61J/iUqXMmgYR1FsevWIVDkMzyqKQ0Judvs2n19z4EoUSk1+hsGg4dba856xYz2vSY5KcgqAD2zt1cA0J1oV1eAda+h2WbjoEcqeXMlYspppSM0shuVLUdClFeSHmxlnIUryNkXkQx6fC9Nk2Pulj6CjnbPfZD37oS8hPuwoflt87cyO0CMdVjRQIQYYPPCInNlz+yVTbVMNp5sEjD1fdoovBD3JJnZ/isU0ddgI3bp8z+YlcjmeWy084bxi5R4G60UPpHE58/3lE7GdyrlKHydJsf1Vw/lTnv9wE5suVgxwCRQ+23NHIFD+xEDzT6EQUEknyj2aXGkmKoc5YTOb4s+w/npnTAVjON9mpW32hIuUwz7jHFH8peQWkhHjX3YGsQGhAUrCPQVG9bS52GCgGTRRzwIZ83+AKaAxmAI0+33gnR4sZMHW4vOIBjVjcsnzxKiTb1tR2bprcq5PPIRSnYp9rt2w+K0pIqrZ/KnOGwpagn1rCZHbS+bFKzd3RrIMrtlLA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VzEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+0Wqp4dTH3XKLQa63pyIQxLlKNiF5/snvJtaD98l0bz6pe/ZmadSxDcIR93NjJ1urzhGJOJtJM2ql84JMeMLRBwjntYNzSM75jwXiFKkD+c3m5DXQ0lz7Ynm5fqpav8GevW5o01Rkmg5V54Yg5JNSX2KaU7QH4jxLC1WjRRrJwUVWattu66leZ4JY39d6MqHLP/PXt2uzb9Z4GbR5XsoNxdxuwkqxJ7CV4RcCxKBZO5+HcbkTgJSa3ZwEbucrtlnFlw4E9VGY6tAxfkZdTb4B62Nj2uTE1MdkqATq3plcA05x9S1eBda740mf28loocH5rY5hisW0hqQrcKVp9k26SWGx5lZJq7sAYm0RzcmNJiH/jgzPLk3ycaJbuqTNRNjycgN6ugq9yJceCYX4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070113", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVR42yXU7dxfXTtQLSCb+/x3IMxK12Hik569XOGoqv0t1Aag7xO+4+TMCYGaI5jx8CE0urjhHhPc8dKmYl36o5fVfpExTztfcebI/F83GuDMx/MaQWzVTBamyPCgnlEpsO6+yP7Q98k1BAgmMdR48w1PZePy6Ge6V+xih/C1HqVCLFlH1OMtMmt+AOYpZAxo8iJ8TTJ+/m5jvDWsPcFZgcfnpRmYlX8hLwG+yF0EdqxewdH5e3eZhTkLmiwLgkT8M3q1XVn0sIlVGcz4RZVlopVIsN825XrsjM8NtljECCGrXhOldRIVxLWQrS21GD94RUyem8lcYtksj51oAyILVA+m3jcTSIRnY17+94cgRZif2NF3HThkC2ChXfPaJvi/8Dsl+3mpbd396dnKE+ZdV/NWpkJd7LMZ2JqyeGaA6FZc51iAzXjONtu6DH8YJibzS0FkNguKzf0+z+NmvH7BWvp86bxi5R1G74TItDJqdmyt1XIbzChIHGcaMy0TQD1D1n5wBpgpRZlyS8UqFXdG5165yNNuXaxXVckkzP0fn2igrtYqpGLa5o91uf/nTMenLRsjZrz0Q8vC0S4gnFXoI2dWkhGw1OWCsJHwgUhGaYIB57Y/GrWk3nCTnUKcY7iE6mDxm4O48A5igg+N1b0g+1ZRADl", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUWWxD2zeT+dWbfFmwFonaNQeNweXWjRLXNeOT6zNdwZ1uMglxp82bOqqbx+xMLhr5S7YvfcicXaY5qxpCH2PbjzDFAPcIEiY9n8JJfVfpExTzhNMDTJecu2WuSIgX+aC39BX40nT/Fn25bp5a14Sa5WN93whQghI59/4gINNKN3OiE6V74iwmU2XaURqkkHlLZpcun+0+Z4IM2sY2OpD7P4eb4lrjW6N0DYwZVusZ+YEmzhLtJ7CI9Ef69ZhZD6OWQbFv4LjyiLgAOtYvg2Xp91IsrSH09+hgGlowWY4Bw2ZX0syE5K8gqFia2t1FSwtb5rk7k5iHmEO2sOhjuDmnN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070114", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddlL1nJjk535mPUoqmw80oBjqVS6p3ffyRDf4VswdWHw6TeynVIMoZNicBx64gNefdUlgGjSNqKYMpmyy6VKUzhcjz9A3V7kyPXmnRfq4K3tSG+Vc4i0hAh1oh+reEyON6enrvT+ki/jwmMzzudTbkkBVvZocatq0eZtoc0ut2AtDzPtPv/2vza48oCbAtG/4Vqb0+phakFuD82WNynKAVC5eyQdVzoKTrjKBkTucfi2HN8x4UsTik1+hsGjopQZ9Nnz5Thrw4+A8M4VQeypgRV1JE8UBHWR7y2w2P26UF/Yns4JYZksSQhpAvcPFs+jmOZDCJehpRj+8IX1QVteS9XmWX0hy2FwHeKe5rs5ZO8iu6wibdn+6JnLVSFdUjXFpkUYLrSZ3R6y/ueCeZ1PZtoWgP0JNQgvDXwLpGB1ioZ2dpgJ3L1/T6YlcjJN1m04NLNhtE2GbAWM9zA59/3v1qHcSbuMXGWJsnxTR/1SnK43QF3oxAg2i9Q6WzcSJpw4DkFm2y+CW1qli7hLGughf5M+IuDfpw43+ys2SAZjvF235nulAkuRgC+n2wDs4qbD1FG3kffEcMG1gArH/hBGJPQ9mSYkjbERDwMP8H4BOWQwjUI2fb9mnRvvpxOUJSNJBjVjdtkfRjmVEBTuEClX8mpAduYEw==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VzEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+3WqY0fX71UarHYPm+xpExN1mGnVd+snTDt7L18l1PgadJ/YaaYixDf4VriMOGwvD/wWNPc+9KnolzpI0eb7ROwynte9rXOb5q3GeWIkuwZSD9EGJ1kDTEmTxXpof7+C6oR9M4zhQgn4JrrcopKJee1bucqE+hxhSX0H6DW/EkEkGVodu66k/crIc5scifon6b9fr92vfH+NsZcUhmt49sI0+rmOUe+TN4Rdq1bhRC8qTTblr5MiGhMhoY/Yv32TRohoEmUHk75xZSh8NVd8xnw4rh/Ds+f9liEHOopkNJyJo+On97DJIimzm/ztr6dfnugg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070115", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfDwI27dBmwF43CFErdmcXXmRrSOLuD32oR4KFKIn1J+4TqGoqv0t1Aag7xO+4+TMC4Gf49q2sPJ1eHj03REPYZKlZJm7J8NcrRBwjntZ9vONPZr3GDADkv0bjj9AGVmnT/Ryn1Yq4q++zP7QNM6xQZyhY5/48E6NdSe17yf8Q27iQiWznKTXalhFRSNuo6840bcqYwsp8SOsCbetPD8jP3f/84GZwZG/4l5I1r8lKcE6CUrWNyxKBFe/fDFc1HRLhStFQsc6sTtjDRdzoc6WCkx7BxOg41RZ9Mz0Jf3qDciOskqATu/40FYxJx9URCTNLK+kGHg5VQsOTo5YIZkuyQ6tBzcKlFyk26aX2ARlZJ/98MNnAcjdGFGkGPljDyOkynPfZ3nq4z1i+/lqap3+6BnLE2FOFnWQp5cZ7bUMGJ3xKmPBaMcIZpgHi3oLplu7jzqNZqA1jcKkNAub2Pv8WqKi8PhMWCpuoG5gdI2ELYWM8PW7Iu0pVDTdDHgLT2Was75XAbkXD4KCfhjZ/xgHEdySEthefWc", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhDJjFV/smLOpuXi8lIcgKYb4J3fcWIAcZl9zdOdl+Hv1H1APcdQk498pJUZPOBIyX2sZ8feMupnwWDCop1qPD10dPCMuvcvAuZVyw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I42yXU7dxYzH3XKKCZ+P4xYJ0KV+MzVR9smLOpuX9+EUKgq1V/c6QdmIXbIprzcKam6T6zWJSOslKm5J74YlTPPVOyH2uYdjPNexvwi6MIkT0YiuuRHl61CLei2xfpoT79Ge4W9cnzwY7goI47t0wKMKN3Oin4Ej4lAODz3SfCK12HkKQscu7q0LcrI0/vM6MvXLe7OT1m/bS5NcEbEhducZ3bEz8g6AM6y94VNC3YBNF9uHDIVjoJGi3KE4J8c6jxW1n0oosTmAntBBAwodfdMVhxZ2kvyc8K9h4FD/6pkhFypFySwTaNKqw2WvsoFQzfH0ldsp6tTk94RuULRR/iXiZXjhYm44pXcOmacJDYFn3WyMkvlOkIQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070116", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfr6OmzCAnIZqnyCXuN2cWPxXaLQfaG+2oJyLxyInht2/WPIt6T5+UBPjqZfqZyWZicRbccv2NyIzuHzhHABMNRRmYlz6NoNc/hFjDSjNN3IL/Jv2meOIAXiYj60C35n1DDYjjxGuoat8CmvXdQwgBQ8j8d+4toxfNiZmauG5FmtlAeOnH6JS7VlH1Oc9cemq0KSo4s9u9nNmDzf/fXFlMTdwtsKcQdc5cZLa178h7oM6y82Us30ZxQL/+XEdEbsLGilNQET7cLmxGcpwos6XmYh5h5Bh4cWY85qlpXrqjc9OsN+VTy841RFyIRwWleXern402fp7UAxfHkqcYNism03pBuLLVFw2m+VSipUhoVl6pALkANqcmFT0Dbshz6PiWuIPIfsq5T0gOHi4Lp2/rcyO0CMdV3WUs0QbL3HMm5h3uCYTa9PPJNmAyvpM5dyQR++R9+6ds1oV0T5/+Pt", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/M2rcEGdd432WRuNgeHSjRqLDfeLwiZ5iZ0ibmF45Clg720YyikIsg2B1JHkzqg==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUyVx/hyvO/NGjTFnAQt3qPS+NwdWLgRq7Aa/6+3Z90Z06GgV47/XCGraTk4kEOg+hd+4GRZCsGbJgvwd7J0+3kx35UIcdDk451pJcQavFNyTO5NNXVJL5twWONMkv5ZDipDX962HHCgnkWqZCo8DWvXdU5gBwh1oR349wuPdOW2ryW7A26n0aW1H7RTattFVGXtsvo+1GZs4c2ociJ8TvVtODxn7jD8c0YYw9X88Zoa1K/n+gB8S0wXcGzYAZYsfDYZBTgLz6mKgsT7Yvi2HApxZclSXwm9RMGh5tVasF90Z2kuDcjL8R+EHO9pktH1ZVsVx6VdbH40mn28lw6Z2lpVjn0x1TVHHuwhoW6MXXPMQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070117", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfH2O2zFCnEFqnzDVqpidWPwXbPbLuTwiZZ/JFWMg08723jCqqSw4FIcz7tU5YuTaWIHe59q2t2A2eHzhHNYc8FBlYdg5YoXdfdBwH2rcdXPNexr3S6BKUGwaTipEWJ1mHHUhWlYrIKp/CKoaNQLzic3l5R345J8CN+ama+W50qqhxaK1XiQRP1gGEeNp8eq/leVr4x4usvNmDzf+7nYiOHS/p4KbAwSm5R+dVK4nqkHuCY5X8+haRVO4qTHYEetJCGxIg0J9dKj33pvypcsU2ox8F9Em8NCasUz4JHquDopPo1nGia0t0VJyYc8XhSCfbO/kGn3oFR/d3U+a45srjR1owqIP1F7lCuSQz5FnMBq8NRZhgt2aWcAtXjkiz7JCdMgPuNWBzz+do5v+Xrhdg==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+z5Z9NFnL0Vxz5H+sW0Qruz05h1bksQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+z5Z9NFnJuVN+smbHsLbx8FZPhqZf4I2eZCcQPp9nycTJ2+35w2RIINJNmcB27YwabudJ2CTtY9XIYPdgyGKVIkvzYj39Bmk0kjDVnnNEu8O58D60Wt53ygAhgsd/6Mc7LtaP0aGQ6UH4gAODyG6DTa4oUVWXsY6840bcoZErsN+ZuD3VtPvvn+rA+dMbbgFUtoNsI0+0kugK9ycoXc2sKAJZ/ufVckfoM2i3Lw8Jucjs2GB7z4A8SWwwtAtJwo9fbMdm34vwtTFwO8R8ECGpqlBZhahr/MtkNikEtMjGng9hKWQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is a correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070118", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQEWcQsHCNEqFxeHjtUOfWZui+2pRwNV+AmUI7/XCGoqvz/lYBm+hZ+4GRaidDcYllzdOdxKT+yjFoPcJNm98wWQfbegBpNasmzFF8SsFUFQ==", 
		"answer": "25mxZZjn1B2q9oYjVw3hhenwdX/ZDSAsZJ1dcd8l1duvcrcy4wy2", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg0hj49Iw0S179w73+O2jZBmwF432RXa1udTHsVq3HbfntiZ5/Z3WHiVJ6snXHreXy8hMOm7xJ4IyKZCcHPp9giMSB0qT7zXxIJ8NA2oFx558Mb7RUw325fdqXYOlmx22IZ0zjJzj9D3Vt1DLZh2xZpoa14We0Upo10ho8jII47MQwM87dHpiQqvlAOng0QhiAiTLgZw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Lack of skilled artisans", 
		"option_b": "Insufficient copper deposits", 
		"option_c": "Limited access to tin", 
		"option_d": "Cultural aversion to bronze", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070119", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4QuURf3y+m/HGXUCmMf422GVap7fjH0UbXHLvn2zNdaKFCInxt8/XrCpaz1+1ccz6RU6o+LdSZcPFzKNcCLJN69Mcz7MUB75RQ=", 
		"answer": "2565ep/yxRjh9sdUluJhABTJVFtdtvqA4Sxm", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHY3hXr5cUnXRL2w/T6OW/DQ3UUsXrDXqx3cWXmUOfLYK3qwZIxNEiImV47/XCGiKTi+VIbjqNapc6Ufi0UcMtpx8LJ3vDkhHZOP8IEl4l87ZQYPPxJ3ymiZs2ZQFbYy08EcLJ+DIck9astlA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Rajasthan", 
		"option_b": "Andhra Pradesh", 
		"option_c": "Bihar", 
		"option_d": "Karnataka", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070120", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTv44QsEgnz1r3xOn/RAW4I42yAU7F3dTHqWufDYO73zJllZ3WHiVJ6snTTt+Xn9kBPjKdW5IGRfDtDa5hqzJCA2aTjzHQBNsdWlol3945fbOFOzzXgedXJK/tqjm2PLkvjOHuE2vUMq/p6d1DkwO2SgG9r", 
		"answer": "24axZIf2w1vW8WHs+8RvTPOvHYcRq+gc", 
		"explanation": "24axZIf2w1Wq84AzQhfmwL32IXiQEWMDqmuaEqp6MFjtUK7DIq3pyIQxMk+MiRty/DbSq6Cw8lIdg6Fe+prfYDcNfYMixdGb3OHzhHJOOshX2oZ98ZQbPP1OjB+kfNXJYuoqkuxDUMVVbQlJzpPJ5fE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gold", 
		"option_b": "Silver", 
		"option_c": "Copper", 
		"option_d": "Iron", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070121", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxz5+JAyURuy1vXwJ3/RBGdRr3aOW7dxdDH3XKKCaujozJt+N1GMg087/XCGouXg5Vwfiroby5yQfjgGPqpozZCA2aT60XJJc8lC2ql84JMeI7a6QHw8YcgNefPluZgpngrA", 
		"answer": "25m5a5qz3h+q44wuEFQngw3fRytiejEgnDHro78=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/0Brht4omEh+yxvLxJmLDF2cftz+QR7NkfGijW6GCeuTwiZ5iZ13Jhl5ismTDorb/+RMYh7Eb5JuceGIMeMtGxtSA1qTzzXUBPclQ2oVq9J8NdfFOzzjtdZTLMvF+y3zABVf/aSO4RFFzkXHBg2he6JCy8imyUtM0wRsm1pJr6IgzOpedy6ed8kj4kgmN0GjRSbNgUV2UpcKt5kaStJF6cM5jPeREU05V5YleJMQP7Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Copper scarcity", 
		"option_b": "Insufficient timber", 
		"option_c": "Lack of tin", 
		"option_d": "Absence of skilled metalworkers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070122", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF79w73WO2/ZAiIZonvDQbZ2Y2XiWrPLb+G+xZJwIxybiEh052TFpra8t0EKnL1X/YeRd2IKcMt7wNXJx/by0nBNNshHn8B94toTefVEjD6ifdrIYPp73GeOIAXxJzq4FmR1nT+WgnVFvIyp/CS6WJonxQc7mYMnr8xvw5uxmk06Mec7xisj9DQ=", 
		"answer": "25S2bJnh0FvR3M4BWV4FstPnyoUqJ6oU", 
		"explanation": "25S2bJnh0Fn6+JYzVw3hwPm/JmLXDWsXqnyCXLc0fHTiUOfQa/7x3IVyIk/FzVd+83LPraKw41xPm6BeqZ6NdTQCco5hy9XJ2OK3yHRAN4ZHlYl899obaeZJwjrtYNzeYOx7wmvAKEOwczG4REN1gDDAi3RXpoKot/guKTzgx5Lp3kStYgvC/WE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Andhra", 
		"option_b": "Punjab", 
		"option_c": "Gujarat", 
		"option_d": "Maharashtra", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070123", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17/xPTxdXjfFnASpj+MVONzf33nFKHNfK3/x5R4IlKdzXJ19n/HreXz/kUGg6FB6JqWfyxDfI5px8KMl/D/wTFUIMMElYYy45UTeLRDwzSjZ5TZJf1vw2vAMEz0YiqtFnV1kG6UyZGI18yf87xQ+4jKEk9nSQ==", 
		"answer": "25K3ZJWz1Rz6+JYpRg2yxvztJ2LVByITuj+RW7VxYjHwQLXHb+DtiZFjKFHJmVN+sl7PrqT89koOnOp8OWZiCw1mFFPP2Q0EVo/F", 
		"explanation": "25S2a5j23w2q3oskWx+yxvLzOW7TF2cV43iMXqc0dHTzW7TLev6+ypZjNVWMiRt56zbUqrP15RMcm7pe6IOMMCQRcYYv3NiMl8z+yXBNMt9FicBz99oLdPEAwTykepTIL+t8zWvAKEOwYDaxADB2kTfZmHkWvIu+tTKoUZo4xlU1mYt8rcszNdmMmaqW60y1g0aV1X+UW612FFWd97PYq5eW1ICqE2YwPQgTpvo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Local gold mines in Karnataka", 
		"option_b": "Gold deposits carried by river streams from the Himalayas", 
		"option_c": "Gold trade with China", 
		"option_d": "Gold conquests in Central Asia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070124", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk9IwlXAqy7PP7PGreQ2YIrX6QRro0eWKjVbTRYe73yIN0IxyehE9zsnPes6n//kcGga8b/YaaMCsRcYUvx8KMxKT4wjFgPcJMiIEy5ZQbPN9B3jOsYNXQIaEsCGQ0EoiRZ9CC/IIwnEWDNg==", 
		"answer": "24a5fJDl0BHr+YQzEBqA52aMBtLElvrjeuRASR8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA0A3r4YQoUxDz1r3+J26QCGwetHHDRqw0eHD1UefHdv3yxp5lIljJmVN+sn/UrKuw+EEKnOhU786+fiYLbIovyd6Nl8/21n9AJ8dPm8wy5ZcQcvMAwymlccabMvtpx2GONAcsXvRR2fiSSCqc/50y8Tc+", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Satavahanas", 
		"option_b": "Mauryas", 
		"option_c": "Cholas", 
		"option_d": "Guptas", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070125", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1xjp44oyEhjzxvTzPH/RF2cV42uLV+N4cWPkUerRbezyzNdkNFnJgl078GTJrb/1t1UAnehI/Y+LZScQPoRpiNeG0/e3zX8BMshHk4V88NoMc+FUxH2EetDSIaEseWXApItgQd2U62YzFw+99A==", 
		"answer": "25S7a5Tgwln++MU0WxCyw+/wOCv9GmMfrn6REqJ6dDH3XKKCQ+zyyI4xN1mHhFVo53rH4X3O5vLesasjEN7vxsq8ao0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/0Avt8sgzUR/+wL3qJm6QDGRRoW2MXLlxMHfsRufReuzq3JJiZ1OPzVx09mWGqquw9l0Mhq1V/c6MfzcXdstGxtSA1qTgxWIBNcdHk4x78JsLefAAziTtYNzeYP9tzWuTNAXkaHmpDX40kiPZhzx7sYK1+CapFNs5xFUmnoI4wMkwPc7fya2d4UOrkwqDnu2MUhZXRPl/vlghBV2nVww=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Abundant copper resources", 
		"option_b": "Local availability of tin", 
		"option_c": "Trade with China", 
		"option_d": "Access to tin from Myanmar and the Malay peninsula", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070126", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR7v+IIyUw76zP7+OSvWBmMFtm2GErB9d3/qUq7Bb+PqxY4xJFOHmUly8GPSpqGw41xPm6BeqYaWYzYMbIJsydzJ0+HhwX1OI8tBlJQy65xfSf5KzTSjNNXVJL5P2G+OM0ywbjf9BX53nTTYnjx/poey9Hj5OLVpfkO4AROrLSaHa+qo2Q==", 
		"answer": "25SuaZj/0Bvj+4w0S179w732J2TeQ20DpmzBgIP30qIbZIYjGwrwXN6uyQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyxxjj+4QiWxL70eS/Om2QCnAerT+MQKZnMGLqU6nLaOT9yJllK0XJjlR15mTPobDk8ldPm6cb/YaaMCoKbZ9g2tmK1ui3wHRXNspLio136o5fc/IA+Tendd3VYP9gyi6UL0CwRi+8CmR91DrfhHtSp477/Cn7VdQ0yRA8gsdR48w1PZUblnhl/kXFXC1uR4VN4hpZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Coastal access", 
		"option_b": "Availability of iron ores", 
		"option_c": "Fertile plains", 
		"option_d": "Dense forests", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070127", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Bz+9olgRR/hhe3tPGbREWsduj+WQaZwMHfsRufBYePt3YVkJEiAglU783jC47H/+F9CgqlQ4ICYMCAGeIR9zZCd3+G303hFNtVUiIVz4NoKb/EAwzvtdsHJLuouzHyJJE7jOHv/zqW0W8iwIYY6z9UAIZFr", 
		"answer": "24GxZZP2w1sUh0DVneipOcu9f0atdXEX", 
		"explanation": "24GxZZP2w1n99pZgRhb3he3tPGbREXtRrn6XV7F9cX2jQbTHaq34xoUxJFOHnk9p53XSqqr+t1IBi+hP5oGTPS8CdYJhz5CL0uL41nQBJ85B2pd74J8MbOZFzTntYcfeYPFojmyVNUvkJzuvDXN/h3HfhDxXpoCy8CmvFPM5xBwz1Gp9m9MHydDmEuD0u1vqXkE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gold", 
		"option_b": "Copper", 
		"option_c": "Timber", 
		"option_d": "Iron", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1hzl8JchQhb7xvzzdW3VAnYEsXqQEqV1c3jvXbPDeuj6iYN5IhyNiE1+/nnWrqD+4xMAiehP4YvfdisRbZ8vzd2Z3vbyhHhPc+tFnYF27JtTPPVOyH2le8ObJPdqjmeUZ1f1azipATBgm3HXym9GrYCy8y64FNQ21AAgl4s4/80vM8KN2q3MqhDRBN+xS6TpGq04B52eBJo=", 
		"answer": "24WqbYL23xrvt4omEhP90PPrNGLeECIQrXvDW7F7fjHnUbfNfeTq2tV2g4VR0NocZy2xmG/2Wy+L", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyxxjj+4QiWxL70eS/Om2QCnAerT+JR7BgMGLsQbPKLuL4iYN5IhykjFx69n7H47f18FoAgeQb74+ceS4Kaop7zdTJ1f230HlEc9ZWn5N36pkaPPtGjDCiYdrPIfdg3S6BKUGwbiuyCjBwkSHZmXVCu8/75Su6Td8zgBRylZVt7sE9MJeN1qSWqES2xhKK2TuVTathHVuJuMum/wOTpsIsvcjNtzvJ5+C5n/XD+cwOIgFc/6t+ZFq4n6lLKAgvugtnGeS4gOXeSkp4WQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Presence of mountains and iron deposits", 
		"option_b": "River valleys and gold reserves", 
		"option_c": "Dense forests and copper resources", 
		"option_d": "Coastal access and tin deposits", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070129", 
		"question": "25CgeJ3y2Beq440lEg37wvP2M2LTAmwSpj+MVONgeHSjWKbQaeiz2pRwK1nJmEh+snnA46fi+F0ViuhS586efiEKe4V7iPmH0+32yjFAIdIEm452pJIQa7RUxDjtddfKNfd9x3qJKEuwaD/9EHl61DfXiXVaoZe64SK/FM4/yQZykoJu6MQzLNqa17zRY7cMtL45w+TwsUP+KfXCOA==", 
		"answer": "25eqZ5/p1Fn99pZgQgz9yPTxMGXEQ2sf422GXqpzeX72R+fRbfjy2YNkNVmawRt6/HKGt6z+t1YBjqpX7IrfZCoGPoh9zdGd3uv5hH5Hc8RWlY5o4doecPhP1S7vTah0LLEhpiJX7HKstDNH5w==", 
		"explanation": "25eqZ5/p1Fn99pZgRRf2wPHmdX7DBmZRpXCREqBmdXD3XanFLv/7xZ52LlOcnhto8WPKs7Hl5VYcw+ha54rfZCsNPpxu25CKxfH0zXBNc8BLiMB/5ZEWcvMAzi+ies7eYP9iwmGZNAmwcDG0B3g0nTzGmHNArYf74S++FNsl1Bwhgo57rckyOJeS3LyS5EGtlAGL33qdCKxxEFiQocet+AOTpsIsvcjNojHO+OTtj+rW45zHdOVDQbLxsA7jtixMU974", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bronze was used mainly for construction, and tin was essential for iron smelting", 
		"option_b": "Bronze was favored for warfare, and tin was scarce due to mining challenges", 
		"option_c": "Bronze was prominent in religious sculptures, and tin enabled the creation of bronze alloys", 
		"option_d": "Bronze was limited to tools, and tin was vital for architectural innovations", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070130", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q8IAvVQzz1fX2NmrcQ2EerXGGUbd9f3/wFLDLeuW+x5J4IFSLgkly/HGGsaD3/lwBnOhS5J6eczZDV4VrwdHOxKT2x3JEINUEjo8y8psNdftV332gccDaLO0ijm+OIwX4aC79AHlw1CXeg28WoY29+TK+WtkygBwmhcdw5NsoM8WW2qmfqEm9kAOO02ucTbNwTha6fNgX3cgpR26zDmlyHLqQ", 
		"answer": "25S7a5Tgwln++MUTXQvmzfj+Jn+QInEYoj+TQKxieXXmUOfFYeH6hddhNVOEgk9y/HGGt7fx81ZPjqZfqY2QfS8GbIhqih6jlBhgkinKS2cGbnjOTqE=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjylgqq9IouXBvx0fTwO3iQFGsFqz+wXbZgeHTiR7OCT/73yNdzNVOcilNvsnfFoKDj5BMbgOhc5oKbPGIUdoJswJCZ2+XuwXUBMoZUk5Z98JsTPOZPwDjtfdqbNOxvymvAJkv0JzqyCX1xhjLTxjxVp42v5y65Qc4+zhJygog45NwvfN+Wyryc+kS7hwrC2H6HTbFrAVmcu9rqPoQI2eL6I4b2LlnvSc31tg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Connections with Central Asia brought copper, leading to agricultural advancement", 
		"option_b": "Access to Southeast Asia provided gold, promoting trade and commerce", 
		"option_c": "Interaction with Egypt enriched India's tin reserves, enabling maritime growth", 
		"option_d": "Trade links with China introduced iron, aiding the rise of ancient empires", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070131", 
		"question": "25Gxe5Lmwgqq/4o3Egr6wL3+I2rZD2MTqnOKRro0f3ejQqbQZ+Lr2td/Jkicn1p3smTDsKrl5VAKnOhS54iTZScNfY5riMSB0qT0zH5IMMMElYYy6ZsLeeZJzTG+NNLUMr5twWCTM1flZC20C340lT/Sym9VvY+r4TKpUZo+zlU2n4F+6No5MsPfy62U4UK2lUaN2juQRr5tFFqN9eem70qd4mOeFeKh2JijdOX9y47l0yo=", 
		"answer": "24GxZZP2w1nr4YQpXh/wzPH2IXKQD2cV42uMErBgf3/mFLPHY/3yzIQxLlLJmVN+smXJtrH4t1IBi+hZ+4ece2IAcYV83MKc1PD+y39Sc89K2pR64doRc+ZUxH8XmubAWnb7L5hOC/SOiXbH", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyxxjj+4QiWxL70eS/Om2QF2scoXqREq9xdDH3W+fReuLwzNdlIlGZgV5osn/I47H48hMcgL1P4c6efiZDfJlmy9vJ1Ov512VTJsVQk49899oWcrRUxDjtetvJNPYuwWjADkv0bjj/fPnHoNaZirrtNlST1hsxqw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Copper availability led to stone temples in the north and wooden palisades in the", 
		"option_b": "Stone availability led to wooden palisades in the north and brick temples in the south", 
		"option_c": "Timber availability led to stone temples in the south and brick constructions in the north", 
		"option_d": "Timber scarcity resulted in temporary structures across the country", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070132", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg0hj49Iw0S179w739J2TeGWdRrH2JV6BgYzHqWufSfOj2wIRlKE6AjhtS/HLPouXn9kBPi71eqZqQMC4Kc4J7zdTJ1uf0wWJSc9JL2r9N26UgQ8t/8wKSS5ZD3BLG0JJSsb/LAtMzk8ZR", 
		"answer": "26GxZtMjfpJxY+0Was7AUjtnZEg4", 
		"explanation": "25eqZ5/p1Fnj5MUtUxr3hf/mdWbZG2sfpD+XW600Z3j3XOfBYf3uzIU9Z12HiRtv+nOGsKbx5VAGm7Eb5ojfZCsNPodmxdmd0uC30HlEc9ZWlYRn544Wc/oAwzvtdsbULuRrjmGCLUDzcyr9DX40hCPTgnVFvIyp/CT7fdQzyRRwlVVpItk+jQfVOiKBeuYcAg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ti,n,in,te", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070133", 
		"question": "25y2bJjylgqq9IouXBvx0fTwO3iQFGsFqz+uS6J6fXDxFKbMaq3qwZIxCl2FjEI74nPIqqvj4l8Oz61V6IyTdSZDaoNqiNyIxePyiWJCMspB2pVh4doQerR/8wKSS+vkH8FR8VHAIUriJyqpBWRhkSKWhXoWr4y/5meyWpokzwAmnsdR48w1PZUiIrOacPXz+CwKBl9yHbE+", 
		"answer": "27eqZ5/p1FseCBAa6V7Sjfa7FRoLJ08K", 
		"explanation": "25S7a5Tgwln++MU0WxCyw+/wOCv9GmMfrn6REqJ6dDH3XKKCQ+zyyI4xN1mHhFVo53rH46Px9FoDhrxa/YubMDYLe8t629XJ2OK3xmNOPdxB2oZ99tocbvFB2DSjc5TINP9622uTZ0r2Jz6yAGM0nT+Wi3JVoYa14WeoW88jyFUbmINx7IpG3vfFJaSgDOa2VFTbrExZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "br,on,ze", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070134", 
		"question": "24GwbdH72Ar++JcpUR/+hfn6I27cDHIcpnGXEqxyMETpXqbLYK3/x5MxM1SMzXpt83jSquX7/l0Ii6dWqZmeY2IQd4xhwdaA1OX50H1Yc89KnIxn4ZQcefAAziTtYNzeYP94z2eMJkf5azCpHTB7knHXiGlYrIK14WeEa+UI/yoNqbhH0vd+6EW+pnsp1f97VTPQIyKxHw==", 
		"answer": "27yqZ5+z3gvv5Md3SNChlx/4JsjmDEyr6K8C", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w732J2TeQ20DpmzDQq91aXTnFKaCbf/ryp5wKxybgld+sn/I47H48hMHhrtP5pyWcyMPPo9q3tWF2PT6wX9Vc8lC2rV47psWcrRBwjntYNzeYN94z2CULgX7bje6AH951DjYyn1Yq4q++zP7fdQzyRRwXHFYmYOpaWxfh7QCsEjDoA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ir,on, or,es", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070135", 
		"question": "24GwbdH12Av548UtVwrzyb3rOivSBiIEsHqHEqp6MFjtUK7DIq33x4F0NEiMiRts+2LO46Li8lIbz7hO+4eLaWIKcMtHwd6NwqT00X1VJtRB1sB799ogQ8t/8wKSS+vkH8EsHJPxMX2Rqs+4dDQ/qIaT4A==", 
		"answer": "27a3eIH2w1u6yfE2W4p9AG5ii0nbrDlU", 
		"explanation": "25a3eIH2w1n99pZgRhb3hfv2J3jEQ28Ut36PErd7MHPmFLLRa+m+wJkxDlKNhFo783jC463/+1ccz7tS7oCWdisAf4V7iNmEx+vl0HBPMMMEk44yzJMReOEA3jS5YdXXM75q22vAM0qwbi2uRGBhhjjCkz7KlOsz5G0fD4maJqLMIxRY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "co,pp,er", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070136", 
		"question": "24GwbdHY3hXr5cUnXRL2w/T6OW/DTyIarXCUXONyf2OjQK/HZ/++zph9IxyEhFVy/HGGq6zj41wdluQb6JyaMC4MfYp7zdTJ3uq30HlEc9VQm5R3pJUZPMt/8wKSS+vkH8FR8SxLX6nh/HMZRnnI8aWotvIR", 
		"answer": "2565ep/yxRjh9sdUluJhABTJVFtdtvqA4Sxm", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHY3hXr5cUnXRL2w/T6OW/DTyIfrGuCUK9xMHfsRufFYeH6iZp4KVWHihc782TD47b540YOm61fqYeRMDYLe8tGxtSA1uq312VAJ8MElYYyz5sNcvVUzTasNkxa1zYTL8/cfpdOl3ojkXk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ka,rn,at,aka", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070137", 
		"question": "24GwbdH/0Avt8sUxRx/80fTrPG7DQ20X43iMXqc0dGTwQOfBYeHyzJRlIljJi0l0/zbUqrP15RMMh6lV54uTY2IKcMt7wNXJx+j2zX9Sc9FBiIUy55sNbv1FyH2vbZTJKehr3C6TM1f1ZjSuRHZmmzyWnnRT6LyEyhiEa+UI/yoNqcUBXZw8Q3C8Jo3CEYnG3D8l", 
		"answer": "252xZZD/0ADr5McjRnrLxAQVQP6UgWuyZEAh", 
		"explanation": "25K3ZJWz1Qz548UpXF7gzOv6JyvTC2MfrXqPQeNjcWKjV6bQfOT7zdd1KEuHnk9p93fL46Pi+F5Pm6BeqaaWfSMPf5JuxpCE2PH50HBIPdUGuoGmtE+4lzgLqJYKdbKB+Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hi,ma,la,yas", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070138", 
		"question": "24GwbdHA0A3r4YQoUxDz1rG/NGWQAmwSqnqNRuNdfnXqVamCavTwyIRlPhDJiENr/nnPt6D0t0cHiuhS+4GRMC0Re5gvx9bJ6NvI+05+DPl7pb9NpJsReLRrzS+jdcDaK/8smt4TMJhC9XOef3wpJAnutg==", 
		"answer": "25S2bJnh0FvR3M4BWV4FstPnyoUqJ6oU", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA0A3r4YQoUxDz1r3qIWLcCngUpz+KQKx6MH7xUbSCaP/xxNdlL1nJrFV/+mTH47f18FoAgeha54rfWyMRcIp7yduIl+L41jFVO8NNiMB79pURMeZFwDy5cdCbIf16x3iJM0z1dHuAjhNAE0xJFbeopLtoG7EA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "An,dh,ra,ras", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070139", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl760PD+OyvDBnYFr3qOV61gYzHqWufrYOn3yNdwNVnJg1pv52THr6npt1UAmqZfqYeRMCoKcod2iNGb0uXkhHBPN4ZWk5Z39toJffhMySS+NMfSNOtv2muEZ0f1cy64AX40gDnTykNpl7yEyhiEa+UI/1eUYvnZlZKZUp0Bi7onuCse", 
		"answer": "272xZJ3gk8QfzfjidH+FpO2vKxSzcAw=", 
		"explanation": "25C5ep3qkRH/+oQuEg330enzMGbVDXYC43aNEop6dHjiFLPHYOn7zddlKByGjlhu4DbPreX4/l8Dluha+4ueY2ICcI8v3NiMl/b+0nRTc9BFlox3/YlfcPtDzSmocJTZJep5y2uOZ1H4Yiq4RHh9mD3FyD0mNs0BWZSipGaUUdaXZiw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "hi,lls,iis", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070140", 
		"question": "24GwbdH13gvn9pEpXRCyyvu/IWPVQ2QYsWyXEqZ5YHjxUefLYK3TyJBwI1SIzVRs93KGrrDz/xMbgOhP4YvfcTQCd4duytmF3vDuhH5Hc/l7pb9N26UgQ8t/832nYcfPYO1h23qIZ0r2Jy21ATBmkTbfhXIUNaVAl+cKfAlcg/8CvqdDaw==", 
		"answer": "27yqZ5+xpdjPtYvKEtkKOZuEPk7t3A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyxxjj+4QiWxL70eS/Om2QCnAerT+RV7B7ZWPgUbSCZPjt3ddiKEmdhRt09DbroqLx81sOz7tS7oCWdisAf4V7xMnJ1Ov50GNIMdNQn4Qy8JVfaPxFjDuiZtnaNPdhwC6PIQXkbzz9AnlmhyWWj3FGoZG+tS61FM4/wQFyhIJ/5McyfofeX9x/C0Pf10D4uE8GNFk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "ir,on", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070141", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh2Bri8pY0Eh391e36JyvdCmwUsD+UV7FxMH3sV6bWa+m+wJkxM1SMzXhz+nnSoqvx8EManehL5Y+LdSMWMst/ycKd3ufiyHBTP98Ek44y8JIaPMt/8wKSS+vkH8FR8S6ELlbkdTC+EDLASLKHDFNnJCIu5+bDPolM", 
		"answer": "24axZpb70xH/+sdi7/6A7PxpL1mTdcHYesdG", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2RHl44QuUxni0O+/JWfRF2cQtjPDQbNxc3jlXaTDYuHniZ5/Z0iBiBtI+3jBq6f44l5Pi6FI/ZyWczZPPoNuzJCd3+G31nhCO8NXjsBx64oPeeYAwTSjcceZRwbAhV3WpLjB4n06hicaEQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Si,ng,hb,hum", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070142", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7xyvTxJieQCGwetHHDU7A0YGTtV6+PY+zswpJ1Z1+GhFVovjbRprf1t14Oi60b5Y+NdycPZ8tgzpC26NvI+05+DPl7pb8y5ZQbPPVSyX2re8HVJL5nwC6iLk3xdXvDwdJlizLh3I4s/OG1DMOg", 
		"answer": "26axZIf2w1tA2N4bOtDgG3Rfjr1RLFGP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7xyvTxJieQAGMdr3qHErNhfnLrGarDfOb7zddyKFWHnhc79HnTraGw/l1PraFT6JzfZycRe8tiydSMl/TlwXVOPs9Km45m6INfeuZPwX2+fdjNJewsWH8L2z0bxGRkdk9OFcc0PA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "si,lv,er", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070143", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUsWw3mhay/ImLECyIdqmyXEvE2aJu0DdLoLg1Jua1OyCQcYA==", 
		"answer": "24OxZpX7yBiq+oo1XArzzPPsdSaQM20dqmuKUaJ4MFfxVaDPa+PqyIN4KFLFrlR64WLHr+Xx5VYOnOha5YGRd2Ikdop725DEl8fiyGVUIcdI2qVq55IecvNFgH2ffcLeMr54z2KMIlzjJzizADBkmDDCj31Du8P2tQK4W9Q4zRwx1qN9+80wM8eS3KaHpGO3lBKK2WmfCLxqFRSOsN287lGS4JA9ssSCv3KWtNj4lP/G8dkOIixbqYNtcFK6nqsI7CM3X4pNd5m5fIwFRCTfwhEnG/dm", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF2Bfu/5whEhP90PPrNGLeECIQoGuGVuN1YzHiFKXNe+P6yIVoaxyFiFp/+3jB47H/t0MAg6FP4I2efGIFbIpoxdWHw+XjzX5PD8hnlYFh8JsTPPVSyTy+NNXXL/BpjnqIIgXVZiqpAWJ61DDYjjxhrZCv8DW1FP0/wQEh1oF57sEwNcOeza2XqE6tihKXznqdCLh8ElyYu8mtq0KSpMIxu9mIozPY4P32lOvv/uwCdA1A/5B+b1e5jrtJ+SQ8Edi4aQZO8PHDIVfiLjyxLgwI7c7nlmBmhocqUmc7+RZFwodTdMV/2YjpuTwkf8xkEXOopldP0oZ/Wlefeqm9wmvr7ls6dm4iaoRRsgM6sxuULUZw2mqSSGxGkZN/+8IX1RZmemZPkmWglTqZhSWOb4Ds6In9ke304K5q5qtnPUmFdVjRQIgOdrrGLmRz3uCUA+ZTNd9rFizhKNQp+Sq7PlJqsMGZwm3AttpVJuelQA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Vindhya mountains,Political Fragmentation", 
		"option_b": "Coastal areas along Ghats,Cultural Exchange", 
		"option_c": "River valleys and plateaus,Economic Development", 
		"option_d": "Northern and western region,Language Diversification", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070144", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUsWw3mhay/ImLECyIdqmyXEvE2aJu0DdLoLg1Jua1OyCQcYA==", 
		"answer": "25a3eIH2w1nn/oslQV77y73cPWPfF2MfoniTR7E0PTHGV6jMYeD3ytdBNVOanV5p+2Lf7+XR9UYBi6lV6ovffyRDaoJhiNmHl8nuxX9MMtQEm452pLcecPVZjC2oet3VM+tizy7NZ3H1ZDGzC3x7kzjVi3AWiYet9Cm4UdcyzgF+1q5q4sZ8M8Wayuia5g2riROW1DuzQbVlAxSYu8rowEKOroMstMaM8X+b0ff2lPfe+d1LUhpdrJZ6cVKojuRJ3yU0VYiwbQJE4u3EchTkLmiIKAIc64vk2XhtwIssUW0ntFIGoYxabc5615SklTw2M9hvGzC/4Vn586ZEzY2sa3YivSZ7TLE=", 
		"explanation": "25CgeJ382A3r44wvXF79w738OnvABnBRrnaNV7A0eX+jd6/KYfn/x5Z2N0mbzVd+9jbSrOXk8lAHgadX5omWcyMPPopr3tGH1OH6wX9Vc8dKnsBx8ZYLaeZBwH25ZtXVM/hh3GOBM0z/aQWzJXJhmjXXhH9T6Iy9tTOyWpo+zlUfj4Z24MkufNaR3ei+6UG5n0aS2XWYRq5xHVXZtsGm/1GVopcssMnNpT2b8ff2lPfe+d1LchpdrJZ6cVKojugI9i54WMayZAdO/+fVZRTuLySsKQcc9Yvq2HJl04cnXmwI+ipSi49feMFn35fq/D02f8R4Gj36rFZF1NR1UVeFe6is2CjG6V0+Zzoqa44tlywnrw6IKV9/2nmZXzldgIVvvtkX1Qd2cXtVjnfswiuZgWucepzx5oHojOf+4Lht9uMiKk6OOlHRVc0Md7zTN2Jgw/2CMah7PJNjVybjLdo99S3qYJ+anxIC3Ngyb3Do+C6fm8j5PXb6o574l9FyVL5AJN7J7Iu+vhzEdC/1NG+SaovgSwn+XHr3wQNkoxEqxmER5maYHIx8/SMCknG3QEdlnmfhaGqgmL1Z54eAa8zGnJ/afJ1CV+835i42imKz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Copper mines in Chhotanagpur,Economic Prosperity", 
		"option_b": "Abundance of tin in Myanmar and Malay peninsula,Technological Advancement", 
		"option_c": "Iron ores in south Bihar and Karnataka,Economic Prosperity", 
		"option_d": "Gold deposits in Kolar goldfields,Colonial Influence", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070145", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC436BXbZgMFL2WLPXfOzyibJpJFSIg1x+sn/I44T+9FoKgbwbwICbeSNZQoVTxoHJ4+zyhEdIPcJMg4Ey6ZUKcuBBxTO+NNXYNPtqjm+TZ0T+JzCzF2VmmT7DhGhXqo++tSW6Rsg+xQdygo95+YgsLtKJ3KaH7Un4hROOyG6DSbEkFEyavc+m7EbcoocsosiIv3LV++btkv3B/p4KbAwSrIlqd1O5haZJ0SQ8WMmIZi5Fo6Tkc1XpJTqwa04Q8Njw33tnx5AgWHp4tB5IhsNVd8xnw4rlsHI8OsxuECGp41RMxo15W1eXNK+33G2k6Vt/YXIuJZ56s2AioBbcPEZ/nG2VT2xeksBo69wNgBZmPW5OmDbsgzGMlWSIedPh7pTrgO3+4L1q9KUiO0SOIRzKU4oVar3TG2lOxLrbOa5Zc5xoFjHyPNlu/Sv8IYXU3jUC3t5gO3/itA+YgdnwK2v6spz9zuNzB6sFJN+FzsO2pE+HaSLlYXCaaML5WASwRnHo0g1x9xcriDUY7SLcDZ96+SIdk3u+XQRrlGfhLH+um65T+Yuaes4yxvn4yCAV2mk5TS5jYrNxjWhdiIeWiqc=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VyEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRomzDRrF1dHTxR+uCY+Tt2p5+KV2bhF5ovjbHraGw9EYDm71J6ILffCcCeo5925CK2Orj1nhDJtJBnsBm69oLdPEAySWufNXVJ/suwWjAJFD8cyyvATB1mjWWhn1Yr5a68iL7Vt8j1xA3mMd85M46OcWa17zT+ki/jwmMz0efe6llBVGUsMC8qxDcqZF4tsKfozfY4LT4ibjH+NtLYQdTrJJ+bxu9ha0I62o5Xce6b1Jf+eGQRFX+NC2xKU4c98+j4XF60oc7UykT/B5SkcNXdtRh15vwuTZwLMh+AT+/sVcAxpp4HwOEdbm9wnuooFYwe245bIh4qCQ7pk+IJxRqkm7cSClHkYxk7t0cmxAjcmkAnTbjjTKbj3aGaJaj6JXwkf3ipfslWLFEP1TYawYlHBvOaiMR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070146", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddYKViAjBxoskTDsKrl5VAKz41D+YKQeTYCaoJgxpCA2aTfzWJVPNRd2olhpJkQbuZFzyn3SNrnLq9HwGqJJgLjJzizB3lxmiWWiG5Zppm+tTO0W9YkgAI3hII4/do1MdaN0KSKqEC5ggPCyWiYRrokBV2X9ci65E7cgYQ/vcyDuCHP9frFlMTdop4/ag0SuYltblqonqcHuCU+Edy8bVJN+PbDdRToLTiqNQtd8MWj+3Vux4YhXCkj9QwGi41QbtV22JvhuHIyJo1+HTb6olJBzph9XR6afamhkGfioFwtenRraphor208r0+IIFE+iG6bRSNfqI5X8INZpg1va2pS3HvpjDqYwGyBPLrt74n9xf/1srwj8awqJE6OOUWYUIIJa7eALmky3uGeTY1UMo1mEDLzL5Um9TX1M9aQyisE3t5gLnnk/S+Xho3hMGi/oND2dwsXM4bGmmIwT4jvxfK0", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VyEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRomzDRqtxMHD1Va7Ob+/3xZ5lPhyGixty4HnI46ri8kBPhqYb+oGKZCpDXIJnycLFl+H212VEIcgEt7A+pJsReLRrzS+jdcDaK/8uzWGOM1f5ZSypAXQ0gD6WnnRT6IW05yq6QNM4zlU9kMds5c18Ot6NyrzT7UCojxSHnHKfCJBlFlWdvc+U5XCIoZY9uMiDpXKItP3q2vvc4swOYRwSvpU/cFKwga0buCcxX82nKBdT+PfEZFCtKSbjMwYYueDr12ZowZI8Tyk8/RNKkcNSd9J62J+kvTwzNshkAXOuqklF1NbY1jakEKdMflQGDqYsozGI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070147", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17UyvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddQKV+AiFVvsl/Ip6zx+RM/na1Y4IGKY2IwaoRhzcPJ3ve3x35TIcNHjtpO6qYRLbRjyTO5ZtXXYNdgymeBawXfdTCuF3E41DDYjjxFp5av/WeSWt4+wVUlk5V9rcMyM8CRma6c+g2olAmGyXiYRrokEBSPtNyh7leF4I0+9d2ftDHS++Hq2uvH/9AOcUQStoh8b064nqYOuDo9UNq4ey5FzeqCIWDlJWi2NAtd9s2j0XtlwsIqUmA6519PjMNXbMN605bw/Bs+O8RrVSS7sARQ1Z1xXgWfeKT41H3hoEEwNW4jYMpsvjg7pQ6SK1E+lW3cQCNSlYwr+d8VkURneH9Pj3/0kQOFvGvcPKPx7oP1iv3j4Kp3/a0iOgGXME7dFoMTcfPVNGJ2iu+UH+ZIIZ5jEmLnM9Fu6zzrJdab0TUUkN8vOnnjtCOX0t7lPGaztZv6zsZzE7YPOMKF5s33mVLDaCKjR5mbLDko1+OhHS6ndQfcCQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRomzDcaZ6ZGPiWOfrYOn3yNsxCE6Ankh6vjbHraGw5Fwam6AbwICbeSNDaY59zZCC2evgyjFHPNQEipJ94I8cdfpHjC2/cdfSL+t9jn2UKEv1dHX9DX53mCTSg3JR6JO+9DW3R5Z31x07lY84+s0uOZeLy6mX7Un4kQ+W1DueXLVhAxSLsMmh5E2PnIwLocyZtD/e+uC5yLja454IbRpAuoVrI1qv17wB/WotQs30ZxQL9uvcZRTuLyGtNE4U94vi2Hdgw4w9HUA68BZHwpRXcYB62J7oqTc+PMhuVTGj41BIwtR9SRafeLy62WTt9Ex/enxraYVuvSF1pgCQLBR6n3uTXyVFh8IJDU2Uo564TjzSMWatXff6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070148", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddQKV+AiFVvsl/Ip6zx+RMjjqZc/I+YdWICcI8v68WFw/HlwTFIIIZHlZJg4ZkLJshO8DP8NOfaLu1l3GeUZ1LxdHm4HHN4gSLfnHlascO44CuvXcw21BA21oZ26YgpMtOay7uH50K8xg+MnHWeWqlsFEaX9c+m7wOLpZEssN+D8SDe8/32lOuT/9hLSwZWtodDbWeyxeg98C94Z8G6bBpS8KTdbkHjNCmqKR1d+Mj303Apx5FpXCk69QtTkIJaIsJ8w5bgvSApf89vASS/pkoA1ZF7VhiYZ/2v2G325RUbZ3s9bI5kvSN1oAGYaH1wnmTRbT5IlY4r8tEXkhFiempT3GHlkDrLk3WAd5bt147Ai7uwlLFmsq4oP0SNMFLMFoIaJaPFKHd+z6maA6IcMIprAzf0PNlu+SH6KJea2DxN0tw0OHLi+mqLl8r8Nmup85H2gMBkHb0VItTBqd+48EjPZGPlJGuWasTkVA3+Wzz31U5k9xsqxTEf+2vMDcl84CEZi2y1CU1q0ibub3WkmKocw4yKdo9zwwiDymnqjxb1BJZdBQoIEA==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VyEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRomzDRqtxMEfqWqPKd+y+xJhkKUiIhFVosmXDs6Ti9kcKi+hJ7ImWfywQPpxnzcKMl8DlxWdIN89FlMB+5ZQYafVHyS7tPMfUNepmjmGGZ3P5aT21HXFn3XHXhHgWgY2/+mqaRsM2zlU+l4l/+Mk7OcTfkaac+lmwxgmEnE2YRrlsCFWK/I6/7lGZ4JEousaIvw7Vx+D4jv3e9dAfIlsStpU/YFSuha0K7Go5QoigYBcL/OvGZFnoLjzjKAhd6c7sxnhshoMnWSk34RNSl5FXboB2zpvsvTw3Oo1oECetpkFOh4Z5WB6Zeq743G3goEEwNW4jYMppuTswrQCMJVFwjiuTSmxQ1INk88AWhg13eC9DiXr0ly2OwGyBPJLt6In5i/ywibdn+6JlEpVeNzsm8JOJePJZMC871g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070149", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddQKV+AiFVvsl/Ip6zx+RM9irtU/JycdWImZptjx9md1vD+y38BOtUEmY9g9p8caK58wgGjJZTyLvpnzymTZ0b/dym4FjB5nT/TmTxBrZG+tTepXdc20hw+j8d04ss9KNKbmaGdqFmwg0aS0HqYRq4kHlLZu8G6/0uZsox4nMOJuDPn+sj3yLj0/9IPIhhevp96Zxu917sA/yQxV8G3aRxfsfbfbVGtKSbjMwYYuc/mwHFlyZIkWGcgtBBAwoFEbc5p09jwsz08LI1uACGzrUMA05x5Hz+XZryowGnqoFY2Y3MnbJBsqCQ6rzOSFFot2l+USWxEgIln98oYgQ1scy9PmjbpkDCFwGOAbtP06pK8hOb04Lp2/rcuP0CUPFPWFo4Ta6fSLmVn3uyfTbJTc4tvEmL0NMYrvDb/YJ+ZzzYfxNguOzfs/SSelsL4KiWzvdL4gNd/EbEUdvjL7cK28nk1hX2Kwly6Vh51Wby9M+Y=", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VzEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZRomzDRqtxMHD1Va7Ob+/3xZ5lPhyGixty4HnI46P/5RMYjrob6ICbMCEWcp9m3tGd3uv5hHJOPdJWk4Jn8J8bPOBPjCmlcZTJKe1rjmGGZ0z9dzavEHF6gHHdg3JRrIy25meyWpo2zhY7k4lsreEyON6emxv/3OXJyE/IDthpTIaXJWM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070150", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hcv2O2/YGmNRrnCWXLd1eX/wFLfOb/T7zddwZ0+AilVy9H/Foqvkt0EAg60b4IDfdCsVd49mxtfJ2+35w2RIINJNmcBz6p5ff+FM2Ci/ddibMvtpx2GONAX5aXm8CnN9kT/CylVYrIq6ySmHWugywQY9mN042cA5fMSP3KmY7V+rxgmEnF+DSattFV2Yu46k6k2btYM/sN7NvTvN8fC5iffG5NZLbQ4Sq456I221mawB4SsrHYijYBtH9KT5b1DibQmxPg8Tucfi2HN8x4UsTikj8Q1DwpBGbct22NjqsyAkN41lE3Ouq0FNhSKOGC7+Mq0uucunjpo47ak=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJv1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZXmnXpcvFHMc+8IKL2rG+BQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt6QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGEpFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhy9hV47xH/Ip63p9hMCgL1V/Y+WfjFDf4h7zdTJ1ve3xTFPMtJRiIF+pJgQafpEzS+0NNbeNOlry2DANUD3bjazFzBjnDTEjzxSoYW98DW+Ws53zBQ8kZJ56s18OtaS0KSa7V74kQOQ2TuCWLJvFFqlu/qg7gOupYMrusPNsj3J5vH6jvTKsNsTcgRTtohsI0+0kugo6zk9Q9y9ZxwLxezVIVDkNiGwLgETucTllnhgyIU8VHog/RwGkIZRa899xdjlsD0+OI1+HTb6lU1Ow5xlXgTWfa743W3q9Fwwe38vJYNj/Dk9pE+MKUdtm2yZAGxGnIV5+5A9hwV1dGtJnXigjj6Fh3COe5bwq5f5l+2ws6ls+aYpaVWPdUjQU80PaqbULyd9zKmPBaMcBZZpEyr/PMZu/Tf9YL+a2zZA8cs5Lnmn+CuXldj0PmCp84b2zsB+Ef8OOcPR4YnmAfobSg5D3VtS28bxJ73J", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070151", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfjnJWffCnYQt3aMXON7djHtVbPXfOzyiYV0NFOcn1h+4TbPreXx+VAGiqZPqaeRdCsCPoNuzJCIl/f+w39INc9Hm45mpJMSbPVD2H2iepTSNO0uxmeTM0rifgWzOH5GkTDFhXIM6KKt9C63Vdg+zBwmj8d364g9PsKR3amd/A2sjwjC1XXRYbNgGFXZucusq1eT4JYwsI2IqSbe+ufwjP2T5c0OIgdU/4RtbFWmkugd9yU0QoiwfQBC/+OQdVzoYACiNQ8N6crtlndg0IslVHM14BZJjMGY6fgiO3mGEc7tKh4fGcah", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJv1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEA7S6+ccbPKfFgjG43sPPgM24hE451hara+ac=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt6QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGEpFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhynjE9u4HfK47f15FwanateqYuHYC4Md59u3NmG2aT+ynVENsIEkoF2pJtfb/1HwjSrfdfaLuoux2OQJkbkJzazRHF6lzjThGgWgY2//Cb8R5o/yQYmmZVhoYg9MtPf2KqG5km5iBLCyHKfCLltFRSausC8+UqetZY99dmC8SbT8bTsif2T/9hLYBpdsZx6I0+zmKQaxCQQXt+xfhdZvaTEaVGtEi2iNAETucLwlnpm0sI9VWx09xBUkIZVdoB2zojovTwxK8RlG3O1pQRUz5E8fgSFca+s2WfqoGI3fHYuJZ5luW0lswqPLVp9nyuTSmxFnY4r/d8XgRZqf3pUmXKgljDLgneAconmq5TziuTj7Pl3+qZnLFmQOVPRQowIbLzOZ2h0iv+aH69TJownBSf1MsA8/zzqYJ6V23kPwtYhK3L1tCOUgsH8OmSuup33nZR0EaYPONWF496kpBzFcyzvO3jTcsT7VRuyihQhgTOsM2vw2BA6b4SMBg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070152", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfDwI27dBmwF43CFErNxf2HvUefDYOm+yoJ9M0mbjFc7927Fq6T+8FZPja1P/ouafmIHd41pzcKM2fC31nRGOslKicB94to2cvBJzX2hcdCbNPEu2maFZ0H1cTyxC2B5kT/CynNQ6IL79ii2RNUkyQE31oRt4dwpLtKj15Sd2ki5lQmMhjulQLgkEluYptqp5wOdsoc5po2MvT3V87Ttkv2T1d8Ydg1AscZ+bV/8oK0a7C8qX4iTYBNf4qTHZEboYCGwKAIc7c7nlnVnwsIhXG10+BZLi5dTZoB62IzhrjMzK8RlG3OtqlBIh5toVxKENK+912Hr7kZ9bUW3zvD6zvHuwvmmB6WSUQ==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6eSvSFnZRt3eGEpFxcWLsWufLfa34yJtiIh5n3K6EanMQTsi2KxWD+OAw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIlq3rDX6xidXzmWrOCYeu+2ZJ+N1CMzVp19jbFtqnk4kEOg+he8Y2XcSwEe8trwdTJ1Ov50GNIMdNQn8Bm69oLdPEAyDi7cdjUMPNrwHrAKEOwZnm+C31kmyLfnnkWq5a34TKpUeY56Bolk5F9/4R8KN+amZqW6V63iEaLzzuXSbF3FBStvcvo+0KPs4M/sI2JvjfItPr2jrje9dAfawdc/49sbFe9g6EG9mo3V4i3ZxNY5eXcIVX/JSmwfE4U99j303VtisIgSSkn4B5Sh5AWdshywtjnszMjK8xmVTKopkVTh5VoSwWXd6m91Cj35UEreX85dspssil1tR2dLFFsiSfcRSJVnYNq6tkXkkRqc3tFjnfjljaEjiWOcpej7pj/jen+p7whw+ev4mU8rRgHwgEEJJqi8w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070153", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gexD2zPy4JivTDHIBpm3DQKZnf2TxV6LRLvr725IxN06MiVR2+3jHrbH87hMDgKta/YubMCsNPp9nzZCq3+z40HBPMsFUj5Iy9JYeaPFB2QGjSNrpJf99wWDaZ2b/dym4FjBjlSKWnnRT6JOp/Cq6RsN3zRAml4s4+Ns5OJedwOiS5k6xgwiWnFKfTLRlH0fZs8G6q06dq4s2so2Zvj3X57T4lPyT+dMbbg1fuohrcBk5SmlLDZnhz3aOgN+Fs4sq", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJv1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEA7S6+ccbPKfFgjG43sPPgM24hE451hara+ac=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt6QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGEpFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhy9hV470X7OrLHx+VIIn71JqZ6TcTYGf54vzNmNl+f4ymVAOsgEiIlx7Nocc+RQyS/tZtHIL+t8zWuTawXxaT39B39khDTEymtXu8Oy+yO+Ud531QY3ksd+4tp8MdaU0KaUqFm3iQqR4HW5R6phB1GL+Y6840bckoc5psKD8TvItPr2jrjH+NtLYQdArYN8dxu5j7gF+SQ5RcG7ZlJE96TEaVGtATuwIhwJ8MTtlkNhz44sHWo75A9DkMNBY9Mzw4vhuH5wNtkqAjKprQNUh4B0WleFe7G9kHj26Vg+Z2NraI95vSFu4QCIIFFs2maZWC1dh8Bn99sc1RBqcy9XmWTlwj6Hk2rPaYfq54nmgOywprZxsqcuL0eFJ1nWQs0McKHQKHR32asbdyFz4bf+IcTwwMrMrxSK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "070154", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gexD2zPy4JivVG3IdrHaXU7d9f3+jW6GCYOzq3IVwKxybiEh052TFpraw+1YLz7xUqZqXdWIGc459z9WH1OG3y3cBOstUlZJm5ZQLPP9Jwjqpe9nIYPdgjniBNUz/cir9FnVznT7YmUBYlI2J8CaoW9RtgCE6k8d5790yONaRzeiS/kyxigeA1XeYXKQkHlLZssGk7wOYtZEs9cufvj+b5v3vn+qT89YKbAZXs5U/alX8g6AMuAIxXMm4aQtK4qTWYFfkLCG3JhoY/Yv3xHVtw8I+VH08tBlJkIZfZc4zxpfzuSAjfY0v2+YeVuXQmZgq+xrazkw=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJv1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZXmnXpcvFHMc+8IKL2rG+BQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt6QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGEpFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhy9hV47927Wr6r541IbhqdVqYGZMDAGbYR62tOMxKTzzXUBMMlKjpJ75o8LebRUw325fNGbMvd9yy6PIQX5aimyFmR1miWWgXVYr4e0+DT3FNs5xFUmnoI47N49Ndue26Gf4VmhxgmEnHyeRLkkF1WavMKh/0KIpYZ4od+MtTfn+sDxn7jh9d8YbQYSvIltcV6/g6QQuC8gQcS1YRxYsfDYZBTMMzumNRoU9sWj4nxshpIoTno18xoGj4ZYdsl82IukqDo1f85lGT+/oFBJyJo8UBHWc7K01Cjg9UYrNXw5aoctriQjpB3cK1x/lGWZQD8d1Jdj99MR1Qdsc3tSlXT1ljqPwHGAPIfx6oT5xen+pPlz/bA0IEOMLBzMXohccrbBK3N6iuadTaVZIYtmHiymL9Ap9Tb3M9aV0T1N29AuKHPo+Tnbxl/ngaup1YumageoDfuN/Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Geographical Setting >> Natural Fronties and culural contacts to Minerals and otehr Resources", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation of the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxRz4+sU3Uw2yxvL2O27UQ2sf4y7bBPo0ZH6jRqLSfOjtzJllZ0iBiBto5mPCuuX/8RMGgbxe+4+cZCsMcJgvytWdwOHyyjFNOtBNlIcy64gYffpJ3zC+NNXVJL56xmuJNQX1aS+0Fn96mTTYniMUYtTayjbnVnx7WP/VnLOQKw==", 
		"answer": "25C7Z5381gCoZo6vQJQ2uRWmnzTnGGu8NQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liVx39yfL4LFeSQ3UQsD+FW7FnZDHgW67Ma+m+wJkxdgTf1Bc783jC46zk5BMWgL1P4YiKfCwGbZgvwd7Jw+zyhGJCOsNKjol07ZlffeZFwjztfcebLvF6y3mPNVH4fnmUCjB9gCKWj31EpJr78SaiR5Z3xRY9moh/9IgrPcTfya2B60ixkAOGnHqCCLwkAkSctsep50qGpYZ4t9+MvzHTtODxm+yT8swKbAtauoI/bF26164b9yd4RcCxKB5K4+PVcxT5Mj2tLE4S/4vh33tlyYUwHV08/QwGgYxYbMVwwpHrsnInPt4qEiG1tkpEwpA8VhnWYLW9kGHq9Ec2e2kiZsp5tSgm4Q2ZPEN7n2XcWCRU1JR88ZAfnAFveXwM3GHpljfLhWaAcJzk8sD5if3zqb1i5qopLgGUPVmYX4MIYKHBJHN7xeeITaRZJ4hiEiymMscp/TfwM5uHnzgD1Jk0J3Lu5mqcnNv8K2q0vpf3msc6VL5ANcPQ6sK2vBzGcjPkImnTac20WwH/Q3P/2g1ku1g20TIE7W/LSvAqEnBQKHujaYbUQZ8wqfc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ethnology", 
		"option_b": "Ecology", 
		"option_c": "Zoology", 
		"option_d": "Anthropology", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjp9oElXxfxhfn2JmjZE24YrXrDRaJnMHjtXbPLb+Hy0NdyKFKahF9+4HPC47H48hMfjrpe55rfdisGco8vx9bJ0uf4yH5GKoZGn4Z99p9fdeAAzjiuddneYP9gjmeOI0DgYje5AX5g1CLDiHZTq5fktwP2DVzVsEo/QVL3elivySQ=", 
		"answer": "25exZ5381gCoW6tGSqyBkBuyuCgH20Mkxw==", 
		"explanation": "25y2YYX60BXm7slgWwqyw/LqO2+QCnYC42+PU6BxMHDwFKaCffj8z550K1jJmFV/92SGt631t1wZirpa+42XeSwEPp5iysKM2+j2hH5Hc8RNlYx944NfVPtXySuoZpibIe0uwXuSZ1D+YzyvF2R1mjXfhHsWp4X74S+yR5oxyRA+ksd86M0sOdma3eTT7U63igmFxTuWWrxgBFWVudfo7EKVroc89d+Isj3c+v3tk/fdsN8YIgkSu49sd1KylLxJ+SQ8EcG6bBdb9OrUZFr5YDu2JQQY+t+j33opz5Y6HWYj+l9Ui4RedoBX04v0tSY1f9liHCD6olFUyJpzUg7aNLSswyj08lo5em8lYcpksjkwsx2ZJFVqk2SSXyRYhMB898QR1QZqcmNPm2+gkDqGgWyBb9P25YT5i+HxorVmsA6dkEu2aECYRzmgr3FyJH0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Geology", 
		"option_b": "Chemistry", 
		"option_c": "Biology", 
		"option_d": "Physics", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUlURH+yvrmdXvCCm8QsXaPS+NnZGTnTefLYK3qzIV8NByGixt3+2DPraKw+EEIjqZS+oOML2AcU/QfsBEzUiI0PxR2zAhn", 
		"answer": "25y2fJTh0Br+/oouQVy/MwzDoBVc6qFyoL2ISzaQ", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5381gCq5JE1Vhf31r33OnyQDHAWonGKQa5nMHjtQKLQb+7qiYB4M1TJmVN+snPItazi+F0CiqZPqbqXeTFDe4dq3tGd3uv5hGZAIIZF2pR3944ecfFO2H25e5TPKPsuyXyPMEz+YHmvAXN7kz/fnnVZpsO082e+V9U7zxIr0ZQ4+MY1LcKama6c61irxgmMnG+ZTf1tH0CLvM2p/0bcsoc0tNmEvjzI/P3pibST4N8fdg1AsZUzI1qyk+gN4SQ5XMG3e1JM/vLVc1rkLi/jIg0S6tLwwnFk1c5pT2gg/BpUwpdeY84zxZfouT4pf85lGzC/rVBSxoB1URDWe7P42Wbg6UM2cW8qacpirio0rwaPJUc84+sHhXZIPjBOhau24tY4ow==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Behaviors", 
		"option_b": "Characteristics", 
		"option_c": "Evolutionary history", 
		"option_d": "Interactions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080104", 
		"question": "2523f9H70Aqq440lEhbnyPzxdXnVD2MFqnCNQat9YDH0XbPKLv3yyJllNByIg18783jPrqT85BMMh6lV7oubMDEKcIhqiMSB0qT+ynVUINJWk4F+pJsYeasCuovSXF6WEOvMhAm+k27azg==", 
		"answer": "24WqbYL2ww/r44wvXF73w/vwJ3+Sz1a6l8H8j4AW8WfTDMlqCw==", 
		"explanation": "252tZZD9wlnk+JJgQgz31vjtI26QDHAWonGKQa5nMHX2UefWYa33x5NkNEibhFp3snXOoqv38kA7h60b6IqJdSwXPoRpiMSB0qT+ynVUINJWk4F+pJsYebRIzS7tcdrcJfBqy3yFIwXxJyq0A359kjjVi3JC6Jep9CmoUtUlzRQmn4h2rcEyfMOX3OiX8UO5iw+BnHmUXKphFFrZvdul6k2P4IM2sY2ZuTeb5Pj4lOyT8dAPIglctot+bxu3nqYO/CU1QoiAYBtYseHGblj4NCGsKU4U6ovz12Z9z4E8UWgm+AYGh5VfZsV9wtjtsnIkN8gqAjKj40xVypVyTFeYe6r41Wbj4VI6NW0icYItqiwnqACJOxRyk32VQisRm5Js/94QhglwMS9MmXfkizGMwHGAPIfr7sDsl+3jpat187cuJk/AOlqYW4wSfPPTN2Jxw+yITbJUIZByECqmOdAi9Tv8MpeA2nkFxdQhITfu+j6cgNvwN3GzvJzqzEtIj2feH+z/BbpUd98YPVA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Isolation", 
		"option_b": "Hunting focus", 
		"option_c": "Preservation effort", 
		"option_d": "Stopped usage", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080105", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sUoRxPzy+6/JXnZDmMDqnOaEqdxYHTtUKLMeq3xx9d3KE7Jnk5o5nPIoqvz8hMOgawb+puNZisVf4cvwd7J1ur0zXRPJ4ZQk41398VdieaBkLzqWniwhMR+kOs1GA==", 
		"answer": "24KxZJWzwRXr+ZEzHR/8zPD+OXiSTTLtQ1d/O/i4O/IryHx6XQ==", 
		"explanation": "25SrKJTywxXzt401Xx/81r3pMGXEFnAUpz+KXLd7MGXrUefVYf/yzdsxM1SMlBt+/HXJtqvk8kEKi+hP4YvfeS8Te5lu3Nmf0qT4wjFSNsVRiIl849oZc/tEjC6iYcbYJe0u2mHANFDjczi0CjBgnDTbmXlavoaotSa1UJojyBA7hMd74sUxKdmWzaGW+w2RiEaW1H6CTf1lH1eQsMC8q1eVrYcr+Y2ZuTeb5+Hqjv3d8dAIZ0hBq5R+d167jugZ6iM1UNq9ZAsL4+HGblj7JSzjJhwS7MXnlnNo0oosT2A6819Ri49SIsV335rouXIgM8xkASD6okpEh5FyWBaRfbO/kGHqoF0qe24ia40tvS4hqBmVPF17iSuoRCkRl49l7cUUhRBqcmEAk3CgkjOKjnGcPJLt78Doje2wsKxx4bYuPQGPMxzfV4AZJbLOLmpzxvrbGqNONt9kEizyL9QivC32YJuR2i0E3t5gIWLz5iONm8L7OGn6oZfom91kEbIFOMXWq00oanzIN+3ftM8uYRcx2qo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Production", 
		"option_b": "Agriculture", 
		"option_c": "Preservation", 
		"option_d": "Wild plants/animals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080106", 
		"question": "24GwbdGz2Bfp8pU0WxH8hfL5dWqQPF0unEC8bZxLTzHwV67HYO77iZF+JEmaiF87/XiGtqv08kEcm6lV7YeRd2IXdo4vwd6d0vb2x2VIPMhX2oJ38I0aefoAwDS7fdrcYPF8yW+OLlb9dHm8CnQ0gDnTg24WrY2t/DW0WtcyzgFyn8ds5c18KNKN1OiW60K0iQGbnmweIg7RdWxvJk+SJhN3wQ0=", 
		"answer": "25KqZ4T91Rv48oQrWxD1h8TKkJnfl7w/D4eNsn6WkM0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7lidx39yfL4LCfsQSIYrWuRXadhc3TnFK7MLrymn849Z1GIn1B+9jbSq6Cw9VYIhqZV4ICYMC0FPoovz8KGwurzxmNEMs1NlIcy95kWefpUxTukd5TdKftiyi6UL0TkJyq4AXtn1CXZyn9ZpZOp8C++Wsk+1hA+j8dt48w5LsSL2KaXqFmwg0aL0m+DQb5lBVHZp8uk6leVr4wrvcSdonLZ8eDun/3dsNICdAFcuMZwcVy9maEa9Tl4UMawKAZD9KTVb0LkMietKgsT7dijwnxs38IgU2E19hZSwrdea9Mzwp32sXIxMckqFjy0oEFQ09RuWgGZeKis2Wfq6U86cTo/bY8trzkgpRbcJ1I+lGqIWT5U05Mr994NkBZgcmFOmXX0izCFkyeNnchfbkGCOf8URyrP6MIR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gr,ou,nd,br,ea,ki,ng", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080107", 
		"question": "25y2KJD90hDv+ZFgRhf/wO6zdWPFDmMf42yWQbdxfnDtV6KCfOjywJJ1Z1OHzVx65n7Dsaz+8BMwsJdk1rGgTx08PophzJCM2eP2w3hPNIZNlMBm7J9fbOZBzymkd9GbL/guxnuOM0z+YHmpCzBnkTLDmHkWroy08We6Wt530hAhmZJq7s0vfNGN1qXT/EW9xhGL0H/T9Ctfabo7ub3IHkEm8/h5hg==", 
		"answer": "24KxZJWz4Qvl85AjV1yT0HZiQUFZD1GhoJAFk+ZQ", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnu/pY0UxDmhe3+Jn+cQ2oErn6NQeNkYnjuVbXLYvS+2oJiM12Ag15/smLOpqjj8l8Zirsb65ffdyMXdo59wd6Ol/P+yHUBI9RLnpVx4dZfb+FDxH2sZ5TdMutn2n3MZ0vlcyrxRHF6kHHGhn1YvJD3tSa1UJo12VUil5Vs5Ms1LNaL0KaUqES2xg6X0m+YRrokEFeNvNih/0qZs8Isuo2OsCLP4eb82vnd+dMKbhsSuYltI12zmKxJ+SQ8Edqxex1e4+fVchTZKC2wIk4N68rgwn1qw5FpSmwm8V9DkZBTbNR615Skuj0if9liEDqo41dV1YJ1SRaaNLS2kGnqoFAxY3M5aoRguSMh4RiULUZ72mqbXiVSgYx/68IYmURzb25DiH/jhyzLl2CdedPt5JS8nO3k4Lxw5qIlJUiTPVncFPLiXPVt8KgavNPWs4trk4U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Wi,ld Pr,od,uce", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0Whuy0fjtOCvsQWcftXaRXa15dX/3aOWCa+P9xpphJk+a0hm6sEXNMVPIeOHP3B5jtdzJ", 
		"answer": "25K9Z5bh0Ani/oZgVBvz0ejtMHiS/SfAGvALtgA3ZxVxi/Pgbg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liVxDkzO/wO2bVDXYt4T+RV6VxYmKjQKiCbOLqwdd/Jkicn1p3snPKpqj1+Uccz+BX4IWaMDEMd4cjiNGAxai303BVNtQN2oF84NoSffoNwTypcZTeLPtjy2CUNAW4dCy+DDB1h3HQhXNS5MOo/SK3QN8ljFUzmIM4+do9MsSP1rqHqEu5hQ+O1W+YTa4tUX2N9cem6E+JpIcr9duMozvU4ee5mffd9NcfawdcrMZzalC517oc6is0HYihehBK/6iQclvuKSfuIg0S98Tu33clhoE8UX0h5h5KzsNXbMQzxpfotSY5PMxmVTKps0FD04c+jByWzy/nmlXq5a0dT1PkrA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Natural surroundings", 
		"option_b": "Socio-economic conditions", 
		"option_c": "Agricultural resources", 
		"option_d": "Geographic features", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080109", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q9I0hXBn31r32OyvTD2scomuGEqJ6dDHxXbHHfK39xoJjNFmazVJ24nfFt+Xx+VAGiqZPqZ2aZDYPe4ZqxsSaiKYrd6bTMGaXirvewgHG+Umf", 
		"answer": "25y2a4P20Arvt4wuEgrgxPn6dWXVF3UesXSQEMYXKYYsV+e8Y2be0OJfiOE=", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ/01Aqq/otgURL7yPzrMCvRDWZRsXaVV7E0c372RrTHfa3yzJMxM1PJmVN+snfEoqv0+F0CiqZPqYGZMCEGbJ9uwd7JxOHj0H1EPsNKjpMy5ZQbPPlJyy+sYN3ULr5hyC6QKFXlazipDX96h3HzkmhErY6+tSapXd4+1Axyl4l8rc4uOdKF0KaUqFm9ixaHznqFXa9hAhSQu46L7k2IsoM09eyeuDOb8OHrk/bUsMoDZ0hGt49tZxu9maxJ6y87XsawKB9C/ejVb1rkIWiBBE4e+N7w03Apy40/WGQx+gsGjYUWcsV8xpTh/CY/KMx4ESD6t0xFh71yWx6Xev2rxWrn71srfHQua54ttSN1sgqdOld22mSaDC0RmY95+5ARmhdzdHtBnnrlwi2Oh2yActPX44nvxeX5p6ti5qooJwGJJhzZRZ4TZrrBM2J2iv6SGa4cJ5diVwvoOdpj3SvgIZjUzCkI0dIlPWSn9SSd0tn9PCWIupW5uNFyHbxAJtTK+cey8iP/ALEXUJ3iAllosVwwET0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Introduction of new technologies", 
		"option_b": "Increase in trade networks", 
		"option_c": "Expansion of settlements", 
		"option_d": "Spread of diseases", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080110", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxbm8sUkWxqy1unwO26QAmwV432MXKY0ZH7sWLSCfuH/0Nd4KRyIg1hy93jS47b140cDiqVe55qML2AZ+W3ZcwKe+vajXDlF7AME", 
		"answer": "25CrfJDx3RD5/4wuVV7m1/z7MCvCDHcFpmzBxscV2qj1kANl+kCd0CFoew==", 
		"explanation": "24asZ5/2kRjk88UiXRD3henwOmfDQ3IdomaGVuN1MHLxQaTLb+G+25h9IhyAgxt+82TKuuXj8kcbg61W7ICLY2I3do52iMeMxeG30WJEN4ZClZIy8psNdftV3329YcbLL+1r3S6MLk71JzGoCmR9mjaaymhfpI+y+yD7QNIygAY9n4s0rckyOJePy62D6V+xiAHCz3KFTa4kF1uL9cq/7k+QqYw/po29tD3L+PG5ifHH5d8fZwwSq456bki5m74M62o2VMmmKB5K+uHDLRT/KT6mNR1RucPq2nh6isI5UWgg8R5Tkc8WY853lo/rszY1O41rBza7sARXz5FuWleCfLihkGvr9Vk7NXk5YIt5uW0hqQqPLRRqlWSQX2xFm8Bu8MMMhwEjaWdFlWSgjjadhWmGdJzs78Ioxa4eIrJ5q2WwrWENPpRB", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Establishing trade routes", 
		"option_b": "Enhancing artistic expression", 
		"option_c": "Practicing religious rituals", 
		"option_d": "Providing medical care", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080111", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEgr31/C/M2TCQ3YZpj+OW6RmcWXqW6mCYeu+2ZJ+N1CMzV1p/XuGgKD+40EOg+h6+oeeMDYMPp9nzZCg2eD+xX8BINNGmY988JMRefpUjDm4cZTPL75r1nqSIkj1JzqyCHQ0gzTXnnRTusO4+im/Xc4+zxshycUhiY4yzKn9V2tbMDww6gfO", 
		"answer": "24W5ZJT83RD+/4wjEgrgxPPsPH/ZDGxT5bDfnE2EpqkkxtSsLKwO0Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+2B749pEpXRCyyvu/JW7fE24U43mRXa40U3TtQLXDYq3f2p5wZ0iGzU9z9zbvraH59l1PnL1Z6oGRZCsNe4V7iNSc0qTjyzFEK9JWn413pJkQcPAA2zisYNzeMr5twWCELlH5aDeuRHln1DDCnm5fqpav8CP7QNV31B031pRo6Mk3OcWMmaeVqFmwg0ar0n+eBZx2CFWX9cKp5USJoYU99cyDtXLP/PG5qPHUsOgOZgFR/5Z6bEuwkug98CMrEcW9bwBK5e3fbxTiIyu2NRwY/YvixHt8yIZpSWExtAtTkI0WbcYzwpDh/CE1PMJkEXO3qkhMwppyVgKbNJ+bkH/s5Vt/YXIuJYlisCl1tgqdPFx7iCufQyFBkYxn+9RZhQFsbWNF3HDyjTLLk2qaaJujyIXykfrxrPlC4aomaVWPdU/dU4ZccrLSKmJgiuiJCKdPcQ2gAC+/uijPLTgNZDURz/o=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Nomadic dispersion", 
		"option_b": "Agrarian consolidation", 
		"option_c": "Paleolithic transition", 
		"option_d": "Indo-Aryan dispersion", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080112", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q/5AtUxCyxP7rPH3ZF2sUsD+KXKV4ZXTtV6KCfejq3Zt0KlmHmRtr82LSprf+5BMOgawb7JaPcSwQd4RhiNmHl+X5x3hEPdIEjol/4YlAPuyA/NLTvD6AVgx32erySpQ=", 
		"answer": "25S8fpD90hzn8os0EhH0hfD6IWrcD3cDpGbBnqZYy7sDPUprVpKDK+xQeA==", 
		"explanation": "252tZZD9kRjp44w2Wwr7wO6/Jn7TCyIQsD+HV6V7YnTwQKbWZ+LwhddyIk6MjFc74mTJp7Dz41oAgeQb6ICbMDYMcYcixdGC3urwhGJINMhNnIlx5ZQLcO0AxTC9ddfPJfou3WuUM0n1ajyzEDBklSXCj25Yu8O6+yP7UcInwRshn4h2re4zLpeW17uH6UO7g0rC2H6XR69hAkCYocen5QOar440utqItXLZ7bT6n+rW8dJLchpdu5N8d1KzmegF/S54Rcf0ZBNZ9uHCIUfoNDyvIgMY99/wlkdgy4slXHs47VMGgYtXbMd2xdjtsnIzM8RnFCe/40VOw9RuVgGTZv27333281AsNXMlY4Z4uSM2pAvcPFx72m+ZXylDgIlk8JAWk0RwcmJF3GXlliuHhWiKcofwq4HygajkqLwj/6wxLEyFO0iYWYtcdbzQMmtz3uCUA7UewHE4b3bY0kaOepVcRSefUw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Domestication of wild animals", 
		"option_b": "Advancement of metallurgy", 
		"option_c": "Introduction of complex societies", 
		"option_d": "Use of renewable energy sources", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080113", 
		"question": "24GwbdH23w/j5YouXxv80b36O2jfDnIQsGyGQeN6f2WjW6nOd63wyINkNV2FzV5393vDrbHjt1Eam+ha5Z2QMC8CcMZiydSMl/fj1mRCJ9NWn5My6JMUebR/8wKSS+vkH8FRgi6XL0zzb3mtCHFt1DCWmHNarcOy+2eoXNsnyRs11o9t4MkyfMSazbyf7UC9iBKRnHqfTP1xA1aYu46k6k2Ys4E5pcie8w70Zc3907+PZVenLFd/PGs=", 
		"answer": "27eqYZX01AqoTJxopJyrfmmjqRx0+tYT7A==", 
		"explanation": "25i5Ztz+0B3vt5Y0QAvx0ejtMHiQD2sapj+BQKpwd3TwFKTNYPnswJVkM1nJmVQ75n7D46D+4VodgKZW7ICLMCAaPo5hydKF3urwhHJOPchBmZR78pMLZbRBwjntcdrTIfBtx2CHZ1HiZjeuFH9mgDDCg3NY6Lez8DS+FMkj0gAxgpJq6Nt8NdqP2KuHqF69khKO2XaURqkkAVWNocu65VDcoYw89difszPVtPD8jP3f/84GZwZG88Z+b1ezgKEH/2o+Xtr0fBpOseHDdVXvLCGwLwMY99+j2XIpxY0kUHw6/QtPh5AWY853loz2vTY1f99lACe/sAaxb2scAqkYJVmZ0ee/UF1q", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "br,id,ges", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080114", 
		"question": "25G9e4H6xRyq440lEhz3yfT6MyvEC2MF43qNRKpmf3/uUanWb+G+zZJlIk6EhFVy4XuGsKr88l8Wz7tT6J6aY2ILa4ZuxpCI1PD+y39Sf4ZNjsB799oab+dFwimkddibNPEu3GuDKEL+biO4RGR8lSWWgmlbqY378CG9W8gj01Uxl4k4/sE7Mt6Z0KuS5lm0n0a940Sud4JbLmum9dqg7gOSoZYtp8yB8SHO5ub2j/bX+dAMcUocUO8faGM7tQ+ImmEpGG0T", 
		"answer": "27y2bp3m1Bfp8sdWhK4YIpIbkvWR/ORC+4W6", 
		"explanation": "252tZZD9kRjp44wvXA2yzfzpMCvRQ3IDrHmMR61wMHjtUqvXa+P9zNd+KRydhV4793jQqrf/+V4Kgbwb3oaWfCdDaoNqiNWHwe3ly39MNshQ2oNz6toMdPVQyX2lYdnaLr5sy2aBMUz/dXmpCzBnmzzTynlOvIa14Wv7XM86wRtyl4Rs5N41KN6ayuif4Ua9xgKH2nSDTa5wEECQusDkq1aOooM2vNeMpTvU+ri5m/bXsMwOcQdHrYV6I16kh6QG8T45RcG7ZlJI8OqQYFj+L2ivIg8Zud/slnVl0oc7XH09+xFVwopYIsVw2Yv9ryY1Mt4mVSG/sEtV1Zd5HxaAdbS00Wrt7FwrbDZrZIRp/CIjpB2dJFg+n2WKRT5emo1u8MQYmURgcmFElWLpjTGYwn5lvnP958XxRRTiS4MPF9U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "in,fl,ue,nce", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080115", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3gv48okhRhf9y739MH/HBmcf43uGVKxmdWL3VbPLYeOyiZR0NVmIgRtr4HnCtqbk/lwBw+ha54rffCMReY4v29Wdw+jyyXRPJ9UEk4x+8YkLbvVUyS7tfNvMYP1mz2CHIlawbjf9O09Lqw7ptUNpl8O49Cn7UMg+1hByhY9x69wvfN6RmaCG5Uy2xhWHyG+dTbBhH0DZpc+8/0aOrpF6SvZ+8Ysm9o7zLUyl8DB3PQ==", 
		"answer": "27m5ZpXg0hj68seqUBlCJFTEgPPOxyZZuUeg", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2Rjk8IAzEhf8hfH+O2/DAGMBpj+RV7BhfGXqWqCCaP/xxNdwJEiAm1Jv+3PV46n5/FZPi61d5pyaYzYCaoJgxpCI2eC3x3RTNsdI2pBg654Kf+BJwzPtd9XVYPJrz2rAM0qwdDG0AmRn1DjYym9TvJe38Cq+Ws530BQmgoJq49t8GNKZ1rqW+1m9gkaDzn6QW/1wA1WXpsin+U6ZpMIxu9mC8TPJ9fb1n7jf8dAPIgtTscZsdkusmLoduCY5Q8+xelJb/vTFbVX5KSetNEJd+sTtwmZgxJc9VGcztAtJwpdeZ4B2xYzlvj45LMVnED2u40tGh4dpXQSCdbOs2WnooEY6YW4nYIdosjkm4SyTJkJ7iHiZQDUd1INj/94ekBcjdGEAn3rpjz6fhSWOcpej+YnqgPqwo7Z24LAiOgGDNFKYV4EPavPMImZ2iv2UTbVZJ4trEi/jM8Fu7zHwJoKHnz0Y1Zk0IDfm+D6cgMzhMGq0oNLwgJRxEbAHJNDV4cK0sVCHYizvJXSHb8T6Skq26Jr+ngJ0eBMtViGKa95Y", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "la,nd,sc,ape", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080116", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+3g/v+oAuRl79w73vOnvFD2MFqnCNQeNyYn7uFKTNYum+25J2LlOHnhtv/TbRorf98kFPjrpe6J3feSxDbI582N+HxOG30H4BNt5QiIV/4doIefVUxDi/NNfULvpn2mePKVawdDGyE3N1hzTFymhercOy+zOpXdk21BByn4ls6NosMNaGmaqW/Fq9gwjC1G6cSbMkHF2ep8+84kyS4IM2sY2yjg3ky8vGpcfssNgKYRxdrZU9nAjqkxYq8glOkFZvU6MF3g==", 
		"answer": "27a0YZzyxRDptb75u1vfYZ9secp7AdHhvvY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+2B749pEpXRCyyvu/JW7fE24U43mRXa40c37vUKLQLv/7zp5+KU/JmVQ75XfUrqDit1IdiqlIqYqKdWIXcctq0MSb0unyhGZEMtJMn5Iy55UReP1UxTKjZ5TfJfNhwH2UNUTkYir9EHhx1DjYjHBDrY248Ge0Upo0zBw/l5Nx7og6PdSL1rqAqEK2xg6X0XqfCL9hGVWPvMG6q3eUqZF4uMSKozPP/fv31rjS454YZw1c/49xI0+0kugE9zw9XM26fFJE96TAZFv9LC3jIRwS9IvA03p91IMlHUgn/R4GlowWdsh2lrHquDsxMY15ADG5rEpUzpp5UQPaNLWx12Do6VI3YWlrbYV6/C45qAKdPF192n2dXiVQgIlk8MNZlgVtPX9Sk3vwln+bj3WacJL34o/yxeX/trxu960zOg3AJlTZRoQSYvPUL2IyzuCIGbRVMYpzHi3ofdoovDHsLZeanykCwMwsLmPu+ySK0sz2K2qpoNL+i9txBr4QPtjGqdmyt1XIbzCj8hyC45qF2C90yCyRa2WrCg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "cl,im,at,ic", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080117", 
		"question": "24GwbdH2wg3r9YkpQRb/wPPrdWTWQ2cQsXOaErBxZGXvUarHYPntiZl0Jk7JgVpw92WK47f54VYdnOQb6ICbMCMRe4p8iMeAw+y3xXNUPcJFlJQy6psLaeZBwH2/ccfUNexty33AMkv0YiuuB39mkSKWnnRT6Iq14SK8Rts7gAc9moI44s58A+ig5pes13KHuUaL0juCXa10HkaNvMCvq0uJrYM29cGEpzfX/fz2lfzAst0iaJZ3CPjgHuJMD0KfWVg=", 
		"answer": "27C2fpjh3hfn8os0EAiohIfNmzQhjGuWcsp3pN4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyxxjj+4QiWxL70eS/Om2QDWMFtm2CXuNmdWLsQbXBa/6+2oJyLxyInhts82LDseXy+FcGirsXqYiaYjYKco4v29+A26i3xX9Fc9FNloR+7ZwaPOdJyzOkct3YIfB6wnfALkjgZjqpAXQ0gDnTym9TpIa44S60Wpo4xlUhk5Ns4c0xOdmLmaSc60ysjwmMzzu0Sa9oCBSRoMOp5QOPpZYsuciAtDzP57Tun+rWsM0fcAlGuoF2YFqwm7FJ/iUtX8yxbFJC/6TRc1HsM2ixLg0VucLtlmBhw5EsHXsx5xBTkIBTcYwz15TosyU5McoqHD2yokZJ05VySwTWYLL41Wbj4VI6NXMlJYtuqCQjqBuVLUc+lmKXSWxZgY5/994e2URlfH1NlXjnzn+KjmHPaJzs583xhOP5rr4jxqsuOgGTLFHaX4IIbLCANWJ+y/2SAqhPO5Z3VyDjKcIr+Te5KIOZ3jcekNguKzfz/C+QgI3wN3OzoZ33g9F4AP8XN8KF+cKhv0jGbWPnLm/Tdd7nTQ3+TnL71k5kuRxl2zQC/mvOCYU9GceZEnIqp2l3zud6+8N8Kw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "en,vi,ro,nm,ent", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080118", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUlXAj71/LxOG7eF2Md43mCUbd7YmKjQ67WZq3qwZJ4NRyKgklp92XWrKv0/l0Iz61d74ucZDFDcYUvwMWE1uq313RVJ8pBl4V88IldGn7/Bpl/2io85Uaf7QkETQ==", 
		"answer": "25CgfIP23Byq9pcpVhfm3L3+O2+QBXAUpmWKXKQ0ZHTuRKLQb/nr25JiZxHJoFJ84HfSqqr+t1wJz7hU+ZuTcTYKcYV8hJDJ9Oz2ynZEIIZNlMBg7YwabrRDwyi/Z9HIYLMu6GGSKkTkbjazRH9y1DTXmHBP6JC+4TO3UdcyzgEh2sdZ+8k1MNad0KSa/FT4iQDC0HqaTa4kEFqd9dyh/UaOs8J19f6YuCba9vj82vTc898fawdcrMZ5bEn8k78M9CYxX8+nKBNF9aTCZEfiNTqgIh1RuePq2nhwhpIlXH0x9QoGjZEWdc980p3g/DMiOsx5VX76h0FTwoZoVhiYNLK+kHvh9EEzcHcua55+/vnQgCGxnJBinDHp/X1c3Jo=", 
		"explanation": "2+T4TYnnwxzn8sUhQBf2zOnmdWreByIXsXqGSKp6dzH3UarSa///3YJjIk/JhFU783iGorf19hMMjqYb74GNcydDboR/3dyIw+34ymIBJ8kEl4l19psLebRUw32ge8beYPZh3X6JM0Tyazz9FnVznT7YmTAWqZD7+CK1QNM4zhA21o52rdw0OZeP2LuA6Uq9ugjQnFiZSbNjFEfZvMDo+UqKpZB4tsKYoyHe57T6m/aT/NsKZkhGsMZ7Zki5hbwA9yR4Xs70exdf5ejVbFHjNDvjJh1d9M7twn1myIctHWA6tAtOh8NGY9Ng15/h8HIxLI1+HTappgRDz5VyWBKFNL653ijt7UU+dm5rcYJo/CwjoAaQKVZ3lmKIVWxeksB8/8Qch0Ric2sAjnPzjSqZg2CcQJ2wq7T0gKjgoapw86QiaVKUNEjdRc0IbbLUZ2Jz2OWCTbVZJ4trEi/jM8E9vC78MpPU0D8Z1ddgKXjy+i6clo37PGSo8574hdFlVLASdsPM/86loxCHdivoInXTdtn7TwH0Sni4wQt2uA03yyQDqGTXGsls4D8bl2ixRQRlnCOgYHW3k7JV4o2Be7I/h7XE1D4cgbg4j5f2wBg9Ukj7gm0DpYuQS1lLjVXEG8wUhAg8CfQMEZjF+2KYkHKQQnJNa8bzQbiG0D9J3eaxj3I9rIUHQY2MIBybhtElyQO4DvNqFWHiusb9KvkZBm0i/aExzvik9960NeesKWw4LwiySuBM4ZZUKANtEALRBCZGbLG6T90fT+QPwnrekglcTn5FRVzD6egNThCrqMjBfWLXbbZcHRv2d78AHsv2WlSNvHejjcNsasiUTIZNKx/wCw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Extreme aridity and freezing temperatures,Migration of populations", 
		"option_b": "Changes in river courses,Formation of early settlements", 
		"option_c": "Availability of lakes and rivers,Suitable locations for dwellings and resources", 
		"option_d": "Hilly plateau or wooded areas,Desertion of settlements", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080119", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fAb/77zdd+KRydhV474mTJtaz08ldPn6lI+o+YdWIKbctsx8Kb0ufjnk1PD8gVwMBX5YgTZbRTySm5eNHWJfB63S6JKQXZaT20BTBjkSPTyntTpoap9Cu3TZoxzwA8koJ8rcY5PcXf1amY7V74iRTCznKHTa93UV2X9cah50+F7MIoucyZtDPOuLT2iLjE/9EPZwwSvpR6Ykj8gKAM6i94Qc27eB5OseffdFjpYCWiLAtd6t/s2HEpx4wtHWs7+hoGloxZbtMzwpekuTMiMY1rVT+ztUFMzpxzUBOqeoG2gjKkw10+e30udspksm02rQaRKUB72mqSSGxDnZZu7JAamhFxbmpT3Hrlhn+fjyWbdJaj74XvgPrkqbZtsqwhaVKPOFmYRYgIcb/FKmJ83vrbDKhYc5JuEDDnKdwh8nn2JtaE0CkY3Ng0Jnjp5xaXrsOmYyWOu5e5mtF1HLEJJ8TA+ou4thzKYCjoL3rTZ4vkVhzkSm6BwE5yvx0gxGER+meYG4By/CEMjD6kRgRwmijzaTy0hbtYqoCXP48/0Pzp0yZQm/1ulpf+zhwoTgu1nj1hETsC96L9YS8IAD+nLTQ7", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhe7qJXvfEXYUpz+BS+NgeHSjRKbRfez5zNdmL1WKhRto5nfSpraw41sOm+he6JyTaWIQe597xNWE0urj1zFWNtRB2oVh8JsdcP1TxDipNNreIewuwm+LIlawaCv9FnlikSPFynVY6JCu/DO6VtYygBA8gI5q4sYxOdmLyuig/EysgwuH0m/RGv1lHV2eu93o/EqIqMIsvcjNoTPI5/X+n7/AsNMObBxbsIg/bF38lKAI9i09Qoi9ZlJI/e3dYEDoYCmtI04P8N3mxDRqyZc7TmwntBZIhI9DZ85w35bj/CI/L9hmFCezrEoC2P2XzDJbt4O4kYi6oQH9qA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "3 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080120", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fAb/77zdd+KRydhV474mTJtaz08ldPn6lI+o+YdWIKbctsx8Kb0ufjnk1PYpwEspV/5ZRfffBWzTOucdneLup9jmeOZ0T+ZDC4CmQ0gDjbj28Wv4ap8GeoW9YyzAxykpVx+80yfNWGmbyb7Q29nhaO03KFSaltHlrZusjo5UKItZA5uY2ftCHU4eb6n+vv/uIFMFISnI5+bVy5hOgA9mo7XcG5aQZOseXeZRT/KT6mNU4e9t7xxXF6hoooWSk6+19Pj5NXYdQz2ZaktCc9PsMqBjaut0hFypFySwTWfbP40Wbn6VAxYTo/bIdorxE7nQHPchRbgn+OSSFU1IF599QQgR0jfGFE3HDyhzqRiWuIPIfm5pD5l+nktatm4eMuJwGjMFLMRIwQJZLTLmYyxuyfTbJTc5JuEDDnKdwh8nntL4GVzT0ekM0oKjfO+i6Qk8O1KnC4sJ33mt14EbEUdtPcqd+/tRzUcSbgKniBdYv7X0jkR3m4+gBhuFUE2jgR5iLUCYd44CwKmzwQ54qkANgiPUCshu/Rrzv3", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VzEhfhhe7qJXvfEXYUpz+BS+NgeHSjRKbRfez5zNBiZ1GMg09y/XiGrKOw8ksbna1W7M6eYisHd592iNGH06Tx1nREKc9KncBm4ZcPeeZB2Ci/ccebKfAu7WuOM1fxa3mcF3l11D3Ti3hfpoT74Sj7WdMw0hQmn4h2rdwzK9aN3bvT/EW9xi+M2HKQRv13BFaausC84k2ZrpZ6wOkJviL/dAbtCddLr9ZqJQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "3 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080121", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcRbzy/r6JivZDSISr3aOU7dxMHDtUOfQZ/v729dyKEmbnl5osnXJrbHi/lEam61fqZqQMDIMbp5jycSA2Oq3yXhGIcdQk49899oecvAA2DWoNNDeM/t82mePKQX/YXmuAWRgmDTbj3JCu7+1ySmJUdskzxto1q9t4MkyfMSazbyf7UC9iBKRnGyUWrgkHlKNsMDo7lCIoYA0vN6FtDab+vH4iLjE8coOcEhQsIJ2Zkjw16kH/Go5XdyxehNf+OvechTkLmigKwcQ+N/mlnVnwsI7VH8x5l9FjZZEccVglpztrjczK8FzVTq3s0VD05F4HwOecf25xmnt7FQ9fHYicZMtsyt1swqPJ0FsmW6PDC1fkMBn98YcmQ1rcmBE3vo0OzZjnEcq2g6q8rtIGxk=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iYN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw41sOm+hY4Y+RdycQPoJhiNOF3un20HQBMshA2pJ78p8NPPdP2S++ccebKfBownuFKUb1Y3mtC2BhmDDCg3NY6I604yK2UdQj01UzmIM4/s0oKNua1K2d/F74sg6HnGmUSa5rHxSauty67kCIrJt4sNWdvTPS+ue5jvDS5J4fag1BusZ8a1qykK0auC4xQ823fB5SseXWZ1HuNC2nZxoV/IviwHVgyoMrVGU94AYGjYUWcMVg2Y32vzcjc419HTq5qwRXwoZ5HxSEYb6x0WSk5lotNW4jYMp+qT8jqBmdJBRxnCuPSThFmIVm+94NhkbFqijE3CerFHWnzt3WzGzo", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080122", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfD2MnnRF2serT+MVONnYHTiX6LQfa3xz9dlL1nJpFV//Tvnsbzx+RMDjqZc/I+YdWIXcZxu2tSal/D/wTFoPcJNm44y948df/tO2DSjcdrPYOlv3S6EMkCwczb9AWhghjTbjzxXuoq//DOiFNs5xFU0hIJ998EyO5eL3KWD7V+5khOQ2WjRQbMkMlGXodyp5wO9s4s5icOxvwDe9ef2lKKTxNYOIiFcu4kyQkmllqZJ9Cs2Vt21bxcL4vTVYF/oMjvjNAEI/sP3lmBmhoc6Xmgk8V9WjY9fdslw15Skvz0+OcFjFiep401Oh7d5UQOEdbH48Xvt4RdDw8eAgqqTtHB2c716yIEA", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RtHeKUas0cWX3Rq7Ae/n72tdlL1nJgFJ84HfSqqr+t0cAz61D/ZyafSdDf5lmzNmdzqT2ynUBNdRBn5p76p1faPFN3Di/dcDOMvt9jkaPMEDmYivxRGR8kXHEj31Fp437/DT7Uts70xB+1oZrrdw0OZeP2LuA6Uq9xgKN2WjRRrJwUVmcu9qh5E3csI00vNmEsjPXtPf2lP7f+d0fcUhTrMZ+I1i9grsMuCw3Q4igYBcL/O3Xc1X5KSetZW7aoaW+JcyFJkKsQyHEFxs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080123", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfjxI2LCDGwcpnGXErN4cWjwFKaCfeT5x553Ll+Ig0874HnKpuX5+RMch6lL4ICYMCoWc4phiMOMw/D7wXxEPdJX2oF84Noef+BJ2jS5fdHIHPBSwFyFJlb/aWP9LGV5lT+Wj3pQp5Gv5me6Rt930xo+k4thrdo5L8eQ17ua6kG9xgCNzjucR7ltF02Qu8no/0uZ4Iw5odifsD6b5+HriPfG/toCbA9B/5JwI0ipnrxJ7CI9WNr0ZhdO9feSpu37DPrLN0nF8TMA6k/vxw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gRhb3hfzsJm7CF2serT+CXKc0YnTiR6jMLuzszNdlNUmMwRtv+nOGsaDx5FwBz6FIqYCQZGIXdo4vy9+Ex+jy0HQBNt5UloF85Y4Wc/oAjCmlcZTeLuhn3GGOKkD+c3m1BWM0lXHSg25Tq5f79yK6RtM5x1U9mMdw+MU9Mpea366c+lmrykaAyW/RQakkEFiKuo67/0KIpZF4ocWMpXLT4fn4lLjW9tgEcBxB/5VqYUiolqYd8Ss0XdH0aRRN9OfEIUDlJWitJhoI68rvlmd81JAmSGcw/RFBkc8WcdV00Z33qDs+OI1rVT6vt1FBy9R1UQOTZry7xGHr7hU9cG48YI9j/CUgrA6SOxR/lG/cWCRU1IVl6NkLmgpueGFU3ppwmcWYmrGamBdrUXwxFqo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080124", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdx/gyeS/Jm7EF24UrnqNRrA0eX+jfanGZ+y+3pJjIhyMnk968HrPsK318xMBiqlJqYKeeycQPoR9iMKAweHl1zFFJsMEjo8y8JIadeYA3z6oet3YYPxrz3uUPnn+WzePAXFnmz+MylBXo4aotSa1UJolyQM3hJQ4/dozKt6b3OiSqEO5khOQ3XfRW7JxA1ec9cGuq1SdtIcq9cyDtXLJ8ef2j+rQ9c1LbA1RupVsYkml164G6mowRMW1ZlJY5PbGaELsLGr3pOnCZ7OZN9f3VzEuU6DE", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iYN5IhzJiFpp/m+GsKDk418Kgq1V/Z3fZycRe8tpx8WH0+HzhH9EMtQEloF54Ylfc+YA3jS7ccbIbL55xmeDLwXgdTarDXRxkHHEj29ZvZG48DT7UtUlgAYnhJFx+8kwfOOX3OiB7UyriQjC33SDWrhnBViA9cuw+0+dqYwr9dqFqHLP/PHqn7jf/90KdgFdsZU/dF6ukugK8CUrVMb0bh1ZsffVdUDhJSWmKRoOu5LRIHd/IeEVXQaVCcYZfD4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080125", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcRbzy/r6JivZDSIDqmmGQON3f2TxR6LRLuzy3pZoNByFiFp/smLJ47H48hMOjalV7YGRfScNastgzpCa0vDjyHRMNshQibx82JQtefVTwzP3NObSNvt8jm2PMlfjYir9AHVgkSPbg3JT6Jez8Ge6Qts+zBQwn4tx+dF8M9HfzqmH7V/4hwiGnGmUW7JxA1ecpo6h5QOd4JA9ssSCv36b4/zwmfCT898FIgFfr4d8dxuon61J7iM5U8G4YQZSsevWIUfoNDyvIgMY99/wlLgArtWdwg8e41/pHgVGt8w=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRri9osnVw2yzPO/J2LGBnBRoHCWQLBxYzHgVamCZ+DuyJRlZ0+MmU9393vDrbHjuxMbh60b6J2MdTAXd4RhiNmal/D4yzFAMdVLlpVm4doLdPEAzzWsetPeM75nwC6SLlP1dXm+C2VmhzTFyn9XpsO38Ca/FM44gBE3hYJq+cEzMpeQ3+iA7VmsigOP2XWFW/EkE0GN9ce8q0eTpZE28tnNsj7a/fm5jvDS5J4fagFB/4dzdFqlhOgB+TooVManKCZD9KTCZFX+LybjLh1d/s7t02Zoyo4wHWo75g1DgZcWYNVnlpbrqHIkN8gqBjy2pgRSwpVvUBnWcrKqkHzs5RU+Zmkud55ksyN3aRLgRcsp7OGQ7v/35kpWCg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080126", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxRzp/4svXhH1zP7+OSvRB3QQrXyGX6Z6ZDHmWqbAYuj6iYN5IhyMi11+8WLPtaCw81YJgLpe+pqeZCsMcMtuxtTJ1PH70HhXMtJNlY4y65xfdPVSyH2seNjONvdvwi6TKEz8JzCzRGR8kXHxi3JRrZey9merWNs+zgZyl5V3+MY4fILPieixyxL6eZ8mvh2ecY2TxKrylLDyHg==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdH63w34+IE1UQr7yvO/Om2QEHYerXrDRqx7fGKhN4ULBa/sm3bUZJj8AdAdZw==", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZZz23xrj+YJgUwz90PP7dT6AUyIzgDPDRqtxMGT3XavLdOzqwJh/Z1OPzVJp/XiGor315BMOgawb+YKQZSULbYNu2tWal+n21npEN4ZF2pRg5ZQMevtSwTy5fcLeYPR7wG2UMlf1JzCzRHhhmTDYynRfu5e05z73FN860Bolk5Vx4898KN+ambiB50uxhQ+H0m/RS7FhEEaYu82tq0ya4IQ3p8iepSGb9fr92uzb9Z4IdwRGtpB+d1KzmegG/moqVNu9ZBtO//CQYFjhNT6qJgJd6sTq2jRdzodpVGc3+w1WjZFXdsl82NjrunI5LcJkVSe1rEhTi9R/VxaEdb6s1Xrt+lA7NXgyJZ5luSQn4QqSIFVwmW6YDChEhoFp99wQgR0jfGFE3HX1liuCjmLPeZXl4oP1gObzufUj9KIkIE2JIV3MU4lccbvFZ3Rr2f2eAKdIOpwnBzDpPtA973n2JtaQ2j8CwtwzO3bz/SWX3o3wN2S4v5v3iZRlG7wJM8XM7Nj3pFOHYizvN3iBcovjVgf0Sni40hxgtgtlwS8E5yLZGoh9+ShNkn++TQRinTWgbXuzn71J5pabbY89k+X5zyIfi/Fr3U948l/li+m0NywJ+WT3X+4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "The invention of steel tools", 
		"option_b": "The introduction of stone tools", 
		"option_c": "The development of bronze ploughs", 
		"option_d": "The discovery of silver deposits", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080127", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRzk4YwyXRD/wPPrNGeQBWMSt3CRQeN1ZGXxVaTWa+m+2pJlM1CMn0g75nmGsLX19FoJhqsb5YGccTYKcYV8iNaGxaTy12VAMcpNiYh76p1fb/FU2DGoedHVNO0xjIi4D4T44PRvkIHnzAgXes4=", 
		"answer": "24W3ZJ3mxRzut5AyUB/8hf76O3/VEXFTB8W8QiD66HLSocREZGRGAw==", 
		"explanation": "25O5fp7h0Bvm8sUjXRD2zOn2OmXDQ3EEoHfDU7A0YnDqWr6CdOLwzIQxMFWdhRtp+2DDsba8t18OhK1Ipc6ZfzAGbZ98hJCB3uj71z0BPs9Kn5Jz6IlTPPVOyH2rccbPKfJrjn2PLknjJzipEGJ1lyXTjjxFrZev+SKpR5ojz1Uil5Vs5MspMNaNmamB7UyrxjWS2XiYTrRnUUacssen5VDcpYw8utqItXLM/eDx2v7S5tEZYwpeusZ8bFW4nrwA9yQrHYi9ZhFH5ODZb1OtISq2KQoc99+jxHVgyIQoUWV4tA1PlIZEIs52wo/rrjkjc41vDSO7rVdJ0ZE8Uxadca70kG7r8lAsYX8vJYZssikmog6MLUcy2mOVQCBI1JRu7MIYnAovPWJJknPygzPLkmCcc4bx6IXvyajxrr0j9KY1PUiMMBzLWYQQdv+AIn932P2eCeZdc5JmECzjKdwtvCnsLJrU0DdNw9w0O3vi5jnV0sj7LWy5upz+zsB+EbJAIt6F7NijsV7LaDDpYX6ca8bhVwHkRnnrkwdr9wwtzTIVqGPKDYhst/kmFuoWcd9R/jIXpnjbjrc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Presence of barren deserts", 
		"option_b": "Arid and dry regions", 
		"option_c": "Isolated mountainous regions", 
		"option_d": "Polluted urban centers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hbk45cpUAvmwPm/IWSQF2oU43iRXbRgeDHsUufWZui+4ZZjJkyZjFU78WPKt7Di8hMOnadO54rfIndTLstN64/LEPT/MIZjZWuA9BesSpO0Yg==", 
		"answer": "25CgeJD9whDl+cUvVF7m1/z7MCveBnYGrG2IQeHQ6AX2s1LsDyCtzm39IHDE", 
		"explanation": "25SqZ4T91Vm4otVwEjzRib3rPW6QAG0ftXqRVaZ6c3SjRKjLYPm+xpExM1SMzWh64HfVtaTk/h9PtqlW/ICePGICcI8v+8Wd2+H9hGNIJcNWicBw4ZkecfEAzX2qcdvcMv9+xmeDZ0v1fyyuRGR8lSWWiX1CqY+i7yK/FM4/xVU1hIhv+cB8M9HfzaCWqGW5lAeSzHqfCL5xHUCMp8vo30uVs8I7usOLvSfe+vf82v3d9NEcZwwSq456I0m5kKEG9movWNy8KBML5OrZcEHoYDumM04S/4vi0mJoyJYoWmwntAtOg5cWcsxyz53g/DNwPN9/Fjq7rwRSyJh5Hx6YNK6w0Xjt7lJ/YXIuJYlkqiQ5qBWdPF1xlCyPDDhDlYpu/cQWhx0hXHGdyQl6eric9g9/GalLcQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Expansion of trade networks", 
		"option_b": "Introduction of iron technology", 
		"option_c": "Arrival of foreign settlers", 
		"option_d": "Development of written language", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080129", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2BT69oY0Ehr7wb3rPW6QEGoYpWuKXKQ0f3ejRq7Ua/++yphkNU+Mnhtz82DD46r+t0MAnLwW/JydcSxDVop9ycCZ1uq313RVJ8pBl4V88IlAPlCVzuHUEB2RuTR5iCiT/9E=", 
		"answer": "25O3epzyxRDl+cUvVF78wOq/J2LGBnAC4ZRKCRr8ISdm8Pzt94zQWfo=", 
		"explanation": "25ehKJDjwQvl74wtUwr3yeS/ZDyAUyIzgDPDU+NneXbtXaHLbezw3ddiL1WPmRty/DbSq6Cw9Fwanbte+s6QdmIRd51q2sPFl+r40HBDP98Ejoh3pKkKaPhFxn2setCbGf9j22CBawX4Zj39AHVghjjbj3JCqY/75yKrUcg01QYhn4h2/ogzMpeL0a3T+EKrkkuXznmQRv1MEEaYpd6p5QOPqZY9po2ZuTPPtPz4nrjX9cgObgdCuoI/alX8g6AMuDg9VsG7Zi5Fzer0dEbkLi/jMwYU6ov333lshpIsT2A78FMGgYtXbMd2xdjtsnIiNttvB3OqolBUwoZyTFeUZrKt12DwoFQ9em8/JYstrygnqAqPaFt42miUTSBdkY5s+8NZkwtxPXtImTbjjTKGlWuGaJrm+MDojenk4LFi9uMiP06MI1ncFoQSJafIIidly+KeTalac4tvEmLiONYi9Tf8YJmSny0F1Zk1PXXm+mqxk9/0KXW7vdL6h8J/GLYaN8XM5sX1HNaBCWTmoEdjovxxqXzAvQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Increase in agricultural output", 
		"option_b": "Improvement of transportation", 
		"option_c": "Formation of new rivers", 
		"option_d": "Decline of cultural exchange", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080130", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q54AvQhL3hf73OmTDBiIFrD+QV7dgfHSjWqLDfK3swIF0NRyDmFV45n/Jrbaw/l1Pn7pe4YeMZC0Rd4gv3NmE0veohgSphsIA8QmK8NS0ytNsFsE=", 
		"answer": "25C5e5Sz3h+q8YoyXxf8wr3rJ2rUBiIQr3OKU613dWKhDJjLNqU1frwq1Jf4nboc9A==", 
		"explanation": "24exfpThkRP/+YY0WxH81r38OW7REWcV43mMQKZnZGKjVanGLuz3zZJ1Z1ScgFp1sn7Hoazk9kcGgKYb65ffYDAMaIJrwd6Ol+L20n5TMsRIn8Bx65QbdeBJwzO+NODTJb5nwHqFNVb1ZC20C35n1D7Qym5fvoap5me1W853zxs+j8d74c09LtKbma6c+kirkhXC3m6FCLxoAlvZs8+r4k+VtIMssMnNuSfW9fq5kvnR+coKdgFdscZ9ehu/ha0I7CM2VoiyaQRE4+XSbVGtIyetIwcJ8MTtxTRvyZBpTmwg4BNDj4ZYdoL1y5TXGTttFhry4xFHPXwN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Availability of precious metals", 
		"option_b": "Presence of dangerous wildlife", 
		"option_c": "Accessibility to modern amenities", 
		"option_d": "Ease of forming trade alliances", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080131", 
		"question": "24GwbdH21x/v9JEpRBuywfj5OnnVEHYQt3aMXON1fnWjV7LOeuToyIN4KFLJgl07+nfUp+Xx+18amaFa5c6MfysPPoJhiMSB0qTQxX9GNtJNmcBi6JsWcucAzS+iYdrfYKs+ni6iBAXnYiu4RH11kDSWmnNFu4q5+SL7QNIlzwA1nsds5c18KcOW1aGJ6VmxiQjC033RXLVhUV2LusDo6luZ4IM2sY2yjg3ky8vGpcfsstKcVRhCdzHBL4EfUrtGrQ4=", 
		"answer": "27yqZ5+zwRXl4oIoQRbz1/i9H/qLxh5QVTQJObC43o0JXA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH31B/l5YAzRh/mzPLxdWreByIStnOXW7V1ZHjsWufNaK32yIV1Z12FgU5t+3fK47b//l9PmK1J7M6ecyEMc5tjwcOB0uC303hVO4ZQkoUy8YkaPPtGjCmlcZTSMvFgjm+YIgXxaT39DWJ7mnHGhnNDr4uo/SapUZo20honmIM4uJhsfPW8mZyb7V69xhKH33OfR7FrFl2atMLo6keKoYw7sMCIvybItPX1lvfE9dpLcQ1Gq4p6cUj8g6dJ+yY9UNr0bh1Z9PfEchTsLizjMwcR9Yv33nEpxYooUWUx+hhPjIQWcc962tSkujMzNsFjATKuqkpHh5V7TR6VYbGsxXrl7BU6bWoqa5lksyN1oAGYaEB2nyubXiNGgIgr8dZZhgF3aWNFkXPulizLiWvPaJvmq5L5guH/rvtM/NNpzBxBVaPkRn0/rRxJ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ir,on pl,ou,gh,sh,are", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080132", 
		"question": "24a9fIX/1BTv+ZFgXhHxxOn2OmXDQ3UUsXrDQapzfnjlXaTDYPny0Nd4KVqFmF518XPC46fpt1YBmaFJ5oCSdSwXf4cvztGKw+vl1z0BINNHksBz99oLdPEAzSusfdjaIvdix3qZZ0r2JwaCO09Lqw7ptUMWq4y18S6vXdU501cGlSkYIBirNnPpyjWLrxFY", 
		"answer": "26K5fJThwxz5+JAyURvhh4m7MMH4DFWZIHqBqD1Kbo8=", 
		"explanation": "25C2fpjh3hfn8os0UxKyw/z8IWTCECIdqnSGErd8dTHzRqLRa+P9zNd+IRyejE9+4DbUprb/4kEMirsboZyWZicRbccvxNGC0ve+hHBPN4ZXlYl+pJkQcvBJ2DSiesebMPJv12uEZ0SwcTCpBXw0hj7ajzxfpsO/8DO+Rtc+zhw8kcdr6NwoMNKS3KaHqEG3hQeW1XSfW/1CEEKWp8+q50bcsoMxu9TNqz3V8ee5jfHH+J4fag1BusZtZkizgroK/Tl4UNygehNI5eHUIUfoNDyvIhwOtYv03n1lw8IoT2AwtB5Uh4JFItd6wpDrqSZwLNhsEzq5qkFO09RrXgOTZv282Xvn70AtdH0uYcplvS88tQ6IIVtw2l+USWxSm41p994YgQ1scy9PmjbzlzafgWeDedPx7pPzkPrzpaoj8awpPVOJN0nMU4lccbyAM293iu6JArFIO99oEWL1OME68Dz0JZiAzHkE3pkzP3Lk/SyQkY3nPGKzvJzqzDz4BtvzEjm1IzBwG/TGeyE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "wa,ter,res,our,ces", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080133", 
		"question": "24GwbdH5xBfp44wvXF79w73rPW6QMGMDomyVU7d9PDHaVarXYOyyiZZ/Ixy6mE9393yGsazm8kEcz7hX6JeadGICPoh93dOA1ui31n5NNoZNlMBm7J9fe+ZP2ymlNNvdYOpmyy6/GHrPWAaCO09L1DLDhmhDuob79DW0QdQzgEdnxtc4z+t+wZTak0VSGDTUs+G6K+QSHg==", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjktShYVvswbDI9MPpoC3x6YoE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hf88pcnVxDxwL3wMyvEC2dRkH6RU7BicWXqGOf7b+Drx5Y9Z12HiRtI52LKpq+w5VoZirpIqY2QfjYRd4l63NWNl/D4hGVJNoZDiI9l8JJfc/IA2DWoNPzaMv9+3m+OZ0blay2oFnU0lSPZn3JS6NHupXf7dvl39B031pdq4tA1Md6LwOic7g2sjgOR2TuDQathA0fZs8+r4k+VtIMssMnNpSDa8PG12uzB8dAYcgdAq4dralSy2+gI9i54UM+mYRFe/fDFc1XhYCmgMwcL8N/q02clhocnXGs4/RFBwpdeZ4B12pfxrjsjN8RkEnO1pQRUz5E8dxaEda2o0Wak41wpfHYif4t5tSI74QuJOl1wnSuIRC1F1JBu7NkWkUa2aO0A//ShOqXe323JZDqm", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ha,ra,pp,an", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080134", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Ar+4IQyVl7hzfT5ISvfBSIDqmmGQON3f2TxR6LRIq3uyIVlLl+cgVpp/m+Gt631t2Aam6Re486efiZDR4pi3d6Im6T/xXUBMoZAn5Rg7ZcacuBBwH2kecTaI+ouwWDAGHrPWAaCO09Lq3HFj2hCpIa28CmvR5o2xgE3hMds5c18KcWd2KbTwEyqhxaS3XXRTa9lUyZ+UvQr/Ix/law61LByLxA=", 
		"answer": "26W3e4W+xAvo9otgeh/gxO3vNGWSQPRc98GyHkpBYHjMuMq+qQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2RDs44wuVV79w73tPH3VESISrGqRQaZnPDHqWqTOe+n3x5AxM1SMzWhu5nrDqeXx+VdPtqlW/ICeMDAKaI5925zJ1uDhwWNSNspd2oF04p8caPFEjC6oYMDXJfNrwHqTZ1H4Zi39AX1xhjbTjjxXrpe+52evXN931Qcwl4k4xckuPceP2KbT+EiqjwmGnDOQWrJxH1DZ5Jn4uwO+g8t4gcWIojeb9/z4lP/W454CbEhAtpB6cRu/mL0b6y8rEcy9ewBe4fDVZRT5KC3jKQ8J7Nni2jR+x5YsTyky+BBRwoJYZoBh04vrqSAzOo1uHCCusU1C0oB1UBnaNL633nz26VcqYXMlYsp5s20hqQrcLFF9lmKSSWxeksB78cMN2BFxf25O3F7hkD6bkGSBPIDm/5TwgOX1rq1wsARYljunIVhhnIYd/UPBG1A=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "po,st,-ur,ban Ha,ra,pp,an", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080135", 
		"question": "25y2KIHh1BHj5JEvQBfxhen2OG7DTyIFq3rDUax6ZnTxU6LMbei+xpExNVWfiElosnfS46/l+VAbhqdV+s6cfCcCbI5riNaGxeHk0GIBMshA2pBg64wWePFEjDusYtvJIfxiyy6DKEv0bi20C35n1DfZmDxpl7yEyhiEa+UIjFUzhcdr6M0yfN6Rmbyb7Q27hxWHnHSXCI1lBVWVvN69/1Gd7MIsvcjNsDzY/fH3jrjQ8c4Cdgle/4pwYFqokqxJ9yR4RcCxKBhe/+fEaFvjYCelZxoV/IvE13puw5FpXGcwtCxJjMNEa9Z2xIumMsLCNLEuDHMemWheqAikWw==", 
		"answer": "272tZZD9kRHr9Yw0Uwr7yvO90auVmxyZo2cTePmjKohGKA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh2A/v5cUqRxDx0fTwO3iQBmQXpnyXW7VxfGijV6vHb//7zdd3KE6Mnk9osnfIp+Xj4kMfgLpP7IrfeDcOf4UvwNGL3vD20HhOPYZ0m5Rz6JMPaeBSzXHtddqbJeZvw36MIgXzbi24ADB9mnHCgnkWuIKo5ia8UZZ31xQh1pRx+d09KNKbmamHqFmwg0aIyXWSXLRrHxSWs46840bch4M2ssie8TPV8LTKlfaT4tcdZxpB/7J3Zhusha0a/SQ7VIi7blJG5OjEaEThJWixLhgY69ij1WZsx5YsWSk18AlHjJdXZcV8w4ukvz0+O8R+HDy0sARGyIY8TBKCYLG93W3q9Bl/dHMvbIRq/CQ74RuULRR5iGSLWCQRm4Yr6tgc1QdqaXYAnXjkwjafkyWKcZbx7IXyhu2woaoj8+M0IEaOPFrRVYwScfPTM2Zmz6mYDLZVJ55rVSpu+TeWTXIfzaUC0yy9pE4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "hu,ma,n h,ab,it,at,io,n", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080136", 
		"question": "252xe4X8wxDp9olgdwj3y+m/fWfZEHZA6j/DEuM0MDGjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc62fTICfZ8vx97J5OHj0H1EPsNKjsBC5Y4LeeZO333leN3INL48h1KOBgXFdDz9C3Y0nSPZhDxCp4y35me9W8h3wwA+go5u7Nw1M9nflOjTqA34xkbCnDvRCP0kWRTI/I6O6lWTsoM6ucjNsj3V8P3tk/fd454NbRoSuodtb0L8n70E+SR4Wcm2YQZK5e3fb2jjAmiQLwcb7Yvs0DR7z5QsTyk3+wpUkYZFIsFh2Y3quHJhaJ06VRGZ4wQAh9Q8F0XWPf2c1Wvo6Vs6NXUtJZpirzl4tB2eKVo+smqOTTxBlY4r7dUNgQhmcGpOiGXcjBzLo2qBapbx7IXyhu2wr78j4KoxLFOTdV3MFocJa7DULmh82anWTeYcc98nV2KmfZ19vHC5BY6E3jce2dYub3jhtCuegMT2LGmupoD4gpRlEasUOtTI7MWjo2DJRWPFJGuWasTkVA3+Wzz31U5VtgwkxCgA/XbKCcQ/tW1N3j7wCQQk0megLDzh1v4cqsLON9pxmrXJ0DcCn/F2nJ632xt8RkSohHhNu4KWTF1B2RTFCswTwUktDaQIAJfdzmPWlGWQSjwAfsT5E+iEyjhRmAECUWtIJO3DdxFtsmW4sXk=", 
		"answer": "25T1O92z81S4u8UDH0++hdmyYSnDA1r0M6NPFYIwXtY9v8MQ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH72Ar++JcpUR/+hfjpMGXEQ15TgHCNRKZmd3TtV6KCYeu+255nIk6azVpvsnzTrabk/lwBnJQZqYKadGIXcct7wNXJ0vznxX9SOslK2o90pJsYbv1D2TG5YcbaLL59y3qUK0D9YjepFzBGnSfTmDxcvY244S60Wsl30Ac9gI586Mx8OtKNzaGf7Q20hwiGnHqfTP1zEECcp4667lCTtZA7sN7B8THJ8fXtk/bUsNgKdAdAvoRzZhu/mKYN8T4xXsanKBRE46TRZkbkIz2vMxsP/Ivi2HApzpckXGd0/B5Ei5dXdsl82NjQtDsjf8R5VSCvs1RP1YB5W1eUbf29yGnp8Fk6ZjonbIFo/B00tQ6QIURrjnmdAGxGnIV5+5ANnQEjfmBOinPyhTqFg2DPc5Wj+YnqgPrj4Lps/Lc1IEOVIVncFpkTJbrUNCd12OaMGa4cMownFmL1NNIg9T/wI5eay3kexNg0Kjfk9TqQhsz5e8nTWmTFwm+fIDJCNGyC9rU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3", 
		"option_b": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", 
		"option_c": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", 
		"option_d": "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080137", 
		"question": "25C2fpjh3hfn8os0UxKy4/z8IWTCQyodqmyXEvI9MDyjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc+9JioFx8NoQcrRzySm5eNHWJfB6jkKPJETkbjazFzA8mDjFnjwE4b+11GeLRt8kxRsxk8d364g9PsKR3amd/A2vhxKHzjuDTa5rBEaasN3opgPc4MJ49Y3N8XKbtLS52riTsJ5LIkgS/8Y/Ixvt1+FJ3SQ7Xt2maRVO9aTDZED5LC2uIgAJucXm12YpyoMiWHp09RFCwpFfdMVhxaTqnnIRKcxjGTK4qkhJ0408UBHWcriqxGHo5RUsenMnJcog/G114U/caBQ+2ivcDGwR1MArvpBZ1UQjPS8A3Dagwn/LwCXPPNOjq8C8xaiw4Pkxu+MOJ0eMIFnWVYgYJbbTM2ZwxuCIBatZPYsnGCSmKMcs/Te5I5Oayzwfw+UuDDfX5iWBm8D8LXz6p525gNViAa0BOpHX7Ni4pU7EZDChYT3eJou0GUiwDzy4k04l91hliGFQqCKYSMk/tW1N3j7wCQQk0megLDzy3/5/5YyabYczxuHp2XIEl7R/jZTgwBV8SAL7jnBCoZCeQxxbwkPYDfEJ4EkdGKYAAJPW+27WmXnTSmgEcMC2B6eVgzha2+f0zmBzu9ANWoGDORfSid8ywRi/Qe92QHPou8a0fahcSkIt+bt9w/mgo8+/NeChOHEmaheyV/tKs5tUaRA7HATICzBOaba9FCO7PwbrBkOBu/ViAO9OMyg=", 
		"answer": "25T1Od2z81S4u8UDH02+hdmyYSlSamX2STV3ViBon6vXe/GJ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w73+N37eB2Mftz+UU7dxYjHxUbTNe//9zIQ9Z0+cjlM782WGr6T78kBPjqZfqZyWZicRbccvx9ad0uq3wX9CPNNWm4d34NoMeeBUwDigcdrPYPdgjm+SIkTjJy61AWJx1CbXnnlE6JS65mepUdszyRkr1oZu7MEwPdWT3OiV51/4kAeQ1XSEW/1qFFGdpo6J/UKVrIM6vMGEpSub+/K5nP3B5NcHZ0hBsI9zI129lKEF8T45Rc2wKBNM4+3TdFj5NTqiK04c+t/qwH19z4c6HWg68F9HlpdEY8Nn05ykrzckK8FvGDa0t1cA94ZzRx6bfamhkHzroFs+YW85ZIYtrigmrhqOK1Ft2meVRykRko95+8MNhkgjcGZOmWThjizHwGSBeNPs/4j5l6jioa4j/6IzLFOJNFDLFoQSY7/VImlxz+3bGa5Zc5h1GDXyNZUh+nntL4GazHkM3t1gLH7z/S+K0v7hK2SutpXwjZR6G7wBItjK59j3sVDIbyShNW+SYs60WAb0D3/33gNwuREmyTUZ52yYGoZq4Sge3nixSk1omzPheHml1qpU78KLZ4050vvr2HIfnrR/kJTzx109SQD7hHtGs5fTD1FOxl3YGY0TzAwjTL0FEZfdsmuZhzbDTmgZc8v7BKaT0G6JjUiyeHLho5f+0RepyqFW", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3", 
		"option_b": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", 
		"option_c": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", 
		"option_d": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080138", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJnl5v5nrDrqD+40BPga1a+86IcTYGbMt9zcOMxfL4zWNSc89X2oN99ogaf+Aa8DOReoWbE/t62mKFKkD+cyr9CnV1hnHai3dTu8O6+yP7QNs5ywZygYJq6Ig/M9qS1qbT4UP4hwiB1X6fXP1NH1CQtI6p5Ufco402ocSDpDeb4Pu5jvDa454PYxFusbpxMRufn6Eb+SQ8Ftv0YR9b/vbEYFruJWiqKU4N687r32d9yZAgXikg/RJDkcNBY9Mz0o3h/CY/f8R+BnO2rEdB051zUVeXYP2s2G2k6kAxdm4iaoQtsyt1tQeZaHN/lGyZX2xQmoQr6tgc1SNrfGhInWThwi2ClmCdb6/t146vxcb1r7Vq5qsuKgGUOlPURc0aaqbOIyd7xKm4Ba9OMpFjVzHzOtIr7y25NJ6Vy3kZ2NxgIXLm5iiA0sv6K2Cpp4G5mdFkEf8QJNjI6Nm+vEWHdDDkJT2Vadm0WA/iRn/t3xpwpR1nzVT/8lGTfsH5vNbMcfSStg==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1Brl+YFgQQrz0fjyMGXEQ2sC43aNUaxmYnTgQOfhZuTsyJl1YE/JhFZr/WTSoqvz8hMYjrsb7ZuaMDYMPoJ725CF2Of20HhOPYZLlMBm7J9fduFOzymke9qbL/gu2maFZ2LxaT64FzB1mjWWnnRT6KSz9CCzVcg2gAc7gIJq/oR8PcTf1K2d/ES3iAOGnHKfCKlsFBSNsNa8qXeZjvCRc7OCeyj+WTTF9Os=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "2 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080139", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJn1Jt92SGqbD+9EcGgKZIqY+RdGIXdo5m2pCb2OjyhHhPc9VBjpR+4ZcacuAAwDKudcDSL/B9x33AJEridTy+ECpImg3Y205fvoaptS2uWtkjyRo8hcd+7Ms1MN6L2LyW7A2wkwuD0juZSb9tBVWNvMGmq0GF4IE0sMyfuDzctPL2iP3A5M1LYwZW/5ZtbE21k6EH/2ovUNyxelJZ9PffdEbuJTufKTITq4vT12Boyos5SH0m9VhVwpBfZc560JHnvTwzOo1rBnO740dJ0408SBaFNLmt1Sjw7xU2YWlraYVuvTk8rgHcKUA+jmOZDC9emoZn69UXlgEjcmkAiH7lwhiKjmKKb9Pi5YS8tuf+4Ktq5KY1On2OCVKLFrkUYPPzKGky2OCNCLQcIJduETbjOZU5+SrtN5eG23kCxtwyb2Pu+S/V0s70LHazvZW5vtViFbMJJsTR+8r3pFOHbSzyJD2acti0UAXgQG7s0gBmslpGMmszVed1gGp1HRzI/XEa", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn2RD488UzRh/mwPD6O3+QCnFRqnGAXbFmdXL3FJPKa63NxpkxNVWfiEk79n/C47b4/lUbz79e+pqIcTAHMstt3cTJ3vC3wHhFc8hLjsBx5Y8MebRwzSmseN3LNep8zy6UKAX8aCq4RHlgh3Hfh2xZupe6+yS+FOo21BQ+n5dt+do9e8TfyqGU5kS+jwWD0niUCKplAhSdoMvo/0zcqZYr9cGCsjPP/fv32vnHsMoDZ0hYqoh8d1KzmegG/mo1RMSgYQJH9KTCaELoMjvh/vV2O30qlEMnc/sDsR9dSA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "2 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080140", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfh/gwvi/NGzCCmEEr2uWQKJ4MGLmQLPOa+D7x4NiZ1WHzU9z9zbhoqv38kcGjOhL5Y+WfjFDbI5+3dmb0uC3wHRHPNRBiZRz8JMQcrRBwjntYNzeYOt9yy6PIQX5dTazRGR7mz3FtnJqprG+9DS0WoB39B031o95/8x8PduTzL6a6UH4lQmL0DueTv1wGVHZpcKp4k2P4Iw9tsieojvP9eD8nrja4tEFIhxdsIpsI1e1nK1J7CI9EcGmZxwL8PzVIVXjJGizKwEI/sPw3nV7w8IvUnt08RlAh4BCa9Z2lpvxsCY5Kcx+HDy07wRXz51/V1eBca+9kGny4VwzdHgnYMpsriIgrwvcfQQu2km/Dj92w8H2ys4uxIbJP8hGYfg=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw5EcOm61IqZqXdWIRe5p6wcKM2uH50DFHPNQEnoV064gab+BB2DSiepTaLvou2maFZ1DjYnmyAjB9hj7YymhZp4+otSG0Rpo7wQc1k8d56to1P8KTzb2B6UH4lQOWyHeURbhqBUfV9c+m7wOIqId4p8iMoj3VtPf2iOrW88oHe0hXp5ZzYlKyhOgd8C94Q8e4bVJE96TZc1vjYDysKAIOucfq3XEp0oosHWAm+xEGg5tTIsF90tj0sD0lOMV5HTKopgRJydR/ShuCfau5xGHq5xUrfX9rbYt/uG00rQOJPl1/liuPQyVd1I9tvsQRkEREfGFHmWLpgX+bjGSGcoChH8R1q5x3J14yD15tMQWWfQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080141", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfHwNmrECm0f436NVuNneWvmFKjELv773YN9IlGMg09osn/I46T+9FoKgbwb/YeSdTFDaY59zZCA2eL70XRPMMNA2oJrpJ8Rav1SwzOgcdrPIfIuyG+DM0ridAWzOH5GkTDFhXIM6Ka14y6pW9Q6xRsml4s468k/KNiNyuTT4UO7ihOG1XWWCK5rGFjZode47g/co44xuMyZtH6b9fr92vnQ89sYcUhGsMZtZkizgroK/Tl0EcyxfBdZ/O3eZFCtNCCmZx0I8N/i1H1lz5YwHWYytAxPloZFIsZ8xNjsqT8xMY1iFDGzt0VUzptyHQeq5ZXi7T2IWueHgq//afI=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw9Fwdna1Y/YKGMDEXf59q25Cd3+XjhHRPJc9WlY5/4ZQLffgAyjyuYNvJM75nwGiMMkD+ZDy5RGNxgCXaj3FTppf7+Si4Vc4+zxsh1oZ26YgvNc2ayuTT6UO8xhKK2TuDTbx3HlrZtM2r/lGdtIc0rI2IqSLX9f33ibjb/8lLdgBXrIM/ZVq/g6cb62o8VNyxeh9C/+HUIUDlJWiwMgcJ+Mnq2n1938ImWykn/QtDkcNQbdIz3o3pvTxwN8xoHCe7t01Pydbmjl5Uu9wDReA1tmMlBTI8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080142", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYBfkwO/sdXjVEXQUpz+CQeNgYnDtR7fNfPm+25hkM1mazVJ1snfIoKz1+UdPm6FW7J3TMDEKc4JjycLJw+u3yX5FNtRK2pJ95Z4MPPVOyH2/dd3XN/933VKOG0vCYjiuC34u1AXejzxQpIy08S61U5o4xlUgn5F9/9t8NNKTya2XqES2xhGDz3OYRrokEEOYrI6u5FGZs5Y9sY2PsDzQ57i5m/Tf/8kCbA8SsYNoI1e9maxJ7CV4U823Zx9OseXGYF3hISqvIk4b9tmj0HV7y4snWitRefgy1adMmVz0FzYofVyt", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhV5prfZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IA2DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQemX0zlHj62pw6Lkn6fw7hx", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gRhb3hfzsJm7CF2serT+CXKc0YnTiR6jMLuzszNdlNUmMwRtv+nOGsaDx5FwBz6FIqYCQZGIXdo4vy9+Ex+jy0HQBNt5UloF85Y4Wc/oA+DWoNNXIM/t82mePKQXzaCuvAXNgmCiWmWhXvIaotTOzVc530hwkk5Vrrd85LtLfzLuW7A25lUaWznqfW61rA0DZp8G9/0aP7MI6oNnNpTretOb8m+vc/p4EbARL/4BwYE6vkrtJ9yR4RcCxKBtG4eXTdRTiJmixLhgY64vl2ntmwosnWik7+l9Kg41SIsFl15HovTA5M8R+DHO8rFYAwZVuUh6Yc/H43mfwoFoxNW4jYIN//D86rQrcKUc+jnmdQj9Bm5J/vsIWgBBmbi0Wq+V6NLgw7LDvc85lhhnn", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080143", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYBfkwO+/P37eAHYYrHGQErRxYnSjVaPUb+PqyJB0KEmazVd08XfSqqr+5BMJgLob7I+NfDtDbY573NyM2uH50GJ9PfpKqIVz95URJrRyxSuoZpTRNfBt2mePKVawZDW4BWJxkHHQhW5Tu5eotSa1UJoxwRY7mo5s7Nw5OJeXzKWS5g2whwSLyHqFQbJqUVCMsI685AOIqIcxp42OvjzN8frwn/bHsNIEYQlGtolxIWjWF2s1ByG2PLQVbCbAy7M=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iaN5IhyInkh+4GLPrKuw9Fwdna1Y/YKGMDEXf59q25Cd3+XjhGNIJcNW2opn6pkLdftO3326ccbeYP9q2G+OM0T3YjaoFzBymyOWj31EpJr75iKvQNYyzRA8gpQ0rckyOJeL0a3T+ki5lQmMnHqSS6h2EECcudfo7luMrIMxu97NpTra4LTtkv3A9Z4BdwZRq49wbUj8lKQM+Tg9VYiyZwBO4vDDIVXjJGizNQEL8M/m0jRohpE8VH019hNDwo9ZYcFn35fq/DQ/LY1iAD67rQRIxpZ1SxaCfbK2ku9T+jubhz50ChPAnS1YPCU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080144", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYRvm0fH6OG7eF3FRqnHDU613eXTtQOfWZ+D72tdmIk6MzVV+5HPU46Dj41INg6FI4YubMCwGf5kv39Gd0va31nRSNtRSlYlg96YRQPpyyTy+e9qBYMpmyy6QNUTzczC+ATB7knHFj2hCpIq18me1UdslgAIzgoJqrdo5L9KNz6ea+l74hAOF3XXRR7NoCBSQu46840bcrY08sN+D8TfJ9basktxsu9d3iIfb3gAaADlC", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIlq3rDQqZ7YH3mFLTHevnyzJMxKVmInxt3833DsOXx+VdPm6lV4p3feSxDf4VswdWHw6TjzXxEIIoEjYh755Jff/tO2C+scN3YNO0u2maFZ0TjdDyvEHl7mnHignkWuoa65ii1FNMkgBs9gsd57sspLtaL3OiS+w2sjgPCzGmQS6ltElHZusjo+EaItI4xu8rNvzfa5rTum+zW4p4ZZxtXrZBwakmv16wA/Go2Xtz0ahdM+OqQblrhOWiqKU4J8c6j23ttw5AnHWwm9V2eGkz6WCdI5nXFU8Wd6iHZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080145", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1xjp44oyEhfhhfzrIXnZAXcFpnvDRqw0ZHnmFLfQa/77x5R0Z1OPzU9z9zbuorfx50MOgehY/IKLZTAGPoJhiNGHl+XlzXUNc9VBl4k/4J8MeeZUjCeietGEYpym9a/GRdYRyLhdKyLYbpQ=", 
		"answer": "25u3ZZD32Bqq+4wmVw3m3PH6dwyPhyp2/0MJnyMqpjMIekg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVRHFRpmeKQbdxfnLmFK7MLuzwiZZjLljJl1R19zbPsOXx40cdhqpO/YubMDYMPoprzcGc1vDyhGNAOshCm4x+pJMRPOBIyX25fN3JJL5jx2KMIkv+biywRFJX2HHYhWgWvIu+tSapXd53wxk7m4Zs6Ig1KMSa1a7RBVqn2k3ihRq28wOOOaN9gA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Limited water sources", 
		"option_b": "Nomadic lifestyle", 
		"option_c": "Abundance of forests", 
		"option_d": "Extreme aridness", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080146", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2BT69oY0Ehr7wb3rPW6QDGwCpmvDXaU0cX+jUb/WfOjzzJtoZ12bhF874n7HsKCw9kEAmqZfqd/PIHJDXKgvwNGf0qT4yjFVO8MEiYVm8JYacfFO2H2kepTyLv9jyW+PKRqygu23F0LmJAe3CQp9pPf53A==", 
		"answer": "25CgeJD9whDl+cUvVF7m1/z7MCveBnYGrG2IQeHQ6AX2s1LsDyCtzm39IHDE", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2yQ348oglXgeyxO/2MSvAC2MCpj+CQKxhfnWjBfeSPq3c6td3KE6KiF879HfUrqDi5BMbgOha64+RdC0NPp9nzdmbl+z4yXRSc8dKnsBz4JUPaLRQzS65e8baLL5gwWOBI0zjanm5EXU0gD6Wgn1Eu4v79ii1UNMjyRo8hcdI/8cvLNKN1r2AqEqqiRGW1DueTv1lFkaQttuk/1aOpcDETHcPRQfbP0p7WfPZvAnM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Expansion of trade networks", 
		"option_b": "Introduction of new technologies", 
		"option_c": "Rise of urban centers", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080147", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q0IQ1Rh//xL3dIG/UC2NRsGqQQqZ6dDHrXbSCeuj/yp94KVvJgFJo4X/JreX04kEGga8b/YaaMDACd4V2iMOM1vf4yi4D79HQZ/hZcrMEd1H1LPBlzg==", 
		"answer": "24e5YZ/qkQrv9pYvXF70wO7rPH3RD3FTzHmaloLnmTXD8Dhpe18wsg==", 
		"explanation": "25K5fYXy3Biq1ZAkVhbzhe7qJnvVDWYUpz+LW7A0ZHTiV6/LYOq+xJ5iNFWGgxt/53OGt6qw/1YOmbEb+4+WfjFDep59wd6Ol/D/wTFVIclUk4Nz6NoSc/pTwzKjOJTMKPdtxi6NJkH1Jyu4A2V4lSOWnXNEo8O//CG9XdkizAFyppV97Ms0NdmYmaGdqEu3lAOL23XRRLxqFkGYssu7qWMvKW1pfSR5ZlvNSdsGqRI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Personal health concerns", 
		"option_b": "Lack of interest from followers", 
		"option_c": "Rainy season festivals", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080148", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRfr45AyUxKyzfzlNHnUECIQsXrDUax6Y3jnUbXHaq3zxoV0Z1+ImVpo5mTJs6359BMbh6lVqYaacTQaPpluwd6P1uj7mzO34Izs9JKU0Z7cDA7kgtO1", 
		"answer": "25O0Z573wlWq/5AyQBfxxPP6JieQAmwV43qCQLd8YWTiX6LRLE1wX3UyCdb8cYC3t8rKaHE=", 
		"explanation": "25O0Z573wlWq/5AyQBfxxPP6JieQAmwV43qCQLd8YWTiX6LRLuzszNd8IlKdhFR193KGoraw+VIbmrpa5c6XcTgCbI98iMSB1vC3xWNEc8BFiMB/64gaPPdB2Dy+YMbUMPZnzS6UL0T+JzG4BWZt1CPXg3JQqY+3tQqyWN531xw8kpQ47MY4fNic2qmA4UK2hwrCz3OeX7h2Ahbzr2EzOMny5mdt7kwvtyyI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Soil erosion and land degradation", 
		"option_b": "Slight temperature fluctuations", 
		"option_c": "Dew formation on vegetation", 
		"option_d": "Floods, hurricanes, and earthquakes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080149", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2BT69oY0Ehr7wb3+dW3RDmsfpj+LU7VxMH7tFLPKa63zwJBjJkiAglU7/XCGsKr98hMljqFV6J3feSxDbplqhf2IwvbuxX8BJ89Jn5MtpqIBDWfjsD8/PCRYNWKUoy4=", 
		"answer": "25CgeJD9whDl+cUvVF7n1//+OyvTBmwFpm2QEJD0YMis8II7ent2YuiiAnc=", 
		"explanation": "25T4bpD+2Bfvt4wuEg7gwLDSNH7CGmMf42uKX6ZnMH3mUOfWYa3qwZIxKlWOn1pv+3nI46r2t0AAgq0bw4+WfiMQPo19x93J+uXwxXVJc9JL2pN98Y4XPN1OyDSsOJTIJftlx2CHZ0f1cy24FjB3mz/Sg2hfp42otSOuRtM5x1UmnoI4/ss9LtSWzbHT212qgweGnHSXCKlhElyXusKn7EqfoY54vMODviTa4P32lOuRk4EnYBZzyvrNEM1zVQXn0Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Emergence of new religions", 
		"option_b": "Expansion of urban centers", 
		"option_c": "Population growth", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080150", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVRHFRonuCQrd1ZHjsWufWYa3/x9dwNVWNwRto93vP7qH15FYdm+hB5oCaMCsQPop73MKA1fHjwXUBJ8kEjoh3pIoNeedFwj6oNNvdYMFR8VG/GHrPWAb9FnF9mjfXhnAWrJap/Cm8FM4/xVUmno5q6YgxNduT3Kad4Vi1xiShnjCHuTiQaf645aNy26JIUVQ=", 
		"answer": "27S8bYDm0A3vtc2rqSvLeoJupDsqlB0RGyA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVRHFRpmeKQbdxfnLmFK7MLuzwiZZjLljJl1R19zbPsOXx40cdhqpO/YubMDYMPoprzcGc1vDyhGNAOshCm4x+pJ4Kbv1Oy325fNGbNPZn3GrAKkz8azyzCnlhmXH0qTAWuoKv/SKpFM4/wRtygo99rckuNdPf2qSa5Uysg0aLyGiURLskMFCcpNup/0bcsoMxu8uMvT6b5+HpivfB5NsPIhxausZ4cVSrg6BJ9yx4Qs2gfB5O/OHedUetISanZw8a68Lgw3h905AsHW0h5hZIhcNCasFnlojhrjs/O4+7Du8RRqg6+Yf9ELpf7GYL", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ad,eq,ua,te", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080151", 
		"question": "24GwbdH83wrv48UvVF7zy736LX/CBm8Ur2bDU7F9dDHzXKbRa63/25hkKVjJ3AsrojbkgOXz+F4fiqRX7IrfdiMRc45925CA2aTeynBMNMdLlMwyyZsXfeZB3zW5ZtWXYOphjm+CJkv0aDf9EHhxnSOWgnNbrZD79Cm/FNszzwUm1rhH0vcDA+ig5pfT5kK1hwKLz3bTYGIADm1rIahwRSTf7fM+wg==", 
		"answer": "26W5e4X8wxjmtXcwlsi04ooGRhXm/cNTIO4=", 
		"explanation": "25S2KJTrxQvv+oAsS17z1/T7dXvYAnEU436RXbZ6dDGyBPeSLs/diYN5JkjJi1Rp8XPC46Px5V4Knbsb/YHfdCcQe5l7iMSB0u3lhHlOPsNX2ol8pLMRfflHzTKjNNXVJL5vymGQMwXgZiqpC2J1mHHYhXFXrIqo+Gv7XdQzyRYzgo526og9fMSX0K6HqEuqiQvCz36FXLFhFRSYstyh6FaQtJcqtMHNvTvd8eftg/TW454fbUhT/4twcV78mqcL8SY9Ed+1cVJE96TcaFLoYCy2Ik4J9ov33nEpzoM7TmF09xBIhopCa899xdqo6SZJPTgFzApVZSNHTfeN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "pa,st,or,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080152", 
		"question": "25T4bpD+2Bfvt4wuEg7gwLDSNH7CGmMf42uKX6ZnMGPmR7LOeuj6iZ5/Z0iBiBt2+3HUorH5+F1PgK4b+oGSdWIpf4JhycPJ0fb4yTFsMsFFnogy8JVfb/tV2DXtXdrfKf8uz33AM031fnmuC2VznCWWiHlCvIaptSS0Wt4+1Bw9mJQ46d0uNdmYmbyb7Q2ogxSL03/RR7skLmumivGX1Hyjn8AysXH3GGPYMHdnJ5JvXOSP", 
		"answer": "26a7aYPw2A3ztQVkrWIwb4sCcECI4HXjeJg=", 
		"explanation": "25O5ZZj91Fnm8oQkWxD1henwdX/YBiIcqniRU7d9f3+jW6GCROz3x5ZiZ1qbglY733fBoqH4t0cAz7tU/JqXMAsNeoJuiNmHl/fyxWNCO4ZLnMBw4Y4LeeYAzzKjcN3PKfFg3S6EMlf5aT79EHhx1CHTmHVZrMO082eoV9slwxwmj8d77N0vOdPf27HT/EW9xgCD0XKfTf1QGV2K9cem70qfoZY9po2ZuTPPtPX9jP3B49tLYQdcu49ralSyhOgZ6iU1QdyxbFJf+e3DIVnkJzqiMwcS94nhio9KcPvJ3+JKvkLIApYg", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "sc,ar,ci,ty", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080153", 
		"question": "25C2fpjh3hfn8os0UxKy4/z8IWTCQyodqmyXEvI9MDGjFOeCR+P4xYJ0KV+MzVR1sl7TrqT+t3IMm6FN4JqWdTFDNodm28TJha3LyiABEsRRlIRz6o5fa/VUyS/tZtHIL+t8zWuTZwWwJ3n9RFE91BfXiXVaoZe64SKoFM4lwRE31oZ26YgoLtaRyric+lm5kg+N0kefGv1CFEaNvMKtq1CTqY549Y3A8XKbtLS52riTsJ5LIkgS/8Y/Ixv81+hJuGp4c4GRZhFE5PbRZlH+YCasKg8Z8Mij2n1vw5E9RGUx5yNI0cN4Y9RmxJno/DoxJcx4ESD64wQAitQ8H1fWNP34kCikoBV/NTprJakt9W0GtB+MJ0ZqiSuPSThFmIVvvtEehw1gaGNUiWThjn+bkmSMaJrg7pPAi7ywk61x87ciLkiDdVDXVYwIbLzOZ2F92KmPH6dYNt8nV2KmffFnvBD3JpqB2jcO1cpgPHLz4Cacn8j7LSWqsobti8Z4B4MOdtDL7Yu0v1HKdC3oInyHb8T6GRr/Wmj9wE4l+lqXd14WwVZTJF7F04phI8Q/", 
		"answer": "2+T1St2zg1TOu8VzHz2+hamyFCkXJHoL10dwLKs7ih92whaU", 
		"explanation": "25S6fZ/30Bf+t5IhRhvghe/6JmTFEWEUsD/DUaJ6MHjtUqvXa+P9zNdiIkidgV5293jS47Xx40cKnaZIqYyGMDIRcZ1mzNmH0KTy12JEPdJNm4wy9p8Mc+FSzzi+NNLUMr59232UIkvxaTq4RHF6kHHFn2xGp5Gv/Cm8FNs01Bwkn5Nx6Nt8MN6U3OiS71+xhROOyG6DTf1lH1DZodyp70agrqQ9p9mEvTeb5/vwlriT9dAIbR1AvoF6cBuvkrwd9C88EcmzehtI5OjEdEbsLGizNQ8e7cLg02cpx5FpVH10/QwGkZZfdsFx2p2kuj0if8p4GiSzrUMAxIZzTwTWdbO8kG339FQ9eXM4bYNju20lpB2RKVp7lH/cXylFgIxu89UXgRdfc0FBiGPygzPLiGSVfYHn+MC8jenmpfl3+qZnOU6UMFLMX4wQJafPZ2N72fuOHbIcO4pqFiymPNY69S/wNJ+RzHkM3t1gPHLz4Cacn8j7LSWqsobti8Z4B/NANdDQ+sK5txzKaCTzIGmaacXnGQn+Szzx3Qhpoh0ryyge7yLcDYp25iQCkDO9SE9tnCDcYk+1hL9I74WHfM493PbtyTsflrR+kIm3wA89QwH7jHFH8oeQQlFaw13VH9kOywduHrsUAJPCsi2QlHXZR3UZftrzEuiT0S1M36+xh29puoIPVpiHIxeXyt8ozFelCfg5UH/uoIf3OvlVBWJs/b1+zv7htsS/NfqgKWQ5I1q+VP9Y8IFYZgU7Ag7JEShKbb2gQt0aRPZK3nramgJGUz9IC16M+L0ESRG4q8iIa3Lda7ASCRug15YWwMrc43/KYFhqHsR9sQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1-A, 2-D, 3-B, 4-C", 
		"option_b": "1-B, 2-D, 3-C, 4-A", 
		"option_c": "1-D, 2-C, 3-B, 4-A", 
		"option_d": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C, 4-D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080154", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVR42yXU7dxfXTtQLSCfOj5yIV1LlKOzU9z9zbPrrXx9EdPgK4b+4+WfiQCcocvx97J/+XlxWFRMsgEiYVm8JYacfFO2C7tfcebI/F83GuDMx/MaQWzVUR8kXH+i25XuJO6+2e4QdYj1Qc30ZQ4/do5L9KR2q3T4UP4hwjC3WmYTP1+Hlqc9ce7q0KItJAxt9iZtDab4Pu5nffc9J4ZYwFcuYdzbxu4groA9i14RcCxKAZD+PbUIVnkLCSmKQAU7Maj9FdVyL4nDykV8AlDkJBTIsV10J3nqCFwMMMqPTKoolRQxpo8TBKCYLG93W3q9EZ/enkocJh/uSl1tgeZJhRsm2KSSi1dmMB5+8QMhwpmeS9UkzbplizLlXaafZ+j54XqgOTMroVtoeMPLECWLBzKV4QSdvPEMnV7xO7bGa5Zc4t1GDLvPtQivDT2LoWb0DdNwNYzJmPu4i+Vi438N2O2ppf3jdFyVLcVO9DLqce2slPVISLvJT2SYdn9Wh38W2nq0gIlthsxwTcZ/GvdG7VxwiUEnXbwWlBlhiLtaXK1hf5d+IfOfIEjwfDvyW1ScGs6H+/EsV/Q6MjU5RLVgA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhP3y+n2OmXDQ3YZpj+CRrdmeXP2QK7NYK3xz9dZJk6InUt6/DbFtqnk4kEKyLsb+ZyaYycNfY4v3N/J0Ov4wDFTMs9KnIF+6NZfffpEjA65dcDeLftg2i7SZ0H5dDqoF2Nxh3HCgnkWqYet8DWoUZoyxhM3lZNrrd80Odnfy6ma5ku5igrCzn6HTa9wFFDZocHo4leP4JcroMyB8T7e4vH12svH8coObw1cq8YsI1izmbwb+S4xUtynKAZD9KTAYEf+IS+ma04c6ovqwjR60oM9WHp04BdHlsNeZ8Flz9j2vTs+LI1uACGzrUMA05x5HwOEe62x02nooFgwe2kkaoQtuCghpB2OLVA+im6TXCBU1IZ58d1ZhwFkaGNBjjb3jS2AwtS9VfmylLfep1n72aW4QBg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "all the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080155", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd/Jkicn1p3sn7HuaTi80BPjqZfqZqXdSsRPohgxsOMxvHyynJEIIZNicBx64gNefdUlgGjSNqKYNhiwWGENAmwbyyvFnl3lT/TmTAWqY2/tSK6Rs4/0QAznYJrrckuOZeR2LyG+ky0xg6DxnqDTK4kHFuLsI6r6leds5Yqut2FuDGb4Pz4lLjb9d8de0hAvo9xZVqwm5QHxCRqEen0bhNG+OrVIV3jYDixIkMw+N7xz3VnhpYgUGwntBNDhsNCbYBn3p2ksTs3Lcx+HDy040tGh4dzUhLWXryx3mn3oFMtendrSItqvSk94RuTaEdxj3+UDAVfkIlqwt4lm1cjT2pTmXfygTeOknbPdJL17sD6kOT8uflq9qYpPUiGPFncFowSYfPEKGRnx+yVGaNYc4tvEmLoPME77jj1YJ6VxTgf1MpgO3/m4Gqak9jmPGH6tZP0h9pzB/8BONWF6sq7sVHOdSrkMkGdUcP9WgCwXGj5xwtoshYx22ER+meYC4Zt5ygOiiHyOXYeTleqDDDzUIFggLlHVg==", 
		"answer": "2+f4Z5//yFuwo8gtRcpR5VdHb9SvxQyG", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEh391+/6Nn/cGiIYp3qNRqpyeXTwFKHOYeL62tsxL0mbn1J483jDsOmw9l0Lz61a+5qXYTcCdY58iNGal+r20GRTMsoEkoFo5Ygbb7RNwy+oNNfaNP992nyPN035ZHmpDHF61DnTi2pP6JG6/Cm9VdY7gCYml5N94M0yKJfNmaya+06tlRWHzzuFQLgkHF2ep8+84kyS4I0+9eeMuDza57T9j/2T5NFLY0hUvot2bV7w178B8SY9EfugaQZO/OHedRS+YCusKRoP+M/q1WB6hpYhWCkk9QxVg4RTLoByxdj2uSE1Pt9pHTaosARIxoJ5HxmZYP2+xWTo+RU2cX8lcYNrtSgx4Q6QJBRqkm7cXyNEhoNu7ZAUkAp3dGBOlXjnwiuDhSWBfYf2+YHwxeDxurhx9rBnKkCVJlXWUc0aZL7JKWJhiuiVCeZfMpNmGivyNNA9vjg6dEqQyqsyIxyqEi63ymM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 only", 
		"option_d": "all the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080156", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfB/m0O/+OSvYAngQsXuQErBhc3mjVbSCaOHxxpNiaxyBmElp+3XHraDjuxMOgawb7I+NZCoSa4pkzcPJ3+XhwTFMPNRB2oNz8JsMaOZP3DWkd5TSLe5vzXqTZ1H4Zjf9DHV1giiWmH1fpoW6+SuHWuY58hAzhYh2t4gaMNiQ3bvfqEWtlBSL33qfTa4oUVWXsY6t6lGIqJMttMaIonLY9fq5mfnG49tLdQFWupVvcV69k+gN/TksQ923fBtE/6TRb1CtJCGwNwIc+s7u03p9ho0vHXk75ApKg5dfbc5glEo0fmkhPTIHlcvEhuHt9xk=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefBYf/szJRlZ2iBiBt64WXDsbH5+F1PnLxa/YuMMDYLf58vxtGdwvb2yDFJMtxFiIRhpJYWd/EAyjGie9DIbL5m23ySLkbxaTyuSDB1mjWWj31EvIuq4CawUcl3yBQkk8d14to5fNSezamA/F+3lg6L3zuYRa1lEkCK9dqg6k3cqIc5o9TNozPS+vL4lvSfsN8FZkhGt4M/cV69hKcHuC8gQcS1YRxYsfDYYECtNCCmNAtd8cr512Zt1cIqXGd0+BpHhsNCbYBk35zhryIiOsxuVTe/sFBS0pdoVhiYNLy21Cjg6UYveXsoYIdosjl1rgncOFtuj2edWCVempMnvtMWmxBxdG1ViH/uhX+fjyWbdJbq+cD/hPzxs61x/bMvIELAO13MQ58ZJ3mEd/lKgqRwB9Tew1bNP8E=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080157", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfD2MnnRF2serT+MVONnf3zmFI3DZ+P/2td3NVOEzXZ69XfCq+Xk+BMcgL1P4c62fiYKf8tr3cKA2eO3xTFRIcMJt4Fn9oMecrRGzTCketGbKfBqx22BM0DjJy21ATB9mjfan3lYq4b7+iH7Wtsj1Qczmsdw7NI9LtOMmaedqEWtiweMnHaeXrhpFFqNpvKm102upYMrusPX8QDe5/H4iPvb9cwYIgBTqYM/ZU6wm7FJ/CU7RMWxZgZO9aTEaVGtLim3Mhwc9Yvr125o1IY6HXsx5w9JjJBfYMx2lp7rrnI2PsBjGzap40VOw9RzSx+TZv270WTl7VwrfH84JYNj/Cw7ogaZJkA+jmKRST8T/5biuEtzW+lJr3RvvnPD1A==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6eSvSFnZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufLfa34yJtiIh6GB1b7ea+qyNYC6T5cLpBo", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/NmTCEWcStz+KXONnZHD3XanFLvn2yIMxM1SMzVZy9WTHt6z/+RMAiehx6IeRcTFDeJlgxZCk1uP2wHkBJ8kEiY9n8JJfVfpExTztcMHJKfBpjm/AIUT9bje4RHl6kDjVi2hTu8Ov/SL7XdQxzAA3mIR9rcc6fNmezb2B6UH4jgeY3WmVW/1rHxSRoMOp5QORr5Q9uMiDpSGb3Pvun+7W4pJLdgBX/5R6YkizmegA62oxX8u7egBO8vCQcl3jIy3jMwYYudvixWdowYdpWWYx519IjZcWb8V9wpHrsnIkN8x+VSG/sEFB1Zd0WgWFNLW5xm2k5kAzeWNrYYVuqSAwrxuZLBRqkm7cQi1FgZJq8pARlB5ib2tT3GTlkS+EjnaGfp/mq4bzl6j2obRq/KY0aUCOMRzXQoUZd/PDJmtzx+CPBKNPc5ZpVyPoPtwr8i25NJ+Z2ipN+ddgKXbk4GbZhsXweXW7oIH4idE2GboOItjK59j3pFTGdWPzJG6WZ9n3UQ3iXDz5wQslrh0xiDUfqGbRG4pw4ygf3m2/XFZnlzSgaHWylatP+YuAeM4l2/D/2HIemeBtjZr7lBU9XQWpiWwB1dz/P/yDkuiUPby2axGrVw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080158", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEhfhhfn6JWLTF2cV436QEqI0d37nUKLRfa33x9dlL1nJv1J8skDDp6SvtduLsZTQ1FOpEhkCcoNReAs=", 
		"answer": "24a5epDgxxj+/sfGJba73BoT5oC74r04mxoB", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4glXAr7yvPsdX/YAnZRqnHDRqtxMEPqU+f0a+n/hddlL1nJvlpp82XQorH5t0EGma1JqYeMMCYGboJs3NWNl+XkhHABNMlAnoVh99hsIa3ylDiZt9zh1ELNhDCR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganga", 
		"option_b": "Yamuna", 
		"option_c": "Brahmaputra", 
		"option_d": "Indus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080159", 
		"question": "24KwcdHywxyq+oQuS17m1/j6JivRDWZRs3OCXLdnMHLsWrTLaujszJMxNF2Kn15/sn/I46T+9FoKgbwbwICbeSNcPJvSXXhQntVvWX3QKfoANEw=", 
		"answer": "25GtbdHn3ln+/4ApQF7/wPn2NmLeAm5Rs22MQqZmZHjmR+WK1XseZm6tcW2mRT6dNAFP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4A4QhLzzPPsdX/YAnZRt22GV7A0cX/nFLfOb+Pq2tsxLlKKgU5/+3jB46v18l5Dz7hS+Y+TPGIVf58jiMOB1un+iDFAPcIEjpV+95NTPPVSyX2ue9rIKfpr3GuEZ1bxZCu4ADB2kTLXn29T6Iy9tTOzUdMlgBg3ko575MY9MJePy6eD7V+sjwORnvzCfSP5ssMMvP0beJx5iNE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Due to their size and beauty", 
		"option_b": "Due to their ability to bear fruits", 
		"option_c": "Due to their resistance to pests", 
		"option_d": "Due to their fast growth rate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080160", 
		"question": "24KwZ9HgxQvv5JYlVl7mzfi/PGbADHAFonGAV+N7djHzRqjWa+7qwJl2Z1+Gmkg7+3iGoqvz/lYBm+hy54qWcX1BqImx/e9jlk9mO/khNmYs5g==", 
		"answer": "25K5fYXy3Biq1ZAkVhbzhyP5XUotbEGze+a4VGTi2Dk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4glXAr7yvPsdX/YAnZRhH6WRqJ5cTHBQaPGZuy+3pZiZ0iBiBt9+2TVt+Xk+BMcm7pe+p3fZCoGPoVqzdTJw+u31GNOJ8NHjsBx640MPPBVyX25e5TPKPtn3C6SKEn1JzCzRHdmmybfhHsWuI+6+zOoFNs5xFUihIhu5Mw1MtDf36ec7AH4kA+W3XeYXKQoUVyctMK84w/coYw89cWMoSLS+vHqibo0i455D2ttQtJIZD8tmHi6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mahavira", 
		"option_b": "Adi Shankaracharya", 
		"option_c": "Guru Nanak", 
		"option_d": "Chanakya", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080161", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q9ZchWhPzy/T8NGeQF2cJt2zDQKZ4cWXmFLPNLvn2zNdTMliNhVJo5jbSpqTz/1oBiOhU786cfzVDbplg3NWKw+34yi4D7wY53tnPI6rVFaUKGiK0+Q==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz0B3u8oFgQBv+zPr2On7DQ2Eer3CREqJ6dDHwRKjJa63xz9d1Lk6MzVh0/GXDsrD1+VAKnOhd5pzfcy0UPphjycWO3/Dy1jO1T/okKgyOfaq6SNqpqEPn", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t5Y0Uwr31r3rPWrEQ2ADoneOU619c3DvFLPHdvntiYRkN0yGn09+9jbSq6Cw1UYLi6BS+prfZCcCfYNmxtfFl/P21n9IPcEElYYy6p8YfeBJ2jjtd9vVM/t/22uOJEDjJzCzRGR8kXHYj2RC6JS05yu/FNw40lUmnohr6IgrNNjf0qGf5Ei8xgWNy2jTrcAMisBn55/l4D+kLI7rMg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They ignored the teaching", 
		"option_b": "They criticized Buddha's teachings", 
		"option_c": "They emphasized the economic benefits of cow slaughter", 
		"option_d": "They considered it a personal choice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080162", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/OG7DEGMWpj+RV6R1YnXqWqCCeuX7iZ5/M1mbjFhv+3nI46f140QKiqYb4ZuScSwQPophzJCH1vDi1nQBOsgEm45x7Z8RaLRIxS65e8bCf7zoV9kfz80RmS3IFLBNJIP9", 
		"answer": "25q2b5763x6q/os0Vwzzxun2OmWQAWcFtHqGXON8ZXziWufHaOvx24NiZ12HiRt182LTsaT8t1UAnate+sxPrFqu1F9spfF9k4fcePSs", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4AtQhbz1vTlMHiQF2oQtz+LW7Bgf2P6FLTKYfjyzddyKFKahF9+4DbSq6Cw+F0IgKFV7s6WfjYGbIps3NmG2aT1wWVWNsNK2ohn6ZsRPPFGyjK/YMebIfBqjnqIIgX2cje+EHl7mjjYjTxZrsO19DOuRts7gBM9hIR9/ooD0h3ZZ8URkVJ67gfZC/Rh", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Nature should be left untouched by humans", 
		"option_b": "Humans should dominate and control nature completely", 
		"option_c": "Natural forces are insignificant in historical analysis", 
		"option_d": "Humans should only adapt to nature without interaction", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080163", 
		"question": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Eg7gxP7rPGjVQ20X42iMQLB8eWHzXanFLuzwzddhNVmaiElt+3jB47bx9EEKi+hP+4uaY2IPd4BqiN6M0um7hGFII8dI1sBz6p5faOFM3zTtY9XIYPNh2meWJlH1Y3m/HTBgnDTfmDxpl7yEyhiEa+UI/yoNqbg4/dozLNKNzaGW+wH4ggOP03WCXK9lBV2Xso6840bcqYwssMqfsCbS+/q5lf6T9d0EbgdVtoV+bxu9gKkb/SQ9Qtv0fxtf+aTTdFj5NTqiK04f/Mfq03J6hEWmXQ2eW5xioJs6fib+k2I=", 
		"answer": "27i9bJjw2Bfr+8cfDIAH4KSWrEsrnmGNxSea", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3wr98pdgQhH7y+nsdX/fQ3YZpj+OV6d9c3jtVauCfv/x2ZJjM1WMnht09DbSsaD15BMDhqNeqYCadS9PPptm2NGFm6T2ynUBJ9NIiYky0JIab/EA2C+occebN/t8yy6DKEvjbj24FnVw1CLXiW5TrMO/4CL7QNV31B03n5U4+cA5LtaP3L2H4U74kxWHzzfRW7VrBleYpsem7AOIqId4ptSDtCDc7bT7n+zE9dsFIg1RsIpwZFK/lqRJ8yQ3RsSxbBVOseXeZRT/JSSqIAcS7NijxHF/w5AsU2oxtBZIwoJYYcl22IyklTw0Nswo8eCEegjtPNa2kcsC14EIZg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "me,di,ci,nal", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080164", 
		"question": "24GwbdH23Ani9pYpQV79y73vJ2TEBmEFqnGEEqB7Z2KjXamCb+P9wJJ/Mxygg19y8zqGoraw9lcZgKta/YubMCAaPqxu3cSI2uW35mRFN85F1sBl5Ylfe+ZP2TOpcdCbKfAu2maFZ0f1azC4AjBgnDDCyn9Zv5D79ii1QMg+wgAmk4M4+cd8KN+ama+B51qsjkaN2juBRLxqBUfZtMCsq1eUpcIop8KbuCHS+/q5lf6T9c0YZwZGtodzI2SDqJc2xxUHbveLVy10zqiQYFjkJyaqKQld7sL33jRohoomUWAn4BZFwpVfZ9cz2Z6ktCc9PsMqBiapt0FOxpp/WleXern41Wby6Ucwe3cua55ssG03oAOdJld72HEu6dyZ71ZN0TZyjcol8P8=", 
		"answer": "27O3Z5WxyGiM304Wq7RlfsXlvnQ5Ew==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHx3Rjk/MUyVxLz0fjsdX/fQ3YZpj+AQLZ3eXDvFLXNYui+yphmNByZgVpi93KGqquw50EAmaFf4ICYMCQMcY8v2tWa2PHlx3RSc+FFj5Rz6ZtfXuFEyDWsM8ebNPtvzWaJKULjJzG0A3h4nTbennlS6Jez8GeyWs4y0hY9mIl97tw5ONmayrvT50v4iAeWyWmUBP1zGVGLsI6r5FSP4JEtpd2Coybe8LTplvnd5J4McAdFq44/YlW417sc6Do0WM2wKAFe4vDVb1XjIy3vZw8R8Mzt33puhpUgSWF0/BZVwoFEbcF304qkrDciLN1vFieztUEAyJo8SBKaePC61WHq5xU+e35rYIlisCIyqAydJBR2m3mRQyJI1p1KY+fuDDociHvdEFY7H+0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fo,od", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080165", 
		"question": "25S2a5j23w2q44A4Rg2yxPn7MG+QEWcdqniKXbZnMHLsWKjQLvnxiYN5IhyrmF9/+n/Vt+Xk8lIMh6FV7s6eci0Wastsx8fJx/b40HRCJ89LlMwy85sNcv1Oy32icpTkH8FR8VG/GHrPWAaCO080nT+WnnRT6I2+7TP7Q9UlzBFykIhqrdw0M8Samb+b5w2zjwqO2X/RS7JzAhbo8P5zGAqoQ/+K6XVuCenw", 
		"answer": "27GxepSz0hbk5IAxRxv8xvjsd3j85KRo/1qJNFftX8JoJZk=", 
		"explanation": "25eqaZn+0Bfj9IQsEgr33ensdXjFE3IesWuGVuNgeHSjdrLGauX32oMxM1mIjlNy/HGGrKuw9FwYz7hJ5pqaczYKcYUvysnJxPTyxXpIPcEElYYy4JMNebRDwzO+ccXOJfBty33ALkuwczG4RH5xjCWWnXNEpIf78yipFM4/zwY31pBw4og3NduT3KzT60KvlUQt08LvS9hxQXJ12Nj1zzvY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "di,re co,ns,eq,ue,nc,es", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080166", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXYC422GVaJmdHjtU+fDYO73zJllZ3WHiVJ6/DbEpqn58lUcz6lV7c6PYiMAaoJszcPT6+rLyiABGsgEm45x7Z8RaLRpwjmkdZibMvd4y3yTZ1L1dTz9FnVikSPTjjxXu8O//DGyWt93xRsmn5Nx6NtwfMCWzaDT/EW9xiGD0nyQCL9hEluUvMCvq1eUpcI1utmFtCCb8/v9nv3A454CbEhCsJVrLm25k6EKuD4xXM2nVBwZsdLRc13iNTvjMxwY/Nij13pthpIlXGcg51MGi41VbtV335bj/Dw1OsAmVSOzs0VMi9RqXgPaNK6w0WXtrBU+e35rcZ9hryR54Q6OLRR9lWWPRShUhoVvvsMYlhZmeS9EiXOgljDLlG2KdYGj5oX4jOv5rrhvsrM1JlGFJ0jRU54ga+CAAGZn3uiWDOZ+JptjHyOmLsE8+SrqJZLUyzEIkMkyIGPi9z6QncO1NmP6sJ3unZR/Gv8BduHE5cL3s13Jbi3oInyfJt/xQRy8D3Dx3QVsuR9lyyAE/G7dSJ1wtT0Bn3CkCUN2nTD0ZDygmLoc4peDfoBxxPDg0X8Snf12mKf56BMrTw24hT9QpoWLSlFKw0DFXswVwUktA6YTEZXFsHDLPGmIQuuCpB1z7GUA49Q=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEh/8wb2tdWrCBiISrG2RV6BgMFDtV67HYPm+4Jl1Ll2HzVl+/n/Dpbaw8l8KmalP7IrfYisVe5l8iMSGl+D+0nhPNoZXjoFm8YlTPONJ2DXtYNzeYNlvwGmBZ0f1bje6RGZxmjTEi2hTrMO65mevXN93zRomnoJqrc8zONOayrvT5EysgxTC03XRfrx2GFuMpo68+UaZs8I5u8nNoT7a+uDq2u/W4ttLZg1XsoN7I0i9lLoM/Go8RM30fB0L5ezVaEatLS2nLg0U98rvlmV8x44gSWAx519ujZRTdMVhmtj3qDMkOsBvGyf68ARJ1NR1URSZZq+903yk1102eX9rQot4qCw4oE++PVB6kmrcSCVV1IVm7tgYhg15eC9Dk2Ggki2ElGCMaJrs5cy8keD1srwj+7BnJ07AOFnWQoQTa/PPISd6w+TbAa9SOJZpEGLlPME68Dy5NJnUzzUM3s1gKGXo4z6R0vn9PCWutortztB5EaxAJcXE/c73pFTGdWPiIGmHas60UQ38Xzz/wQFy9wgpyS8E+y6YCpxrtTkFl23wQEBhk2fpfzyvmaoc65aabYczxuHp2XIEl7Rfno7j1RA9ByauiXtLs8bw9JnPmIS4PkwTwi4dEcOh", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080167", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJjFV4+3PIt+XZ+VcGjqYb64uTeScFbctuxtTJx/b2x2VIMMNX2olhpJkQbuZFzyn3SNrnLq8u+maFZ3f5YHmLAXR11CHZmGhEqZqotTOzUZoEwQczhZF5+cF8Lt6J3LrT6V74h0aF03+VTa53XRSLsN667lCZrpYxu8rNpTretPDwjPHd+coSIglGq5R2YU6okqxJ7CV4Q8GibQBYse3eIVXjIyGmKRpd0MXn33VVyL4nDykA5hpDkcNXbMQzxpTlsiYjf8FjHjb6rUFFytg8Tx6GdbH0kH7l9Bl/ZnIqaIMh/Cw7pU+IPVhtkyudXikRhoV9+8IckURnaGoAiHmgljeOiXfPcZbn4oP1i+n84Klx/bMiO1WJME+YV4MYJbLSIidi2OyICLRKNpsnAyr0MsAp9HnuL4SH1zAd7NccISSn0yuMhsz4OCWYppb9htUxB/8BMsfK6sq0qRzBbjGhInKEJtvmVhz1TGjx3AAlpAwgxSwV7CLeGoZytSUEjT6mQEFz0jPobWjhlb9I/o6LP50kw+XjzyZQiPh5kY+30w8zUBCzzX5NtsScQFJb313UC9kChB0hTLwUGZffsnqTmXqdSXkEccnKD5SJ9CRB2euxnXV8q5UDUIKaP1namNtmyRSyFO94QWKy6gqTQVJr5zmZH/vNp+IuGG4=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEh/8wb2tdWrCBiISrG2RV6BgMEXrUefwZ+q+/5J1JhyAg19+93KGs7f15FYBm7sb/YaaMBECbIp83tGd3qTlzWdEIYZFicBzpJ0QePBF3y7hNNzSJ/Zix2mIM0z+YHmpDHU0hjTAj25TpoC+tSCyQt85gAE91pVx+80uL5eW1+iS5k6xgwiWnFKfTLRlHxSaoMK8/lGZ4LQ5p8SCpCGb4Ob8n+uT8dAPIhhevohrcBf8nqYK9D88WMazKAZD/vfVIVjkMzymI0Jd+NnmlndmyJEgWWwm8RsGkYJVcMV3lpzxuXIkMI1+HTazsQRNwpB1XB6YdbH4wHrr8FAtYXMudspssil1oB2ZaEdrmGGZTzhC1I9tvscWhxdrdH8AtHn3hymOkinPb4fi/4XxgObk4Ooj+7BnJ06UdVnWQoQOYL/ZZ2ZxyfyJDLJZc6hvHi7jffIv6S34LZfU/SwJ1NEhb3Lq5CKYgcTvPGH6sJ3uzsRkG6sFNcXM5sX78EjPZGPxIG6AZ8zxGQz/Sm+43QFx9xkx3DMZ6nfMDcl3/D5NiHe1XgRwnWf0ZHnhn7pZ68Kad48lk/btySYcnbRriovn2w8oBxS3jHFX8oONQEtbxRTiFshHxwYgArECAJ/e/C2UkGLHTnkDP835FrvHwiJMmvP9j29p/5ccWpuaJFnSmZ4rzRmlCPJ3UGOh6ITsKbwbBXBs/rtjz+61u9P7efqqJ2AuLw64GchY5oFQZQM7Mx7ZASxOJ6vuVJgSSOVJwTf13zoJS+w2X2rUUM8pquHF", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080168", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he/6I27CBmwSpj+FXbE0Ynj1UbXRLuztiZN4MVWHiBt+/GLPt6z15BMGgeha542WdSwXPqJhzNmIl+3khHRXOsJBlJQy4ogQcbRUxDikZpTfJe5nzXqJKEuwbjf9FnV4nTbfhWlF6Je+7TOoFNY+yxBygo99rfo1O5ep3KyS1EOEiDSH3WieRuckJVyc9fyh7AOqpYY59d2CoybJ9e3q2uzb9Z44YxpTrJB+d1L8haEf/Th4UNv0aVJM/uDUZEf+bGiwPgMf9sfqzH1nwcI9VWx05A1JhIxDbMQzxYjtrjskKsxmVSCzpEpJwZ1/XhmVcf25xHz26VcqYX8vJZ5i/D88twqOOxZm5lTEqd9vQ1nbEraugaKs", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I42yXU7dxYzH3XKbWLv/335JjNByeiEl+smTDpKTi81YLz6lIqYqWZisNe8tmxpCI2ef+wX9Vc+9KnolzqNoIdeBIjCmlcZToIexv3XiBM0ywdTCrAWI0ljTfhHsWrIar/CSvUd53wQZyl8d/4sw4OcSMmaGdqFmwg0aw1XzRfrhgEBStvcvo+Uads4029d2fviTS8PHq2vndsN8IYR1AvpJ6I16kh6QI9issWMe6JFJK4qTEaV3+YDisNRoP+NLi2jRgyMI7WGU98xZJl5AWdsVrwoukuDc9MMN5ASG7t0FTh4B0WleScbiokHv06Uc2YW8qacp+tSo7qAmVK1VwmW7cTThFholp68QckUR3ci9SlWDlkCzJHX5Y5j39DpQSRc0C7cIIuA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080169", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZgz3wO6/NGXUQ3IdonGXQeN4eXrmFKnHa+CyiYd4N12FwRtt82KK47b49l4Gw+ha54rfZDcPbYIvycKMl+f4ymJIN8NWn4Qy95scbvFEjC2/fdnaMvdi1y6EMkCwczb9EHhxnSOWiWlavJap9Cv7R9Mwzhw0n4R548s5fN6Rmamd60S9iBLC9XWVQbxqUUSLtM284kCZs742icO/tDPI+/qj2szb9c0OIhxAuoNsI1qyk+gZ9Cs2Rdv0aQBOsfLRbUHoJGilKBxd7cPm32Ypy4ctVGo9+h5KwpNEbdB2xIztuSF8f8FvFDezrUMA05s8Sx+Tfa/4wHrh81AtY3s/bIVj/Cw7pU+LJ0ZtkmKMDnn4RR/f/Yiw6Hgw9ajJAzM=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjJ1721ktgw/yfEcV3+ayWaI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiICqnGAV+NgYnTmR+fOZ+b7iZl0IlHFzUty4nfK7+Xm9kdDz7tT6IOWPGICcI8v3MWFxO23xWNEc89KnoV34Nocc/pTxTmoZtHfYO1vzXyFIwX5aXm8CnN9kT/CylVYrIq6+2erRts01Bwxk5Q42cA5fMWa2Luc5g2xlUaD0GieCKl2BFHV9cy9/wOVtMIxpo2Dviab4Pz82ujB+dMKcBESrYN+cFSy164G6mosWc29elJY8OfCZFCtMzyiMxsOuf/r0zR51IskXHsttA1Dg5BZbIB12YqkqDo1Nt8qBzasplZFyZd5Hx6FNKmw1WH2oFYqeW4+d4th/Cw7pU+POF1sk3+JTSARh4ls8NkfnAdic2xF0Db3ijaHhSWbdJbq+cDxgOz5o7Bt869nOVOPJVnKQoQZdvPDKGlm2OCZGLJZc4toVzbuONw8vCnrJYWRzS8MxNAvITfm+i7ZhcLnKm2zo9AzimYM7vzw/0R9/s+f4y/h", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "080170", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdR/n0fzyNCvyFmYVq37DU6dif3LiQKLGLuvx29dlL1nJnUl05nPFt6z/+RMAiehY5pmMMC8Cd4Vj0ZCNwuG30H4BJ85Bk5Iy9pUTebRJwn2gdd3VNP9nwGeOIAXkbzz9AXN7mD7Rg39XpMO59Cu6WtkygBo01oZ27sE5MsPf8KaX4Uy2xhWN33KUXKRYH2iXh8up+EyS+sIbtNmZvTeb9/v3jura8ssfZ0hGsMZvb1qyg+gO6iUvRcD4KAVD+OfYIV3jYDy2NQBd6dnswH1tw5FpWHon8RFSi4JaItJ2xZfxrjE1LI1sGiH6q1FNxpo8SBKaePC61WHq5xd3HIJ6E8mx7qHJ9sXCS2Om", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I42yXU7dxYzH3XKbWLsr/3INwKl3Jr05/9n7H46T04VwMjrxe7c6ZfzBDfYR4iMCb2PDyx2VIPMgEso9l4YwabrgA2DWoNMbeIe1hwC6JNAX5aTqyFmJxlyWWvXRfpIb79iavQNYygBw8koJ96Yg/M9mLy6GR/Vm9xhKNnGudSbNwUVOLutm84w/ctIo99cCMuDyb5vH4iffdsNgEcEhwqoJ7a1r7hOgI/Dw3Usm3cVJc8PeQb1v5YDyrIgcPudns2nEpz4xpUGg9+gtHi41fbMcz05vrsD03Ns5rGXO4okhByZd5HxWDYP2q0Xzs5Ud/YXIubJgttSAlrh2IKVp9nyuVQmxBho9999QQmwMje2BPmDqglDafgWmGaIqvq4j5hOTkqPUj860jaUmBJUzRWIgPdvPUKCdiz+aLAaMe/NYLZWxSfpGJy7ojCVgW0A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Ecology and Environment >> Ecology to Ancient attidues towards The Environment", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5EoV170yujtdWbRCW0D43OCXKRhcXbmFKDQYfju2td4KRygg19y8zbHoKb/5VcGga8b/YHfVzAKe5l8x97OxKTk0WNXNt8b2HEVoZZjM4LWFNB/dnEPrrg=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJ6+8Avz9otsEjrgxOv2MWLRDS5RgmqQRrF7PVDwXabWZ+6yiaN4JVmdghZZ52TLoquy5rm5tjvaepcE6sq2GGAYsw==", 
		"explanation": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7VwPLtMm6QImADoneCX+NTYnjmRrTNYKrtibt4KVuchEhv+3WGkLDi4VYWz6ddqaeRdCsCMst7wNXJ0evi1jFMMsxLiMB+5ZQYafVHyX2qZtvOMO0ux2DADkv0bjj9BWJxzg3YtnJ/poe0uAapTds5gBkzmIBt7M85L5vfzqCa60X4hxSHnG+ZTf1pHkeN9dmh70aQucIrpcKGtDyb+PX3ne3S99tLZAlftopmI1Ky14EH/CM5Efy8bQsL8PbVIUDlLz2kLxpd7cSj3nV/w8ImT2Az/RFHloZSIsl9lrvhsiYiPsEqNCCzogRByZA8Sx+Tbf2v1XrhoFctem8sbZ4tqCJ1iAGYIVU+mHLcWCRU1KF559EX1RRmcn9MmWWggy2ElWuLPMKvvtCsxcrThflX+qZnJE6TIRzPX4kZaaqANHd9weyVTY9SN5AqNjD/PNtu8Dj3J4OV2DwekNAub17p8COY0sznPCWSupz9h5g2NroOMdDJ4If3nV3VYDfpKDHTZ8XwGS/lRX3q0hpsixYB2iAG4WbRCYc/+SwDmWuxTkF33mf3ZHWinv5d+IfOa4Y+xvLkyXIEl7Rwno3ylBIuTgOyg35Xt4DfRlIP2VzTXuQJwAAvAvQSAZTS/WOCnHjVRWhNftz5FKaDg3gEirOhznh4voIdFY2JI1nvgts/iBajBL1qRWjmrYi5P+VVBXIp6PIjmr3husO3efqrIiU6ahWnVeoZ+psRQQx/GAqRRRddafiCV5MVQKwP4nTBnhRcRnEFRVvC/+gqXAqtpsXMa3nWI4UUC17vbKARU9nxSkLDLLG62D/CA7HcsVW/SU0hRzuTYbwM6wDle4v3N1OygW0kzcDoO10XBLcSMDL0YSf5jqKNBQc+fmBlKYRDOmrURxE9lTLCKsVprLITZAoiQLuuGEQflVFDnjDVG1lCtV9SH7KlSVAvaqhXJRsSwjmmGKQaThnOxi4FzlSZgjbkLLpOMFsvcmGAmwzskpxhivb6loeCStPwIqgLkoQNaJ9VQJPXX28Un+qk7vPlUXgxCXhwJuyISu2RuE7gB4j7sMrdzFJK3bsMdlY1ZS2DjN/w/j5kLqsPfGVIvnwXuMPcZwi+mYlL2kVmVBW6uRG0ESc4sxBhfdPqbdKcHpOgsHFKBTDVWLhQkf1s1C+kOd7fYw8+AGYm0QaCc5LZ1zuIOKK7wrRJCg6nxdmaFdot4UF1wtW9zQxQrjRlg3miAniaS+np4R8YYl55RbOTG1lYlR9ulTu/2hPbMpq+j6MInaQB+aYa4EzDqiQ2glGfWwrZanfv0u/epHbJtUIviYt2T3KxVHJ+xw0wTfNr/nhgRzggTqRn/L/7bJjKmmiubp2qyMwg8FhQR+fLIbn7lt39Nqr5IZHl24WXID/D5IFkBfvvKd8LJ2PMYzgM6P7jao3HZUmSLm7EwauXGS6AZSJCrnZ4n3DOAEg8bW26R8VUETgSgId5M7UU5Mfq8HlqaX7IWpB70KBF235YH0QZa+/omT0NGfZmeb2TZ0tl+lcPHa80eWS2KX5+Ypxy0mGxVyjiyTyujrtgRNvqmxNsKQyf1GSJa3Cc/ON7PyutS4LRzdeRAxOn4PsySFZZ+6lGlwDND3JRYm1h4yLNjuR7WVfMXhwtKvsT0pwUWdbiuAFOw413Vl1acHzZDyn5Gp/LF+EDD9ev3Ksz640XyzVOHtEdaIOJQhiNp2eNH3pdMWBXdEmfnlD67JF6kN/JFAjP5iPwr9rgFlKcvXFc3v7yCMMXz1ZuKLiYncLyAu143/nvCGQkQ9Ad6XhWI53qW65Y6HcfHc1AFDx1QQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Indo-Aryan, Dravidian, Austro-Asiatic, Tibeto-Burman", 
		"option_b": "Uralic, Sino-Tibetan, Afroasiatic, Austro-Hungarian", 
		"option_c": "Austronesian, Altaic, Semitic, Austro-African", 
		"option_d": "Bantu, Uto-Aztecan, Japonic, Sino-Korean", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXj+YI1Ww3mzP6/MnnfFnJRqmzDUax6Y3jnUbXHaq3qwZIxIl2bgVJ+4WKGqquw3l0LhqkEq/esFQ35DTyg+LGLLGvW0fY=", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh3lTL5IwhRhfxh5tWZznBunCWv3FZZyBdv5U=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YohQRfz0fT8dWfRDWUEoniGQeN1YnSjQK/Ne+r23ddlKByBjE1+snnUqqL5+VIbiqwb4IDfZCoGPqJhzNmI2aTk0XNCPMhQk4536o5ffeZP2TOpNIKXcK4+jneFJlfjJzi6Czw0gznfhnkWvIu+tQOpVcw+xBwzmMd07MY7KdaY3LvT6V+9xhKK026WQKkkBVvZvc++7gOTsos/vMOMpTfftPXrle3d9J5fLlgC78ZmZlquhOgI/yV4ZcC9e1JG9OXechT5KCm3ZxoV/IvCw2d91I0oTmA14BZFwo9XbMdm15/hr3InOt9vVT+zqEFM3tRvTxidcbP42WakyVs7fHtrY4V//Cx1rQCSL1Fs2nuZXiVekMBk+JANnAlmPXtInXigljeOwEGdfYXq74n9i6j8obdk56IgLFLC1Gg++llg7tCuDzlN2BwHKg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Austro-Asiatic", 
		"option_b": "Tibeto-Burman", 
		"option_c": "Indo-Aryan", 
		"option_d": "Dravidian", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090103", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7zy+n3J2TADG4epHaQRrA4MHnsQ+fGZ+m+3Z90Z32cnk9p+3WGs6D/518Kz6RS4ouTaWIOd4x9ycSMl/D4hFBUINJWm4x75cVdiCzlbHQrJmk7he1ZjwmNDw==", 
		"answer": "25a3aYLnkRbst5EoV17by/n2NGWQEHcToHCNRqp6dX/3FsPeKPszU0fBXapwYyWyDyA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwaYWz2Aqq9sUwXQ3hzP/zMCvEC2cesWbPEqFhZDHqQOfLfa3t3Z59KxyNiFl65nPC46T9+F0Iz6lV/YaNfzIMcoRowcOdxNj58HlEc+dRiZRg7ZlfbPFP3DGoNNXJJb5vjmKJKULlbiqpDXM0kyPZn2wWvIu64WeyWtk71RE3hcds5c18L8ea2KOW+l74iQDCyHOUCJxxAkCLusCt+EqdrsI0tMOKpDPc8ee12u/b+d0DIglAusZsc1S3kqZJ8SR4YsehfBpO8PfEIXX+KSnvZyMc/crk12dqx5BlHWg68F9SioYWUsFw357tv3IZLMFrGzep43BIwtRdSgSCZrS7kHjh70UzcDoqd48tvSEmrk+IIFtrnWOIDDhe1IJuvsQRkERic2xFj2LvkCzLj2PPaJvmq6HplvziobVq861nCEOPJ1XfX4MdafPQImhixuynA4lSNt9zHyfpL8xu9Sq5NJ6Vy3kZ2NxgDmL04DiQkY3lPGqqv5e5g91xBr4UM9WF79m4vRzmZzHoInzTcsS0agflW3T90h1x9zk2wSBQ/mvZSJ138G0OkX+jXQRrlGf0ZHnhv7BY44OAP50k0fbj0yYZlvF2i9vD3BQvBxCziHBRq8SWXBxNzEfTGo0Iykk6BLFBEpfS5i2CnXfEC2gFetzzQamVxmxb1e70znJ0spkCVJ6HOBDemZ4kzQOmBPh3FXPlrcbYKO8BGGsi/6F4y+Phu8u1cualK2A5Lxu5Xa9N+5ARTBB6BwLZDCVBILSvWJoLQOdKwTmKgA9BRHcJBEjJu7sYUg+vpITBYCr3bbUVD1yPZHu+MxpdBfkLw3J4Q8nF", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Coast of the Indian subcontinent", 
		"option_b": "Through Siberia", 
		"option_c": "Across the Pacific Ocean", 
		"option_d": "Through Central Asia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090104", 
		"question": "2523f9H/3hftt4QnXV72zPm/PX7dAmwC43mRXa40UXfxXaTDLuD3zoVwM1nJmVQ75n7D46H18kNPnKdO/YbffyRDV4VrwdHWlQfeoh6Mg5yjNRDqzgWw/1Y=", 
		"answer": "2+DoJMGjgVnz8oQyQV7zwvK9iG4zcS98e/rx5Pw2g+cluA==", 
		"explanation": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV71wPP6IWLTQ3EFtnuKV7A4MHn2WabMfa3425h8Z32Pn1J48zbAqrfj4xMChq9J6JqadGIXcct7wNXJ0+Hy1DFSPNNQksB94to2cvBJzX2vccDMJftgjjvQaxWgN3m8CnQ0wmGa2iwG6Jq+9DWoFNswz1UGnoJr6Ig5PcWTwOie4UqqhwiWzzuGTa9hUVmcuMyt+VDcr4R4ocWI8RPV9/HqjurS/J44bR1Gt8ZWbV+1lqZJ1CM2VMmzbVID0Nf5KBitNyCqJAZd8Nij1zRuw4wsSWA3tBNPjIZXZcUzwpDlqHI5LI1sGia0pwRJydRxUBOTZrP11Gn9oGYwYG4jJaNjuCQ0rxzeC1pL+L20fuYyfv2iw4/zHQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "10,000 years ago", 
		"option_b": "20,000 years ago", 
		"option_c": "50,000 years ago", 
		"option_d": "100,000 years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090105", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7V1/T6J3jfDSUC42yWQLVxaT2jfanGZ+y+wZZiZ1KMjEl36zaG8v2gt18Oga9O6ImaY2ICcI8vydKGwvC3+05+DPl7pb9N29obdfVMyT65Z5bAZoOVOjhxuVu7Pd6eO24C", 
		"answer": "zOHs/GOSFKseACEzacMdQNU3ew==", 
		"explanation": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7V1/T6J3jfDSUC42yWQLVxaT2jfanGZ+y+wZZiZ1KMjEl36zaX+/Ww+1IBiL1a7ouMMCMNestuyt+cw6SikCUBN89FloVx8IkjcshO+DWoNPjSLvl7x32ULkawVCyvEnVt1D7QylVYrIq6tW+XZ/N+jFUzmpR3rcMyM8CRmamAqGqqjwOQz3SfD64kPV2Xstuh+FeVo8ILoN+btCuXtP3q2vmT89EGchpXt4NxcFKqkuga7TguVNH0ZxQL5ezVIVjsLi+2JgkY6ovs0DRL1Is9VHo8tDZIhopXLoB304vnrjsyNsNtVWDs9wRMxpp7ShaRca740WbgoFE2dHYuZp5+/Bk9pE+PPUZon3LcWy1C1IZi7MMN1RRxcn9Pj3Pkwj2SwEKKc4Hk7sDdh/rxqLhusoQ1IESSJlPWGs0dJb7FKmV32KmUC+ZIO5onPiziNNQgvBrwNp+YnwoIws8pLHKn9SSd0sy1NWy0tIfwncA2A7cPdtDR/c65tFnDITfpJD2gY93xVxz4D1X2xwt3uRkxwS4e6W6YJ5t28CMZn3LwaktqlTXlf2/hnrtQ7sKPa84H2vDi0zNQkfo4rJ7nwBgxRQGpzS4b6tLdQyexf7WWsulYThgnVD+N5g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "5,44,45", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090106", 
		"question": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YwjEhLzy/rqNGzVQ2QQrnaPS+N9fnLvQaPHfa3q3pgxNEmLi1p2+3rPpraqt3IanLxJ4I3SUTEKf59my5CI2eC35WRSJ9RLlIVh7ZsRPMNIxT6lNNvdYOpmyy6GKEn8aC60Cnc0hjTRg3NYu8Oy5me6R8k4wxwzgoJ8rd81KN/fzaCWqGytlRKQ03WUW7RlHxSKoMyu6k6VrJtn91AaRGZLSHwwvhsJVzeAzI0=", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh0BXj9sUhXBqy9vLqIWPVAnEF416QW6I2fSaePilbEHpQ2QlQ1Aj8WA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YouVw37xPO/Jn7SBWMcqnOaEqxyMGXrUefje/7q255yZ1CIg1xu83HD46Px+loDluhS+s6MYC0Ie4Uvwd7J9vHk0GNAP89F2oF84Nosc+FUxDisZ8CbAe1nzywnlRsWQBaJrqQ3jB+8d1cY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Indian subcontinent", 
		"option_b": "Australia and Southeast Asia", 
		"option_c": "Himalayas", 
		"option_d": "Nicobar Islands", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090107", 
		"question": "24GwbdHexBfu9sUsUxD10Pz4MCeQAiIBom2XEqxyMGXrUefje/7q255yan2ahFpv+3WGsLDy8VIChqRCpc6WY2IQboRkzd7J1f2303lIMM4EipJ96ZMRefpUjCm/fdbaLL5p3GGVNwX5aXmpDHU0vT/Sg31Y6JCu9yS0Ws4+zhA8gsUkNYnJxbFfbSUtMyEfu2ck", 
		"answer": "24a5ZoX70BX5tYEp/4VkAb7IGP82I/yQZHw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA0Bf+/4QsQVKy0vXwdWjfDXEFqmuWRqY0ZHnmFKvDfOr72oMxM06Aj1p3snHUrLDgt1oBz7xT7M6MZSAAcYV7wd6M2fC7hGJRNsdP2pR64doyafpEzX2hddrcNf9pyyzMafLK4BLB2FaKQSR6n9Tx", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Khasi", 
		"option_b": "Mon-Khmer", 
		"option_c": "Santhals", 
		"option_d": "Hoes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090108", 
		"question": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YwjHz/hzPzrPGiQEHcTpX6OW69tMHLsWrTLffntiZh3Z0ieght54HfIoK315AlPor1V7Y/fcSwHPrRQ9++26NvI+04Dh8JLobk2qiev9EN2jiq6fw==", 
		"answer": "25i3ZtzY2RTv5cclFvfU5C0DPHQs1spE7Yvd", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YwjHz/hzPzrPGiQEHcTpX6OW69tMHniR+fWeeK+y4VwKV+BiEghslvTraHxt1IBi+h25oDSWyoOe5kv5d+Hms//yXRTc9RBipJ3958RaOcA2DWoNP/TIe1njmKBKULlZj64RHF6kHHfmTxFuIyw8Cn7XdR30hA1n4h2/ogwNdyambyb7Q2TjgeR1TuQRrkkO1WXocepq0uVrI4r9cSD8R/e8/z4lvnK8Z4KbAwSq456I3W1lKcL+Th4eNu4aRxP4qYcPY4en4oymKfA46HDARFA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mo,n-,Kh,mer", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090109", 
		"question": "24GwbdH63x/l5YghRhf9y73+N2TFFyIFq3rDc7ZnZGPqV+fOb+P53JZ2IhyPjFZy/m+GgKr+5FoLirob/YaaMCQMcodg39mH0KTk0HBVNstBlJRhvqYRQPoRjAmlcZT6Ne163GeDZ0nxaT6oBXdx1DfXh3VascOz9DT7QM04gAYnlIF54MEwNdKMg+iy/V6slA+BkVqCQbxwGFfZtMCsq2KJs5YqusOIojva+sj3pvaBsOoDZ0hzqpVrcVSykrsA+SR4Qt22bhNG+OjJIV3+YDuzKAUY94vq2DRI05E9T2g4/R4Gg41SIvN8w4zsuTMjK41LBjq7n0p8ycc8ax+TNJytw3z26VZ/eXslYp9suyh1pw6RIVhn2mKPDChYgolv+9RZnAp3ci9UlGTlh3+YlWeJfZ7q54n5lrKwibdn/e4CPFOPJVnZWMFcVrrOKCpGw+ueGadSf99mGSamGccv6jD9KZeand/5En3CfdauLEPVwa5Nnoo=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbbDmwg34/oZgXh/8wuj+Mm6QBWMcqnOaEqpnMHjtUKLHaq36wIF4I1mNzVJ15nmGt7L/t0Aaja5a5IeTeScQJMtO3cOdxe30iVBSOsdQk4My5ZQbPNVV3ym/e9reM/dvwC6pMwXxayqyRGNkkTLfjHVTu8Ov/SavFM4/xVUTg5Rs/8cyOcSW2KbT+1i6gAeP1XeICLR3UUeJusWt5QOVrsIZoN6ZozPX/fW5m/bXsO0EdxxauodsdxudhKEIuAI3Rs2ibQAHsfDYZBT5KCGxI04O7cr303lsyJZpVHp0/RFFjZFEZ8Nnlpn3/CY4Oo16FCCpokNFh5BzWgTWerKskGXh7kE2enRrcYJo/D0npByZJld72mSaDD9EloZq89kVnAFwPWNJl3OgqzGPjyiqaYHs+4X9i6Swk7Bt/e4TIEOFIV3WGs0Td/PkNWZkw+2SDKgcJJZzHyvofcEm+XnYNYWAzTAOkNUhIXDy9S2c0sv0NGy2qtCylYw1Vj50xQfBZt5plBtp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090110", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdDqO2/RQ24QrXiWU6RxMHjwFLTSYeb7x9d4KRyIzVd64HHDseXx5VYOz6tU5J6eYicHPp9giMSB0qTay38MGM5Jn5Iy6JsRe+FByziReujVEvtv3WGOfQXEbzz9N3F6gDnXhm8a6Jez8Ge3VcgwxQYm1pNq5Mo9MJeYy6eG+A2xiEaW1H7RYbNgGFWX9d296UCTrpYxu8iDpX6b5+T8m/OT5NYOIiVHsYJ+I1e9ma8c+S09Ecm3eh1Y4qTDdVX5JTvjKwcW/IvJ3nV7zYooU214tD1PioJELoBE04vw/BA1McprGX/6okpEh7tuVgSFdf8aY/D1YWC5YYeHefIt7709", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddwKVjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMGnOhP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjO8rPV+nXo8G+gZITEyovIU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+QRqJgdWKjQK/Deq3qwZIxCkmHiVo7/nfIpLDx8FZPhrsb+p6QeycNPoR5zcLJ1qT7xWNGNtQEiIV17ZURPOBIzTPtYNzeYNNhwCOrL0j1dXmxBX5zgTDRjzxioIb75yK6R9U5gAUgmZFx6c0vfNKJ0KyW5k69xgCQ03bRXLVhUUSYpt2p7EbQ4IcgpcGMuDzS+vO5jvDS5J4fag0SjIdxd1O9m7tFuD4wVIi4aQBM9PfEIUD/KSqiK04a68T2xjgp1ZIsXGJ04BdDwq5DbMRylpTlsjUlPspvVTq041dF0ZFuXhvWZ6m5xG33oHovYXMka8pM/CQm4RuULRR9lXmOSS9F1IFl7ccch0Ribi9Ck2LowiuDhSWOb4Dm+ZT1iuawobdnsrEiKFKPOxzZRIhccaHVIisyy+efTbJUNt91EiP1Mttu+SHpLJed0SpNx9E5b2Pv8WqYgd7wK3GzvJy5h8c2AK0VM5Oh4xNqTCroPQqTY2W/U5W6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090111", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXr+YI1Uxn3hfv+OGLcGiIYsD+AWqJmcXL3UbXLdOj6iZVoZ1Wdnht/+2XSsazy4kcGgKYb4IDfZCoGPoVg2sSBmuH212VEIcgEiZRz8J8MPPtGjBSjcN3aYP9gyi6SIkL5aDeuRHl6lz3DjnVYr8OP/CW+QJZ34x07mIY0rckyOJeywKmd5Uyq2US4yjV4uAKTFssFFR7ttklX", 
		"answer": "24GxapTn3lTI4pctUxCwGVSFk2VLBp9fwbGvnp+NGQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH2Bvv44ptcAvgyPzxdWfRDWUEoniGEqV1fXjvTefLfa3t2Zh6IlLJhFU75n7D46v/5UcHwq1a+pqaYixDbZ9u3NWal+vxhFhPN89F2oF84NoaZOBFwjm+NN3VNPEuwGuJIE3yaCu0Cnc0hjTRg3NYu8EIfVNz9C/D+0CXzYQWIuD5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indo-Aryan", 
		"option_b": "Dravidian", 
		"option_c": "Tibeto-Burman", 
		"option_d": "Austric", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090112", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71FnD+YEpUxCy1uj9NmTeF2sfpnGXHuNgeHSjcLXDeOT6wJZ/Z1CIg1xu83HD46Px+loDluhS+s6PYisOf5lmxMnJ1vfky3JIMtJBnsBl7Y4XPONIxT6lNNPeL/l8z36ILkbxa3m8FnV1y3PhyW6QpfsXOlrhmCDhNgSJ", 
		"answer": "24a3fYX7kTDk84whEBlPqDlV4Qd9GMsgg9yfUOQ=", 
		"explanation": "25GqaYf61RDr+cUsUxD10Pz4MHiQAG0Hpm3DU695f2L3FLPKa637x4N4NVnJn158+3nI46r2t2AAmrxTqaeRdCsCPophzJCMz/DyynUBOshQlcB864gLdLlFzS65ccbVYM18xy6sJkv7ZntOWXpEiBMjQjl7wkTiaaTS", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "South India", 
		"option_b": "North India", 
		"option_c": "Eastern India", 
		"option_d": "Western India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090113", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQB2sCt3aNUbd9f3+jVqLWeej7x9dlL1nJpFV//Tvnsbzx+RMOgawbzZyeZisHd4phiNyI2ePixXZEc8BFl4l+7Z8MPP1OjCmoZtnIYPFojnqIIkziJzW8CndhlTbTynNEoYT5z+x/8A0h3oOZSqhvX4YMdQ==", 
		"answer": "25y2bJ6+8Avz9otgUBv+yvP4JivEDCIFq3rDe61wfzzGQbXNfuj/x9d3JlGAgUIgslLUorP581oOgehS+s6MdTICbIp7zZKiNfyFPoIAR75puAon7jhe", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJ6+8Avz9otgXh/8wuj+Mm7DQ2AUr3CNVeNgfzH3XKKCR+P6xtpUMk6GnV56/DbAoqj5+0pDz79T4IKaMAYRf51mzNmI2aT7xX9GJsdDn5My5YgaPPdPwi6kcNHJJfouzy6TIlXxdTipATB4lT/Rn31RrcO99CqyWMN1pRO1LxQn+0JSRS11nktymg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both belong to the Austroasiatic family", 
		"option_b": "Both are branches of the Tibeto-Burman family", 
		"option_c": "Both are derived from Austric languages", 
		"option_d": "Indo-Aryan belongs to the Indo-European family; Dravidian is separate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090114", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsXqEW6x6YzHrVbSCb63t3JViM12HmVJ6/jbWsaDj8l0MiuhU7867cTAHd4gvxNGH0PH2w3RSf4ZTkolx7NoebvEA3zKgccDSLft9jm2PKVb5YzyvAXQ0lXHUmH1Yq4v7+iH7fdQzz1gThJ5545d+CsedHMh0mrQ80j6iFyE0Lw==", 
		"answer": "25C5e4X2wxeq1oMnWh/8zO7rNGWcQ0wesWuLEpN1e3jwQKbMIq3/x5MxDF2ahVZy4DTmDOaAHLAZgThlIowHV38H", 
		"explanation": "25G5epX60lnm9osnRx/1wO6/NHnVQ3IDqnKCQKp4aTHwRKjJa+O+wJkxIl2amV5p/DbnpaL49l0GnLxa58Lffi0RaoMv+NGC3vfjxX8Nc8dKnsBZ5YkXcf1SgH2seMDTL+tpxi6UL0DiYnm0FzBnmzzTynhTqoKv8Ge6VtUi1FUmnoJx/4g/MNaMyqGV4U65kg+N0jnEog5BzVr6yfPbW65pynQr", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Western Rajasthan", 
		"option_b": "Southern India", 
		"option_c": "Eastern Afghanistan, North Pakistan, and Kashmir", 
		"option_d": "Central China", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXj+YI1Ww3mzP6/MnnfFnJRqnHDRqtxMFjtUK7DYK3t3JVyKFKdhFV+/GKGqraw9kAcgKtS6JqadGIUd59niMSB0qTLhl9ENNRNjo9OptoNffdJzTHtcN3NKe1nwWDAJkv0JzCuRHJxmDjTnHlS6Je0tS+6Qt934QAhgpVx7ogwPdmYzKmU7Q27iQiM2XiFQbJqAgvbDvpbhYF1AMdiX/OQblFEDQ==", 
		"answer": "25a9eoXy2Beq45cpUBvhhfTxdX/YBiIwrXuCX6J6MHDtUOfsZ+7xy5ZjZ3WagVp19mWEsF9cIj2dKVnrqW0zb7MeFw==", 
		"explanation": "24GqYZP2wlnj+cU0Whuy5PP7NGbRDSIQrXvDfKp3f3PiRufrfeH/x5NiZ12biBt64WXJoKzx41YLz79S/YbfZCoGPqVqz8KAw+u31nBCOsdI2oR78pMMdftOjDyjcJTaMvsuzGuMLkDmYj39EH80hyHTi3cWiZao4TWyV5o7wRs1g4Z/6Nt+1opiMNm2W33Yawuy5d1/4A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Certain tribes in the Andaman and Nicobar Islands", 
		"option_b": "Himalayan communities", 
		"option_c": "Dravidian-speaking communities", 
		"option_d": "Mongoloid ethnic groups", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090116", 
		"question": "24GwbdH/2Bft4owzRhfxhfTxIW7CAmEFqnCNQeN1fnWjVqjQfOLpwJl2Z16MmUx+93iGp6z28VYdiqZPqYKefiUWf4xqiNeb2PHn1zFIPYZtlIR75doebvEA3C+kedXJKfJ3jmqSLlP1aXm/HTBjnDDCynpXq5e053j5NJPL7uO6N7pbOM+zn1DkuA==", 
		"answer": "24a3a5j8nBzp+IsvXxfxhfTxIW7CAmEFqnCNQeN1fnWjXK7ReuLswJRwKxyAg09+4HfFt6z/+UBN7l+Eq+UMy6kLYaNCI+OnGw==", 
		"explanation": "24a3a5j8nBzp+IsvXxfxhfTxIW7CAmEFqnCNQeN1fnWjXK7ReuLswJRwKxyAg09+4HfFt6z/+UBPh6lN7M6TdSZDaoQv3NiMl+ni0GRAP4ZGlZJg640WcvMAwzvtY9vJJO0uzGuUMED1aXm5DXZykSPThGgWpIK18jK6U993xwc9g5drr1ruVt0DevpxI/OpIwyfo8U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Religious conversions", 
		"option_b": "Socio-economic interactions and historical interactions", 
		"option_c": "Geographical proximity", 
		"option_d": "Political dominance", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090117", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liVRHm1/zsCSmQCnFRoHCOX6x6fGijVbTRYe73yIN0IxyehE9zsmHOqqb4t0AAjKFa5c6YYi0WbstmxpCd3+G37X9FOsdK2pNn5pkQcuBJwjijYIuZ+0r9DkNmadJc/ZyTZKxZDw==", 
		"answer": "25eqaZn+0Bfr5McrhnJKTOsZrOlEKOIMc0cE", 
		"explanation": "25K3fIPywiWot4QyV17xyvDyOmXcGiIQsGyMUap1ZHTnFLDLeuW+3Z90Z36bjFN283jH47b/9FoOg+hc+4GKYGIKcMt7wNXJ/urzzXBPc9VRmIN96o4WcvFO2H9nqnMkCZGXoLc0iyyosBTs", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Chamars", 
		"option_b": "Brahmanas", 
		"option_c": "Negrito tribes", 
		"option_d": "Dardic communities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090118", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3RDk8JApQQr7xr3rJ2reEGsFqnCNEqx3c2TxRqLGLuTwiZp0I1WMm1p3smLPrqDjt0cHjrwb5YubMDYMPp9nzZCN0vLyyH5RPsNKjsB94toSc/BF3jPtZtHcKfFgz2LAK0T+YCy8A3Vn1D3fgXkWgIq18S73FPgyzhIzmo40rckyOJey2LqS/EWx2US9cIt3XzvKLK5xYpTWr3G0", 
		"answer": "25SoaZP7wxjn5I0hEhvkyvHpPGXXQ2sft3DDX6xwdWPtFLXHaeTxx5Z9Z1CIg1xu83HDsOfJnbXRlE/kw8iWmaCrR0L+", 
		"explanation": "25SoaZP7wxjn5I0hHl7zhfvwJ2aQDGRRjnaHVq9xMFjtUKiPT//nyJk9Z1mfgldt93KGqqvk+BMCgKxe+4DfYicEd4RhydzJ2+X5w2RANMNX2ox7759fVP1OyDThNPbeLvlvwmfMZ0T+Y3mQBWJ1gDnfynVY6I6+8S6+Qts7gAE7m4Jrr0I4OdbXrqpob2SWOEfDS10=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Dravidian languages merging with Indo-Aryan languages", 
		"option_b": "Tibeto-Burman languages influencing Indo-Aryan languages", 
		"option_c": "Austric languages becoming the basis for modern regional languages", 
		"option_d": "Apabhramsha evolving into modern regional languages", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/r9JEvQF7xzfzzOW7eBGcC42uLV+N3fHTiRufGa+D/25RwM1WGgxt09DbUoqb59l9PjqZfqYKWfiUWd5h7wdPJ0+3hzWJIPMhX2ol8pI4XebRpwjmkddqbM+tszWGOM0z+YjepWzIbooRgA00hcB7Wh/YpuNwc", 
		"answer": "25y2fJTh3BDy45AyV179w73vMGTAD2cC436NVuN3eHDtU67Maa3uwY5iLl+IgRt993fStrf15BMLmq0b/YHfcy4Kc4p7wdPJ1Ov5wHhVOslKicI0mZ60Q/i+hvAbxtXe4V6G", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63w3v5YgpSgrn1/i/Om2QB2sXpXqRV61gMGHmW7fOa/6+yJl1Z1+BjFV8+3jB47X47kAGjKlXqYiacTYWbI58iNSc0qTjyzFCP89Jm5R759occ/pExSmke9rIYPNvxWvALlGwYzC7Anl3gT3CymhZ6IC38CapWMN3xBA/l5V77Nw5fMWe2qGS5A25iALC0HKfT6htAkCQto6s4lWVs4s3u97PEexsBJ07WQgZvUISCvQxQQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Stable geographical boundaries", 
		"option_b": "Strong colonial influences", 
		"option_c": "Isolated cultural zones", 
		"option_d": "Intermixture of peoples and changing physical features due to climatic conditions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090120", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEh/i1e/wLWLdAnYU43GWX6FxYjHsUufOb+P53JZ2Ik/JmlJv+n/I47H48hM7hqpe/YHSUjcRc4phiNyI2ePixXZEc8BFl4l+/cVdGhyga/x1mJQ5BvmhxOuq1A==", 
		"answer": "yuXoDnShWZ4drNKofHuEdwF7+g==", 
		"explanation": "24a7YJ7/0Av5t4AzRhf/xOn6dX/YAnZRt3eGQKY0cWPmFPWXPqCtmccxK12Hik569XPV47L541sGgehP4YvfRCsBe59ghfKcxen2yjFNMshDj4F14doZfflJwCTtQNzeYMpnzGuUKAjSciuwBX40mDDYjWlXr4b78ya2XdYugBwh1pNw6IgyM9nS6qGd4VmxhUaAznqfS7UkHlLZocatq3CVro11gcSPtCba+rT1m/bU5d8MZ0hUvot2b0Lw178B8SkwEcGnKAFb/u/VbxTkLmiiZxkU/c6jxHVnwYdpUm909xBTjJdEa8VgmtjtsjE8KsljGzT6gExJyZUwHz6YcLS5nCjK5UU+eTZrR4J4qCw77U+xMVVwl2qOAGx9lY94spAtnQVqcW5OmDqgtDaOlGuOcd+jyYHyguTxpLxw+u9nKE+EdWzZXYQPcbLOZQr7PLx8K87YOqyiruxiXNc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 50, 
		"option_b": 100, 
		"option_c": 200, 
		"option_d": 300, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090121", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF79w73WO2/ZAiIZomzDRqtxMHnqU6/Hffm+yph/JFmHmUl65n/JreX/8RM7hqpe/YHSUjcRc4phiNyI2ePixXZEIJkGV4wyM/3XIdLE9cwXdqqliA==", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nBzr5JElQBCy1un+IW7DQT0HiYuJcoUfD4nYwFG4nhQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1B7j+ItgXRiy7PP7PGqQFGsFqz+XWqY0eHjkXKLReq39xplyIlKdn1pv+3nI46r2t2cGja1P5sO9ZTAOf4UvxNGH0PH2w3RSc89X2q599o4XefVT2H2EetDSIb5axmvACUriczG4BWNg1BjYjnVXpsOo4SavUcl3zxNyt5Vt48k/NNaTmZiB6Um9lQ7OnFqCW7xpURyRvMKk+AOdroZ4tNiZvjzU+fvsibjQ/8sFYQFerM8zI3a9maEZ7Th0EeWxbxpK/eXJYBitDSG5KBwc9Iej+HVux44oU214tCxPiYhfb4wz15bg/AYiNt1/BzL6olZFh5xzUhLWYLL40Sjz6VE6NWwqd4NoqDR1rgncHF18n3+TAQ5Eho1q8JAVlApkaG5HmWWiYgGc3+iZvvogRRYo8Tee7w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Western Rajasthan", 
		"option_b": "Central India", 
		"option_c": "North-eastern states", 
		"option_d": "Southern Kerala", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090122", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRz+/4spUV711/LqJSvZECIQsGyMUap1ZHTnFLDLeuW+3Z90Z3GGg1x0/nnPp+Xi9lAGjqQb7YeJeTEKcYUvyd6Nl/TlzXxAIc9Ig8Bh9J8ed+cA+DSvccDUbdx73GOBKQX8Zje6EXFzkSKJyDiH+KCJHKrjFqwnE50OjF8=", 
		"answer": "25i3Zpb83Rbj88cqsjwubzm8J8MjaZPw5qT9", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2xRHk/oZgVQz90O2/JXnZDmMDqnOaEqJnY37gXabWa+m+3p5lLxydhV4733nIpKr8+FoLz7pa6oeefGIHd51m29mG2aT2ynUBINZBm4t76p1fSP1CySmiOfbOMvNvwC6MJkv3cji6AWM0lSPTymhercOt9DWyW88kgAEgn4V9/og9MtPf2qee5Vi2jxKL2WjRTrJxH1DZvMDo/0uZ4Iw3p9mFtDPI4PHrlLjB9dkCbQZB/4l5I3Kyk6EItGo5QoijbR5HseXDIV3jYDivJg0Y6ovv339shrYgX2wguF9kipZCY84/lrbhrDM8c41rGzf6sEtNwtRsXgWCZ/231ijX70ArfX8qdp4tnT48oE2B4JSGqjJRIMpLV9CY+DPJ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Negrito", 
		"option_b": "Caucasoid", 
		"option_c": "Australoid", 
		"option_d": "Mongoloid", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090123", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXj+YI1Ww3mzP6/N3nRDWEZ43aQEqB7fmLqUKLQa+m+yNdiMl7Ej0l6/HXO46r2t0cHiuhy54qQPQcWbIR/zdGHl+L2yXhNKooEiZB9758RPP1OjBS/ddqbIfBqjnmJM02wYjivCGk0hjTVhW5Su8O9+jK1UJo+zlUmnoI4180yOJe+z62A/EznxAA5fv2J89+OicjQ5XSoW3E=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJ6++Avr+YwhXFz605P914lt/4gzu2u1E/Rm", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3luqwyUxD7xPO/N3nRDWEZ43CFErd8dTHKWqPNI8jr25hhIl2HzVd6/HHToqL1t1UOgqFX8M6WY2IQboRkzd7J3uq37WNAPYoEu4Z17JsRdedUzTPhNOTaK/d92m+OawXZaT20BTw0lT/SymxXupeotSi9FPkyzgEgl4s4zNs1PZer0a3T7Uyqig+Hz2/RWrhnHkadpo6n7QOIqId4nMOJvn/y5vX3k/ndsNIKbA9HvoF6cBu9ha1J/iUtX8z0YRwL5ezVIW7oLizjBhgY6t/imjR+zosqVSk9519HwoBZbsx21YztszxwMMsqBjK5sUFEh4B5RwOFNLK+kFLr8lo+Zm45bItjtT444TuULRREn2WYDA1HkZN//5AQhkR0b2ZUiHPuwjaFwGTPcJLt7JX9gu2wo7hv/qYjaWCWME/MV4NQJaTILmR6iuCITadSc55pFCvjM8Fu1Sv4Lp+V0XkB0dcnOnbg8Wgz8MOnc3oqM2KkwFhQTXHe", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indo-Iranian", 
		"option_b": "Dardic", 
		"option_c": "Tibeto-Burman", 
		"option_d": "Austroasiatic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090124", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXr+YI1Uxn3hfv+OGLcGiIYsD+CQbB7c3jiQKLGLvr33Z8xM1SMzXV+9WTPt6qw8kcHgaFYqYmNfzcTPophzJCL0uj+wWdEN4ZQlcBw4doMbPtLyTPtds2bNPZrwy6JKQXkbzz9JX5wlTzXhDxXpof72y64W9g20lUbhYt548wvY5VcARnS9F0V0qjEiI6R9It/", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh2BqoISBbWK/O40RZsrjAaslnfA==", 
		"explanation": "24y9e92zxRHr48UpQV7xyu/tMGjEQ1YZpj+tV6RmeWXsFKLWZuP3ytd2NVOcnRty4TbHsLb/9FoOm61fqZmWZCpDaoNqiPGcxPDly3BSOsdQk4My6JsRe+FByzjtctXWKfJ3gi6XL0zzb3m0FzB2kT3fj2pTrMOv+me5UZok0Bo5k4k479F8KN+a1Oia5g2sjgPC/XWVSbBlHxSYu8roxUqfr4A5p42koj7a+vDq2szb9Z4qbAxTsodxI1qyk+gn8Sk3U8mmKDtY/eXeZUetITqmZw9d/tnsw2QpyYRpVHo49RFCkcNfbIBn3p2knjMpf8JsVRG/rUNBy9g8UBGQNKmw1Sjn71QsYTokY8pEsik8oDOSFFpKkm7cYilWhol/8ZAJkAtzcWoAnWTlwiuDj3CIdIej/4+8h+2wtLFmsqw1IEaJO13UFoQSbbLCLnNzxP2ITalac4tvEmLHM9Ev8Tj3YJea23kj2dovLXb1tAOKnsz7PXb6h5r8l5R3BrpAN5HB6Nm8/U/MaC3vJHnTds77SQT1D2vxxwYlpBAq2jVQ+3bZHJxt8G0MkHrwT1ZtiD35LHSgn6wc3oqLZs4wwfCs3D4Dl7RzkZTg2l06SBb7mXdGu5bfR0lB2VHEU8oG0AErHrETVJrY9GiFgW/cTjwMccq2FaCCyj4Iz+34n3R4/5MbWZibPhyZeTeqdIvn0GzScvMCO56Ogg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Tibeto-Burman", 
		"option_b": "Indo-Aryan", 
		"option_c": "Dravidian", 
		"option_d": "Austric", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090125", 
		"question": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YwjHz/hzPzrPGiQEHcTpX6OW69tMHjtV6vXaujtiYNmKByLn1p18X7DsP+wyGwwsJdk1s6efiZDU4RhhfuB2uHlhuznpID6P6/5H0spNyO6N5M=", 
		"answer": "25itZpXyk46Z1ZUrJO1SakPyULRIW5I=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHexBfu9sUsUxD10Pz4MHiQAnAU42yTXahxfjHhTefDbOLr3dcgdwzJgFJ3/n/JreXg8lwfg60XqYOQYzYPZ8tmxpCg2eD+xTF1O8Nd2oFg4doLdPEAwTK+YJTaLv1ny2CUZ0fiZje+DDB7knHCgnkWiZao4TW0Vck+wQE7lcd07MY7KdaY3OiV6UCxih/OnHqfTP1wGVGA9c+67gOIqI0tssWZ8SbUtPz4jP2T/8wCZQFcvpJ6Zxu1megd8C94Q82zYR1FsevWIUDlJWiALwEJ+IvN13N505BpbWU14BpHl8NfbIB214vwuSA+f+RkETq7n0p0z5E8chiYOZaw3W32oFk+e30+ZI1or200swrcO0RxkW6SDC5I1IFp8cUN1VU2LS9NlXrsizCFwHWKc4Pv7sy8iOfjtLV6sqopaXKPIEjQU4wPcfPhNG5zit2TCL8cMo1iVzbuOJUj8yrtYIGd2zwewMslLnOn9jiYnM79eWq884bxi5RXAawUJN7E+sK2pFXEIS/gL3qGZ8zxGQ7xQnX0ykIlthYhiDUY7XuYCZt6tTkFkWu3QVAkhiigZH23k/5T+IuJdoAwx/DonTse2OBwmtvl0Ro1SAr7gnkDpoyaD3FKxlvYGY01zR8rHvYB0nh0x2VsXYfJJgylnUyy", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mu,nda,nde", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090126", 
		"question": "24GwbdHA0Bf+/4QsQVKy0fX6dWfREWUUsGvDRrF9cnDvFKDQYfjuiZ5/Z0iBiBto53TFrKvk/l0KgbwXqZ2PdSMIPp9nzZCkwurzxTFVPMhDj4Uy7ZRfb+BB2Di+NNjSK/su5GaBNU74Zje5SDBWnTnXmDAWn4ao4WeZUdQwwRl+1oZ26YgDA+ig5pesqjRBhujrvKdjkf25QC+fZAg=", 
		"answer": "25qqYYLg0FsXf8ziMtvvz1CN98EoCc10", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA0Bf+/4QsQV7z1/i/NGWQIncCt22MU7B9cWXqV+rRfuj/wp5/IBykmFV/8zbDt63+/lBPiLpU/J7ffyRDaoNqiPmH0+32yjFSJsRHlY5m7ZQacuAA+DWobZTaMvsu2maFZ0nxdT64F2Q0gCPfiHkWoY374S++FPA/wQc5noZ26Yg9MtPf7q2A/A2agwiF3XfRQbMkBVGLuN3o5EXcsI0ooMGMpTvU+rT4lPyT8cwOIglerIk/ZVSpmaxJ8SR4RcCxKAFf8PDVchTiJmiMIwcO8cqvllZgzoM7HWg68F9nkZBXb4BH3p39/DMiOo1+HTb6r0VSwJFvS1eTYLW22Wuk7VwxemgicZMttSN1rwCOPFx7iGXcbi1fk4xq+tUKnUNwPV1BlmXogzeCwEGGaprw4o/yxen+pPlR860gOVSSdXjRQIQPbLzOZ1N6z/DbBadKNt9mVzHvJ9Av/jX8YIabzywB0c0pIHmn/STZvMjlOGn6h5r8zud3GqsIN92F+c64oFDCITDxJHyYJvj1VxzxQ3W0kxptslgoxzIEqHXRDIxz7G0ejnG7TEokvzLuaH3hmr9S7ZePeIsik/rqnRMFi+BqkNb2xxQ9Uw24zXNCvIOKTltKjVLXE8QL3UuL8t82w/Z6PC/jnQzz+p4T", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Or,is,sa", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090127", 
		"question": "24GwbdHjwxbp8pYzEhH0hen3MCvUCnEBpm2QU680f3ejQK/HLsnsyIF4I1WIgxto4nPHqKDi5BMGnOhe+pqWfSMXe48v3N/J3+XhwTFSJ8dWjoV2pJsNc+FOyH2SS+vkH8FRjkyjZ0T+Y3m+C35gnT/Dj3gWvY2v/Cv7AIpnkFUQtcUgBAwRWgdTJuvV8mVA/o6M", 
		"answer": "yuXoOMFr2HXR+IW0x2VCQ8qAStPc", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxbp8pYzEhH0hen3MCvUCnEBpm2QU680f3ejQK/HLsnsyIF4I1WIgxto4nPHqKDi5BMGnOhe+pqWfSMXe48v3N/J3+XhwTFSJ8dWjoV2pJsNc+FOyH3+JJiLcK4u7E3AJkv0JzqyCmR9miTTjjxDppey+WfvBIpngDcR1rNw5Nt8NcTf26mA7Un4iQjC0HKfT6htAkCQto6t/UqYpYw7sIHNpjrS9/y5ie3U99sYdhsSq45+dxuon61J3Dg5R8GwYRNFsejRb1P4IS+mNE4Z8N3mxGdgwIssWSk74hpUwoIWbs990dj0uSA5MMkqGjX6t01NwqhyYxmifLj41Wn27Fw6Zm5rboRiqyN1hR2dPl16k2qSDCBQmod+/9cchkRib2oAmnn1jDvLiWvPaJvmq6nygf3j4I9i/q8iMAGjPErRWoQGZKfJKGk+iv6TBKVUc5lrGDf0NMYm+T25JoSb0nkMwtY1IXOnp3nJwo3hNiXr6sKpzvZVMf8oOcbA/86l/BzTaSahBW+ScMLwUAn+D3D53Qlwth8g22ER+meYHIFw4CoFij6kRgRskzHlLHOzn7lV5IOaeopx2vus3HICnfNxkJW3wBU9U0Synj9NvZPfX11d2RTZGI0u1gggTLsTVKbQ+WSFgXfeCb5pRxydls8ByzC0TEDeUcM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "30,000,20", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090128", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+xA3/9olgUBHg1/LoPGXXQ20X42iMQKdnMHPmQLDHa+O+zZ53IVmbiFVvsnrHraLl9lQKz69J5puPY2IKcMtGxtSA1qT1wXZAPYZFicB05YhffvVDx32sZ5TkH8FR8VG/Z1H5ajyuRkXnNTyLVU64la8j19kZYmg=", 
		"answer": "24O9bJjwk9N49K2nBwT5X+N+O4c2YaY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+xA3/9olgUBHg1/LoPGXXQ20X42iMQKdnMHPmQLDHa+O+zZ53IVmbiFVvsnrHraLl9lQKz69J5puPY2IKcMtGxtSA1qT1wXZAPYZFicB05YhffvVDx32sZ5TtJfpnzS6wIlf5aD39RER8nSKWg28Wqoa49DKoUZojyBByv4l85MkyfMSK26uc5lmxiAOMyDuZSa4kE1Gcu46pq0COr5Erp8KMtSGb+/K5me3f5MsZZxsSuYltI1i5mbwc6iM9QoT0aRxPsfTVbkThJWilNQEQuc/q0HJs1IcnSSk34RNSl5FTcYB7147h/DE/MsgqHD2urARDyJpoXhSCNKqxxGCk5VQ8fTokcYJorm00rwvcLUx9kmqSSylV1Ilv+9EK1QVteS9Xk2TkkQOFtmCLdZCj24XujOf04PFi4KwyJ0XAZAmIBv5JNeOABURXg7PbOa5Zc6liEyvlfcEr5C3qYIWc0C5N1c8pK3Lp9y/Zncu1NWq7vYX2nNBlVL4OMpHM5827pVnJYibyYXuBaca0Vhz4Sm643w9rsA0kzyQDqGPWDMl84CEZi2y1WggkgTLna3mygrdS7cKad48lk/nl0zUFkedslpi30QU/TwW1inoDpYWMD11D31HXGtRHywotGaYTHZjWsmmDh3/eTDwZd8flQbiC0SVH3qH02J/0wbGcYc5HacmWmIMA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ve,dic,icc", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090129", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH2Bvv44ptcAvgyPzxdWfRDWUEoniGEqV1fXjvTefAa+Hxx5BiZ0iGzU9z9zbKorf38kFPsJdk1rGgT2IPf4Vo3dGO0qTxxXxIP98G8gT0XCTyNYi8aZZkyrNodg==", 
		"answer": "24axZp6+5RDo8pEhXFzqctXeR9b3GGwG7GULwxO6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH2Bvv44ptcAvgyPzxdWfRDWUEoniGEqV1fXjvTefAa+Hxx5BiZ0iGzU9z9zb1qqv/umcGja1P6IDffCMNeZ5uz9XJ0eX6zX1Yc/JMn8BB7ZQQMcBJzji5ddqbLP9gyXuBIECwYTiwDXxt1DjFymhercOo8CS0Wt53zBQgkYJr+YgwPdmYzKmU7Q2+hwuL0GLRQbMkBVyc9dmn+U+Y7MIvvNmF8T3N8ea5zqiDsNIKbA9HvoF6cBuvh6cC/SR4U9H0ZwRO46SBNBTvKSSvLgETudvm2WRlw8IASSk9519VkoxdZ84z35akmTMjK41LBjq77wRzyIFoV1e3Z7S5nCjl7lF/RnU+cYJovT4h4S6PIVU8Wjl4VMyip+/EDQLZXCsevA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Si,no-Ti,be,ta,n", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090130", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl70yu/ydWTWQ0YDommKVqp1fjHwRKLHbeWyiahOGGO2smQ7+2WGparl+VdPhqYb/YaaMCwMbJ9nhceMxPDy1n8BI8dWjsB94toLdPEA5TOpfdXVYO17zG2PKVH5aTyzEDLxaR5B85e1FCxKhD6KYQP+", 
		"answer": "25eqaZnm2FvUxjfMBFSpc3Euydcfcmd5", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl70yu/ydWTWQ0YDommKVqp1fjHwRKLHbeW+z5hkKVjJhFU75n7D46v/5UcHwr9e+pqaYixDbop93JCG0aTjzHQBGshAk4F8pIkKfvdPwimketHVNL5n3S6iNUT4cjD9LWQ0nSKWizxyuoKt/COyVdR3zBQ8kZJ56s18L8eQ0q2dqE+hxgeA026FCO8kHF2Vucen5QOMpY0oucjB8T/U5+D1g7ja/p47YwNbrJJ+bRuehakB7SN4WNv0fBpOsevebU2tBDqiMQcZ8MrtlnhoyIU8XG4xtAxWjYhTbIB8w4z3tTY1f8JsVRq0p01BhbX7KZce+JKooNrsZ3bsfU0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Br,ah,ui", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090131", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh0Brj9olgVhfkzO72OmWQDmMVpj+KXONgeHSjWq7Ma/n7zJllLxyKiFVv52Tf46bx41YIgLpS84ubMDIGcZtjzZCA2fD4hHdOJtQEn5R66pMcPPNSwyi9Z46bDvtp3GeUKAmwRiyuEGJ1mD7fjjAWhYy18ii3W9MzjFUzmIM40vcDA+ig5uriO17xg9PwzUhsNm0dgmcP", 
		"answer": "25a5fZLywhbj88eW5XRzQ41HlEYLKVF6I9se", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh0Brj9olgVhfkzO72OmWQDmMVpj+KXONgeHSjWq7Ma/n7zJllLxyKiFVv52Tf46zjt1gBgL9VqY+MMDYLe8tMycWK1vf+xX8BAcdHn8BG7J8Qbu0A5SntfcebIb5gwXnNI0zjZCu4AHlgkTWWnnRTp5GitTOzVc53xBwkn4N96YgsOdiP1a3T4UOsiUaE026DCLBlGFrZp8+r4kKQ4IUqutidomjn+sj3tP3U4tcfbUhCuolvb178lroMuCM2VcGzbRxE5PeQcVHiMCSmNE4S/4vQ2WF9zocoTn101QxPg8NXbMQz+ZvhvTw5PoEqFju7sUVD05FuVg2TcP26ySjg4Uc0NWkgbIQh/D49rh2IaEdqm3+JXikd1IFl+pAfhw15Z3YAlHfpkAOFoXCcaIHi54/1gajgpbZz/qZnKFOFdVXWUoQbYL3PMnQy2uyUHapZIN9oEWLHKMY67jj1KZfU3jcJkPclODfA4SOXl8y5eWaysoD4jcBzBrYaM9WF69L3tF3VamPyKnSdKov3TBr8Vjzw0gd3+1gkxiVQ6nDXCY0/+yIem22MR2lrnCDvYHOokv5M742ec4tx0ufpnTsenP1/mpX4wQ58VwG0nXNGocSQSRxqzEfCXuwUzQhiTIcOAYLZ92yFgTbxWHUMM473D6zH1yRNmsL8i3N0vJEdGcyNJBjJi90yzQW4G/h9FWX06J/8MfAaHSQ/8bt/hq2yo9i6fPSsOCUibhOlFa9Y/ZERbRJyEgrTESxGY/ioWZEaUtxB8XTflAZbTn5HRUrJ9LgEWESruMGIZ2TaarYZABH3cPMVFsHoQkLcdf6viBXcFLCMkAv+cUs3WjLdALYf7ATxNszzKhfzpG137YHEIVhaCMMUNCbhdWitoLGKEQM+Py48aJ1Pc1PQCwMvnTCPZ+pzn6YJdxA5Aae1WUcXgAgPlz/bHBQFsUIaH6usUkEoPelLL0gU3nXMobWHKiwFfnLnmSCHvebV", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ca,uc,asoid", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090132", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUMWw3mhay/ImLECyI9qmyXEvE2TCxPeoofWDpCjEeFkQPDEA==", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh3lTL5IwhRhfxhbC/G27XEWsFrDPDZqp2dWXsGYXXfOD/x9c8Z3GGg1x0/nnPp+mw00EOmaFf4I+RMG9DX5583MKI2+v+wD0BGshAlc1T9oMecrQNjB6sYdfaM/Fnyizk3oBhU3AbJbVPbgdxwtKE", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1B74/pEvEhvmzfP2NivXEW0Esz+KQeN1Y2LsV67Deuj6iYB4M1TJmVN+slfTsLHi+B4unKFa/YecMC4CcIx6ydeMl+L2yXhNKvpKt49845UTc/1EjDi5fNrSI75p3GGVNwX5dHmxDX5/kTWWnXVCoMOv/SL7YNM1xQE926Vt/8U9MpeT2KaU/Uy/g0aE3XaYRKRYH3eYoM2p+EyVpMI9ocWDuDGb8+b2j+iT8c1LcRhXvo16cUj8mK5J+iUsWYiQehNd+ODZYFqtISanZycT/cSu92Zwx4xpUWg68wpHhYZFXs5H3p2knScjK99rGTyzpwRF05xyVhTWc6+3xXiooEE3em8sbcpjszl1pBeMJF19k3+QVWxckY5/998XkAAvPWxBkjbih3+CjmOKboHm78D9lqjzr7dt96AzLEXAIVOYQoUZJZfSJnF7zuCaA+ZQMpFgAiPhOJUo/TTwLI/Yny4F2doob370tDqLl9v0NWC0p9LwgJRlG6oUPpHs58++sRzGbyehL3KBcsO5XAnjW3nq3U5WpRFl5CAe42OaU/wMJZ01pk1BIFmOULUNcQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Austro-Asiatic,Negrito", 
		"option_b": "Tibeto-Burman,Mongoloid", 
		"option_c": "Dravidian,Australoid", 
		"option_d": "Indo-Aryan,Caucasoid", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090133", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUMWw3mhay/ImLECyI9qmyXEvE2TCxPeoofWDpCjEeFkQPDEA==", 
		"answer": "25K9ZpTn2Bqq4YwlRV6/hdD2MW/cBiI0omyXEqJmf2TtUOeRPr2umddoIl2bnht69XmK44n5+VQahrtP4I3fZisGacsiiPWF1um3xWNOJshA2tYitMpfZfFB3i7tddPUbL5K3G+WLkH5Zjf9F2BxlTrTmG8R6I6y8jW6QNM4zlV/1rR3+Nw0fP6R3aGSqFuxh0ay3XCYW6llHxSYp8uppwO1roY3+OiYoz3L8fX32v7S/dcHe0hftoFtYk+1mKZJtWobVMagehNHscXDaFWtNCfjFAEI7cPm12d9hqM6VGh2rGC2e9hxtCjRXRTOamYT6A==", 
		"explanation": "25K9ZpTn2Bqq4YwlRV6/4dPedXjEFmYYpmzDQbZzd3TwQOfWZuzqiYd0KEyFiBt2/WDDp+Xk/0EAmq9TqZqXdWIud49rxNXJ8uXk0DFAMclRjsAhtNZPLKQA1TisZsebIflhjmyFIUriYnmuFGJxlTXfhHsWvIz71DSyVZo2zhFys5Jq4tg5fOOX0LvT4Um9h0aLzzuQRK5rUUeMpd6n+VeZpMI6rI2ZuTvV8+e5lvHY9Z4EbgwSq4lwb0j8lqYNuCg3X82nKBRE5OrUIV3jYDyrIk4a68T22HBVyK4gU24h/QxSi4AWdMl2wdipjz09Oo16EDyqr0EA05x1URzWeLy2133l51AsNWk7aoFosm08r0+vJ0Fqkiu1QihYlcBm99cRgURrfHlF3HrpjDSYwHGAPJLt6In5i/ywrLht9bYmLkSTdVrKWYBcZPPQK2Zxz6mYDKpQNpsnMi7nMJlu6zHwI57U1ipN3tY3b2fm5j7Zncu1EHe7vdLNht1lVLcFOsHWqd6k8EnJZSbzMmmSaM+0UQfnD3D53Qlwth8g22ET4GPWD4w/+jsIjD6kQElhrinEfn23n7pV64zObJ400v7pzyFX2PlxmIn2wBQzSUT2zU9GvZSTShxYxVuWDd0CxQJuKKYAAp/V+2yY1XrRRXsYfsnzEuiG0SkIzuv+m2Z1q9AaWsyGLQ/eytMp3hK1Qel2FVTivZLxfdUbDm0turRjxeDho8K+Nf2rPnEieB+kTa9t+5BIKA5yGg7RHGRfYau9U5leVehd3WDNn0dcT3oJBEjJ+ugcVQW+6s3bLmTRdPEsDxXrcKcEHY7MRk7cdfitzTGJD6zcl0atWkBlQTTdNbgE6wDjOoD7LxbzgGFp8M3kIBFMS5ETL2fyem/5qq+HSwcoayUjKYlTaXvbYh4gm3PmMutonaIBflgrQKWuFUlWmxhIjT/GB1dL8AEuWqq9TFZnPaFKYEgBwjywUYkRWBOHoy8YgUaZwyysJftFNlwifGGAz1zylJBnnfPwwp2VC8b2KLlb24NDC7NVUIjXExs9ifrlr+DuFSwtDmh5bvXHSOfV8Fv5Qsz9pMXf11lF3f4YOl44ICrLhZbS9XpIOrdAf3UKvH0d7PnddxKi3IlKwRBJQ1zttXXsSHRhtxd1a5D/b9mcPpOgsFxeGCPSVr5Gi7x50yikIt7Id1owASM5mAGVNtvEhyCLMr/+gKwbABmxlZ1gvNwf3hNgJM9w/2hHAuA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Genetic view,Middle East around 30000 years ago", 
		"option_b": "Linguistic view,Elam around 6000 years ago", 
		"option_c": "Dravidian speakers' migration,South India via Pakistan area", 
		"option_d": "Indo-European family migration,Central Asia to Southeast Asia", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090134", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUMUxD10Pz4MCv/EWsWqnGQGq99Y2WjBe6CeeTqwddUJk6FlBtJ93XJsaHjtxsDhrtPqdzWMlFPKhJH4S1B3Xjcdb0lsIM=", 
		"answer": "25GqaYf61RDr+cUsUxD10Pz4MCudQ00DqniKXON9fjHGWKbPLq3txoJlLxyeiEhv92TI44zi9l1Dz4FV7YHfUTAaf4UvxNGH0PH2w3QBfoZ3ioVx7ZcacrRGwyijcJTSLr5Uy2CEZ2TmYiqpBTw0oDjUj2hZ6KGu5yq6Wpo7wRs1g4Z/6IhxfOWa2qeB7Ei8xgSbnFiZWrR3BV2Yu46l4lCPqY02tN+EtCGb/fq5jvDWsNACbA1GuoNxd1P8lK0H7D8qSIT0SQdY5fbfIXX+KSm3Lg1d9crt0WFowYdpECkZ/RhUg5dfbc4z0IrrsXIdNsluGTb6hkVT09R9TRiDern4gzi0sAV/bH8qd5ktvSo64+Meyb5N1/ODZYp9eFf/GYE=", 
		"explanation": "25GqaYf61RDr+cUsUxD10Pz4MCudQ1EernrDQqZ7YH3mFLPKZ+P1iYN5Ihytn1pt+3LPoquw+1IBiL1a7ouMPGIOf4JhxMnJxPT4z3RPc89K2rN98Y4XPN1OyDSsOJTWKflm2i6IJlP1JyqpBWJgkTWWg3IWqcOr+Sa4UZo0wRk+k4M4yMQ9MZvfzqCa60X4jxXC0nSGCLRqUX2LtMCU5WqSpI11lN+UsDyb+PX3ne3S99tLLzxausZFZlW414kf/TksUIT0aRwL/ujUIVbiLyPvZwYc6ovw2Xlsho0vHX088V9Ai5FFdoB2zpnprD41LI1lE3OTrUBPirVuRhaYNLG53m/x4VI6ZjoCccpluSElsk+JOxRrlG+ZXj9FlY5vvtgWgkR3dWZT3HrhjDiegWKKPITi+MDplu304LVs/KRnKEaPCVLsX48ZcbyNBXJgx+iVTapdPZhyFiXjfZhu3zHrKYWA1jgDkNQpPGTu+ySYgMTwKiWtoZ3ti5RyG6gOdsLK5M73v1qHdSvkYUmaZM7gVkXSWm710gAluxkrzzQR72fLSIBxtTkFmz7hERQ0gWfUZHWy1rZZ5pKLe84h1vr80TdQlPF5jZW32RIuQkS6j3BWpsSLR1lcyBTaH8MA0QgpCac9GrfE4XmEmjvxWHUMa8f1QaSGzStd2+T0ziw9jJ8DUMyMKRXSj8gjiAO5AOk5dHL+vJT2cN0GA2U487ExxuyvsN+6cva3bGYlehazGedY5ZARaw12FEvbFytCIKirWY0SRKBY2nqKmgheQnsJA0jD9ugcVQHqh83MambbI5QdHQqiYrEKBtq4HReDZaH5iCnMB62P1Ua5UAQRRjOOYbkJ4Aawc5+yKhyn039t/cTpKxFaR4ASLDP2cCf5sauMHgEyPYP9RXtLzSnY7Vmo9CWHp7Q=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Dravidian language,Origin in Elam south western Iran", 
		"option_b": "Indo Aryan language,Specimen found in Zend Avesta", 
		"option_c": "Tibeto Burman language,Recorded by Christian missionaries in the nineteenth century", 
		"option_d": "Austro Asiatic language,Migration from Middle East around 30000 years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090135", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJgVp19WPHpKCw8VIChqRS7J3feSxDV4VrwdHJ3ve3x35TIcNHjtpO6qYRLcBIyX2MYcfPMvdtjmKBKULlZj64RHZ1mTjakzxeqZD74TC0FMkiwhMzm4505M0vZpe+zLuH+kS7yyeR1XqFQb4kEFqd9e+9+FeOr4w9psSMvw7VyPqr2tXc/pMgagVXrcZtZkuukrsM9j4rEdy8bVJg+eXDaBThISakMg8a/Ivwxntiw4xpVGd04BdDwqheY9N6lpnquHIaPsN+HDL6q01My4c8VhnWWbi/2Gno4Uw+SXQXa9ktiCUw4TuVKlFqlSa+WT5clY4r8tEXkhFiemoAmnftizOSwGycPIPx4o39l+H8uflw4qwsLE/APFKYd5gPcaHBK25ziuiVCeZvPIpzHyfnLsFu3SrwIdQQNJirdaNeFY9sXsp2sjuM", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YwjEhLzy/rqNGzVQ2QQrnaPS+N8cWKjQLDNLv7ry5FwKlWFhF5osnfIp+Xk/1Ibz4VU58O0eC8GbMt9zcCb0vfyymVSc9JMn8BZ7JsMdbRMzTOqYdXcJb5H2i6EKEDjJzeyEDB5kT/Cg3NY6IK17DOzXdQwgBQwmZJsrdw0OZer0KqW/EL1pBOQ0XqfCLFlH1OMtMmtq0WdrYs0rI2PtDvV87TqivfY9dBLawYSnpNsd0m9m6EIuCs2VYiHZwdf+eHRckCtATuqJkyP7HgdzD0GqgsxPe5ThOxf", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090136", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd9JlKOmFp89zbAoqj5+1oKnOhS5862fiYKf8tm25CK2PblwXJVafpKpo4jpK4XebR0xT+oYNuWAut8w2+OZ0nxaT6oBXdx1DfXh3VascOz9DT7WdUlxVUhhoJ55s0uL5eW1+iH4Ej4rwiG1XqfCK5xE1eWu9qh5UaStMIsvcyD8SbT8bTYj+vH4tcIIg5Tso9zemeyq6ZbuB4wVIiQehNd+ODZYFqtLCmtIBsc/s6j0HVkz44wHWYm/RhPjIJCZ8Qz35akqDo1f8NlByey7lNF1IB5TRnWZLyqxCjr5hUrfX9rTIRptSw74RyJKldxlH+VQilfgLxlwt5K1S1teWANvWT5gzHLjGSBe4bi7IXvxenipflz4KoqKFOJOUWYRZ0TbrbOZ258iuqeA7JOMpMnPiziNNRs6LQ0KfIiYL/dKuxtQVBuWg==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH2Bvv44ptcAvgyPzxdW3RDmsduj+LU7A0fX7xUefRfuj/wpJjNBydhVp1smLOpuXR4kAbnaFYqYiefSsPZ8tuxtTJw+z20DFVO8MEs45269c+bu1Bwn2hddrcNf9py33AJlf1JyqtC3txmnHfhDxYp5Gv/We6Wt53wxA8gpV54YgVMtOW2Oi6/A28iQORnHWeXP1pFFqNvMGmq1eUpcIcp8ybuDbS9fq5lvnd98sKZQ0SuYdyalel16cb8S0xX8mgYRxMse3eIUDlJWitKBwJ8Yb002d9w5AnHXk15gsE4/sG4VQpe/sRHNulchARqg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090137", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJgVp19WPHpKCw81YZiqRU+YOafjZDd4Uv4d6N3uW3zWIBMMlWiIVx8MAjcshOnX2Pe8DTYOpmyy6hMlbkdTC+RHF6kHHig35TvIz21zKpWds5gBM9hIprrcc6fMSP3K2Q4A2whxCHnH+UXrhoHkScsY6k4leZsoMsoN+I8T3N8ea5jvHe9eIFXgYA/6JtYk21k6EI9mo0UMazfRNM9PeQbkbkJyGtJhoY/YvlxHtkhqclXGR4tBNJgYJCZ8Qz35aksj0iK8UnEDKptwRpyZB1XiuYSLPrkFzs5RUQeX5rTIRps2AUsxadJhR9lX2ZXj8Rl4xq7cMQlgVvPVxBkmXrkDafwpDJA63jLrUmgHbLYlEhYFU=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "25u3KJ36xRz49pE1QBuywfjpMGffE2cV43aNErd8dTHCQbTWfOT9iZZ/Ixy9hFl+5nmLgbDi+lIBz65U+4OMMC0FPph/zdWK36Te0DFAP9VL2oVq9JYedfpTjCmlcZTUMvdpx2DAKEOwQyu8EnlwnTDYynBXpoSu9CC+R5ox0ho/1qJ07MV8Pdmbmbyb7Q27iRCHznqWTf1rFxSauc+7+EqfoY54hsyDojnJ/eC5k/aT5NYOIideu8ZWbV+z2okb4Ss2E9XwyVBVvU0G64e8MLJigdw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090138", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJgVp19WPHpKCw/l0birpa6pqWfyxDd4Uv4d6N3uW3zWIBMMlWiIVx8MAjcshOnX2ZfNGbMOxhzWuTNAX/YXmxDX5zgTjFnnVV6Iq14SKpVdkjyRo81oV9+d85Odnf3aGV7kiqgwiWnHyDR6h0AhSbsMmp5QOYtZAxu8rNpTretPn8nvHW5t8HIhxbsoNsX1WAmfpJzCI9EeG6bB0G0PbJYFqtLCmtIBsc/s6j0ntkz4woU2oxtBNDhsNCbYBn3p2kuSozM9h5HCW/41FTwtRzWVeCfLixwijo4Vs4YHssYMpksm0hswaeKVg+m3mZTT9tmrxlrZAtnQEjcHpUiXfswj2EkneAa5rt7MDzg6jnr6tn4eMlLFWXMFnWFokVY7XFNWJ83qmXDKhbJp5gEmLhL9o77Cq5N5eHnzUE3dA0KnOn4CXZu8PxNiiboYv4gJR3GrtAEsPE/8KzuV3JIS/gL3qGZ8zxSkqoD+m4KDVPSutG9Hb4Jx/G", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxbp8pYzEhH0hfH2O2zFCnEFqnzDW61gdWPiV7PLYeO+y5J2JlLJiU5p+3jB45P181oMz7xS5IuMMCMNest7wNXJ2vHj0XBNc8RLiJJ985MRe7RPyn26e8bfM75r1nqFKUH1Y3m/AWl7mjWWgGlFvMOS+yO0Gfsl2RQ81oZ26YgYLtaJ0Kya6UP4igeM226QT7h3U9UARMIsV5qio+QCd3DIMrk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090139", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVR42yXU7dxfXTtQLSCb+/x3IMxK12Hik569XOGpaT9/l8Girsb6ICbMDYLe4J9iNSAxPDlzXNUJ89LlMB799occ+ZSyT65LujVHPA/gE+VNFHiaDe4F3l1mnHai3JRvYK88DT7VcgygAYimYx944g1Mpe+zLuH+ky0jwfC3XWVCI5rBECRsM+7/wO9s4s5icOxv2CV2fv319Pb/dsZIhpXr5R6cF6yg7tJ7CI9EeO8aQFCsejRb1P4IS+mZx0N9sDm2DRgyMI9VWx02hZFjYFXcIBaxZTlsjYjA8NWG2D0l0xFh5l9VRiEfamhkGfioHwxcXVmRJh0vSN1rQ6SL0F/nW6PDC1DkcB47t8SkAojdGEAiH7lwjGEknGHMZbi+JT5l+aws61i5qY0aU6GdXXWUoQdJyu/EpvnDtqydY5s5ed/Mj8=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "25Ste4Xh3hfv5IwhXF7+xPP4IGrXBnFRom2GErBkf3rmWufLYK3f3IRlNV2FhFo783jC45b/4kcHiqlI/c6+YysCMstuxtTJ+uv5iVpJPsNW2pJ39Igab/FO2C7tYNzeYNVmz32JZ0nxaT6oBXdx1AXejzxCoIqp8WeoQNsjxRg3mJM45Nt8Ndmc1rqB7U6sxgeRnHaeW6kkOFqduoOJ+VqdrsI0tMOKpDPc8ee5m+rWsM0bbQNXscZ2bRuymLod8Go5X8z0axdF5fbRbRTELiyqJkwzI84Kody+tsaI3lwE/eOh", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090140", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd9JlKOmFp89zbJsaz3/l0cz6FVqaeRdCsCPoJ8iNOGxfbyx2UbD8h4lNEy0JIaPPtSxTqkepTUJr56xmvAA1fxcTC5DXF61D3XhHtDqYS+tS6oFNsj1Ac7lJJs6Mx8KNjfzaCWqGCxggKO2Tu0Sa5wLVqlu5zo30qepZY3+O+Yoz/a+rTqiv3W89ZLaxsSr5R6dVqwkqYduCM2Edy8bVJj+OnRbVX0ITvjIRwS9IvCxWdoy8I9UikE4RFMg4FqbPx9hdjNsjY/cux4DDK040hByZNpXhCTZ/2owmHp4Uc2eWNrYY97uSE6sQqYaFJslWbcbTxQloh5/90KnQUjdGEAkXPkizqdgWnPaJru7pO+KYeyswn5SeDnzW0RSDkpoQ==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH8wxDt/otgXRiy0fX6dU/CAnQYp3aCXON4cX/kQabFa6332tdwM0ibhFlu5nPC47H/t3YDjqUb4IDfYy0WaoMi39Waw+HlyjFoIcdK2rR64doNeedUjDKrNMDTJb592m+UIkj1aS2uRHFmkXHXiX9DuoKv8GUZu7a4JdgQnn5DYt6DYRgm", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090141", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd9JlKOmFp89zbAoqj5+1oKnOha54rfZCoGd5kvzNmaw/b+xmRVOslK2olhpJkQbuZFzyn3SNrnLq8u43uOI0SwZje5RF17mnz9gnFTusO65yL7R881xhQ/n4tx6Nt8M9HfzaCWqGytlRKQ1Xjcaa5tEECQto6k6k2btYM/sI2LsD/S+O3FlMTdop4/awpXq4kyQU6umqkHuDkoVM23YFJC4qTAc1H7ISSmKRpd8MWjwnxshpEmSH088Q1IwpBCY9R2xdjrunIZMcljFA+0n0oTh7BuXgGfcLS53ijo4Vs4YHssYJktvT8w4R+OIVl/iGKQVWxChI9g+95ZnAojc2BSiH6thz6YlGCdctPQ+Ym8qen+q7ghUD9MUEilh+1oIDWzMOLFRA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZd436QEq5xfmXqW6nHaq33x9dlL1nJnVpo4XfBpuXD41IbiqVe55rfImIKbctmxtOGxfbyx2UNc8dX2rR75p8Lc7li2S+gddqbM+5ry22IZ0DoczyzAGM0lT3ZhHsWvIu+tQ+yWds7wQwzhcd+/8cxfNmQy7ybpUi5lRKHznXRaa53EFnZocHo5UyOtIp1sMyepXLr4frzm/qTw8oKdg1fuohrIwj8nrtJ8SQ7XtqmbRFfvaTRchTJMim1LgoU+MWj2nVnwZcoWmwntB5Uh8NGcMVl15ThsiZwNsMqBjyvt0wA7pp4VhbUiuYQW8Lckzn4AS3SpFx/cQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090142", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3dd9JlKOmFp89zbPrbH15VIMm6FU553feSxDV4VrwdHJ3ve3x35TIcNHjtpO6qYRLbRpwjmiOfXJOf9gjmKBKULlZj64FzBngSHTmG9TrIa/tSq6WsN31Ac7lIZ0rcQ9MtCK2K+W+w28kwPCyHTRW7JnGFvUsM2n5UyRqYF4scKAuDza+vf8pvbv/oxLVgBX/4tqd069m+gL9zgqXt+9ZhUL/uKQdlv/JDvjJQsJ7s7m2DRAyIYmEEgm7R5IwoJYZoBXxJnytTY5PsMqGTK0pFFBwJFvHxWTc7y2kGHqoFg6cXMuc4th/Dk8rAqPFFpClDjceCRU1KF+7cQLnAcjcW5Om2PhhTrLhmSCdZ/6q4nvxfz4pflu/bAzaUWPOFXWV4MIJb/BKWBny+6eTaBdPpZrDmLvM5UH8j3wIdSWHkwKdTQVcffQ6VVlhq3G", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfz8Nn7CAnYU7z+CQeN5dX/3XajMa+m+wJkxM1SMzUt64WXHpKCwxEcOm61W7ICLMHBDd5gvydya2KT0y2NTNsVQ1sBz99oLdPEA3Dy+Z9XcJb5qx32DMlbjYir9EHhx1DzDnmlXpMO5+jWpW80+zhJymYE4+scuOMTf262H/0i9iEaW1H6CTf1oEFqeoM+v7gOaoY8xucSIonLo4PXtn/XW/spLMUhbrMZ2bVizhboM+z50EcmnKAZD9KTAYEf+IS+mZwoS/NjtkWAp1ZYoSWx04BdHlsNCasUz9433qCA5PI1sFD6zr10Azoc8Sx+TNLC3w3yk5FoyfHQqa542/CQ74QmdK0Ay2mKIDChYh4N+7cMchkRsaWdFjjbsgzGMlWSIedPl6o31ieH1s/l3/axl/X/Q51/E0OMluu0T96WzuA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090143", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdzqJn/CCmFRr36NVbZ1d3SjUqbPZ+HniZ5/JFCciV5osmLOpuXj4lEJjqVS5YeaY2Iia5h72tmKmsXkzXBVOsUEm452pLsKb+BSwzOoZ93aLrIu2WeULwXRciqpFnl32RDFg31CoYD79yKyWt130wU9nYJ2rcEyfMOX3Oi65kmxhwjCz26TS7JqBV2XsMC8102grrA9tN6Cv2ibwPz82tnG48oZawsfnpV2Yk+1lOga7Sg+UMW9ZAsL8uvecl3+NDvjKAhd7dzslnZ7x4wqVWwnuF9Ig45Tbtkz+43quDNwPsNuVR61rQlrz5l5TVvWY7Ss2Cjo4Vs4YHssYJktsCQ+pE+3IFVtkyudQigRuZVl+tELnERheGZOmzbwgy2fwGqJPIfr4pO8lv3yprhu+68+ayCqFVT7niOWlRTvJk85ATY=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+HV7B3YnjhUbSCeuX7ibZkNEibhFg7/nfIpLDx8FZPialW4IKGMCMNestm3MPJxPH1wnBMOspNn5My0JIaPOZFzS6iepTLMvF4x2qFNAXxYz20EHl7mjDaynVYroyp+CavXdU5gBQwmZJsrdw0OZeLzqfT6l+5iAWK2WjRR7skBVyc9e+9+FeOqYF1lN6EsCbS97Tqj/rV8dMCbhEe/5F3ali016EH+yYtVc2nKB5K/+PFYFPoM2ivLgUYueDr12dghoMnWSkZ4RFCg5FfIET+sYKE3UPZthR3nv1sFGs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090144", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfD2MnnRF2serT+MVONgeHSjcLXDeOT6wJZ/ak+ZiFpw+3jB47X1+EMDiuhP5s62fiYKf8tm25CIl/fixntEMNIElYYy4J8dfeBFjD+oYMPeJfAu2maFZ0L1aTypDXM0lT/SynBfpoSu/DSvXdl31hw3gZd35MYoL+uR5aah7UyriQjYnE+ZTf1jFFqcocerq1WVpZUousSDpXLL5vvplevW454faglG/5J3Zhu6nroa7Go1UMK7elJG+OPCYEDkLybjLgAJ9ovK2HBgx8ImXmoh5g1DhsNXcM9m2Jyk72J8b506VSq/olZTh5V7UFeQZrK1kHzs5RUSfH4vaY8tmSwmtUPcP1x3lm7cWCRU1Ixi8NcMnBd3dGwAin/llS+EiWubPID27If5lvzj4K1r87dnPUmFdXjKV5sVYbrBKXQyx+CcH6dINpsnETDpMJUL8Dj0YJeG0CwD1Jl2fye3tDOck9/meWS9vNCfK5odqtgxa1ll0lc+HwC3", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzfT4PWfZBGoFsD+XWqY0dHThVbPHLu/73YB0IlLJmVN+snHDraDk/lBPjqZfqYKWfiUWd5h7wdPJwe3y02FOOshQicBg4Z0ebvBJwjrtYNzeYPNnyXyBM0z/aXmyAjBQhjDAg3hfqY325je+VdE+zhJyhoJ3/cQ5fMOQmYGd7ES5xjKK2TuDTbx3HlrZpdyn/UqYpZF4tsKDpTfD4LT/leqT5NYOIh5bupFvbFKyg7tFuC8gQcS1YRxC/+OQdVzoYDyqKgcT/ovi2HApyZAgWmA6519JhMNCasVg09j0rj0gMN5vEXO3qkNSxoB1UBmFNsJCyScayFxeRRCs7rDHj7s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090145", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdDwOyb7C28UsT+BQKJ6c3mjW6GCeuX7ibZkNEibhFg202XPorH59BMcmqpd6IOWfDtDd4VsxMWN0ve30HlEc+1Mm5N7pJYecvNVzTqoNMfLL/VrwC6JKQXdYj61BXx1jTCaylVYrIq6ySmHWugywQY9mN04wMcycfyX1K2BqEG5iAGX3XyUW/1lA1HZpdyt/UKQpYws9cSD8SbT8bTSkvnA+Z4KbAwSlYdxd1K916AA9CYrEcG6KD9O9uzRbVX0IWTjJh1d7s7v2jRo1cIgUykg/BoGrIpVbcJyxNjtrz4xMcl5V4pL2fk6BXFpnZst+bae3eE=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+KVqZ6ZHjlXaLRLvn2zNdcKFLEplN292SGobfx+VAHz6lV7c6WZDFDf5h8x9OA1vD+y38BJM9QksBm7J9fV/xB3zTteNXVJ+tvyWvAE031Jyu4BWN7mnHGmHNAoYe+5meoRN80yRM7lcdq6M81M9mMmb+b7V+9xiuN0ja6QLBhAxSVtMCv/kKbpZF4tN+I8SHL+//8lLST48sbcgdAq49xZBuon61J+TkrVNqgYR1Fs1fq6LweMDW6xhxhlgKFTpU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090146", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hcn2N27EDC8ztm2OU600fHDtU7LDaei+z5Z8LlCQzVN64TbH47b58F0GiaFY6ICLMCwWc4lq2pCG0aT7xX9GJsdDn5My94oQd/FOjDSjNPfTKfBvgi60Lkf1c3X9BX5w1BzPi3JbqZGH+xu1Zt820xo8zMdM5Mo5KNjS+72B5Uy2xgqD0nyESbphAhScrdqt5UfcoY43u8rNpTretNzwl/nf8ccKcUhUrYlyI1WzhbwB/SsrRc2mZlJq4vfRbBT5L2itKBwJ8c7ixWBs1IxpbXw6/h5EwopYItR709jNsjY5PsMqBia4oEtO051yWhmCNkvQHk/WqnVqS2T6BqaiQmg=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjJ1721ktgw/yfEcV3+ayWaI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxPP7dXnVAnEerT+CQKY0eX/nXbHLavj/xZtoZ1+Gn0l+8WKGi6rn8kUKneQb/oaWfCdDaoNqiOSA1eHjyzxjJtRJm44y4psSdfhZjDSjcNHeJL5mz33AK0T+YCy8A3Vn1CLGhXdTpsOy+2eYXNM5wVlyoo566NxwfNaR3ei+8Uy2iweQkDuFQLgkA1GYpsGmrFDcqYw+ut+AsCbS+/q5m/rc5cpLdgBX/4Nnd16yhKEG9mo5Xce6b1Jf+eGQSV3gISSiPg8OucLwlnpm0sItVHsx9wtKm8NEZ8xywp3g/CY/f9liEHO9pktH1ZVsVx6VdbH43Gfn4UE2enQ4JYdosjk8rgGZLBR3lCuIRCkRlZN4+8INnAttP1oFy2TjHGM9akWWYAbW96g=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090147", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdgzz0/T7PGreQ24QrXiWU6RxYzHiRqKCfv/7zZh8LlKIg087+3iGkKrl41tPpqZf4I/fcSwHPo533NWH06TjyzFPPNRQkoVz944abvoA/y+kNPjaLvVv8mC8KXf1ZiqyCio0tiPXgmlf5MOv/SL7UdslzBw3hZM468cuMZeQ3+i3+kyujwKL3XXRW61hFFeR+Y6h+AOar5c2sY2Ev3LP/PG5lPfB5NYOYxtGupRxI0u9hbxJ9yx4RcCxKDtF9e3RbxT+NSqgKAAJ8MXm2GArC8WWoJGOQsu/bU0VkTvpTA==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHxUabRYeO+wIQxIV2Fnl45oLDgcbBIQ1kx++Pbe7CGMA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+QRqJgdWKjQK/HLun32oNjLl6cmVJ0/DbJpeXU5VIZhqxS6IDffCMNeZ5uz9Wal8z403RXNtQI2pR64doNefVTwzPtfcebKfBtwXySIkbkPHmfFnF8gTiWg28WpoyvtSG0QdQzgBw81pNw6IgyM8WL0a2S+1m9lAjCzHqDXP1rFxSNvcvowk2YqYM29d6YszHU+uDwlP3d5IVLaxwStpU/YliogqkF9DN4V8ehZhYL+OqQdVzoYCasNRoV7s7wwnF7yMI5XHsguF9RiopVaoB6xdjtsnIAPsZjBie7rQZBT9+cTSETs1wm0c+4d43U", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090148", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gexD2yrDeJ3LRDSIdonGER6JzdWKjVbXHLv7uxpx0KRyLlBt6smXPpKv58VoMjqZPqYCKfSAGbMtgzpCZ0uvnyHQBMsVWlZNhpKoed/1T2DyjOJTyLvpnzyLABUT+YDW8AHVnnH2WuW5f6K+6+yy6GJo2zhFyuIJo7MQAMuuR662S+0K23Ea21H7RYbNgHhm4p9ep5QOQoYw/oMyKtHLc5vvsirjQ/9MbcAFBupU/d1Oukq1J6z86HMqmaRxI+eHDOxTELiysaicP+MXq13olhqYoT20991MGg41SIul90pepnSApPsMoraA/4wCPCACSYVN6cmpWzw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+HV7B3YnjhUbSCeuX7iYB4I1nJil509WTHs6359FIDz6xS+pqNeSAWaoJgxpCG0aTeynVOfudWg4F8pJYecvNVzTqoZ5TvKPsu3GuBNEr+Jz+oFmR8kSOWj3BXqoyp9DO+R5o4zlUmnoI4/t0+cdWN2KaQ4EirxhGLyHOYRv1wGVHZnMCs5A69sps5u42BsDzc4fX+n7jU4tEeckQSr5RwdVK4nqYOuCk3X9yxcAYL9+vCIUDlJWiiNB0Y69/q2XorSIXUA4PkK65rqIU8G3TCSQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090149", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfn2JnvVEXEYrHHDXaU0UWTwQLXLba3/x5MxE1WLiE90v1TTsajx+RMDjqZc/I+YdTFDaYp8iMCb3un21nhNKoZLiIF+qNoNeedVwCmketObKfAu2maFZ0TydDyzB3U0mzeWj31EpJr74jWyQM4yzlU+n5N9/8koKcWamaGdqFmwgxWHnHeQRrpxEFOcpvKm102upYMrusPX8QfV+P3yn7jH+NtLSwZWsMtecUK9megI9i54ddq1fhtP+OXeIVjsLi+2JgkY6oej92F60pAgXik1+hsGtopUZ9R8m7rxrj8xMY1mFD29tkVHwoc8UxaVf7i8kGmk80wsYX8mJYVr/DonqBuVJlMy2meZTShYmocr6t9ZlERvfGxL3HnmwjuOlmCDc4Pm78DwjPz1srh357Eia0QWzQTM7/8O77PqXkEz5Ss=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2pR64doeb+dF3imke9qZ7HqExfwy8rgs6bBMHujlqw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I43eKVat4eXbrQLSCeuX7iZZzNFmHjl47/XCGpqTi+0pPmLpS/ZqafmIPd59q2tGdwvbyhHhPc+dRiZRg7ZlfffpEjAmkdtHPL7NM23yNJkuwazizA2V1kzTFykhercOp8CaoW9R3wRYxg5V5+c0wJZeawbif6US2lUaW1HKCCLxmAlGXtsvo6VrcoZYsp8SPpCbS+vO5k+yT5NFLdgBX/4d9cF6ylK1J9yx4UIijehtf+OrXIUf0MzymKk4U94v33nF6w8IlXGcz4R5Bh8NRcM9mxoumF0X2kZfPB2ZdVzRYEx+ZQg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090150", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he3tOmjVEHFRrHnDXqp6d2TqR7PLba33x4N0NV2KmVJ0/DbHraGw9VwdnadM4ICYMCAGapxqzd7J0+3xwnRTNshQ2oxz6p0KffNFjDq/e8HLM75sy2mBKQX5aXm8CnN9kT/CylVYrIq6uWe6R5oy1hw2k4l76Mx8Ps7fzaCWqF2qgxWH0niUCLJiUXmMu8qpq0KSpMIcp8ybuDbS9fq5jffB9M1LawYSq456I2m1kOg//S45bcaIZiBO8Pffbw6tFCCmZwcT7c7x231nwY4gU250+xkGjopYZdV6xYztv3I3LcJ/BSD6sUFT0phoWhPWfbP43X3w9VQzNXgkd5hiqyQ7pk+TLhRplXmYX2ARkZN7+9MQlAhvZC9CmWL3hzqFwHGHedPK5YTzyMniubhtsq8mJ0aVNFvdFowSYfPWJnV7xfyITbJOOp1mG2LqPNsp6Tj+JYXWzGkkbIUjW5mOdWFR0txSQw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJn1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB94toLdPEAzS6+ccbPKfFgjJ1721ktgw/yfEcV3+ayWaI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+QRqJgdWKjQK/HLv3szIR0KV+MzVR9snrPraLl/kAbhqsb4ICLdTACfZ9mx97J1urzhHNOIdRLjYl849oWcrRBwj6kcdrPYNdgymeBZ23/cDyrAWI41CXejzxErYKo+in7XdQ0zwcgk4Rs4dF8PcOLy6GR/Vm9lUaW1H7RSrJ2A1uOvMCvq1OOqY85p8SBqHLP+7TQlPzcvf8Zewlc/4dxZxuohaEL+SZ4Xcm6bwdK9uHDLRT6KCGvIk4J8c6j12d6w5A9VGY6tBpIgYxbcsFgxZ33/DNwPd9lFDe/sQRSxpp7WleZcv2x3nzh8lQ8YXMka5ktvightgqZJhR6k22aST5UmpQr8tEXkhFiemoAm2Tvly+YwkwV/5p8eKGzfRGszRtY50Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "090151", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt8IBQAfzy7q/MW7eDHYUsD/LA/otKTihsKzp9AwnJucyhHGQmKwmag==", 
		"answer": "27T4e4H21Brit4IyXQvih0ODGUPMZliwJFRRx1FBBdE=", 
		"explanation": "25SqcZD9kRD5t4wuEhjzxum/NCvcCmwWtnaQRqp3MGXmRqqCZ+P6wJRwM1WHiht6smXWpqDz/xMInadO+c6QdmIqcI9ghfWcxevnwXBPc8lWk4d76tZfffpEjDS+NNrUNL5vwC6FM03+bjr9EHVmmXOtM+T+nRdzCYfmNvT3O1xT", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The linguistic Background >> Principal language to Etinic Groups and Language Families", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "an ethnic group", 
		"option_b": "a nomadic people", 
		"option_c": "a speech group", 
		"option_d": "a superior race", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100101", 
		"question": "2523f9H83R2q/pZgRhb3hdj+J3/YXCAjucENLFZ7HYetMUXV61pE", 
		"answer": "2+HuOMGz3BDm+4wvXF7rwPztJilbd/MvXv1iC9RPU1yQPvMO", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Av+/8UpQV7zx/LqISuEVjZRoXaPXqp7fjH6UabQfa3xxZMxE1SAnhty4TbEorb18xMAgehP4YvfYiMHd4RizcSb3ue3wHBVOshD2o90pJcaaPFP3jS5cceXYOlmx22IZ0TiYnmpDH9hkznCymhZ6Iu64yL7UtUlzRA21oZsrdw0OZeM2KWWqFmxiwPC3WjRXLVhUXGYp9qgq3GdpIs3uMiZozvYtPD4jvHd954CcUhT/4t6d1Ozk+gG/mo8VNyxeh9C/+3eZhT5KC3jJgkYucTllnVnho0rV2w34F9Em8NbZ8Fgw4rtsjVwK8VvVTK3rFFO09RzWVeEdbmx32nn9FwpcDomZJ5oriQ0rU+VPBR9lWWITSVfh8Bq8NRZgQxmPW5Nk2Puln+EhiWGaICj74X/hPGwsKts9rYkPVLCfb6EEjDJnjLZlRbaTHsVoA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "2000 million years", 
		"option_b": "4600 million years", 
		"option_c": "500 million years", 
		"option_d": "8000 million years", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRz6+IYoEhLz1un6MSvWEW0c4y3DX6p4fHjsWufgTa3qxtcgdRDZ3Qs70FWZ4eWc7R0r/lRBA2Tg1U1g7eM=", 
		"answer": "24W0bZjgxRbp8oslEL7vMUvAmyWCRBwFgcppveM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3Rzj5JEvURv8wL36JWTTCyIdomyXV6c0dmPsWeeQO7W+xJ59K1WGgxti93fUsOXx8FxPm6cbuN/TJ3JTPpJqycKal+XwyzFoJ4ZNicBz6IkQPP9OwyqjNNXIYOpmyy6JJECwZj64Ru8+NQPMqsNIztbrAvU7KIY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Holocene", 
		"option_b": "Pleistocene", 
		"option_c": "Mesozoic", 
		"option_d": "Cenozoic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100103", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut4kpVBuyx/j4PGWQDGxRhn6RRqsrMlBRJM1RUp+S7PazEd5Jry0=", 
		"answer": "2+bvOMGz3BDm+4wvXF7rwPztJivRBG1Tiky7kFflk5NTRuDlJXmThQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl730/T7MGXTBiIepT+PW6VxMH7tFILDfPn2iZR+KlmazV1p/XuGsarz/EBPm6Ba/c6eYidDf4lg3cTJhLO3xnhNP89LlMBr4ZsNb7RPwDntQNzeM/su3GGDLFawZDazEHF9mnHZmHtXpoq4tSq0WN801Rk3hcs4+sA1P9/f2LqWqFmwg0aAyXKdTLRqFhSbucGr4FDcr4R4ucSLtA7V3Pvun+7W4pJLdgBXrYM/akj8hKcE/Wo9R8GwbRxI9KTEaVX5YCSqIQtd9Mr6lnxo0IdpX2wz4REGh5VTbIB214rotTcif+tlB3O/u0VN15h5E1eFe7C9kHvn6VAxYXM4cZktvig5qAqKLRRqkmqIDDhZkcBk8tQchhAjdmFPi3igkDCIi3bPc52jzoHukeC84K5r+6AvaUCSMBzZVIIJcfOUdzQyyOCXAa9TPd9+EiP0LpUh8D21YJuVxnkM3Movb3To+j6Ym8O1Nne9spzwjZR7G7MFNcTJ7Nj1IqqFzOr5eUr3pQtRrt5xPg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "1000 million years ago", 
		"option_b": "3700 million years ago", 
		"option_c": "4600 million years ago", 
		"option_d": "500 million years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100104", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut401Xx/81r35PHnDFyIQs2+GU7E0f3+jcabQeuWhix2kSNmaIkADG20bKBkLv/U=", 
		"answer": "24WqbdzD3Rzj5JEvURv8wL3+O2+QBmMDr2bDYq9xeWL3W6THYOi8Im7pZA68XUn6tBly/JTdew==", 
		"explanation": "252tZZD9wlns/pczRl7z1e36NHnVByIVtm2KXKQ0ZHnmFLfQa6DOxZJ4NEiGjl519zbHraGw8lIdg7Eb2YKaeTEXcYhqxtXJw+36wWJ1O8MEn4Fg6JMab+AAyjK+Z93XM75hyC6oKEj/Jyq8FHlxmiKaymhercO2+iO+RtR3yAA/l4k4/tg5P96ayuTT4Eyug0aA2X6fCLllBVGd9dqnq0KOr5c2sY3f4WKXpKSp2uHW8cwYIglVsMQHKojYAW3fdZ3uejrQIX2e", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Pleistocene", 
		"option_b": "Holocene", 
		"option_c": "Pre-Pleistocene and early Pleistocene", 
		"option_d": "Cretaceous", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100105", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17hzOf6dWTWQ0MEsGuRU697YHj3XKLBe/652tdzNV2Ag1h64XOZ4YoA1Nd4sgWyue6NCURZvGQ=", 
		"answer": "2+HoONHwxBvj9MUjVxDmzPD6IXnVECClgZZnWD9JlHf14Mk7rAJ7", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSxAr+5YQsXQ770fX6Nn7DQ2oQpz+CErVxYmijR6rDYuG+y4VwLlKKjEh+vjbLpqTj4kEGga8b6JyQZSwHPt8/mJCKwub+xzFCNshQk4138Igab8BIyX2vZtXSLv1v3WvAKEOwRiyuEGJ1mD7Gg2herYCu5mesVcl3wRc9g5M4+cA5fMSWw63T50v4h0aB1HKcWLxqC1Gc8t3o6VGdqYw7tN6I8+ZJOj6oleEKz/5rDTOYUg4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "200 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_b": "400 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_c": "700 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_d": "900 cubic centimetres", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hHr5YQjRhvgzO7rPGiQB2sV416WQbdmcX3sRK7WZuj93IQxKVOdjFl36zbWrLbj8kAc0Op/9g8ryVfcA4E7AZSQX3zY", 
		"answer": "25exeJT30BWoxrQ08YE+L2BwBsvDonJavQ==", 
		"explanation": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6/ImrDQ2kfrGiNErd7MGbiWKyCYeO+3YB+Z1qMiE83smHOqqb4t1ocz6xe+o2NeSAGestu25CL0u35wzFDOtZBnoF+pv8c/6Od/fPUC2P3oWHDbME=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Quadripedal", 
		"option_b": "Amphibious", 
		"option_c": "Flight", 
		"option_d": "Bipedal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100107", 
		"question": "2523ZZ6z2Rjo/okpQV7lxO6/M2TFDWZRom+TQKxseXziQKLOd632xoAxKl2HlBti93fUsOXx8FxQzQJwRgkkGav3fsdsrVvhmIQ=", 
		"answer": "2+fLOcSz3BDm+4wvXF7rwPztJivRBG1TOfnOBbDF+XX3pIAXMq7IWg==", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6z2Rjo/okpQV7lxO6/M2TFDWZRqnHDV6JnZHTxWufDYOm+2phkM1SMn1U703DUqqbxt1INgL1PqdzsIXdDc4JjxNmG2aTuwXBTIIZFnY8wkwraBShXAlJspBekXvl30A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "4-3 million years ago", 
		"option_b": "2â€“15 million years ago", 
		"option_c": "1-05 million years ago", 
		"option_d": "6-5 million years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17hzOf6dWTWQ0oernDDWqJ2eX3qR+DRLu/syJ5/JF2aiAQ5Z8+mDfaRwAbhmqpIl7LWAg==", 
		"answer": "2+DoOOKkgUmq9JAiWx2yxvjxIWLdBnYDpmzBQmK67JDEplQ/xzGEGWsLrQ==", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6z2Rjo/okpQV76xPm/NCvSEWMYrXyCQaY0fXTiR7LQZ+P5iZV0M0uMiFU7pyaW0PKgpxMMmqpS6s6cdSwXd4Zq3MKMxKbbq9X6azbTxFiysOdhT5+V", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "200-400 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_b": "500â€“700 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_c": "800-1000 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_d": "1100-1300 cubic centimetres", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100109", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHl+opgQQ73xvT6JivRE3IUom2GVuN1dmXmRufqYeDxiZ9wJVWFhEgksMIvkERh63M56zB6EtkTSgw=", 
		"answer": "2523ZZ6z1Avv9JE1QVwD3tO2b7Vxt+stkUd6Xsk9", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkTHl+opgWh/wzPH2JieQK20crD+GQKZ3ZGTwFKbSfuj/25J1axyCg1Rs/DbArLew/kccz71L+4eYeDZDboR83MWb0qZI34o9E+6fxkjFk4C06B7w", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Homo sapiens", 
		"option_b": "Homo neanderthalensis", 
		"option_c": "Homo habilis", 
		"option_d": "Homo erectus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100110", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hezqNH/VEWwQsWbDW7A0ZHnmFKvDffm+xpExM1SMzV1052SGsLHx8FYcz6ddqZqXdWIGf5l7wJeal+fl0WJVc8NSlYxn8JMQcrR8wgGjRtHaM/FglC60L0Cwdiy8EHVmmjDEkzxfpoC34CO+R5ojyBBypot95NsoM9Sa163T6UO8xi6N0HSSTbNhUVGJus2g+AF3+5hlxz99sHF2vk8TNoGs", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z26MjEh0/DbPsOXk/1ZPjKdJ+4ucZGIGZptjyd6Iw+34yjFONYZliZN39o4Wc/oCVT4ab5GbX9domoyaXsm+3A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYP2kRj48sVgVBHn173sIWrXBnFRonGHErBkdXLqUq7Hfa3qwZZlZ0iBiBtq53fSprf+9kEWz6FV6oKKdCcQPp9nzcOMl/DgyzFEI8lHkpMwUOXhKnQlXFNRlzNTZ8Wbjw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is correct but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100111", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehH/yr36J27TF3cC43KGU61nME2hXKbMavS+xJZ/Gx7JsVVH/ETDorb/+QlPp6dW5s6XcSAKcoJ8iMeIxKTjzHQBPMhB2pd669oKb/FEjCmie9jIYmLRUvyHTl/z+WcdTvj9lz8=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV77y/7wJ3nVAHZRoWqXEpFxcWLsWufLfa39xoVjIl+dzykgG7VmASWYwI73I9qoAlQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH90BTvt60vXxGyzfz9PGfZECIFsX6NQa91ZHTwFLPNLtG8wZZ/I0XJgkk74X3Pr6Pl+xMCjqZnq6aQfS1DdoptwdyAxKT+1zFtMtJNlMB064hfQLZIzTOpbZTWIfBSjC60L0zjJzCuRHJxlzDDmXkWvIu+7GesUcgygAE6k8d+5NovKJeX1qWa5kS8lUaW0zucSbZhUVWXsY69+EbctI03ud65uTeb+vX0n7j7/9MEIg1AuoVrdkj8g7oI9jk0UNyxe1Jf/qTsI1H/JSu3ZwEPud7zxH1uzpZpUGg6tjeieRn1gDtG1/t+5Qe5PHs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is correct but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100112", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcwvh0e/+OWTACnYZpnyWQeN5dXDtR+f+LP7x3IN5Ik6HzVpr90qE46z+t38Om6FVqbKRTCwxe4p8x97Tl8Xi12VTMspLiolm7J8caecAwy+kc93VIepryi6JKQXjaCypDHVmmnH3jG5fq4L59aCbNf975dDlnF7T2pDXnQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+y4JlZ26MjEh0/DbPsOX++EdPm6BeqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgElYYyxYkMeeZUxTKjNmOExV6J1TyPycig8BuBx+g=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt6Q1QQrgxPHwJWLEC2cStmzDXbF9d3jtVbPHfa3425h8Z3CImVJ1snfIp+Xk5VIBnKRa/YuMMDYMPrct29+cw+zy1n8BMtZBpsIyxY8MaOZBwDK9fcDTJf173S6JNAXxJz64CmVn1D7QynlOvIq19jP7XNU6yRs7kpQ4+cA9KJeT0L6W7A2xiEaj2mmYS7wkF0aWuI6p6UyJtMJs542AuD7X/fv32uzcsIxLbwFes49wbRulkqkb62o5Vsf0XxpC/eGQdVzoYCaiKgtd/cTmxTRkw4MnHVV25xBTlotTcM4z14jhgHB8f9liEHO1sU1Hzpo8UxiVdamx32ak6UZ/e3U/JZ5luW0npA6PJ1o+nGSODCVFh8Bl/90c11plxJ2mRzYxiUvVzB/T6nc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is correct but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100113", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hc3zMGLDF20SpnGGEqZkf3LrFKXHaezwiZZjKEmHiRspsnvPr6n5+F1PrYsb1YCjfhAGf5hgxorJ/vC3zWIBMspXlcB56pUIcrRB3325fNGbKf1rjm+HIgfthxbuvKsjfDfeabVk87Wt", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z26MjEh0/DbPsOXk/1ZPjKdJ+4ucZGIGZptjyd6Iw+34yjFONYZliZN39o4Wc/oCVT4ab5GbX9domoyaXsm+3A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3Rzj5JEvURv8wL36JWTTCyITpniCXON1Yn72WqOCPK3zwJt9LlOHzXlYskTDorb/+QlPprwb4J3fcS4Qcctkxt+e2aT21zFVO8MEk4N3pJsYebbp4QXvyTExfwKXb6dgLtpv", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is correct but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100114", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehH/yr36J27TF3cC43OKRKZwMHDxW7LMaq2vkddlKBzY2xt2+3rKqqr+t0oKjrpIqY+Yf2I/cLdh+tWIxOv5njFpPMtL2oVg4ZkLaecAwTisesebHLxr3GuDMwX/dXmoFGJ9kznCynFXpsG1Ujk6XvXKnDLIlMM2f0s2", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7xyu/tMGjEQ2AEtz+xV6Jnf3+jXbSCZ+P9xoVjIl+dz0ZAAHxcwkN9pdWptrT+3Q8=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sU0WxP3w+/+OG6QCnFRoHCRQKZ3ZD2jQK/HLuD7yJl4KVvJgl075n7D46vx+lZPhrsb54GLMDYLe8t9zdGa2Oq3wn5Tc9FMn44y8JIaZbRMxSuocJYg/Q539vh4RpspfRFqfWsA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is correct but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect but Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100121", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Av+/8IzEh3g0O7rdW7GDG4Et3aMXONneH70R+f9UdLB9qhOGByamVp892WEhpTmWRFYzhAOq92re7EniQ==", 
		"answer": "27O3fYOx14M8WnacPQ7wayvVo0bktQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYP2kRj48sUmXQvghe7rNGzVECIepT+XWqY0dXDxQK+Ffa3924JiMxyMm1R352LPrKuyTZ84dDrL2a/9g8sqXc9+lg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "fo,ur", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100122", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV7h0fz4MCvfBSIFq3rDV6JmZHmkR+fBfPjt3dd0MVOFmE9y/XiGqraw9FIDg61fqZqXdWISa4p7zcKH1vbuhvhPY3rv5bHUkNfsqr+X84A=", 
		"answer": "27O3fYPn2Vt7ZBVDg/R/6aGVmfNc0ux6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13gz4441gQQrzwvi/Om2QF2oU43qCQLd8N2KjV7XXffm+zIF+K0mdhFR1sn/V46bx+18Ki+hP4YvfYTcCao59xtGbzqZkg88hO5RULYHH2inc6zjR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "fo,ur,th", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100115", 
		"question": "2523ZZ6z2Rjo/okpQV7n1vj7dVTvPF0unEC8EqJnMGXsW6vRLG4pew3KLsQPOjOThf9JAbk=", 
		"answer": "26awaYPj1Bfv88UzRhH8wO69kTAK3z8Vf9SakQBYbEXBIA==", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6z2Rjo/okpQV7w1/L0MCvDF20fpj+KXLd7MGHqUaTHfa3/x5MxMk+MiRtv+nPL46Tjt0cAgKRIq0WjNccvd7aXyREycjYoPmU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "bones", 
		"option_b": "leaves", 
		"option_c": "wood", 
		"option_d": "sharpened stones", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100116", 
		"question": "24asaYX23Bzk499gfhf0wL3wOyvVAnAFqz+BV6R1fjHiRqjXYOm+msAhdxyEhFd3+3nI47z19kEcz6lc5s6oeCMXPpxu25Cd3+G3wH5MOshFlJQy6JMZebRGwy+gNNLUMr5jz2CZZ0j5azW4Cn59lXHXjGhTusO3/CG+FNgyxxQ8ycVZy8JXhH50sRFVAp6CnjVB", 
		"answer": "26W0aZ/nwlnr+YFgUxD7yPzzJikWzVzC4rchhJM7ld6pju9K", 
		"explanation": "25O3etH+0Bfzt4gpXhL3y/P2NCvRBXYUsT+PW6VxMHPmU6bMIq333ddmJk/JjlR19H/IpqGw41xPn6Ra55qMMCMNestuxtmE1ujkhsSR+jZ1SkxmhCOePOnglsE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "bacteria", 
		"option_b": "mammals", 
		"option_c": "humans", 
		"option_d": "plants and animals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100117", 
		"question": "24asaYX23Bzk499gZhb3hdXwOWTTBmwU43qTXaB8MHPmU6bMLuTwiZZzKEmdzQopviaW8+XS1BM4h6lPqYGLeCcRPoVuxdXJ3ve3w3hXNsgEjo8y8JIaPNxPwDKucdref7yK64i4GPVkQWoAd04xPKHt", 
		"answer": "26W3e4W+2Brvt4QnV1wwS30R5av8NC1S7v0kQBzT", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb3hXl9IAuV1771r3tMG3VEXAUpz+XXeN1YzH3XKKCfuLt3dp4JFnJjFx+sI6QPpVYRnqnumjm7n8crc0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ice age", 
		"option_b": "bronze age", 
		"option_c": "iron age", 
		"option_d": "post-ice age", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100118", 
		"question": "24asaYX23Bzk499gehH/yr36J27TF3cC43eCVuN1MGL3RqjMaeHniZVkLlCdzUhw53rK45L49kdPmKlIqZqXdWIOe4p83cKM2uH50DFONYZNjpMy5ogedfpDzS6oK5btpWkPoPOxC2KQjKeRBKbr", 
		"answer": "2+3oOOKig0m6t4Y1UBfxhf76O3/ZDmcFsXqQEA3EMENePSPtbH0vpTYcDfU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2APvt4omEgr6wL3XOmbfQ2cDpnyXR7A0cmPiXanBb/77iZ5iZwTZ3SgqoCaW46bl9VoMz6te55qWfScXbI58iviDNJvjs7yT8k2nc2qjE+o=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "400-600 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_b": "500-700 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_c": "800â€“1200 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_d": "1000-1400 cubic centimetres", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100119", 
		"question": "24asaYX23Bzk499gcwvh0e/+OWTACnYZpnyWQeN8cXWjVqjWZq3/2ZJ9LleMzVp19jbOtqjx+RMMh6lJ6I2LdTAKbZ9my8PJ4Oz20DFOJ85BiMB85ZcaPP1TjCmlfcebM+5rzWeFNAXxayqyRGJxkjTEmHlS6Je0tSaoC5govm08OhnTtqkHznKGGCpH", 
		"answer": "26WqZ4X8nBH/+oQuEKkDgnWh58e97XaQz5JWrRQ=", 
		"explanation": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6/ImrDQ3YZpj+PU7BgMH7lFLPKa63u25I8L0mEjFU7+nnLqqv580BDz6Va4oeRd2IKast/2t+d2Kn/0XxAPYSyvZAio5KlCWsvWVVKvkwN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "pre-human", 
		"option_b": "neo-human", 
		"option_c": "ancient-human", 
		"option_d": "proto-human", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100120", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vwz/her2IWOQCnYC43KGU619fna5FreOhSzj3+6bMh+MJuQX0Gg=", 
		"answer": "24W0YZTgxRbp8oslHzfxwL3+Mm6cQ0oer3CAV61xMDyjZKjReq33ypIxJluMwRtT/XvJ463x9VoDhrsbpM6XcSwHZ8tiyd7Fl8z4yX4BNtRBmZRn99pSPMFQ3jSqfMCbLf9gjEsRMNM9HCXwhspbSwcp0Bw=", 
		"explanation": "24W0bZjgxRbp8oslCF7GzfTsdWLDQ2NRpHqMXqxzeXLiWOfHfuL9wddlL12dzVd64WLDp+X25VwCz6lZ5puLMHBVPoZmxNyA2Oq30H4BYpcIzdAipIMafeZTjDyqe5ibI/F4y3yJKUKwczG4RGd7hj3SzW8WpYyo4WepUdkyzgFyhoJq5Mc4fNiZmbqW+Ei5kgOGnHydSb5tEECQusC7pwOfr481usOBqHLJ8fL8iOrW9J4fbUhTrMZra178q+og+y94cM+xVFB3/9jeSVvhLyumKQtHuf/r32cpz5FpSWExtBxTkJFTbNQz0Z3rsD03Ns5rGXO/s0tDz9RVS1eUcbq53ijl8EUtemIiaIt5uSEs4V7NZAMuyiuFSS1Dh8Bq+d9V1QVlaWpS3GLoh3+HgXabPJ7i4Y/uxeHzpfli9aZnYVWIMBzoWogVdqfPJGJ8z6DXTatdOJZpEGLvKZU69Dy5HNSk0CoZkNAjKjfm8y+l0I3lPHezvJa5p8A2EbEDOdzV6NiktU+HYC/tYXKVJtnxWgfiS3n8kwZwuhkriCkZ+3bXGpA/9CMJ3nejCUdskzXhb2ikhLdG74bOfZdxx/3pnTcdneZ/mpX00V09SQD7im1MpZCXD1NJjVzDE8wJhAonGr0NHYzQ5mSZm2XsRUADV8H7DuiPwi5B1uri1CFcsdALVJ6CNVnTn9MnxleiEfh6XGL+6JLxPOhVBm06/7Yxy/2xpcWjfP6lOGAmdlrlDa9N/NUAPEJ2GAfRDCtBIKGrV48NAeFI3TX+nwIISX5EABrwuYAHUAvqosXKZ2bXcI1eTgrwYr0WH8/sS1SPIf7p9HLBB7GYjAezXkppcnjdL7EA4AOwfIPgZBqngCh37NH1PUJeQMMWPi7/fX+g5beMSwM8eSkmPINRf0vMCwU3kX7XKPZrnpsOTBYFTqWoWVUEkxJbii2ITmxNuV9eTLWoQ1oiOelJKU0UyXezA68SHB3IiS8ezgfFgi/lJfZCPkdjb2vTjl7vjpxi36640sLRWoSiNLgawJ5DKbFUBJvYGxsVibPv4e73Hyw/CX83J+zbHvfBokbxCty0sdfby19Ohf4AM1E4IHmfgZqZ/jtgKuVzLUVar3oepN6Sbwek5coZ4VhhQxX/5UTnSGIy9hhgLpLnedKcOZKi/llZHyfGWa0DnvNqnSXwJp/Edx9/CGV1lw6Cc5LLyTDDLaPvxaMdDBmu24CLUYJorE143NC7xl9U6z16nXHxS3ncIuvs5hlBI3t9C7WRHh1OiRQr1Dbx0UHvPIGjnacdh79Pmqd4iWba1VAPw3FvI6H8ICY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Pleistocene,Ice age", 
		"option_b": "Holocene,Post ice age", 
		"option_c": "Homo habilis,Handy man", 
		"option_d": "Homo erectus,Upright man", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100121", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUlQhHxzb3oPH/YQ2sFsD+XW65xMHfxVarHNK/TyqAasw5VURBUJrWclZrv", 
		"answer": "24W0bZjgxRbp8oslH0yyyPTzOWLfDSIzgD+XXeMlIiGzBOfgTaG+4Zh9KF+Mg1428HPBoquw9kEAmqZfqd/NIHJTPqlMiMSGl/TlwWJEPdIGz1hBGUlP54PIxxDABueMOA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb3hXl9IAuV1771r3rPW6QAHcDsXqNRuNzdX7vW6DLbezyiZJhKF+BwRts+n/Fq+Xy8lQOgeha+4GKfiZDL9kjmIDZl/3yxWNSc8dDlcBz6p5ff/tO2DSjYdHIYOphjnqIIgXgdTyuAX5g1DXXk0BYnIu+tRe3UdMk1Boxk4l9rcEvfNbf3q2c5EK/jwWD0DuUWLJnGRSNvc+8q0+ds5Y9sY2Loz3WtPXpiurc6NcGYxxXs58/MRuxnqQF8SU2EdGxaQBYseXXbhT5L2iiJQEI7YuyhDg5ltJpRGw15gwGg4RZIulnlpH3/D02K8hkVSG/pUFS1ZF4HwOZNLyrkHzs5RUDN1MoYMpMuygJ40+ZOFt9kinF1+NADpMcJIdQHPKQ0kHi", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Pleistocene,2 million BC to 12000 BC", 
		"option_b": "Holocene,began around 12000 BC to present", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100122", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUzQhvxzPjsdXzZF2pRt3eGW7E0c3niRqbBeujswIRlLl/Tz61VaNAD3izj/Di77MTGBQI=", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6/eCvyCnIUp36PEqJ6dDHzW7PAa+HywJJ1a3SGgFQ7+nfEqqn55BNCz4pJ5oWaMDEXcYVqiNmHw+u31HhEMMNX2oZ99toLc/tM33GFe9nUYPt8y22UMlawKnmOEGJ7mjbakzxUvYq34WeoX887zFkQmZVxoOU9NNaN2Lub/F+5xCv6Ojrgvu3CWftC/d/qSz8=", 
		"explanation": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6ldUDeDHUf43mMQON2dXjtU+fNYOi+xpExM1SMzV564HrPprbkt1sAgqFV4ICMMDYMPpxuxNvJwvTlzXZJJ4oEjoh3/doebvEAwzu5cdqbJPt9zXyJJUD0JziuRHJ9hDTSi3AWqY2/tS+6UJo2gBc9kp44/sA9LNLfyqee7VqwhxLCz3KcQbFlAxSNuo6l5EeZsox4vdiAsDzItPbsjrjE+coDIgkSsoltZhuA1bgG7Gc6VMS4YRdPzaaQYET9JSmxJgAe/Pft/ntkycIhXGs9+BZV2MN9bM9k2Njlr3IkN8gqKXGyokpE3tRxXhnaSP/4xGDt8xUsZX8obI9+/DgmpAvcO11zimeZDD9Fm45uvsQWmghwPW5OmDbpkX+EhnGKctPg+YX4jPz1pPl0+7cvaUOFPFLfFoISYPPPISdmwuzbC69OIIsnAy3pMZg77zD3J9ac0DQE3tAuPEvp3CWUnY3wK2C5p4fq1JRYG6sBNN3Aqc24ohzOdTChNG2Bb8z8TUjjW3320AslthYhiDIE+m3WD4VmtS8Yl3KkCVdvhyvsLEipn60c+ZKLfIc0wLXt0SEf2OFrmp+32RIuQkS6iWlCvIeaSxxbwlvaDY0Gyg1uBadBB5/W/GSQnHXRRWhNecHkQaGT0GxdyeaxgWc9uZkcUM4zUTxKMTIqB2+KQzXWmgkO", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Australopithecus,Bipedal and potbellied", 
		"option_b": "Homo habilis,Broke stone into pieces for tools", 
		"option_c": "Homo erectus,Strongly built skull", 
		"option_d": "Bori,Maharashtra", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100123", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUjQBvz0ejtMCvHCnYZ43aXQeN2YnDqWqTDfei+2p5rIgbLHAoaj+vHFwkqI93QL+duGQ==", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6/eCuEUzJRoGqBW6A0c3TtQK7Pa/nszIQ9Z3SGgFQ7+nfEqqn55BNCz/0Luc6Lf2JULtsvy8WL3ue3x3RPJ89Jn5Rg4YlTVPtNw32oZtHYNOt9jiPAfxWgJy2yRCEmxGGWiWlUoYD79iK1QNM6xQEgk5Q68mL5njeR2GqeE7EstMd58g==", 
		"explanation": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6ldV/YCnFRpn6RXro0eH7uXanLYK3t2ZJyLlmazVN69jbH47b99l8Dirob65yeeSxDfYRi2NGb0uC30H4BP8dQn5Iy7I8SffoA3y2od93eM7Iu2WeULwXxaXm4F2R9mTDCj3gWqpG6/Cm4VckygAY7jII44s58PcWQzKaXqBno1kaByXmYS/1nFFqNvMOt/1GZs742ncKAvnLT9fbwlvHAqp4gbAdFscZ+cBuon61JxGgwUMawcVJG8OqcXRatNCCqNE4O6c7g33F6hoooWSk1tAxKi4RedsxqlpTlrjU1LY1oBzKzrUdB1JE8Sx+Xev2ZxXvw8lQzemoicYJovzgm7U+ZO0B3l2qISSgRgI8r/NVZlwF3ampFkja10m/41zXfPJD26Yn/xev1rq1q/6YzO0STCVLwWYATJbbSImRm3/rBTZJUOownBDLjPtwr73nxIZLU3nke2d4uJnHu9yuXhsHseWm7oZX8nJR0Br4JOJHR4cq58FXTcmPxM3iXY8jxShv/XW+0kxlsoxBlyjMR4WzbCZp6tT4EhHujCUF3hi7tbWikkv5I5cKcfoA21rXqzz0d2Kwoz9vj211tFVTrzXxWsI2cD19Kw0DfE8gT1gw9Ts/OEpo3iibD/PROHmObmv0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Australopithecus,400 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_b": "Homo habilis,500 to 700 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_c": "Homo erectus,800 to 1200 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100124", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vwz/her2IWOQCnYC43CRW6R9fiuhwB23HFjLAyo5AXoLhsywFQ==", 
		"answer": "25Ste4Xh0BXl54w0Whvx0O6/eEfRF2sf42uGQK40fXTiWq7Maa3txoJlL1mbgxt64nOK443/+lxPh6lZ4IKWY28mf5h7zcKHl+X5wDFSPNNQkoVg6to+euZJzzzvJc1TrlEcHNfK1sW7s8+7EA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH90BTvt7licwvh0e/+OWTACnYZpnyWQZ82MHLsWaLRLuvsxpoxC12dhFU783jC46j19l0cz5QZ+oGKZCoGbIUvycCM66a38HlIIIZWn4Z+4ZkLb7RUxDjtctXYNL56xm+UZ1H4Ynm7DWJngHHQhW9FoY+otSi9FM4/yQZyhZd97sE5L5eI3LqWqEmxlQWNyn6DTbkkGFrZpsG9/0uZsox4lMufuDHayPrRlfXcsNYKYAFetpU/ZVSvhKEF62owUN6xKAJZ+OnRc13hOWihIgsTuc3sw3pthosnHWw15wtDkI0WY853lovrqSY4Ot9kVRK8sU1Dxtar/vLLk23F2KXg+MOA42en", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Australopithecus,Latin term meaning southern ape", 
		"option_b": "Homo habilis,Eastern and southern Africa", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100125", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr++IslEgr9yvG/PHiQAG0fsHaHV7FxdDHuW7TWLun32oN4KV+dhE1+smHPt62w31wCgOhe+4ucZDcQIcmr3qvABjYbLicThY2+Uw8t", 
		"answer": "2725ZpWz0AHvtYccoXDVcP8UehYxlQPyscA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH70Bfut4Q4V1771r3rPW6QDm0Ctz+HW7BgeX/gQK7Ua63qxph9Z1qGmFV/smHPt62w31wCgOhe+4ucZDcQPIU/xsIDeJhbb+yjx+hEDoI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "hand axe", 
		"option_b": "chisel", 
		"option_c": "blade", 
		"option_d": "scraper", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100126", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhDt+YwmWx3zy+m/MWLDAG0Hpm2aEqd9dDHLW6rNLujszJRlMk/JnV504nrD46jx/FZPna1X6JqadGIXcctpwcKMiKYOXl+fnJmMfL5HoY59pn+K", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz1RD59Io2Vwz3wb33OnyQF21Rrn6IV+N1fnWjQbTHLuv325IzB40wD8tH7LBTSlEsYBOZ7g==", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6z1Avv9JE1QV72zO78On3VEWcV43eMReNgfzHuVazHLuzwzddkNFnJi1Jp9zTrTA2ffvy7YakzFKe7W992", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They invented the matchstick", 
		"option_b": "They discovered how to make and use fire", 
		"option_c": "They learned how to cook with fire", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100127", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRHr4YBgRhb3he/6OGrZDXFRrHnDeqx5fzHmRqLBevjtiZV0IlLJi1Ru/HKZ4XHi94egBMCsgBquKvFwozE=", 
		"answer": "25y2KLD1wxDp9slgcRb7y/yzdVjfFnYZ416QW6I4MHDtUOfxYfjqwZJwNEjJrEhy8zTDZ8+mdJAdmT/uRAbXHxwU", 
		"explanation": "25y2KLD1wxDp9slgcRb7y/yzdVjfFnYZ416QW6I4MHDtUOfxYfjqwZJwNEjJrEhy8zbHsaCw5EMKjKFd4I3ffC0Af59mx96al/P/wWNEc+5Ll48y4Ygaf+BV332/cdnaKfB9jmaBMUCwZTy4CjBwnSLVhWpTuoa/tz8cBw3zuiUTrxall6BrCp8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only in Africa", 
		"option_b": "Africa and Europe", 
		"option_c": "In Africa, China, South Asia, and Southeast Asia", 
		"option_d": "Only in Asia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3xjn8sUpQV71zOv6OyvEDCIFq3rDVLZ4fDzlWKLGaej6iZp+I1mbgxt283iZ4bEmpoa0bIbuYxHz62YkAYc=", 
		"answer": "2523ZZ6zwhj6/oAuQV7hxO32MGXDQU9VbJ9qOJLCRlARV7cRtXI=", 
		"explanation": "25i3bJTh31nn9otgew2y7fLyOivDAnIYpnGQErB1YHjmWrSAk4NH9YMmDz6t4zOygLmb+w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Homo sapiens erectus", 
		"option_b": "Homo sapiens habilis", 
		"option_c": "Homo sapiens sapiens", 
		"option_d": "Homo sapiens neanderthalensis", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100129", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhzgxPTxNmrDBiIHrHOWX6Y0f3ejfKjPYa3tyId4IlKazUh64n/DrbavtXfN2koUKatRraCA4POyZMA=", 
		"answer": "2+TqOMGAg0m6p8UjRxz7xr38MGXECm8Ut22GQeGKOWWqW2UIrfnBEPWs304t", 
		"explanation": "24aobZL61xDpt5chXBn3hfvwJyvEC2dRoW2CW613cWLmFLHNYvjzzNd+IRyhglZ0smXHs6z1+UBPnKlL4IuRY2IKbcs+moDZpLanlCEBMNNGk4My558RaP1NySm/cceZqvvxevCEpBU5IJSSTktgvg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "500â€“1000 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_b": "1000â€“1500 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_c": "1200â€“2000 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_d": "1500â€“2500 cubic centimetres", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100130", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehH/yr36J27TF3cC43yMR69wMHTtULLQa639xpt1Ik7Jjldy/3fSprawy10zgZpe6J2QfnhDVoRix5CMxeH00GRSc8pBm5J84Z5fdPtXjCmiNMHIJb5ox3yFZXekOHrlFJPL7fhBlS0ITdE=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z26MjEh0/DbPsOXk/1ZPjKdJ+4ucZGIGZptjyd6Iw+34yjFHPNQEu5Nh4YgLdftOjned/rpKGFzoApw3GzC+OL0=", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6z1Avv9JE1QVnhhfz9PGfZF3tRt3DDX6J/dTHiWqOCe/77iZF4NVnJjFd3/WHDp+Xk/1YCz7xUqZ2LcTtDaYp9xZCA2aT0y31Fc8VIk41z8J8MPtqgBZmkpZowxdEKKWrPMEY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct but Reason is not the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100131", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehH/yr3sNHvZBmwC42yCQqpxfmKjXKbGLun335JjNFnJmVR0/mWGn6vM+WEKjrtU59TfRCoGZ8tnydTJ1qT7xWNGNoZClZJ37J8eeLRBwjntYNzSLvBr3C6CKEv1dHuRG9r6pqE/EIAXQGnoDmrT", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+y4JlZ26MjEh0/DbPsOX++EdPm6BeqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgEnI9gpLsMb/FS2DSiepaM2OZD6OMPAdyiSxD8enpF", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gQQrz0fjyMGXEECIQsXrDRrFhdT2jW6nHLunxzIR/YEjJiENr/nfPreXk/1ZPgLxT7JzdtCpSHfXgr3rTr7jg0mi/2g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct but Reason is not the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100132", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfBvzy/n6J3/YAm5Rrn6NFbA0YnTuVa7Mfa3pzIV0Z1qGmFV/snnIr7yw/l1PqK1J5I+RaWI/cLdh+tWIxOv5njFvNsdKnoVg8JIecLRNzTPtccLULOhryi6JKQXVciuyFHU2Xtnq7wAK4F7CJinmYbxxcw==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6eSvSFnZRkXqCQax6MHjwFKHDYv77iyIewcsRG3rfmz+jJeaBeLo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1Bjk84AyRhbzyb3tMGbRCmwC42iGQKY0dn72WqOCZ+O+3Z90Z3KMjEk713fVt+Xx+VdPiqRI7JmXdTAGPoJhiMSB0qTYyHUBBMlWloQ+pJQQaLRK2S65NPPeMvNvwHfCAgr3g8YB1/WsYe9vSmaGmQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct and Reason is the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct but Reason is not the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100133", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b3+N2TFFyI/pn6NVqZmZHniWOfPb+O+wIQxJl+KmEl65nOZ4a93i1lzllwQg/p0Q0uXWkQ=", 
		"answer": "25yse9Hxwxjj+YYhQRuyyPj+Jn7CBmZRon2MR7c0ISOzBOfWYa2vkcchZ1+cj1J4snXDrbH5+lYbna1Iq2OfreSMZE61rHmI1joXqVg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4glXAr7yvPsdX/YBiITsX6KXKB1Y3SjWaLDffjszJp0KUjJi1RpsmLOpuXe8lIBi61J/YaefGIOf4UtNWbdbhSMrRv3htMYN3Il0g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They lived only 100,000 years ago", 
		"option_b": "They evolved in Africa", 
		"option_c": "Its braincase measured about 1200 to 1800 cubic centimetres", 
		"option_d": "They used advanced machinery", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRD5t5EyRxuyxP/wIH+QK20crD+QU7N9dX/wFLTDfuT7x4QuZaOU70XhyIEvggi+7N8gC3E=", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz1Rj+8sUiUx35henwdWrSDHcF4y7SB+8kICGjTaLDfP6+yJB+Z1WHzUh052LOprf+t3IJnaFY6MwBF/s4AkkwQQtbPic6z7kR", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t5Y0Uwr31r3rPW6QF2scpnOKXKY0dn7xFI/NY+K+2pZhLlmHnhto82bPpqvjtQG5mXM+0QRWe8gvrZbI47o=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They never used stone tools", 
		"option_b": "They date back to about 115,000 years ago in southern Africa", 
		"option_c": "They had the smallest braincase", 
		"option_d": "They evolved in Europe", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100135", 
		"question": "25y8bZ/n2B/zt5EoV17xyu/tMGjEQ3EFomuGX6Z6ZDHiVqjXeq3zxpN0NVLJgFp1sM1uInmBk/5mm3qLR4CPbwY=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdH8wxDt/otgXRiyyfzxMn7RBGdRqmzDXKxjMHPmWK7HeOj6iYN+Z16MzVpp/WPIp+Wlpx9f3/gby63d7zgrRv8h8gG85UZYNcFsvg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1A/j5IAkEhrz0fi/M2TCQ3YZpj+MQKpzeX+jW6GCYuzwzoJwIFnJhEg7pyaK8/Wgt3EszbRhL/UFtU2XFRhcjn/f57Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Modern man has the smallest forehead among hominids", 
		"option_b": "They evolved around 230,000 years ago", 
		"option_c": "The origin of language is now believed to be around 50,000 BC", 
		"option_d": "They never used tools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100136", 
		"question": "24KwaYW0wlnr9IY1QB/mwL3+N2TFFyI5rHKMErB1YHjmWrSFLujoxptkM1WGgwQ5m0LluhPp4Yfs6XLMtsNBbw==", 
		"answer": "25qtetH8xheq5JUlURf31r36I2TcFWcV43mRXa40WH7uW+fRb/33zJliZa2Xm73xT2KrhXToAz+MUaI=", 
		"explanation": "252tZZD9kQr68oYpVw2ywOvwOX3VByIXsXCOEot7fX6jR6bSZ+jw2tVEI47s3hv45iyoM4D0S1nE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Homo sapiens never used tools", 
		"option_b": "They were the first to discover fire", 
		"option_c": "Our own species evolved from Homo sapiens", 
		"option_d": "They evolved in China", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100137", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3ib9kKl2HzUhr93XPpraw8kUAg75e7c6ZYi0OPqNgxd/JxOXnzXRPIPpKpo4grdordPEA3ji7fcfeJL5qz3qFZ0P/dXmpDHU0myPfjXVY6Iy9tSu6Wt0iwRI31o5rrZ1scIfPieixy3G2ugjRlTu5R7BrUVGLsM28/lDcpIs8u4qZ8SbJ9eL8lrjf/9AMXgZlt498axuzkegd8C94UMq7fhcL4vDRdVHgJSa3NE4c686j33pqyZA7WGogq10otviQU/6OyPJ2fURhyAa3", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6z1Avv9JE1QV7m1/zpMGfcBmZRr3CNVeNweWL3VanBa/6yiYB5LlCMzXN0/3mGq6Ty/l8GnOhf4Irffi0XPOaILvW9t6KwKNw3q7/7fMw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100138", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhyniFp19nPUt63x+xMCjqYb+4uMdS8Bco5riPiG2uu313BROsNKibx82JRNNbRh3Di+NNLSMu16jmqFMUD8aCm4ADAnxHHbg3BaoYy1tT6+VcgkgBQ1mbt20cZvdZer0a2B7Q25lAPC2nSEWv13BVWesN3o5EXctIo99ciMoybTs+e5merG48pLZx5ds5NralSyq6Y+8CM7WYi7blJf+eGQYFbiNi3jNBoc7c7u03p91cIqUnsm8RxS3cEEgrUMKHB1Cr/RRBR1QcdU", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNHn2Ryq9ocvRBuwTFEBCg9dupS5SfARl++4hA==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7Gzfi/G27RDWYUsWuLU680fXDtFLDDfa3/iYRhIl+AiEg7/XCGq7D99l1Pm6Ba/c6TeTQGestmxpCswvb41HQBMshA2qFh7ZtfeuZPwX2sdtvONL48nj7MdxWgJy2yRCMk2GGG2jxPrYKp5me6U9V39B03j8dv6No5fMeXwLua60y0ih/Cz3KcQbFlAxSNuo6A5E6T4JE5pcSIvyGXtPbsjrjH+NsSIgBTu8ZzYkm7krpJ+jg5WManKBNF9aTRIVDkJi6mNQsT7Yvw3WFlysI6VWgk8SNIvo1ldsFn05XhsiZwbZcqNCO/sARGzoZvS1eScau93Gf05VF/dHgkcJ4t7311rAaQJF1xlCuFSS1Dh8Bq+d9ZoQxmPWpBjnrphyyfwGSfeYCj/IXugKjjrbhv/u9nPVOFMBHcQYgQabrOICdx2OyaGbNONownODTjL5U69TT8bNaVzzwekNw2IHvx8S7ZhsK1O2C5vJ/8zth3BrgFJJHE58/3vVPVZGPoL2mWasf9Xg3+W0D27wBWoxkxzSwV5naYW9M/wSUI3nuxW1Bs1TSgb260haoc4oOdP4sn3Pn62DZQjPxqkI7w3F06SBGpzWxXs4OaXAZzw2DeG40vxQ0rDbpBEZnfvi2BnX/TQzwBft3iBKzHxT5H16Ol2CF/tpwCXIOAbA3Uyopmyh69DfR2Wyf0rYfrLrwUDWsQ9IZ5z62ApcmzcPKqbGAlYVb3TudQ8J0RZANoBQ7ZRSJdb7XuAt0cSOxD23rE1xNHBy0cRVjF96QBUgrqs8HJfHmeYrYTMhDWa7ZFI9z3WkLdOuumwTOJA7CS2QepV00mRnqRIKMZ4AOwfJ79KVPhxihm8M3pO15VBJcYfHKnJSu0rK+PAgk0PzUgKZhUOkbSRCwqoDbGZ8lvjKkFYhc3TqGkWVUZmF0PiDbbDVAFuV9eS62oAFAyOLtALk9RyDi7UaERWFzChylKgleP1ifoafxZPkRjLjDCz0Hpl55vkPGpm4uAGMeiLLoUkpkMaKJTQdrGDV4Pn/3wrQwRrMD8nERxldbTOB4xtwo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100139", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3ib9+KlPJnlpr+3PIsOXk5VIBnKRa/YuMMDYMPrct39ma0qT6xX99cfpKpo4grdo3c/lPjDWsdt3XKe0uw2uBKVawW3u4FnV3gHHZmDxDuJGy8i+vFNc2zilwqokrpIgUM9qQma2B7U6skxXC0X6QRq4kLRaRtMCs8gOTssIrvsSBtyfXtPn4lMSRzNA8agFRt8ZwZRuon61J+Sg3R830ewZK5eHdZFr5M2iiNQtd8MXg2WZ7w4E9Ait99N9FQ57bSu3TgVaVYB88", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqq+IssS1z5CJjjQYToCkb2LtWsGmEU", 
		"explanation": "2523ZZ6zwhj6/oAuQV7m1/zxJmfRF2cC42uMEp82Z3jwUefPb+PCi5V0JF2cnl47+2KGqraw41sKz6dV5ZffYzIGfYJq25CG0aT/0XxAPYZQkoFmpJIeb7REySuoeNvLJfouzWGNN0n1f3m+C3d6nSXfnHkWqYGy+S6vXd8kjFUhg4RwrckvfNue16+G6Uq9ykaD3miFWrxnBRSNvcG97EuI7MI5u8nNoSDU9vj8l7XA/9IdawZusa5wblT8n6kL8SYxQoi5bRNF4qTsI1zsLiy6ZwEPudjo33hv045pUGg6yF1ujY5ZIshy1JHotSFwNt4qASG7rVdMxoB5W1eCe/2EkmDl7lEmNXcqa7Yv/C8wog6JO1E+k3/cWy1C1JRj+5AfnBZwaS9TjHPjizqYwGqJPJv25oHyxfz/4LRi+aZnKE+EdUnLU80IarzMNFt84uaWAuZZIZpkAzf1fdgr/TfqYKrW2isI081gIGWn4TqLm8r9LSW3spzFzNZzF74VJdSF4N/3p13UITfpJD2Vb9nnTUjjX3n72gt29xcjiCkF5WPWSJ1wtToMknXwXFR2myDoeD6Fbimf7aue/5njq8YoRrRy", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100140", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhysjElv+jHV46Dj41oCjrxe7c6edydDd5gvycKGwurzhCUXY5YEl4l+6JMQcrRZyTy/Z+jVHPA8hy60L0CwczyvCTBVgSLCmH1ap5Oy4S++V88kgBogn4Bx48koOcTf37qc5Q2UhxKL0juQRrkkBUaYu92k6leZs8Isuo2x8yHU4eDxn+rdsN8bZzQQg4hDbQj115wB/Wo9UNq4YRdY5aTRb1foMzysNR1d9s2j12Rs1cIvVHsn4F9HkpNTY9J20tjlrj0lMckqRmP6rk1My51zUVePcbyqwyjl51oDe00jbIll/CIz4RuULRR/mGSKSWxCgIF/+90cmxBwPW5SmTbpjDyEkneKf4e8qapfBJcdUF5OFRyz49Klm3w=", 
		"answer": "25u3ZpSz3h+q440lEh/wyuv6d9zw1yvjvQfBR2mrD6vVc9Y=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Av+/8IzEhvh0fTyNH/VByIQpHrDW7A0cWPsQanGLrmomccxKlWFgVJ0/DbfpqTi5G8Bu6BeqZqaYi9DX5583MKI2+vnzWVJNsVRicB99pMYdfpB2Di+NNLJL/Mu4m+ULkuwZje5RGRmlT/Fhn1CrZD74Sj7aJgkzwAmnoJq44g9LNKjm5Sd3EW9xgODzneYTa5wUVWXtsu7/0yOs8I3s42MoTfItPLwiOvHsN8bcg1TrYN7I1qumL0H/GprAYi5YR5H+OveIU3oITqwZw8a9omaqo1tE07nC2EQ2o0GzyWK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100141", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRHr4YBgQRH/wL3wMyvEC2dRpn6RXqpxY2WjR6zXYuG+z5hiNFWFnht593PI46P/4l0L0Or49SVo5nQG7FUwMu2UebMJ", 
		"answer": "24axf5D/2BKq/4wsXg2wXq6Ekig+USu6tqr6kVCIZg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA2A7r+4wrEhb7yfHsdWLeQ0sfp3aCEqJ6dDHTVazLffn/x9d5JkqMzUh0/3OGrKOw41sKz61a+4KWdTEXPphk3dyFl+L412JIP9UGd0l1rgxjugvA0RC/A+UP7w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Siwalik hills", 
		"option_b": "Narmada valley", 
		"option_c": "Fa Hien cave", 
		"option_d": "Potwar plateau", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100142", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rz88okvQhv2hfLxdXjRDWYCt3CNV+N9fjH3XKKCXvjww5ZzZ0ybgk1y/HXD46r2t2MOhKFI/Y+RL2D7eHzul4TkmUe2EbUBj5kG", 
		"answer": "24W3fIbyw1n6+4Q0Vx/nh10DDO8Ujt8chq3w4XROCPI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3g399pdgQhLz0fj+ICvUBnQUr3CTV6c0f3+jR6bMav7qxpl0Z1WHzU9z9zb2tqv69lFPn7pU/4eRcydDcY0v+NGC3vfjxX8DfWzd9+vbSJ3ABYNKCj0flQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Siwalik hills", 
		"option_b": "Narmada valley", 
		"option_c": "Fa Hien cave", 
		"option_d": "Potwar plateau", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100143", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrh4oksQV7iyu7sMHjDQ2oernaNW6c0dnTiQLLQa/6+y4JlZ06MnUl+4XPIt+Xx51Yc0OpFDui7mY2utg5cD8sdNIZD", 
		"answer": "24e5ZZDj2A3i8oY1QV7zy/m/BmLGAnIYt3eGUbZnMtyNizcoVFTsPegoIvKKafQ=", 
		"explanation": "24e5ZZDj2A3i8oY1QV7zy/m/BmLGAnIYt3eGUbZnMGHsR7THff6+2ph8IhyBglZy/H/C46P19kcana1IqYyKZGIRe5t9zcOM2fC3xWFEIIT4QH8pWbwcfjNU4W0YUTgr", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ramapithecus and Sivapithecus", 
		"option_b": "Homo erectus", 
		"option_c": "Homo sapiens sapiens", 
		"option_d": "Homo sapiens", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100144", 
		"question": "24e5ZZDj2A3i8oY1QV7lxO6/IWPVQ10unEC8bZw2znPfAJHDSiPOfBIwFiTWXQ==", 
		"answer": "27O9ZZD/1Ft7mgxBmsT+fJqgF7UT2BI6", 
		"explanation": "24e5ZZDj2A3i8oY1QV7lxO6/PG/VDXYYpXaGVuN1YzH3XKKCaOjzyJt0ZbeiahYaU1IAVUMtslibZC4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "female", 
		"option_b": "male", 
		"option_c": "neither", 
		"option_d": "both", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100145", 
		"question": "25T4epTjwxz58os0Uwr70/i/Om2QMWMcom+KRqtxc2TwFKbMaq3NwIFwN1WdhV5452WGparl+VdPhqYbzpyadSEGPoJ8iNSIw+HzhHBTPNNKnsBN26UgQ8t/jve3eaUWlG+zA53cioyuszA=", 
		"answer": "2+ToKJz63RXj+ItgSxvz1+6/NGzfQX/uwgWES/Y3KY04EIv6DdY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1An48pYlXArz0fTpMCvWDHcfpz+KXONTYnTmV6KCZ/6+zZZlIljJjEl053jC4/Sgt14Gg6RS5oDfaScCbJgvydeGlf2rtzqlSwQmQ8/ldsDZfto=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "10 million years ago", 
		"option_b": "50,000 years ago", 
		"option_c": "34,000 years ago", 
		"option_d": "22 million years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100146", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg2gzm+5ZgXRiy9/zyNHvZF2oUoGqQEqJ6dDHQXbHDfuTqwZJyMk/JjEl+snXJrbb581Ydiqwb/YHfcidDdoR4iN+F07u1+Cb/QOWN/RSlDapdQde16Q==", 
		"answer": "2+fqKJz63RXj+ItgSxvz1+6/OmfUQXkKyKqoMsiM9nInO1WF7z0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+1Bf+/oouVxqyxPr6dW3fESIFq3qQV+Nne2TvWLSCZ/6+yIdhNVORhFZ65nPKuuWipRMChqRX4IGRMDsGf5l8iN+F06aKMfOp0BZtstAbEbLK96QG", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "22 million years old", 
		"option_b": "34,000 years ago", 
		"option_c": "10 million years ago", 
		"option_d": "50,000 years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100147", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4kvUR/mzPLxdXzRECIQrT+CXq57Y2WjV6jPfuH73ZIxL1OEhFVy9jbVqLD8+xMLhrtY5piaYicHPoJhiIHQj7aohi8Phmk2Rxe8jDdq0bJ4vEI=", 
		"answer": "27ixbJX/1Fn89oksVweyyvu/IWPVQ0wQsXKCVqI2TXTtKNNB8JiFEyBml5BkZg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/3hrr44wvXF70yu+/IWPZECIVqmyAXbVxYmijQ6bRLvn2zNd8LliNgV475HfKr6Dpt1wJz7xT7M6xcTAOf49uiqDKy4HoaByoP8Y4d1agc3I=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Siwalik hills", 
		"option_b": "middle valley of the Narmada", 
		"option_c": "Potwar plateau", 
		"option_d": "Fa Hien cave", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100148", 
		"question": "24GwbdH13gr5/okpSBv2he70IGfcQ2QetnGHEqp6MGXrUefsb//zyJNwZ0qIgVd+6zbRoraw/l0Gm6Fa5YKGMCECcodqzI/LmpmL24WaDl1q/lFviN9gog==", 
		"answer": "2523ZZ6z1Avv9JE1QVwD3tO2b7Vxt+stkUd6Xsk9", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13gr5/okpSBv2he70IGfcQ2QetnGHEqp6MGXrUefsb//zyJNwZ0qIgVd+6zbPsOXz+F4CgKZX8M6NdSQGbJlqzJCd2KT21zFVO8MEpsJc5YgSffBBjBCseuiZYPF8jlLCCUTiaji5BTBHnyTahkAU6LSz8Cn7Xc531xQh1oFx/9sofNOWyquc/kiqgwLOnHKFCKplAhSQscum/0qaqYc89cye8TDe+Pv3nfHd954fbUhTscZ6YkmwjugB9ycxX8G6KBNF9aTHYEetKSaqMwcc9cf6lndoyo4sWSkItjdJj4wWZ9J21Yzxr3I+Pt9nFDe/rVdJ1Kg+HxWXZ7i8kGfqoFwrZjomaph9tCI5rgiVK1Vy2m2ZTThEhoV4spAOnQ1gdS9TiXHnhyyfhWHPdYej/IHvxemwrbxu8KY1aU6GdUjQU800ar7PZ2Jgz+qPGLUcII9iFCvjLpUa9Dy5DpeG0jgJ0ZkNLnmn/TnZgcTyN2y8upH4gMA2FroDN8TW7Iu+pBzVZDPzJG6WaN/nGQf+Sjz31U5xvx1lzSAC5GvdG50/5T8IlnejXUt2mySgZGmsl7Ac7I2dbIc9wLXq0icenLRxkdvj3Bh8bgq/hH5N8peKTV9Aw0DfEMgJ0EvYQLnPT+McyUXujJ9qREbB", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ramapithecus", 
		"option_b": "Sivapithecus", 
		"option_c": "Homo sapiens sapiens", 
		"option_d": "Homo erectus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100149", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRHr4YBgRhb3he/6OGrZDXFRrHnDeqx5fzHwVbfLa+PtiYRwN1WMg0g78HPDreXi8kMAnbxe7c6ZYi0OIclI5eYnezjTyBy0aMkXCJyJ", 
		"answer": "24aqYdHf0Bfh9sczyq393jG3g4mVE1E0x7RV", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1BTr/oszEhH0hdXwOGSQEGMBqnqNQeNncWHqUanRLuX/35IxJVmMgxt9/WPIp+X5+RM8naEbxY+ReyNBvmaWX9WYwyG77FQM9eLkFQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sri Lanka", 
		"option_b": "India", 
		"option_c": "Pakistan", 
		"option_d": "Greece", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100150", 
		"question": "24GwbdHyww3v8YQjRg2yw+/wOCvEC2dRhX7DeqpxfjHgVbHHLuzszNdwN0ybgkNy/3fSpqnpt1sAmOhU5YrAMgZpI4/DzxinUHkgIruZUPw=", 
		"answer": "2+bpJMGjgVnz8oQyQV79yfm9baoA5xWgd+0J0yD4lZwsYQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy1hyq+INgRhb3hfztIW7WAmEFsD+FQKx5MFfiFI/La+O+wIQxJl6GmE87oSeK8/Wgt0oKjrpIq9dngm6MosOBLdZZnN2V8CA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "34,000 years old", 
		"option_b": "10 million years old", 
		"option_c": "31,000 years old", 
		"option_d": "22 million years old", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100151", 
		"question": "25i3bJTh31ni4oghXA2yzPO/IWPVQ0sfp3aCXONnZXPgW6nWZ+P7x4MxJk6MzVh0/GXPp6Di8ldPm6cb64vfeC0UPoRjzI/LtqaVEYJKryouS0pO4lwgkA==", 
		"answer": "2+bsJMGjgVnz8oQyQV79yfm9g/4l42gpo/xnEluMWuQuiQ==", 
		"explanation": "25i3bJTh31ni4oghXA2yzPO/IWPZECIDpniKXa00cWPmFKXHYuT735J1Z0iGzVl+siWS7/WgpxMWiqlJ+s6QfCZBVxiyZuBK/y5re/FuvmkuKg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "31,000 years old", 
		"option_b": "10 million years old", 
		"option_c": "34,000 years old", 
		"option_d": "50,000 years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100152", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7/yvn6J2WQC3cconGQEqp6MFjtUK7DLuzszNdzIlCAiE1+9jbSrOX49kUKz6lJ+4eJdSZDeJlgxZCe3+30zDFFOtRBmZR765RAPuFB6U2BjVyJz1AL0acxs3Q=", 
		"answer": "24a3fYX7k5bwwu0n5oUrB2c1G81VdMQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7/yvn6J2WQC3cconGQEqJmdTHhUavLa/v7zddlKByBjE1+snXJrqCw8UEAguhP4YvfQy0WaoMtab9ORVEYTCBouUxZgS3nRg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "North", 
		"option_b": "East", 
		"option_c": "West", 
		"option_d": "South", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100153", 
		"question": "24GwbdHx1BXj8pMlVl7/zPrtNH/ZDGxRrHnDV6JmfGijWajGa//wiZ9kKl2Hnhtv/TbvraH59hMJnadWqa+ZYisAf8tnycCZ0urywDFAI9ZWlZh76ZsLefhZjDWiY5TWIfB3jneFJlfjJzi6Cy82tZNOIYnp1vm3U59fO3kFjQ==", 
		"answer": "2+DoJMGjgVnz8oQyQV7zwvK9iG4zcS98e/rx5Pw2g+cluA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHx1BXj8pMlVl7/zPrtNH/ZDGxRt3CMWeNkfHDgUefDfOLrx5MxcgzF3Qsrsm/Dorfjt1IIgOqruGkOqRFhmXVSEQQupXF4", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "31,000 years ago", 
		"option_b": "34,000 years ago", 
		"option_c": "10 million years ago", 
		"option_d": "50,000 years ago", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100154", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr68oYpVw2yzO6/N27cCmcHpnvDRqw0eHD1UefBYeD7iYN+Z13JiV569jbDraGw/l1Pm6Beqb2WZyMPd4Avy9Gd0uP41mgBPMAEko9/7ZQWeOcfjrvwrv13L6kux4x8W+ntNpk=", 
		"answer": "24e5ZZDj2A3i8oY1QV7zy/m/BmLGAnIYt3eGUbZnMtyNizcoVFTsPegoIvKKafQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2xxbm4pEpXRCyw+/wOCvEC2dRkHaUU699ezHgVbPHaeLs0Nd3KE7JmVN+4XOGsLX19FoKnOhI7IuSY2IXcctnycaMl+f4yXQBJ8kEm8B24ZsbPPFOyH93KS6QneC2H+ud4BzFXkwE", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Homo erectus", 
		"option_b": "Homo sapiens", 
		"option_c": "Ramapithecus and Sivapithecus", 
		"option_d": "Homo sapiens sapiens", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100155", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/l5JYpXl771r3+O2rEDG8YoH6PXro0YnTgW6DMZ/f7zddwNByIn1hz83/F443/+lxPnKlL4IuRY31Bt/JkYkY39urQUK4aWiv2aQ==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHg2gzm+8UkWw3xyuv6J27UQ2sf4y7aCvE0eX+jeqbQY+z6yNdnJlCFiEI5+hSBxtjyRqle6el0PsdASw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13gr5/okpSBv2he70IGfcQ2QDrHLDRqtxMF/iRqrDauy+35Z9K1mQzVJosnjJtOXi8lAAiKZS84ubMCMQPop9y9iI3ue37H5MPIZXm5B74ZQMPuSYDOO2nl5vhUcyW0p/oVw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The skull discovered in Siwalik hills", 
		"option_b": "The skull discovered in 1982 in Narmada valley", 
		"option_c": "The skull from Fa Hien cave", 
		"option_d": "The skull from Greece", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100156", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3RDs8pY0SxL3hfnwdX/YBiIXrGyQW69nMHfsQanGLuP7yIUxM1SMzX16sl7Ppquw9FIZiuhJ7J6NdTEGcJ8wimwVJSbRCDLr4tvKiKlZh1g=", 
		"answer": "272tZoX63x6q9oskEhj91/z4PGXXQeyGzpH4zSABaEJPrf+HIRk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13gr5/okzEhD3xO+/E2qQK2sUrT+AU7VxMGPmRLXHfejw3ddwZ1Scg09y/HGGoqv0t1UAnalc4ICYMC4KeI583MmF0qZwyj2MaUjeM5t8GgfbWvxf", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "farming and herding", 
		"option_b": "city dwelling", 
		"option_c": "trading and commerce", 
		"option_d": "hunting and foraging", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100157", 
		"question": "24GwbdH13gr5/okzEhjgyvC/BnnZQ04QrXSCErR8eXLrFKbQa62tndshdwzJlF564GWGrKn0t1Idiuha/ZqNeSAWao5riMSGl/P/zXJJc9ZBiIl94IlAPhMiSWmdVu/AAoGJilGVgrw=", 
		"answer": "25m5fJSz4RXv/pY0XR33y/i/NGXUQ0cQsXOaEot7fH7gUanHLP8jm0Q3Q8qothLZ+17CkDc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13gr5/okzEh/gwL3+JnjfAGsQt3qHErR9ZHmjQK/HLsH/3ZIxF1CMhEhv/XXDraCw9l0Lz41a+4KGMAoMcoRszd6Ml/Ty1nhON9UGIJiIW4Z1owMwv0ElKk5SBw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Late Pleistocene and Early Holocene", 
		"option_b": "Mesolithic and Neolithic", 
		"option_c": "Early Pleistocene and Late Holocene", 
		"option_d": "Upper and Lower Palaeolithic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100158", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWxCy0fX6dULeB2sQrT+QR6F3f3/3XanHYPm+wZZiZ12bmV5983XSsOXk/1Ibz6lJ7M6eYi0WcI8vm4HFh7SnhGhEMtRX2o9+4MVd90wirOXE2vRB+f9/wZawIQ==", 
		"answer": "25O5KLn61Beq9IQ2V1x01WP7FD80pOptFxvdGx1B", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHV0FnC/oAuEh3z0/i/PGWQMHAY41OCXKh1MHLsWrPDZ+PtiZZjM1mPjFhv4TbSq6Tkt1cOm60b64+ce2IXcctu2t+c2eC3lyANY5YU2pl35YgMPPVHw32EYJPIYPFgyy6PIQXkbzz9C3xwkSLCymxErYuy5jO0RtM0gB0nm4Z2rds1KNKMmaGdqFmwg0ar0n+YSbMkAkGbtsGm/0qSpYws9fmFtHL99bTRk/3dsN0KdA0St4dsI0uumL4A/C88Ed61ZAdK8+jVIV3jJiexKg8J8MTtlnVryZc9HX088V9Dg5Fae4B62JDlvjskPsN+BnO1pQRUz5E8TRKRfbK2kGnq5BUrfX8id8p6vTR1rgncJF14nyuYWT5Ymocr6tgc1TFzbWpS3Ebhjj6Oj2mGaJvq6MDsgPr5r70hKm/L1jV833usunIK/hMNzA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Narmada valley", 
		"option_b": "Siwalik hills", 
		"option_c": "Potwar plateau", 
		"option_d": "Fa Hien cave", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100159", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg2gzm+5ZgXB//wPm/B2rdAnIYt3eGUbZnMHDtUOfxZ/v/2Z5lL1mKmEg75XPUpuX0/kAMgL5e+4ubMCsNPpxnwdOBl/byw3hOPZkG4F6ccxX2uS1FTtn3xH9PEg==", 
		"answer": "24W3fIbyw1n6+4Q0Vx/nhfTxdVvFDWgQoT+TQKxieX/gUefNaK3OyJx4NEiIgxkAy4eQUclcn5/Mux+f3Wpp", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2gzm+5ZgRRvgwL35On7eByIYrT+XWqY0QH73Q6bQLv3yyIN0JknJhFU75n7D45Xl+VkOjehL+4GJeSwAe8tgzpC51u/+12VAPYQdIaoIwa7vuFbZlnpRaA7Z", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Siwalik hills", 
		"option_b": "Narmada valley", 
		"option_c": "Fa Hien cave", 
		"option_d": "Potwar plateau in Punjab province of Pakistan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100160", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3/Z90Z1qGnkhy/n/cpqGw5Fgag6Qb74GKfiZDd4Uv3NiMl8r21nxAN8cEjIF+6J8GPP1EyTO5fdLSJfouz33AD0r9aHm4FnV3gCTFtnJqptHytROzUZolxRgzn4lrrcc6fP+Q1KfT+0yojwOMzzuCSa1tFFqK9cap/Ubcooc9u42LvifV8LTwlLjg4tdLTglctIdDbWeyxOFJzCI9Ee61KDpC9OqQYlX7JWiqNE4J8c6j03V7yptpVGc89R1PloJYdtMz2Z6kqDo1f99vEjq1rQRJydRJTweTZv2I0WTl5VozfG4jbIktryQhpDOSH1x3mWPcQyoRgIhuvtEbmhJmPXxUnWLljzqFlHbPfYHmq4nyhufisrxg5vxlakGYD69zE/byZIFGRD32UA==", 
		"answer": "25u3ZpSz3h+q440lEh/wyuv6d9zw1yvjvQfBR2mrD6vVc9Y=", 
		"explanation": "25T4bp7gwhDm/p8lVl7hzujzOSvHAnFRp3aQUaxidWPmUOfLYK3qwZIxCV2bgFp/8zbQoqn88kpDz6lV7c6WZGIUf5gvwdSM2fD+wnhEN4ZFicBw4ZYQcvNJwjrtYNubCPFjwS6FNUDzcyyuRER8nSKWjnVFq4yt8DWiFNMkgAY7kYlx68E/PdmLmamAqESsxhaQ022YTLh3UVGPvMqt5UCZ4IQ3p42ZuTeb5Ob8if3d89tLbQ4Suodtb0L8n6cE8SQxVdv0YRwL5ezVIX3jJCGiKU4O7Mng2Xp9z4wsU30I+itOh5FTIslglp3ytTY1Mc5vVSeyolAAypt4WgWYNLWt3Wnq8xl/XXUmasp+vT08pAGPaEd/imKZQj8d1Ixi6NUd1Q1tPVxSlTbMgzGAgSWLaYHq5Ye8lfr1qLBw5qw1IELAIVXVU55cUbvFZ25hxuiVCeZUMownBCfwOMcv8HnpMpOc1ioZ38spLDf0/T6cgY3hMWSu84LrgcJ/ELpAM8fM7c65s1mHbiWhJHyBatK0UR39TnK42w9nvgwk3Cgf5l7WPIF6tT0FjH+jQEpj0ijmLGipn60c+ZaPa4s81vv4nTsD2PU4nZLjlBwrTBO6n3sP8oaKWxxbxVGWOMxH7AArAvQCFYDUsmSY1UXCQjwhfsD9AOiO0GxB1Of0i2U9sJ4LFYOIbA3Tj54v2xuwD/k+Rif+oYH3NPocCWUi7vJh2OipvtmveuGtLyU5Zg6ySq9w59VZaRE7CALYCSBKZPirQJQaRO5M1zXFkUdYVXpBDEnY9LoBXkSiv8nJYCrWYrMVGh/2arwLU8r5Wk7BMrGryTPCRquT1VO2WgQQXiqYM/A95Avxf4P+LQe7mmsk6cT3O15fBKsYKyLlcXn15aqXTBV6ej82LYRTc0bZCwQr1C7LNfh0iOcUeB1tUrymDVUbkx9b3zPdHF0Fs0AbXrehWRMzJelHJRsQzjSgA6ELWV4LKMIuVVz7bwGX8POd0IQY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "100161", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhyMjEl3+3PVt+X9+FcKnaYb4ZuScSwQPop9zZCL0uj+wWdEN4ZQlcB65YwaPPdPwTjtcsbULb56xmvAFErlczGBCkx6xniWvnRT6IG++S6+Qt8zgBg7kZV5+cEzMpeL1qeYqF20hwWHnHqDR6hqFRTM5YL4uxPcuYc5p97NsDXUyPrFlKuasOoDZ0hUsJVsale1ja0NuDkzRMS4KBRZ/umQdVzoYAaiNQMc/cqjwHVlyocwHWAntBFJlcNEZ8N80Zbtpjc0f8x5VTKooExBzpc8dxibe/2r0Xjt5VssSXQcbYNutG06p0+IIFE+m2mTWikRh5Rq6tUUkAp3bi9BjnOggTCZkmCMaMyhZx8QKWKPZUmj8ScBk3Ixsg==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuq+IssS1zFcTLAp79rBM9JHXd+bJt+", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7/yvn6J2WQC3cconGQEqJmdTHhUavLa/v7zddlKByBjE1+snXJrqCw8UEAguh675yWcyNPPophzJCd3+G3xnRNOsNSn4Qy6ZMYbvVUxTKjNMDUL/Uu3mKBJECwZiuyEX5w1GSGxiwG+MOi8CapR5o2xxpyoo9x/og1L5eMzLiD51+sgwLC3mLRTrJ3Al2V9cu+4keZroE9+Y2auTvY/LTqkvfE454faglG/5J3Zhu5lroF8S8rRYi5ZxZO4+qQaUHgISawZwcTue72xHt5w8IoU2101QxPg8NXcMUz0pnwuTZwK8IqFCG1tkpEh4B0VgTWYLS11VTq3FsLfX9rY4V+ryQ5qBWZLBRtkX6QQGxXho9mvsQRkERNfH1NnXLhwimKjGmKZdPq+MDyiv+wsrxg/aQpIFuFMRzZRc00ar7PZ3Rz2uCeA7UcOptmGzbzcZU59DD6KNadzHkM3pklN2Pu+imN0t7lPGaztoG5gdI2Fa0DPtDM6oufv1HIITDgMXSWaNi0TQDxWzz02hhgs1gsxmEx7nDRC4g/9ygZiXu1RwQ1xHesPCzx1r9S7sLfJtt9g6W8nSsVmeZr35rw210PSEj7hGsDu5ffQVNbjVXYXsgfxQQ+ALFBG5CR82PWkHfCR2VNcsHyBLqJgyRd1+L/zCtVT6PmhCFXN2pqLjbGsK0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> African Ancestors of Human Beings &  Early Man in India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "2 only", 
		"option_b": "3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwRHr5IAzEhfhhen3MCvgAm4QpnCPW7d8eXKjdaDHLuTwib5/I1WIzV9y5H/CpqGw/l0bgOhZ6J2adGIMcMt83N+H0qTjy35NIJkGDSUPjR4NxiWmZ2NgQMoXnA==", 
		"answer": "24GwepT2k+dHOls6BeiqHwTnzctKUcw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD0BXr8oosWwr6zP6/FGzVQ2sf41aNVqp1MHjwFKTDeuj5xoV4PVmNzVJ15nmGhqTi+0pPgLobxYGIdTBPPqZmzNSF0qi3xX9Fc/NUioVgpIoXfedF332vdcfeJL5hwC6UL0CwcyCtATB7knHFnnNYrcOv+ii3R5oi0xA21CJSiP9Xoewpa9IBiNbdgTo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "One", 
		"option_b": "Two", 
		"option_c": "Three", 
		"option_d": "Four", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxRDn8sUmQB//wL37Om7DQ3YZpj+mU7F4aTHsRufuYfr729dBJlCIiFR3+2LOqqaw5EMOgfcZ/Ex+z6A5HL0cNJ0LMHgsIw==", 
		"answer": "2+brKJz63RXj+ItixtMroV5AIQOCuSkyuv+Knw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHf3g7v5cUQUxL3yvH2IWPZACIYsD+XWqY0dXDxWK7Hffm+2oJzI1WfhEhy/XiGrKOw41sKz5ha5YuQfCsXdoJsiN+bl8v7wDFyJ8lKn8BT459fVeAA3y2sesebNPZrjnqJKkCwYSuyCTB1hj7DhHgW+9D7+C63WNM4zlUrk4Zq/og9O9jfzqCW5g2sjgPC2nKDW6kkFEKQscum6Ebcpo0q9d6ZvjzetOD2lfST4MwEZh1Rq49wbRu9maxJ7Tk9EcqtKBpE/O3eaFr+YCmzNwsc69ij33op0oosHWoh5g1DjJcWY9Jw3pnhsz4/OMRpFD/6sUFDyIZ4E1eDeqmx3Cjl8loqe35rNto98H1l8U+FLVVsiSudSyMd1JN7/94XnApkPXtImTbPjjuEl2SBPNvfqY3zge2w8YUhu+MmJ0XAFF/QU5gQYLLOZy9OiOSUCaMcYaMlXmLqNMEm9TrqYJ+a2ywexMspKmSlDqLmcGeMr5zYiPn092jk8g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "27 million", 
		"option_b": "33 million", 
		"option_c": "15 million", 
		"option_d": "31 million", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110103", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRDkt6ghWh/gxO73IXnRQ2sC43yMXLB9dHTxUaOCeuK+y5IxM1SMzV564HrPprbkt38AmK1Jqb6efCMGcYdm3NiA1KTkzWVEbITUESbjtabRs7cdDTWs5z6F", 
		"answer": "25e3epixnU/p4TMyH1osiG/QcPxtzg==", 
		"explanation": "25e3epiz2Aqq9otgUwzxzfz6OmffBGsSonPDQapgdTHvW6TDeuj6iZ5/Z3GIhVpp82XOt7fxuxMmgaxS6MLfcSwHPoJ7iNmal+f4ymJIN8NWn4Qy65QaPPtGjCmlcZTeIexix2uTMwXcaC64FjBElT3Xj3NaoZez/CT7R9MjxQZyn4k4+cA5fNSQzKaH+lT4sg6HnGiYXLgkGVWK9cyt7k3cpIMssMnNpT2b9eTpiPfL+dMKdg1epsYpMwvwx/hZuDM9UNqnKBNM/qT5dRTkM2iwLgkT8M3q1XVn0sIrWGo14QxDwopCItBh2Y7tuDcjf8h8HDe/rUdFh5t6HxKXZrGhkGDx7VQxNXsocYN7tTks4Q6SLBRqlWSQDDlCkcBv68IQmwMjaWdF3FrvlTqZwFWOcJLm5Iz1keD5o/lz97EuJkXAFE7MX4sdZqfTZ2F93+efTadIc71oBSumNNst8Cz9JdaHyzYD1Zk0IHjr52qVm8bweW27vZa5j8xzB/8BONWF6seysUrCczCtYWqbb8j8GQniSjz72w93thsxzTMZ+3bRC8lw820ZlnvwZUtzlzWgXH2tl7tT5ouad4cykbJvRuhi2s5TNlb/195O/rY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bori", 
		"option_b": "Bhimbetka", 
		"option_c": "Didwana", 
		"option_d": "Nagarjunakonda", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWh/hheT2MGfUBmZRoXCXWuNZeXXnWKKCb+P6iaJhN1mbzWt6/nfDrKn541sGjOhI/YGRdWIXcYRj25CA2aTFxXtAINJMm44tpt5IhtEJwSHk5ELDoI9fjJQ=", 
		"answer": "25GxbIby3xiozeyVBkMCsUrl1UCLeIFpuQ==", 
		"explanation": "25GxbIby3xiq/otgYB/4xO7rPWreQ3sYpnOHV6c0ZH7sWLSCaP/xxNdzKEiBzXZy9nLKpuXx+VdPurhL7JzfQCMPf45gxNmd3+30hHBGNtUGMBAiuwPRL4vucp+AU1Q9dA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bori", 
		"option_b": "Bhimbetka", 
		"option_c": "Chirki-Nevasa", 
		"option_d": "Didwana", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110105", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt5EvXRLhhfX+JivzC2sDqHbOfKZicWLiFK7MLsD/wZZjJk+BmUl6sm/Ppqn08ldQzfdfId/wVCPgTqW+p7ChgIs=", 
		"answer": "y+XoOMp7iQiBXf+VzwaosmE7ASs=", 
		"explanation": "25awYYP42FTE8pMhQR+yzPO/GGrYAnAQsHeXQKI0eHDwFL7La+H6zJMxJk/JgFp16zbHsOWipwNfz7xU5oKMMnmEpXa64a689prZ0OWicuQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 1000, 
		"option_b": 2000, 
		"option_c": 3000, 
		"option_d": 4000, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17/xPTxdWTTAHcBomuKXa00f3ejRKLNfuH7iZNkNVWHihtv+nOGj6rn8kFPvLxU54vfUSUGIckRQZ2w3Jg2nrh2fBily38T", 
		"answer": "25O3Z5Wz1hj+/4AyVwzhh0ALF2LAn84tkwcPQ98QUqs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy0fX6dUffFGcD40yXXa1xMFDkUefVa//7iYdjLlGIn1J36zbArKr0t1QOm6Be+4uNY2ICcI8v2tWF3uHzhH5Pc85RlJR76p1fb/lBwDHtc9XWJbIuyGeTLwmwZje5RHJ9hjXFyO3DakKpvvk9Fh6CK2ZBXMU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Tool makers", 
		"option_b": "Food gatherers", 
		"option_c": "Agriculturists", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110107", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yyfL8NH/VByJF9j+IX+Nnf2T3XOfNaK3cwZhhJlDJjFV/sn7HsOXF50MKnehr6IKedS0Pd59nwdPJxev0zzFSO8NIjoVg98Vdzq9VZKYyBJLqiV3saAg1aw==", 
		"answer": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sdLXirx6167altjdEFS9nNb", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9slgXhHxxOn6MSuEViIarj+QXbZgeDHsUufgZuLuyJs9Z1qMjE9u4HPV47f/9FhPnKBe5ZqaYjFDeJlgxZCd3+G38WFRNtQEqoF+5Z8QcP1UxDSuNMTTIe1rjABxJ9gge3JHH0MXA2tyQ6s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Bori", 
		"option_b": "Bhimbetka", 
		"option_c": "Chirki-Nevasa", 
		"option_d": "Didwana", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110108", 
		"question": "25Gtepj91ln9/4wjWl7zwvi/Im7CBiIFq3rDUK91dHTwFKbMaq383IV4JlCazV1053jC46z+t34Oh6lJ6J2XZDACMstO+JzJ/OXlynBVMs1F1sBz6p5fc+BIyS/tZtHcKfFg3THCLPmSA+W6hSFHWB0HvGYXpQ==", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NimBBVvzhA30bn2/RHhcB277", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZX2wlnr+YFgUAvgzPzzJivHBnAU42uMXa9nMHLsWarNYOHniZZiNFOKhFpv93KGtKzk/xMbh60b3J6PdTBDTopjydWG2+3jzHhCc9ZMm5N3pkTjuqgg3aPAGe+G1KB4xLY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Lower Palaeolithic", 
		"option_b": "Middle Palaeolithic", 
		"option_c": "Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110109", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRHr4YBgRhH9ye6/J27cAnYYrXjDRqw0cn73XOfvZ+n6xZIxJlKNzW5r4nPU45Xx+1IKgKRS/YaWc2ICeY58iNKM0uq3wn5UPcIb2NCirUm2r+0Qty1eZhJje+Q=", 
		"answer": "25G9a5Ly31na+4Q0Vx/nh6hmXb35+dTo1n2Ed7F/Q1M=", 
		"explanation": "24G3Z53gkR/4+IhgUBHmzb3rPW6QLmsVp3OGEqJ6dDHWRLfHfK3OyJtwIlOFhE9z+3WGoqL15BMHjr5eqYyadSxDeoJ8y9+f0vbywDFIPYZQkoUywJ8cf/VOjA2hdcDeIessUtEk+mKlHWtUXrODE49R2A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Thar Desert", 
		"option_b": "Belan valley", 
		"option_c": "Deccan Plateau", 
		"option_d": "Bori", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF77y73WO2/ZAiIYsD+NXbc0f33nUbWCeuX/x9cndwzF3Qsrsm/Dorfjt1canaFV7s6LeCdDW4p9xMnJ+OjzhEJVPMhB2qF14cVdNMIc0/nClb9SBnv4bk7pOQ==", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjyk7ZqZKivw9rSb214+RXRxvc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Avm7sUPXhqy9unwO26QImUU432GVaJ6MHDxW7LMaq3q3pgxKlWFgVJ0/DbfpqTi5BMOiKcb4IDfUSQRd4huhJCLwvC3zX8BGshAk4E+pJMLPPBB2Di+NNbaI/UuwWCMPgXkaHm8Fn9hmjWW3CwG5NPrpWeiUdsl01UzkYg6ur8V2rsjmOEENLuaOO9uSQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Africa", 
		"option_b": "Europe", 
		"option_c": "Asia", 
		"option_d": "India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110111", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7myvLzJivHAnFRtmyGVuNwZWPqWqCCeuX7ibp4I1iFiBtL83rHpqr8/kcHhqsb4ICbZTEXbIJq24/LRWM9YR4CAhK+rAZ+FLc2AQ==", 
		"answer": "25O0aZr2wlvzo1CT8XsHNuBwSIVYEXJ6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe2B3u+4BgYh/+xPjwOWLEC2sS43aNVrZnZGPqUbSCfv/3xJZjLlCQzU5o93KGt6r/+0BPjalI7IrffyxDeIduw9WalcYdpTAMlF+EXIHHXoYj2FM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Stones", 
		"option_b": "Bones", 
		"option_c": "Flakes", 
		"option_d": "Metals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110112", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRHr4YBgUwzmwPv+Nn/DQ2QDrHLDRqtxMFzqUKPOa63OyJtwIlOFhE9z+3WGoqL1t1EKiqYb7YeMcy0Ve5lqzJCA2aTlwX1AJ89LlMBm69oLdPEA4jy/edXfIb58x3iFNRqyOBvQxCRHR0ADTh7QHcbMFA==", 
		"answer": "24a9fpTh0BWq54khURvhhfLxdX/YBiIDqmmGQOEDGh4l9+/CdOfXQKwchdNJ", 
		"explanation": "25ixbJX/1Fna9okhVxH+zOn3PGiQAmUU436RRqZycXL3R+fKb/v7iZV0IlLJi1Ru/HKGorGw5FYZirpa5c6PfCMAe5gvx97Jw+zyhGNIJcNW2q5z9pceePUCEvdX0KARBl47iz9ZmChQjw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "At the source of the river", 
		"option_b": "Several places on the river", 
		"option_c": "At the mouth of the river", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110113", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt5YpRhvhhfvtOmaQF2oU40qTQqZmMEHiWKbHYeH33Z94JByZhVpo9zbOorP1t1EKiqYb74GKfiZDd4Uv4d6N3uWohkLfU84CD8ByX8MZStFSLzo=", 
		"answer": "zOPuI74LcChzWZy+brUn13lEmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25T4fJ7n0BWq+INgB0ikhe72IW7DQ2QDrHLDRqtxMETzRKLQLt3/xZZ0KFCAmVNy8TbWq6Tj8hMHjr5eqYyadSxDd49qxsSA0e3ywDFIPYZtlIR75dhpwP0GjWxgRlmRQvJxiaAM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 150, 
		"option_b": 566, 
		"option_c": 1000, 
		"option_d": 2000, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq+IslEh36xO/+Nn/VEWsCt3aAEqVxcWX2RqKCYeu+3Z90Z2mZnV5pskbHr6T1+F8Gm6BS6s6eYzEGc4ljydeMl+L40X9Fc89K2qdn7psNfeAA3zyjcJTfNfBr3THCyTm/SmO8bb1ynb/GIB9sNQ==", 
		"answer": "25a3ZYHywxj+/pMlXgeyyfztMm6QBW4QqHqQEObK4HYlcZJkGXbKJ5/W4W0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRomyQV652fHDkUefEYfjwzdd4KRydhV4752bWprew+1YZiqRIqYGZMDYLe8tI3dqIxeXjhGJAPcIEnpV84YlfdecAzzWsZtXYNPt8x3SFIwXyfnm+C31klSPXnnVArY+itSu6Rt0ygBM+l4x9/oR8PdqQ16/T51mwgxTCyHSeRP1wCEScpoxV+UzWiyA6SLa0DLovecQd", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Tiny blades", 
		"option_b": "Small burins", 
		"option_c": "Comparatively large flakes", 
		"option_d": "Rounded stones", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ/r+4klS1771r3tPGjYQ2sf42yXXa1xMGXsW6vRLuzwzddwKVWEjFc79HnVsKz85BMGgatX/IqWfiVDfYp73NyMl+X5wDFFNsNWxcLBJip75E+dsZI0aZEpR2g0", 
		"answer": "25e9ZJD9kQ/r+4klS1waEzXqDyVDmfCil1G7IG2v", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR1BXr+cU2UxL+wOSzdWffAGMFpnvDW600RUGvFK7RLv/3yp8xLlLJnk90/HOGt6r/+0BPjqZfqY+ReS8Ccstpx8Oa3ujkiDFIPcVIj4R76p1faPxP3zjte9KbI/962mKFZ0T+Y3m5AXVm1lm9668dn+/js5z/aibDFIs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Thar Desert", 
		"option_b": "Deccan Plateau", 
		"option_c": "Belan valley", 
		"option_d": "Bori valley", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110116", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEgjzyfH6LCvZDSIhtnGJU6E0OH/sQ+fLYK3OyJx4NEiIgxI7+nfV47z58l8LiqwbzI+NfDtDUYdriOOd2OryhFBGNoZXk5R398VdDxHJxzy/Y40GahWCdF7y8A==", 
		"answer": "24a3ZtH8w1nZ+I0hXFyojDam2qeWkdJB09a483DZ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHl0BXm8pxgXRiy0fX6dXnZFWcD40yMXON7YjHQW6/DYK33x9dBMlKDjFk7unjJtOX5+RM/jqNS+pqefmtDdop8iPWIxejuhF5NN4Z3jo984do+e/EA3zS5cceZh5o8pmxaqxkeO2R26A6TgQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganges", 
		"option_b": "Indus", 
		"option_c": "Yamuna", 
		"option_d": "Son or Sohan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110117", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn3hbm5MUmXQv8wb32OyvEC2dRgXqPU600ZnDvWKLbLv/7xZZlIhydghts+n/Fq+XD41wBiuha7ouML2ALAPAyTojLf59iW1N05T/j", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz/Rb98pdgUxD2hdD2MW/cBiAxBN+r8GMsLeQOirhlwm/Q", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR1BXr+cU2UxL+wOS/PWrDQ3sYpnOHV6c0ZH7sWLSCaP/xxNdzKEiBzU9z9zbqrLL15RMOgawbxIebdC4GPrh7x96Ml+XwwWIDX9P1SZVtN43xcKitVX67uQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only Lower", 
		"option_b": "Only Middle", 
		"option_c": "Both Lower and Middle", 
		"option_d": "Only Upper", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110118", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiy0fLwOXiQFGcDpj+TQKp5cWPqWL6Ce/77zddzPhyZiFRr/nOGp7Di/l0Iz7xT7M6zfzUGbMtfydyI0uv7zWVJOsUEm4d3u9jZ5JNp4PH1h5MxOxMX0z0T", 
		"answer": "2525ZpWz0AHv5MlgURL3xOv6J3icQ2EZrG+TV7FnMmABXHgV/G2vGpMedrTfM0g=", 
		"explanation": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgfhHlwO+/BWrcAmcer3aXWqp3MHDkUeuCeuX7iYdjLlGIn0I75nnJr7aw4kAKi+hM7JyaMCoCcI8vyciMxKi3x31EMtBBiJM+pJsReLRDxDK9ZNHJM7w0DPbm1Z6v2EgGtwmpw4T/", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Blades and burins", 
		"option_b": "Points and borers", 
		"option_c": "Hand axes, cleavers, choppers", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr68oYpVw2yzO6/N27cCmcHpnvDRqw0cnSjVbTRYe73yIN0IxyehE9zsmLOpuXV9kEDluhU+86zfzUGbMtc3N+H0qTWw3QBOsgEs4527ZtAPvZ3IRdkEw4JPbQOgWcd9hg=", 
		"answer": "2523ZZ6zwhj6/oAuQV711/LqJSkGLjIEpM25kKxGEg/cIad4", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Avm7sUvQF7eyur6JyvjF20fpj+iVaY0eX+jfanGZ+y+wIQxJVmFhF5t93KGt6qw9VZPjrtI5o2WcTYGest4wcSBl/D/wTFRNslUloUy65xfaPxFjBWiedubM/9+x2uONAX3dTaoFDLclMx3Em0VvfT9d13yqV2o", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Homo neanderthalensis", 
		"option_b": "Homo erectus", 
		"option_c": "Homo sapiens group", 
		"option_d": "Homo habilis", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110120", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohcn3MCvgAm4QpnCPW7d8eXKjdaDHLuTwib5/I1WIzVh6/DbEpuX0/kUGi61fqYeRZC1DaoN9zdXJ0+3k0HhPMNIEiohz958MPPZB3zipNNvVYO16wWCFZ1H/aDWuRHF6kHHVhnVbqZey9me4XNs5xxAhqolE44gOOdaM1qbToH/x3Ea21H7RXLV2FFHZpcap+EaP4IMqsI2osCDX7bT2iLj//8kOcEhivop+ZlSwnrwB8Sl0EeW9bBZH9KTgYFjsJSevLhoV8MivlnVnwsIcTXkx5l92g49XZ89/34zstTFy0ML5xC/H8ecRVQnuzOhdRw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzmTijt4QuVl6697S/NHnVQ3YDtnrDU61wMDnRHefLfa3qwZIxJFObn1545jbDu7X89l0Om6FU586QdmJLX8ItXL6kpvkfb2z9/1PHqtICoA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD0BXr8oosWwr6zP6/FGzVQ2sf41aNVqp1MHjwFK7Mauj7zdd1LkqAiV5/sn/It6qw41sdiq0b+YaeYycQJMt7wNXJ8uXlyGgBPNQEto9l4YhfTPVMzTiieN3PKPdtgi6UL0CwSjC5AHxx1AHXhn1Tp4+y4S+yV5Z3wRs21pNw6IgJLMeay+ij6UG5gwmO1W+ZQb4kJVyQpo6s4lWVs4s3u42EonLZ9ef8nrjc/p4fag0Sq59vZkj8mK5J6z43X830fB1E/feQdEfoJGinMhwU98yjwnxs1YdpTWwm/RBCkcNXbMQzwpDh/DE8NsBrATq540dIxpp7WgTWYLW5xCjt7lMzYH8lZo9p/CUgrA6SaFV6m3uITThYm44r/94d1Rd2b3lJinfswguDhSW9eZLw5I68zdq54Lhg8bY1KFWFOUWYU4EdZ7zSJnN32amUA+ZIO5onNjH1OMc69Tb3YN61lnVN3dgrJnngtCiWhsW1KnG7p5f0i9piB/8UJMTAqcq5tBzVZC/gNXiXJK78LtIXCG0D4B/D9H+3jRk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both (A) and (R) are true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)", 
		"option_b": "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is not the correct explanation of (A)", 
		"option_c": "Only (A) is true", 
		"option_d": "Only (R) is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110121", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohcn3MCvVAnAdqnqQRuNYf2bmRufyb+H/zJh9LkiBhFg74X/SpuX5+RMmgaxS6M6WY2IPcYhu3NWNl+35hFNOIc8I2q1z7JsNfedI2C+sSNrnLsxrz32PKQW4VXDnRFJ7hjiWg3IWhYKz9DW6R9Ij0hRykoZs6Nt8Ptac0uiH5w25lhaQ02OYRbxwFFiA9Zj4uw/M8NJ4rMiMoyGb9fP22Gtg+7gP2U/CHnpEYnZYogg=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzmTijt4QuVl6697S/NHnVQ3YDtnrDU61wMDnRHefLfa3qwZIxJFObn1545jbDu7X89l0Om6FU586QdmJLX8ItXL6kpvkfb2z9/1PHqtICoA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7eyur6JyvgAm4QpnCPW7d8eXKjR67Wa633x9dYKViAjBty4TbPraH18ldPg6dY6JqadGIKcMtNx8KAm6TaxXlAIcdXkpRg5do2aLRJ332ue9rIKfpr3GuEZ1H/Jzu4RH96kXHZjDxCoIb7+iu/UckjgAY7goJroYg4PcOW16/T6ky7jUaW0zuQWK12HkyQuM+87k+F4NRo5YHd4WKb7fH4iOuT8dkEIjxausZNZlqvmKZJsBhxEcm3awdZ8PDVbU2tJSSiJQEP+N/mxTRmyMI9VWx01QxVh5FCa899ltDF9X5wMsxhHD2940ZP05w8TAOXYLi11Wbw8xUrZ28uJYtjuG0npAOdPFF62PAi2F2KiYCW+wdz6E4iWVI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is not the correct explanation of (A)", 
		"option_b": "Only (R) is true", 
		"option_c": "Both (A) and (R) are true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)", 
		"option_d": "Only (A) is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110122", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohcnwOmfDQ20X42uLV+NZeXXnWKKCb+P6iaJhN1mbzWt6/nfDrKn541sGjOha7ouMMDUGbI4vzt+c2eC3zX8BJ85B2qR355kecrRwwDy5cdXOHPBSwFyFJlb/aXn1Njku1AXejzxyrYC49Cn7ZNY21BAzg8dx/oguNdSXmaGdqEyqhQ6D2XSdR7ptElWV9c+6/0qaoYEspo2Loz3WtOL4iPHc5c1LYw9XrMTAiyUOtD9Q8e/kKcyEKi9q", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzmTijt4QuVl6697S/NHnVQ3YDtnrDULZgMDnRHefLfa3wxoMxM1SMzVh04GTDoLGw8ksfg6lV6JqWfyxDcY0vgPHAlYMpUnNNWCpxAV00kn6sQNs=", 
		"explanation": "24G3Z53gkRbst5EoV17fzPn7OW6QAmwV40qTQqZmMEHiWKbHYeH33Z94JByIil5osn7HtaCw/l0Liq1fqYyadSxDeIR6xtTJ3uq30HlEc+JBmYNz6tovcPVUyTy4NODTJb5Ky22DJkuwVzW8EHV1gXHfmTxXpJC0tSy1W805gBM9hMd66MEyO5eN0KubqES2xgeQ33OQTbJoHlOQts+kq0KOtIs+tM6ZonLd5vv02u7S4tcEdxsSvoF6cBuUmL8M7i8qHYigYBcL4+3TaVroMzvjKAhd7cPmllBsxYEoUykE+B5Sh4JDIsl9lpn2vzoxOsJmGjSzoEVMh5VuSx6Qdb6swyjt8xUxem5rdppovyQzqAydJFhn2mqSDClJhIxq8NENnAttPWlPjjb3iibLrWyLeJ/mq4HygajFsKlm4OMXKE2BMFPUX5kUbLCAM2h9xvrbGqNONt9hGDfoOZU69DzrJdag1zwf1d8vPXKrtCiWhsW1KnG7p5f0i9piB/8BJNSF/dmitRCHYzb1YU+WZ9j7V0i4fTW42h0luRcxiDUY7SLbB5tt8C4Z3nuoWUhlnCb0ZXOv1rhT+MKvbJ00weHl0jxQ0NUx3VsaR25eVrno926MYKZzqZU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Only (A) is true", 
		"option_b": "Both (A) and (R) are true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)", 
		"option_c": "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is not the correct explanation of (A)", 
		"option_d": "Only (R) is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110123", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQnv5YwvVl7w1/L+MWfJQ2YUpXaNV7A0ZHnmFJLSfujsiadwK12Mgldy5n7PoOXg/1IciuhS5862fiYKf9QtmhzV8S5lt/nVkKanzo9lFw==", 
		"answer": "2+btJMGjgVn++MVxAlKila2/F0iSPxDLA6jbk7W7HmNLAtPrRg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRs3eCQaY0eX+jfanGZ+y+wIQxJU6GjF936zbCpqP5+VYLz7xUqYaeZidDaopkzd7Jx+j2x3QBMcNQjYV36tpMKbgQnG3tddrfYK8+gj7QdwXSRHu+GUcP6Wr1OK0A6EyKMSuH", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "150,000 to 35,000", 
		"option_b": "600,000 to 150,000", 
		"option_c": "10,000 to 1,500", 
		"option_d": "35,000 to 10,000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110124", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7myvLzJivHBnAU42+RW651YnjvTefXfej6iZNkNVWHihtv+nOGj6rn8kFPv6lX6IuQfCsXdoJsiN+bl/D/wTFkMtRIg8Bd6J5fT+BPwjjtVdPef7wYA0i8aPp3rPcuJcYhQmKV", 
		"answer": "2525ZpWz0AHv5MlgURL3xOv6J3iQAmwV43yLXbNkdWPwFnToSrsMr7/2ub3BNzI8QEI=", 
		"explanation": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgfhHlwO+/BWrcAmcer3aXWqp3MHDkUeuCZuzwzddwP1mawRt4/nPHtaDi5B9PjqZfqY2XfzITe5l8iMeMxeG31GNIPsdWk4xrpI8MefACUgpGwZghx7SSW8Lxf7vE5Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Hand axes, cleavers and choppers", 
		"option_b": "Spears", 
		"option_c": "Bow and arrow", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110125", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5MhXhL33L33NH3VQ04etHqREpN1fHDmW6vLeuX3ytdlKFOFnht593PI46P/4l0Lz6FVqbuLZCMRPrt9ydSMxOyohpvHGD6+1hs46jOwhiNJ/lo=", 
		"answer": "25e9ZJD9kQ/r+4klS1waEzXqDyVDmfCil1G7IG2v", 
		"explanation": "25m3f5ThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NivEDG0dsD+LU7VxMHPmUamCaOLrx5MxLlLJmVN+slTDr6T+t0UOg6Re8M6WfmI2ap9u2pC5xeXzwWJJcaUJPbwhaxhBOcuCKnuwFg0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sohan valley", 
		"option_b": "Belan valley", 
		"option_c": "Deccan Plateau", 
		"option_d": "Thar desert", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110126", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17iwPLvOW6QDGRRt3eGEo97Z3TxFJTWYeP7ibZ2IhyAgxtS/HLPouX99loBg7Eb+4uTaWIMcMtpx8LJxPHk0HRPMshHn98wQsBF3TMMYht46mc0k0c0Dw==", 
		"answer": "252tZoX63x6q9oskEhnz0fX6J2LeBCB0pJvfX+yZBoQ1p2EBeVc7", 
		"explanation": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgfhHlwO+/Bn/fDWdRgniGEqp6MFjtUK7DIq3uzJhhK1nJnUly/3fUqqnpt0EKg6Fe7c6QfmILa4V7wd6Ol+X5wDFGMtJMn5J76p1fevtSjC64Z8DeLv9gzWvOZ3H4YiD9DGV6gDTSymtfpIf79CmyWds701UnhY526ogsLt6S0Lya/kj4kgmN0GjRSbNgUVeWucKt6FeZpMI9scSPvTeb5Pj4lOzAvJ4NcB1bq5UzI1qyk+gH7T4rEc6mZx8L5ezVaEatJSa1LhwS98bm2GAnhqMuT2A34RNSl5FTIsF90tjnvSYkM8gqHTaop01OwNRrWgWTNLO3xCj95UF/ZWgqZp5kvygx4QuJOl1wnSuIRCVC1JBu7NkWkUojW2ZTlH/uhXPLl22GcJaj6sDvkPjgrLxu960zKFOZdVrXWYlcdrzVNWR3hqmMDLUcPZBzVzbuOJUj/TD3M4KVxnkC1pk0J3Lu5mqdm8jhdyfJ/xd2Lvo2P0ZYIX2DD0WK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Agriculture", 
		"option_b": "Fishing", 
		"option_c": "Hunting and gathering", 
		"option_d": "Herding cattle", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110127", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhykhF9//nOGk6T89lYAg6FP4YecMDILf5hqiNmHl835wHhAc89X2pB+5ZkaeLRCySm6cdHVYK87niLQdxWwZje5RCMh2GGG2jx0i7+1p277dtUlyVU7hcd74sYvNdOay62XqFmwg0aH3WmdQbh3BRS1utmt+W6Zs400vNmFuDGb5/3tn8Tdo5dLURxdsYM/d1Szm7tJ7y8qVIihexdPseLfcxTrITquLgAaxcXU3n1qzsImWykg/BoGg4FZdMUzxYzlqDc9OsN+BnO7sUEAzpp/UAWEcb6sjyo12GuX+inuHvRnlBZ8QCKI", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqq+IssS1z5CJjjQYToCkb2LtWsGmEU", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe2B3u+4BgYh/+xPjwOWLEC2sS42+LU7BxMHjtFI7MauT/iZ5iZ0yFjFh+9jbEprHn8lYBz/kOucLPIHJDf4VriIPcm7SnlDFjEPpKuI9g7doWb7RDwzO+fdDeMvtqjnqIIgX1ZiuxDXVngHH6hWtTusOL9Cu6UdU7yQE6n4Q4/sEoOeuR6ryc5kj4kgmN0GjRX7h2FBSMpsusq0WTssI7vcKdoTvV87i5nvHU99cFZUQSvoh7I0i3nqYH8SQ/E3w2cwF/nIdx3PB9mMrowN8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110128", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhybglhwsmXOpqnk8kEcz6ddqayXeS8Be59kyZCE1v23zHBXNoZGn4V8pI8MefAAzS7tZNHJLf9gy2CUZ1f1dDC5AX53kSLqhC4f6Ku6+yP7VcIy01U0hIh1rdw0OZez1r+W+g2IhwqD2XSdQalsGFfZtMmtq0udtod4t8iIv3Ld++H3nrjX5cwCbA8Sq456I0+1mq1J9yx4RcCxKAZD+PbUIXzkLSmvJhcc94vq2GBs1M8uUWg3/R5Si4xYXs4gn9jQsz08LI1sBzy340ZP05w8Sx+TNJCx1Gzo5RU+e35rUJp9uT91kQ6QKVFxlmKIRCVS1IFs+8NZnQV1eC9CmXPuwjuCk2aAapbx7oS8jOawtLFmsociKkKBOxzoWowIYLLVG2lFwuCYBeZTNd9zHyemPNch6jy5M4KVyzwA1dc0PDfm5i/ZkcLnK2C5p827dluEdSgWZdXgbvbi2d3aYg==", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh3hrht5YoVxLmwO/sdWbRGiIZommGErBxYmfmUOfDfa3tzJZiKFKIgRt483vWsJn+w1sKluhM7JyaMCQMa4VriNScxe35wzFVO8MEiYVx65QbPNxJwTyhdc3aLr5nwHqFNQj3azi+DXFgnT7YtnJip4y35me9RtU6gBc9go84+cA5fPqW3ayf7Q25iALC6WuBTa8kIVWVtMun50qIqIs79cyKtCGb/PXvn7jR9dsFIgxbrIVwdV6ukqxJ8SR4RcCxKDZO8ufRbxTdLCm3Ig8IuyIbWQwPONQ7/1MhwCx7WSU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110129", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3ibZkNV2Hilp583KK46n/9FIbiqwbvdvfey9DbYR63NjJ2OK35nlOI8dI1sB04ZsLaeZF332/e9fQYO1my2KUIlfjJz+vC300gDnTyklGuIaptRe6WNsyzxk7go9x7ogsNNaM3JSd1EPqz0ag0HqVTa4kEFqd9cy9+UqdrJF4osiftHLP+/v1ibjQ/9MGbQZepsZ+cEizlKEI7C88Ed+9fBoL5ezVIWH9MC2xZz4c9crm2Xhg0oogXikk/B5Vh79YXs4gn9jQtDdwHchmFD36tUVMy5FlHx+XZ/2h2W3o5FA7NW4kaoZ+/CsnrgLcJ1pygyuxRShVmIUr7cQWmwEjfGhFoHjXijaIiCWAetP344W8hOr/trwj4bcmPUSNMFLMRc0dd7aAJGhg2OyYGfke9+D5oLZvJovzGMdrw6Ev7g==", 
		"answer": "2+f4Z5//yFuwo8gtRcpR5VdHb9SvxQyG", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9slgXhHxxOn6MSuEViIarj+QXbZgeDHsUufgZuLuyJs9Z1qMjE9u4HPV47f/9FhPnKBe5ZqaYjFDeJlgxZCd3+G38WFRNtQEqoF+5Z8QcP1UxDSuNMTTIe1r8mCiK0T0Yir9BX5w1DPDmHVXpJD74iKpUZojzxo+hcd74sUxM9mTwOiS+163hQ+DyH6VCKptBVzZocatq3aMsIcq9f2MvTPe+/jwjvDa854baglBurpxV1O514oM9Cs2Ed61ZB5O6KTYYEetOSGmKwoY/Yv32Xtl1cIvT2Y5tB1JlosWdsh2lrTrqzcif8xkEXOXqkBEy5E8bAOZerj40W/h8xfWaYM91cJKChfhGgX8Z138", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110130", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUzWwr31r3rOivEC2cYsT+RV7BkdXL3XbHHLv7qyIN0NB7NraXVuADX3Q5OlOM9HtsC", 
		"answer": "25e3epi+/Bji9pchQRbm1/yzdU/ZB3UQrX7OYKJ+cWL3XKbMIq3QyJBwNVacg1pw/XjCoujR+VcHnakb2ZyedCcQdsmFYjOUScl67si2rplZfAIg", 
		"explanation": "25e3epiz2Aqq9otgUwzxzfz6OmffBGsSonPDQapgdTHvW6TDeuj6iZ5/Z0iBiBto5nfSpuX/8RMijqBa+4+MeDYRf8tG3JCAxKT8yn5WPYZClZIy7Y4MPORSyTWkZ8DUMvdtjmiJKUH5aT6uOH5ImhXfjmtXpoL7/DT7WNU0wQE3ksdx44gOPd2eyryb6UP4hwiGnHKCCK5tFlqQs8er6k2I4IQ3p42EpSGb5PX1n/ff+coDawsSvoh7I1a5hKcF8T4wWMv0bhtF9e3eZkfRLhStCQ8a+Nnpw3pozY0nWWh0/QwGg40Wa81j2YrwvTwkf+9/ETeyqldUh4d1SxLWeLK70Xzh5BU2ezoKa45lrix1kR2dLFFtkikOudFNtzXZPwl/gkBSS1SP", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bori,Maharashtra", 
		"option_b": "Didwana,Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "Nagarjunakonda,Andhra Pradesh", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110131", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0XRH+1r3rOivEC2cYsT+TQKp5cWP6FLLRa/68cRDx5f1iEJw1/F9ndx3yXQ==", 
		"answer": "2525ZpWz0AHv5MgjWhHi1fTxMieQIG4UommGQLA5Y3rqWqnLYOqyibR5KEyZiElov3LPpKL5+VRNlvz+7f+0WS64Ffkf0pqKYA==", 
		"explanation": "2525ZpWz0AHv5MUhQBuy0/jtJmrECm4U42uMXa9nMGXrVbOCeejszNdhNVWEjEly/m+Gtrb18xMJgLob6oaQYDIKcIwv39+G06T2ynUBMclKn8wy5o8LPPdP2TGpNNXXM/EuzGvAMlb1Y3m7C2I0myXej24WuJap5SioUcl3zBw5k8d85M87NdmYmaeBqE6tkhKL0nzRRbhlBWiXicCL50adtocqpo2atCDetOfpn/va8dICeA1W/5JwbFev16UI8SQ0SIihexdPseLfcxT+KyGtKQcT/ovi2H1kx446HWg68F9Fl5dCa850lpXhvSYMMfFkNju1s1RF1Yc8SBKEcf2qxWzt7VAxYXs5fMp5syI5sk+JO1F62m2TXmxQ1JZq7NkcgR0jcmkAjGPykjCYhXbDPJrt6IzpgeH+p/ln+6QgIE+HeRzbQ5kIbL3HaydzxO3bD7RZMpRuGSWk/GKsLappr5zZLXH4eqwrKw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hand axes,chopping", 
		"option_b": "Cleavers,skinning", 
		"option_c": "Choppers,digging", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110132", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwWh/hwL3rOivEC2cYsT+XW65xMGHmRq7Nav68hBO5x3zPTkRUhwXekZ6nPg==", 
		"answer": "25C5ep3qkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NiaGUzJB8y/DRqw0ISSzBPeSLs/dhbp4I1iFiBtL83rHpqr8/kcHhqsWuNvPIHJTPp9giIPch7SnhFNif4ZxipB39tovffhByTKhfcDTKf0jnTvQdxWwczb9VSAkxGGWqF8UlHOaFQnkZx7lSQSeMCPwXg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Avm7sUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRs3eCQaY0eWKjU6LMa///xZtoZ1+Gg0hy9nPUpqGw41xPnLha586ZYi0OPop9x8WH06ShlCENY5YU2pR9pMtKLLgQnG3tVvebCeoux33AJE3xdTi+EHVmnSvTjjxUscOv/SL7QckygBo01pRx4NgwOZeX2KaXpUyggxXC3XWVCL5sHkSJsNy7102grrYwsI2guDbf+PG5qvnf8dsEbgFGt498I0u0lrsMuDkoUManKBNb4fbfeV3gITymKxdd/9ns2zQ4k9JlDTlktAtJwtADLpAjhtjGn3IEN8R5VSO/sU1Pw9RvXgDWYLW9kH335RUwczomapho/D46sQeVO0B3mWqISSgRkoxq9dVZgQtscXx8kkrutjeOwFCfbJbxq7D9ien1r7Vq5qsuKgGQPV3LU80TZrDVNXV3zqmZCLJLNpppV3GzcYV+rHntL9bFj3VdgIlgDVSnwCKQgY3lMWSpttLwnZR7Fa0LM9WF69L3pFTCITbyJD2cYIv1XR7xQX/9105xuBcp22ER5maYHIF6tSgAm2y3TEpnl2fvajyyj7Ne5Y6HfM4wweGs3DwU2PtqkZr60RMoRhCygnEBnsLkJwXI7ulTStI/FrZVoQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Early Palaeolithic,600000 to 150000 BC", 
		"option_b": "Middle Palaeolithic,150000 to 35000 BC", 
		"option_c": "Upper Palaeolithic,35000 to 10000 BC", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110133", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwVwz7yvm/ImLECyIFq3rDU7Bnf3LqVbPHaq323JpwKRyOn1Ru4jTLyT6DeEByIiF0GE4cZSGY", 
		"answer": "25C5ep3qkRb4t6kvRRvghc7rOmXVQ0MWpj/OEot7fX6jR6bSZ+jw2td2NVOcnRnPr+Ij4s7PWEYL9iGjHI0q", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Avm7sUvQF7eyur6JyvjF20fpj+iVaY0eX+jfanGZ+y+wIQxJk+aglhy82LDp+Xn/kcHz7xT7M63fy8MPphu2NmM2fe3w2NOJtYGdxAqHI5Xf6ybDa/Iw5u3eA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Neolithic Age - Homo erectus", 
		"option_b": "Early or Lower Stone Age - Homo sapiens group", 
		"option_c": "Mesolithic Age - Homo neanderthalensis", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110134", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUzWwr3her2IWOQF2oU43GWX6FxYjHsUufWYeLy2td3KEmHiRl4YR9oYQIYHF5BGaDgyVii", 
		"answer": "25awYYP42FTE8pMhQR+yiL2tZTuAQ3YerHOQEL9YceNgeQOtLWZdJ7V+zAM=", 
		"explanation": "25awYYP42FTE8pMhQR+yzPO/GGrYAnAQsHeXQKI0eHDwFL7La+H6zJMxJk/JgFp16zbHsOWipwNfz7xU5oKMMnmEpXa64a689prZ0OWicuQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bori - 500 tools", 
		"option_b": "Didwana - 300 tools", 
		"option_c": "Chirki-Nevasa - 2000 tools", 
		"option_d": "Nagarjunakonda - 100 tools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110135", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuy6PT7MWfVQ1IQr36GXa99ZHnqV+fLYOnr2oNjLlmazVl64XPC46r+qBHliOWo/FzNV5p8nBSa4DqP", 
		"answer": "25O0aZr2wlnl5cUzXx/+yb3vPG7TBnFRrHnDQbd7fnShPvDdQqhlv/o/1i0F9R29pw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe2B3u+4BgYh/+xPjwOWLEC2sS43aNVrZnZGPqUbSCe/77zdd3K12CiEg7/WSGsKjx+19Pn6Fe6ouMMC0FPph7x96MlaqCQ3V2jkwz9k8rqHJ3pHo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Flakes or small pieces of stone", 
		"option_b": "Large stone boulders", 
		"option_c": "Metal tools", 
		"option_d": "Wood pieces", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110136", 
		"question": "24GwbdHjwxDk9IwwUxKy0fLwOXiQDGRRt3eGEo59dHXvUefyb+H/zJh9LkiBhFg78XnLs7f55FYLz6ddtsz4LzRYqRlm78N+6nwte0BR", 
		"answer": "25e0aZX2wlWq54opXArhib39OnnVEXFd436NVuNnc2PiRKLQfa/TvyKkenDBFJRgCxaGcjzE", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+0BDkt5EvXRLhher6J26QAW4Qp3qQHuNkf3jtQLSOLu/x25JjNBDJjFV/smXFsaTg8kEcw+ha5YLffSMHe8tgzpCP2+X8wWIDQrBhl6CWfjzY+VsRy4wHjQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Blades, points, borers, and scrapers", 
		"option_b": "Blades and borers", 
		"option_c": "Chisels and hammers", 
		"option_d": "Spears and arrows", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110137", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRj48sU0WhuyxO/rMG3RAHYC43CFErd8dTHOXaPGYui++ZZ9JlmGgVJv+n/F46T38hMJgL1V7dHdpJ6XyD4NEkdOr8SeU9w8Wg==", 
		"answer": "24exfpThkTfr5YghVh+yxPP7dXjfFnYZ43CFErd8dTHXQanFb+/2yJNjJhybhE1+4DTc3895R1Qj6isGKOkYQ+9p", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyww3v8YQjRg2yyvu/IWPZECIQpHrDU7FxMHfsQanGLuzqiYR0MVmbjFc74nrHoKDjt1wBz7xT7M6NeTQGbMtBycKE1uD2hHBPN4ZXlZVm7NoQerRUxDjtQMHVJ/9sxm+ENUSwdTCrAWI2pIyy/Xe6XL3s9hODYpkQvQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "River Yamuna", 
		"option_b": "River Ganges", 
		"option_c": "River Indus", 
		"option_d": "River Narmada and south of the Tungabhadra river", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110138", 
		"question": "24GwbdHR1BXr+cU2UxL+wOSzdWffAGMFpnvDU7c0ZHnmFKHNYfn2wJt9NByGixtv+nOGlaz+81sWjrsXqYeMMDAKfYMvwd7WlQ1Y7wVM7z49/drlOVrVBbc=", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kQ3l+IkzEh/8wb3+O2LdAm5RpXCQQap4YzNt/gQ3lRvJX4vyZO8euAsq", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR1BXr+cU2UxL+wOS/PHiQEWsSqz+KXONnZH7tUefWYeLy2tdwKVjJjFVy/3fK46P/5EAGg7sb4ICcfDcHd4VoiNOIw/D7wTFAPcIEnoV39tgKSjFTc4wpwxkbJr8TMdCl", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone tools and animal fossils", 
		"option_b": "Precious metals", 
		"option_c": "Clay pots", 
		"option_d": "Ancient scriptures", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110139", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt5YpRhvhher6J26QBW0ErXvDW600ZHnmFJLSfujsiadwK12Mgldy5n7PoOXg/1IciuhS5862fiYKf9QtTsmJjYlZ7Sc+zQB/z1cssw==", 
		"answer": "zOPuI74LcChzWZy+brUn13lEmQ==", 
		"explanation": "2+DuPtHg2A3v5MU3Vwz3hfvwIGXUQ2sf42uLV+NBYGHmRufyb+H/zJh9LkiBhFg74n7HsKCw/l1PpqZf4I/donxViWMR/FHHn9p9856EWQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 650, 
		"option_b": 700, 
		"option_c": 600, 
		"option_d": 566, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110140", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnf55UlQF7CxPH+MGTcCnYZqnzDQqt1Y3SvFLDKb/m+xJZjLFmNzU9z9zbHs7X19kEOgateqYeRMDYLe8t4x8KF06T0y39VNt5QxcLGeZTd87XvE0CfFFPxM/it", 
		"answer": "25u9f9H13RDk48UpXBrn1untPG7DQ2Mfpz+rXa57MGLiRK7HYP6+2pZhLlmHnhn8h1VM8lekzPRLRUnFQ2ML", 
		"explanation": "25ysKJzywxL5t5EoV17z1e36NHnRDWEU43CFEq1xZzHlWK7Meq33x5NkNEibhF5osnfIp+X98l1PgK4b/YaaMC8Meo59xpCdzvTyhDlpPMtL2pNz9JMacucA3zy9fdHVM7csz/4Dua33nRDMDW3QbHSTig==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Advanced farming techniques", 
		"option_b": "New flint industries and Homo sapiens sapiens", 
		"option_c": "Introduction of metal tools", 
		"option_d": "Rise of empires", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110141", 
		"question": "25e0aZX2wlnr+YFgUAvgzPPsdWLeQ3YZpj+2QrNxYjHTVavDa+LywIN5Ll/JnVN64XOGqquw3l0Lhqkb/ouNdWIFcZ5hzJCA2bu1oFVt/EA0Dn/vpjRGKqDpqw==", 
		"answer": "25SIJNHY0Avk9pEhWR++hdD+PWrCAnEZt22CHuN3dX/3RqbOLsDOhddiKEmdhV5p/Dbzk+mw3VsOnaNT6ICbMCMNestuzNqG3ur+ynYBMtRBm5MwHj1akVKSijnlkU+aRck4Lg==", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZX2wlnr+YFgUAvgzPPsdXzVEWdRpXCWXKc0eX+jQK/Hfei+25J2LlOHnht/52TPraKw41sKz51L+YuNMBICcopqx9yAw+z+xzFRO8dXn8Ld0gj4VbHDfM75BqIACIok", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "AP, Maharashtra, Rajasthan, Gujarat, MP, UP, Bihar", 
		"option_b": "Kerala, Tamil Nadu, Telangana, AP, Karnataka, Maharashtra, Goa", 
		"option_c": "AP, Karnataka, Maharashtra, central MP, southern UP, Jharkhand and adjoining areas", 
		"option_d": "Delhi, Haryana, Punjab, Himachal, J&K, Ladakh", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110142", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7v5YBgUR/kwO6/NGXUQ3AeoHTDQatxfGXmRrSCaOLsiYN5Ihy8nUt+4Db2oqnx8lwDhrxT4I3fYCoCbY4vzNma1OvhwWNEN5kG4emlGztD3BS77kwckWn4ZA==", 
		"answer": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sdLXirx6167altjdEFS9nNb", 
		"explanation": "25a5fpTgkRjk88UyXR35he73MGfEBnAC43mMQONhY3SjVr6CZvjzyJkxJVmAg1xosn/I47H48hM6n7he+86vcS4Ce4RjwcSB3ue31HlAIMMEkoFk4dodefFOjDmkZ9fUNvt8y2rAJlGwRTG0CXJxgDrXyMyCBNVVGtGr5l6Mv+8sdlk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Elephanta Caves", 
		"option_b": "Ajanta and Ellora Caves", 
		"option_c": "Bhimbetka", 
		"option_d": "Badami Cave Temples", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110143", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRHr5MUhXF7H1e36JyvgAm4QpnCPW7d8eXKjVbTRa+D8xZZ2IhyLiF51snDJtqv0t1oBz7xT7M6cfywXe5N7iN+Pl8PiznBTMtIb2KufMTRdhJPbK6betdIhUtU=", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkRXv4YAsQV79w73rPW6QJHcbom2CRuNncX/nFKPXYOjtiy1LBF7dA5V5L3awER2V1xs=", 
		"explanation": "25S2KKTjwRz4t7UhXh/3yvH2IWPZACIQsGyGX6F4cXbmFK/Dfa38zJJ/Z1qGmFV/sn/I47H48hMan7he+86TdTQGcpgvx9bJw+zyhFZUOcdWm5Qy95sReLRE2TOoZ5YsQ/uRSCCGQirgHl67B5VM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Base of the Gujarat mountains", 
		"option_b": "Rann of Kutch", 
		"option_c": "Coastal areas of Gujarat", 
		"option_d": "Upper levels of the Gujarat sand dunes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110144", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17/xPfwJyvVDXQYsXCNX6Z6ZHDvFKHHb/nr25IxI0mbhFV8smLOpuXF50MKnehr6IKedS0Pd59nwdPJx+z213QecRmdo25Ur7F/7XneKIpZaV0=", 
		"answer": "25KqaYLg3Rjk88UkXQrmwPm/ImLECyIXpmjDRrFxdWKh5RiTpenL4v9o5JD2phVpjA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH01Bfv5YQsEg7gwO76O2jVQ20X43iRU7BnfHDtUOfGYfnqzJMxMFWdhRt992GGt7f18kBPmKlIqYCQZCMBco4vzMWb3urwhGVJOtUEiohz959dCyR9ax/CqyQVITmMLfD6mw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Dense forests", 
		"option_b": "Deserts", 
		"option_c": "Grassland dotted with few trees", 
		"option_d": "Lakes and rivers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110145", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEhfhhfzsJmTTCmMFpnvDRapgeDH3XKKCQ+T6zZt0Z2yIgVp+/XrPt6359BMOnbxe74+cZDFDf5tu2sTJ0fb4yTFvMtRJm4Rzu9hNiBC6s/OQPQt/9+d6NJP/", 
		"answer": "24GtZpby0xHr85chEErSXLuBGNPzz3RYII6/GRg=", 
		"explanation": "25SoaYPnkR/4+IhgfB/gyPz7NCeQF2oU436RRqZycXL3R+fNaK3qwZIxClWNiVd+skbHr6T1+F8Gm6BS6s6edydDf5lqiNGFxOu3wn5UPcIEiY9n8JJfc/IA2DWoNODOLvlvzGaBI1fxJyu0EnVm1jgB5F7EfznW4a35rYST/Yg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Yamuna", 
		"option_b": "Tungabhadra", 
		"option_c": "Ganges", 
		"option_d": "Brahmaputra", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110146", 
		"question": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRs3eCQaY0eX+jfanGZ+y+2pZmZ0iBiBtu4XOGrKOvtZOQd/cYomku7ue/OciY0fQ=", 
		"answer": "25e0aZX2wlnr+YFgUAvgzPPsd+vEaEPTLJ1NNa54+OqIkNM=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KLj91RDru8UkRwz7y/q/IWPVQ1cBs3qREpN1fHDmW6vLeuX3ytdhL12aiBc75XOGrark/lAKz7xT7M6KYydDcY0vytyI0+HkhHBPN4ZGj5J76oldhm6dm1CN6AUV8S2G5ICsQQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Hammers and nails", 
		"option_b": "Blades and borers", 
		"option_c": "Blades and burins", 
		"option_d": "Spears and shields", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110147", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF77y73WO2/ZAiIYsD+CQbB7c3jiQKLGLvr33Z8xM1SMzXl+/nfI47Px+18KlvcZ2LURNMf3PdgyQZPPzbvgVQ==", 
		"answer": "24CIKNnGxQ3r5cUQQB/2wO73fCn/4CMR/fEdmvAL1VpBSkkN", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR1BXr+cU2UxL+wOSzdXzYCmEZ43OKV7A0cWWjQK/HLuvxxoN5LlCFnht09DbSq6CwwVoBi6BC6J3TMCsQPphm3MWIw+HzhHhPc/N02N+y9pfFsEX5FH3Lt4bv84s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Maharashtra", 
		"option_b": "Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "UP (Uttar Pradesh)", 
		"option_d": "Karnataka", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110148", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7myvLzJivTC2MDonyXV7F9anSjQK/HLtju2ZJjZ2yIgVp+/XrPt6359BMOnLte5IyTcSUGPoJhiPec3eXlxWUecalbHi8ZbADKawfOS9yLja4=", 
		"answer": "25m5epb2kR/m9o4lQVKyx/H+MW7DTyITtm2KXLA4MHDtUOfRbf//2ZJjNB57wld7lBr6BW18wGsMCome", 
		"explanation": "25S2KKTjwRz4t7UhXh/3yvH2IWPZACIQsGyGX6F4cXbmFKTKb///yoN0NVWTiF878G+Gt6315FZPm6dU5Z3feCMQPolqzd7J0eviynUBOsgEvZV45YgeaLZh6PWlSyqnyBM7Zra4KQok", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Small flakes and borers", 
		"option_b": "Blades and chisels", 
		"option_c": "Spears and arrows", 
		"option_d": "Large flakes, blades, burins, and scrapers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110149", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2hDk88UvVF7gwPD+PGXDQ2MDpj+FXbZ6dDHqWufWZui+65J9JlLJm1p3/nPf/OcTIPUAksZuOqLa0z+PYiRb", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kQ3l+IkzEh/8wb3+O2LdAm5RpXCQQap4YzHqWqTOe+n3x5AxJF2dmVd+snfIp+X08lYdzbkRSf95gtXa0kxIOAmKA0E=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR1BXr+cU2UxL+wOS/PHiQEWsSqz+KXONnZH7tUefWYeLy2tdwKVjJjFVy/3fK46P/5EAGg7sb4ICcfDcHd4VoiNOIw/D7wTFAPcIEnoV39tgKSjFTc4wpwxkbJr8TMdCl", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Clay pots and metal tools", 
		"option_b": "Stone tools and animal fossils including cattle and deer", 
		"option_c": "Ancient scriptures", 
		"option_d": "Caves and rock paintings", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110150", 
		"question": "25ewYZzx1A3h9slgU17+yv7+IWLfDSIXrG3DZ7NkdWOjZKbOb+jxxZ5lL1WKzUl08X2GsK31+0cKnbsXqYeMMDEKap5u3NWNl+z40zFHMtQEnJJ96do9dPtQzTHyNvY7SJ3l5SHNL++pPwQiRfo=", 
		"answer": "2+HtKJr+kQrl4pEoEhH0hd/3OnvRDyCBZFt+Mkoy6AUF6EwFy0eI", 
		"explanation": "25a5fpTgkRjk88UyXR35he73MGfEBnAC43mMQONhY3SjVr6CZvjzyJkxJVmAg1xosn/I47H48hM6n7he+86vcS4Ce4RjwcSB3ue31HlAIMMEkoFk4dodefFOjDmkZ9fUNvt8y2rAJlGwRTG0CXJxgDrXxjwC/cOw+GeoW88jyFU9kMda5ccsPdvdKcUVFkTOWVRSxKz1Qwji5A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "45 km north of Bhopal", 
		"option_b": "20 km east of Bhopal", 
		"option_c": "60 km west of Bhopal", 
		"option_d": "45 km south of Bhopal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110151", 
		"question": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRomyQV652fHDkUefEYfjwzdd4KRyumFF64HfS47bx+VdPi71V7J3feTFDfYNu2tGKw+HlzWtEN4ZGg98w8+icaBXIQvyXLEAcDJpz4Q==", 
		"answer": "25a3ZYHywxj+/pMlXgeyyfztMm6QBW4QqHqQEObK4HYlcZJkGXbKJ5/W4W0=", 
		"explanation": "25S2KKTjwRz4t7UhXh/3yvH2IWPZACIQsGyGX6F4cXbmGOfBZuzsyJRlIk6Al15/snTf46b/+kMOnalP4JiafDtDcop9z9XJ0ej2z3RSf4ZMm5My5p8acrRGwyijcJTSLr5J22SBNUTkJZsWoI/Q1zjK/HdCCRJgr94=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Small blades", 
		"option_b": "Miniature tools", 
		"option_c": "Comparatively large flakes", 
		"option_d": "Metal tools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110152", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd/6OWreQ3QQr3OGS+N9YzHvW6TDeuj6iZ5/Z2m5zWd1znj0pqTj+F1Vz4FPqYeMMCwGf5kv3NiMl9L+ynVJKsdX2DwG7OZG83NEg/Sj7I5F91w=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKAYoDiPwUFL1OJkhzyYRO9vQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7iZZ/IxydhV474HPHsKr+t1AAnbpe6pqTaWIGZptjydmHxKTjzHQBMtVXn5Jm7ZURPs7i4Qo/k5tiCVRppScBh7U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Assertion true, Reason false", 
		"option_b": "Assertion false, Reason true", 
		"option_c": "Both assertion and reason are true", 
		"option_d": "Neither assertion nor reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110153", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdD2MW/cBiIhonOCV6x4eWXrXaSCeuLxxYQxMFmbiBt283LD46r2t14Km6lXqbKRTCwxe4p8x97Tl9D/wWJEc9JLlYxhpJMRf/hVyDipNNbXIfpr3S6BKUGwdDqvBWBxhiKU8ajxInspKHFhzqcmAfdxow==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUmUxLhwLG/B27REG0f42uRR6Y2MRh6kvDXQ9t8g0Yvv3yy4g==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/M2rcEGdRtHeKXqY0ZHnmFLXHb/7xx9d4NBydn05+sI0p0znO2rRdzvCvitqYjC4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Assertion true, Reason false", 
		"option_b": "Assertion false, Reason true", 
		"option_c": "Both assertion and reason are true", 
		"option_d": "Neither assertion nor reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110154", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb31/i/NHnVQ20Hpm3DBPMkMETzRKLQLt3/xZZ0KFCAmVNy8TbVqrH15BMGgehy54qWcR4NQoUv+tWIxOv5njFmIcdXiYxz6p4MPONJ2DXtctHMYOp8y2uTZ1L1dTz9B395mT7YynhDuoq18mevXNMkgBAgl8XF34p7+v5BoQkNsIBF4T5B", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKAYoDiPwUFL1OJkhzyYRO9vQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefWfPj7hddzMkjJmVN+smTDorb/+RMLgK1IqYCQZGIGZptjydmHl/D/wTFAINVBiJR765Rdyy9Zfp+PIZISyWTxeGo3Rw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Assertion true, Reason false", 
		"option_b": "Assertion false, Reason true", 
		"option_c": "Both assertion and reason are true", 
		"option_d": "Neither assertion nor reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110155", 
		"question": "24GwbdHyww3v8YQjRg2yw+/wOCvEC2dRjnaHVq9xMEHiWKbHYeH33Z94JByIil47+nfQpuXy8lYBz7hJ5oOWficNaod2iNSAxOf40nRTNsIEm5J98ZQbPOBIyX2/fcLeMr5R8VG/GHrPWAb/sW6q2/pODsCrVBpY5cfYoQ==", 
		"answer": "25u5epzy1Rioj0HcSgrUCmjrowUaiwzyyA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh2A/v5cUOUwz/xPn+dWLDQ2NRsHaEXKpyeXLiWrOCfeTqzNd3KE7JmVN+snLPsKb/4VYdluhU786yeSYHco4v+NGF1uH4yHhVO89H2oFg8J8ZffdU338ZAH5Ypa+fS73WREdWW6FV", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "nar,ma,da", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110156", 
		"question": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgZw7iwO+/BWrcAmcer3aXWqp3MGHrVbTHIq3qwZIxJFCAgFpv9zbRoraw+1YcnOhk1rGgTx08QbQt3lkS8oX1RUwoEzVXQ40waQ==", 
		"answer": "272tZZj3kxNorOYlixM7ZMFD6ZIC+Ac=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRpm2CErR1YzHgXKbQb+7qzIV4PVmNzVlisneGr6Dj5BMHmqVS7c6cfCsOf59qilOxlxmYmwSx2Xk8OL56iZk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "hum,id", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110157", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnf55UlQF7CxPH+MGTcCnYZqnzDQqt1Y3SvFKXOb+n72tdwKVjJj05p+3jV47L15VZPiadO54rfeSxDbZ9u3NWal+j+z3QBDPl7pb9N26UgPPVOyH2AddzaMv99xnqSJgdIrCgMO4gJzaENfH8kN9QZ", 
		"answer": "25SIKqE5fSJK4od1N0/n6h9H7/k=", 
		"explanation": "25SIJNHy3Rbk8JYpVhuy6Pz3NHnREGoFsX7PErR1YzHiFKnNeuz8xZIxNVmOhFR1smHOprf1t1EDjqxe+s6efiZDfJ59wd6al+Lly3wBJ85B2rVi9J8NPMRBwDyoe9jSNPZnzS6QL0TjYnmqAWJx1DXfmX9Zvoap8CP5D2Ml8ahRza437DBFBdnteA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Karnataka", 
		"option_b": "Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "AP", 
		"option_d": "Gujarat", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110158", 
		"question": "25ewYZzx1A3h9slgRRb31/i/NmrGBnFRonGHErF7c3qjR6/HYvn724QxMFmbiBt/+2XFrLP15VYLw+hS+s6MeTYWf59qzJC26NvIhHpMc9VLj5R6pJUZPNZIwy2seJbTJs0/IA0LnxjwHGI8jvji", 
		"answer": "zeBhbn4a3EwoL88T9p9hVXsk", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sUpQV7+yv7+IW7UQzZE43SOErd7MGXrUefRYfjqwdd+IRyrhVRr83qK46jx/FoBiOhS/c6eMDEKeYVmztmK1urjhGJIJ8MEnI9gpJsNf/xByTKhe9PSI/9ijmiJKUH5aT6uRq4uVoznuHDLrcuIg5yU/Bk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 30, 
		"option_b": 45, 
		"option_c": 60, 
		"option_d": 75, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110159", 
		"question": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Egr9yvHsdWTWQ3YZpj+uW6dwfHSjZKbOb+jxxZ5lL1WKzVJ19mPVt7f58kBPmK1J7M6dfCMHe5gjiMCG3urj1z0BMclWn5JhqNoecvAA3z6/dcTeMu0u73yFZ1H4Yiq4RGR7mz3FynFXrIb7+iH7UtY2yxAhycWVY8lPCf9hYDEm7OkTz6Cz", 
		"answer": "24y9e9N/hWK43Zm+L4ryH8J/o85e", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQ3l+IkzEhjgyvC/IWPVQ08Yp3uPV+NEcX3iUajOZ/n2wJQxLlKNmEhv4H/DsOXn8kEKz6FV7YuadGIOf49qiN+Pl+L7xXpEIIQlYtnJSveF2xgHSVXhncM8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Yes", 
		"option_b": "No", 
		"option_c": "Maybe", 
		"option_d": "I don't know", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110160", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnf55UlQF7CxPH+MGTcCnYZqnzDQqt1Y3SvFKXOb+n72tdwKVjJj05p+3jV47L15VZPi6FI6oGJdTAGestmxpCuwu721nBVc8dKnsBA5ZAeb+BIzTPtXcebNPZn3S6TM0TkYjS4CmQ0gCPDjyMUPEXlMUn4GpztE4FKWkN5aw==", 
		"answer": "25u3KvbPQs+PdzlTrpwWiBW0ScA=", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZX2wlnr+YFgUAvgzPPsdWLeQ3YZpj+2QrNxYjHTVavDa+LywIN5Ll/JnVN64XOGtKDi8hMJgL1V7c6WfmIiTscv49Gb2eXjxXpAf4Zpm4hz9psMdOBSzXHtddrfYPF6xmuSZ1f1YDCyCmM0liTCynJZvMOo5SK4Xdw+wxQ+mp444M0yKN6Q162XqEu3lEalyXGQWrxwUVWXsY6a6kmds5YwtMPPLu4RCnZKMcNNzEf9tbnhrw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Yes", 
		"option_b": "No", 
		"option_c": "Maybe", 
		"option_d": "I don't know", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110161", 
		"question": "24GwbdH01Bbt5YQwWhfxxPG/PWTCCngerT+MVONgeHSjea7GauH7iadwK12Mgldy5n7PoOXj/kcKnOhS+s6JcTEXcpIvzNmP0eHlwX9Vc8BWlY0y8JIaPNhP2zi/NOTaLP9rwWKJM035ZHmuDWRxh3H/mTxCoIqotTSvVc4yzRA8gsd57sspLtaL3PfRxb5FLQrdf6oGaSstsJY5GQ==", 
		"answer": "25u3KvbPQs+PdzlTrpwWiBW0ScA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH01Bbt5YQwWhfxxPG/PWTCCngerT+MVONgeHSjea7GauH7iadwK12Mgldy5n7PoOXj/kcKnOhY5oeRcysHe5gv2t+c0Oz73TFWOtJM2pR64dozc+NF3n2dddjaJfFix3qILkawdDCpAWM2FtUrUuAsbUw1Lv8N061X6A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Yes", 
		"option_b": "No", 
		"option_c": "Maybe", 
		"option_d": "I don't know", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110162", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQF20er2zDRapgeDH3XKLLfK39xoVjIk+ZglV/+3jB46T38glNw4ynXaYRAsGdYuD3+6QoPg==", 
		"answer": "25e0aZX2wlmnt7AwQhvghc3+OWrVDG4Yt3eKUeFaWEbQ3PuqKC/ucqIxbMc2", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZX2wln98pclEg7gyvD2O27eFyIYrT+XWqY0RWHzUbWCXuzyyJJ+K1WdhVJ4smbOorb1uxMYh6FX7M6PfysNapgv39Wb0qT8wWgBJ8lLlpMy4I8NdfpHjCmlcZT2KfpqwmvAF0T8ZjyyCHlgnDjVyn1RrcE2biXFIn0Q215BlrKawmLw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Blades - Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_b": "Blades - Middle Palaeolithic", 
		"option_c": "Points - Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110163", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQEWsHpm3DRapgeDH3XKKCb+r7iZ5lNByIn09y9HfFt7aw4FYdiuhd5puRdHhBYSi+nuwt8g0Yn3l/iiFSkg==", 
		"answer": "25u5epzy1RiqusUNWxr2yfi/BWrcAmcer3aXWqp3MnUs7t3r0SgFZp0Uf32yaK4=", 
		"explanation": "25SqfJj10Br+5MUmQBH/hen3MCv9CmYVr3rDYqJ4cXTsWK7WZuT9iZZ2IhyeiEl+snDJtqv0t1Ibz7te/4uNcS5Dboduy9Wal+v5hGVJNoZWk5Z39toxfeZNzTmsNtrfH515VzP/SPFiiUcUznI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Narmada - Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_b": "Narmada - Middle Palaeolithic", 
		"option_c": "Tungabhadra - Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_d": "Tungabhadra - Middle Palaeolithic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110164", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQD20SomuKXa00Z3j3XOfLev6+2p52KVWPhFh6/HXD46z+t0cHiuhY5oCLdToXPoRpiMSB0qTHxX1ANslIk5R67ZlfffNFln8yGu9wEHhzYnABP/Vq6/dn", 
		"answer": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sVtEjr71v7wI27CGiIepT+AU7VxYzHiWqOCfOL9wtdiL1mFmV5p4TQ6AH4VhPTSJuhTOJMd0oZ8", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sUpQV7hzPrxPG3ZAGMftz+FXbE0ZHnmFKPLfe7x35JjPhyGixt482DDsOXx+VdPnadY4s6MeCcPao5925Cd3+XjhGZEIcMEj5N34NodZbRI2TCsesebJOt8x2CHZ1H4YnmIFGBxhnHmi3BXrYy3/DOzXdl30B0zhYI6oYfADnq1L3aD/gn/STDgww==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bhimbetka - Discovery of tools", 
		"option_b": "Bhimbetka - Hunter-gatherer site", 
		"option_c": "Bhimbetka - Discovery of caves and rock shelters", 
		"option_d": "Belan valley - Discovery of caves and rock shelters", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110165", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHw/Z90Z2mZnV5pskbHr6T1+F8Gm6BS6s6edydDfYpizZCd2KT2yjFEPcIEm5J98ZQbPKUQgG39JJT5A8Jg8mC0L0CwYje5RH9y1CXejzxmpIay5jO0V985xVUll5Q47sA9Ltacza2B4Ve9gkaAxTuSR7FgFEbZtMCsq06Tsod4tN+EtXLY+/r9k+za/9AYXgZusbJ3ZhuRkrsG9CMsWcG3KBNM9KTDZEb7JSzjJh1d+Iv3xHVn1Ys9VGY69RMGkotXccUz1J3wqzc1MY1+HTb6k0VMxpFzUx6CfLS7kGnq5BURcHUnbJ5ltS51oAiZO2hwpmWrRCVSnMBk+JANnQEjfG1PinOgkSuKlGCCeZ33+MD1lqfxsrwj+60kJlOSMF/MCc/DYaA/EjMnkKsHLEuj4Xkx", 
		"answer": "2+f4Z5//yFuwo8gtRcpR5VdHb9SvxQyG", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRoniGEqRxfnTxVavOd637x5N0IxyIn1Ru/HKG8vW8pwNfz4p4pc6YeTQKcIwv39GQl/D4hGVJNoZpn5N96JMLdP1DjDyqcejVFPZrjmuOIwX/YXmpDHU0pD3Tg29Cp4C++yL7Q9skgBQxgpJ54cQlfNSX2LqS61m9lA+Y2X/RSqQkBlWLuMu6q0KSpMI1ut+I8SHP9fb1n7jQ/NcGYxxbvMZ8bFW4nrwA9yQrHYi6ZwYL8uvcZVH/YCmtI04Q9tnmlnV7z4YVU1088V9rh5BZbsln3pHn/DM3Oo1uHDf6sEFS0ZE8XgTWdf2swmnq81wrfHUlZIYtrCU0sgrcKlFqjW6ZQmxFnIUrztEVlAFscWZUlH/jwj6FhCWbdJajxYXzieHkqLBgsqIgLFLMdUvRQoVcZrvBKWB32amSA+ZIPJBrBGLnM9Fu8DD/JYWAxjUIkk+F8GuHrJsSr4lLLa6rOzo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110166", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf/6MmLeDWsfpD+MVONgeHSjeqLNYuTqwZ5yZ1+cgU9u4HOGtKTjt14OnaNe7c6daWIXdo4vzN+E0vfjzXJAJ89LlMB94toPcPVO2C7tddrfYP9gx2OBK1a8Jy61DXxx1CXejzxVoIKp9CSvUcg+0wE7lcds4scwL5eQ3+iH4Ej4qwOR03eYXLVtEhSYssvo/EaOpcI1vM6fvj7S4Pzqpvbv/uwOYxtdsdw/V1O517sA7C94UNz0ShNM/vaQaFqtEimpJh0J8crtmjR+zosqVSkj9QwGlYZabo12zpvlqjMkOskqFD2+40xBw9R9HxOfZ6mx3mvw6UM6NXciZphisCQhqQafaF1wnn6PWD5I2MB8/8NZmgdgaH9JmXKghDCZwGTPcJzt7MDsgPr5r70j4bMmJ0+JO1uYUJ8TaPPUL2Iy5+yIAqpVJ5duFGLyMpU69Dy5DpOb0zAZ2NAjb3bg8TnbAAZGxTUiai190iewrkeWZQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhDJjFV/smLOpuXi8lIcgKYb4J3fcSxDf4hs3cKIw+G3wWlRP8dKm5R765RfevtSjCmlcZTaM+1r3HqJKEuy8vWk6JxShY+l7HhtwVVtMw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHx1B7j+YspXBmyyvu/IWPVQ0wUrHOKRqt9czHgQavWe//7iYBwNByAg19+93KGrqTi/FYLz6pCqZqXdWIHcYZq28SA1OXjzX5Pc8lC2pB+5ZQLb7RBwjntddrSLf9i3S60L0zjJyu4FGJxhzTYnm8WqcOo/S69QJox0ho/1o9t49w1MtDf2KaXqEq5kg6HznKfT/1wHhSY9cOn+Ubcs4csocGItXLM9e25lf6T/NcNZzRcg4hSaliumKQA7CIrEcmmbVJI+eXCYFf5JTqqNBoU+ov32Xtl1cImWykg/BoGr4ZFbcx6wpDtv3IxOMgmVT67p0EA05s8TAKfYP25kH7l8lw6YWNraowtrDgnsQCPLUcy2mKSTyBEkIll+ZARgAp3dGFH3Hfuhn+IlXGbdZ3k147Ai9z4pflw+7ciaUCUdX7ZUYIOJbrOZ1VzwOiIGa5dPd9uBGLnfcIr8DW0JY6X3i8MxNwkb2Tu4C/ZhsX0LSWyspa5j5RyHawUP9/G/cKhtRzKaCDzLnGacsP9Wkj5QXjtwBp3rlgM3GEA+m3OAY165m0IiHe0TEpnl2fmY27hgrZZqpacfoAi2uHl0jxQnuZ3ktvj3Bh8agGognNKpoyWTBxbwhTCFshH6gwhAL0VHJ/SsmyRkGWQQnJNa8b3FeiVxitB1e2z8bk4edkAtrN68MYB2GUFdQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is an accurate explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, but the reason is not an accurate explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both the assertion and the reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110167", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t5EoV173xO/zPG7DFyIUtXaHV613dTHlW7WCeuX7iZN+KlmamVJ482LPrKuw+FVPjqZS5I+TY2IKcMt7wNXJ/urzzXBPc9VRmIN96o4WcvFO2H2re8HVJKEsqDahn2QB/wKsbPYDtIJ8Lg==", 
		"answer": "25i9YIP00AvitcEjxmki05yh+VPloeNGkhk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl730/T7MGXTBiIXrG3DRqtxMHXsWaLReuT9yIN4KFLJgl0783jPrqT85BMGgehP4YvfWSwHd4phiMOc1ef4ymVIPcNKjsB799oZc+FOyH2sYJTPKPsu42uINULxdTH9F3lgkXHfhDx0qY+09i+yR842zllypoZz5NsoPdnf9K2b+kq5lA7C1WjRSbMkEEaavc+t5E+Tp4s7tMHNojvP8bTtkvnHsNoKdg1B/4R+YFD8g6dJ7CI9EeaxZx5C5ezZYhT9JTqqKApRucrx2WFnwsJ+ETlkpF9kocNiasUzxZHwuXI4Pt4qDDq/r0BFw9R5SR6ScbO71Sjr5hUrfX9rYYVguT4hqAydPF1xlCuTSmxQmolm/9wK1Rd2fmcAnWWggT6flGmKMNPw44X5laSwobdnsqQoKFWTdxKIJgpcB3gtmoB2VSfmfew=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bori", 
		"option_b": "Chirki-Nevasa", 
		"option_c": "Didwana", 
		"option_d": "Mehrgarh", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110168", 
		"question": "25SqZ4T91Vn9/4wjWl7iwO/2Om+QCnFRt3eGEqBhfGXqQqbWZ+LwiZh3Z0yFjFVv4TbVtqL38kAbiqwb4IDfQiMJf5h7wNGHl+Lly3wBJ85B2oR39JUMdeBTjDKrNOfaLfxmz3zfZXg7hgx2y0Ly8VlgCYBKgdY=", 
		"answer": "2+ToOMGjokG6p9VgcD2wrF5urqrEh85gMq4KywN6pA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHwxBX+/pMhRhf9y73wMyvAD2Mft2zDW600QnDpVbTWZuzwiZFjKFHJmVN+snLDs6rj/kccz6ddqb2efSALf5kvwcPJxPHww3RSJ8NA2pR9pJIeavEA2DymcdqbMPJvzWvAJlf/cje5RGR8kXH7j29ZpIqv/S64FMoy0hw9kss4+sA1P9/f1amA/Ei8xgCQ03bRGe0oQQTJ9dqnqxvQ8NJo9e+u8yfLF8czbAQJuljjWieWSdA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "8000-7000 BC", 
		"option_b": "9000-8000 BC", 
		"option_c": "10000â€“8000 BC", 
		"option_d": "5000-4000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110169", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHw/Z90Z3GMnlR3+2LOqqaw9EYDm71J7M6cdSMQe48v3N/J1eG3zXxRPNRQm45mpJsZaPFSjG79JISbAt1SwFqIIgXzazCwBWRx1CHZmWgWmI++/DSvW9kyzhBylIJ77MU5fNSQ1azT6UO8xgeQ1X+tRpBtEkaWuce841Dct4cqsI2BsCDc8bTtlfff454ecQ1W/4JqcVKykOgd8C94fM2nZx5C5ezZYhTsJy2fKTkV8MjrlntvhpYhWCk19hBQh8NFdsFn05XhsiYjf8x4EHOzrUdP1YZ5XAPJNtcNLlkD8nuXSSxoQcJbjZA=", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNHH2Qvv8sc28wb2WvtN4UCXkNbXO9Ql", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhf7qOX/FEWdWsD+KX7N7YmXiWqTHLvv/2550IxyLlBtp93HPrKuw9UYbz69e54uNcS4PZ8tsx96d3uriwXUBJ8kEmIUy95MYcv1GxT6sesCbNfB6x2LAM031Jzi5EnV6gHHZjDxCoIb72yK0WNMjyBwx1oZ/6IR8PcWQzKaXqBjo1lbC/ljRXLIkQgTJ5Y6KyA/cpIcosMOJuDzctPv32uzb9Z4ZZw9bsIhDbW+0kugK9CM1UNyxKAJE4vCdUVjoKTu3KA0Y986j13d904MlUXB09hpFg45TItdyxJXhrnIxMckqGDyopgRT05V+UxLaNLO3xCjn71k7NXslYcpsriQxnQGxIVdslWeVWCRC1Jdu7NVZhglicWMM3Hjvln+HgXeIed+j6o74xf/1srwj8asmO0CDIVnKX54IbLCAKGEy3uGeTYtZIJBrHjbuNNZu/T78Yi51WWHWQ6+Jj+J1CO0aTB4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Only 1", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All Three", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110170", 
		"question": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhfz4MCvAEWscom2KXro0Y2ThR67Reuj6iZh/Z0uBhFhzsnnA47H48hMJgKRX5pmWfiVDf4h7wcaAw+3y1y4D1X/oFlysgMVR7exHLGb1qg==", 
		"answer": "252tZoX63x6mt4MpQRb7y/qzdWreByIXrHCHEqR1ZHnmRq7Maa/WmIywmvSzxxL9nuZL0h0i", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhe36OnvcBiIdqmmGVuN5cXjtWL6CYeO+wYJ/M1WHihc79H/Vq6z+8B9PjqZfqYiQfyZDeYp7wNWb3urwhtxgCjDGlA4lYPqFUrpcbFc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Farming", 
		"option_b": "Mining", 
		"option_c": "Trading", 
		"option_d": "Hunting, fishing, and food gathering", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110171", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjt8sUmXRL+yur6MSvEC2dRjnqQXa99ZHnqV+fDaeihi+nEsQT6u6QgUA1yAyPyCUk=", 
		"answer": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUvQF7cwOq/Bn/fDWdRoniGQeFXCeUxJjshv0JH5pjWrv/G", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhfz4MCvHAnFRsGqAUaZxdHTnFKXbLvn2zNdfIlOFhE9z+3WGrLew2VYYz5tP5oCaMCMEe5gt3AEwaJytTaheOxrNUvAvrA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_b": "Mesolithic", 
		"option_c": "Bronze Age", 
		"option_d": "Neolithic or New Stone ages", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110172", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRj48sUNVw39yfTrPWLTQ3EYt3qQErNmdXXsWa7Mb+PqxY4xIVOcg187+3iGiqv0/lJQzU4XkMMAFmNNF/0D7srmTMk=", 
		"answer": "24e5YpDgxRHr+clgQRHn0fX6J2WQNlJd43yGXLdmcX2jVanGLuj/2oN0NVLJpFV/+3eK46T+8xMcgL1P4c6QdmIXdo4v2tmf0va372NIIM5Km8J8EQ6gz6KxmE6hM59J1E+X", 
		"explanation": "25i9e57/2A3i/oZgQRfmwO6/PGWQKmwVqn7DU7FxMGHxUaPNY+TwyJllK0XJi1Ru/HKGqquw5VYIhqdV+s6MZSELPop8iOKI3eXk0HlAPYYMuIF164hTPMBJwCqsZtWSbL5Dz2qIPkSwVyu8AHVnnHGeq3hXpYS65y/3FPg/yRgwk5Nz7IFwfOKLzamBqH2qhwKHz3PRAI5lA1WQ9eCp40KO4LA5vITB8TPV8LTbk/DS4p5DUglbrJR+KhuIn60a/WorWNyxe1JE9+LVcxT+KS+tLggU+srtwjRgyJEgWmEg519PjJdZIsVyxJT9/DolMsxkVSC/t1BMwpl5UQOFNLy21Cjw6FA2Zzo/d4tjryQhqACSaFJslWbcTWxZgY5/994e2ANiaWdFjn/uhX+HiWOKb4f654W8keewrbZx9+M0LFWUOVncFo4TaL7VKW5mw+yIQeZTNYtiGWLoONQ8vCvwNpOGzHkM3t1gI3bs8TnbkMBj/VGQsFR8B4iobD9j0w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Western India", 
		"option_b": "Northern India", 
		"option_c": "Eastern India", 
		"option_d": "Rajasthan, southern UP, central and eastern India, and south of the river Krishna", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110173", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgQgz90/T7MHiQBnQYp3qNUaY0dn7xFLPKa637yIV9LlmamRt//XvDsLH59FIbhqdVqYGZMCMNd4ZuxMPJ3uq30HlEc9VRmIN96o4WcvFO2H2sZtvOLvoumz7QdwXSRGb/eF1uKS9cKpIcQG0ivfAAxw==", 
		"answer": "25e5b57hk9R4AnkHbqGwB8HjyvtbtU4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2A3vt5EoUwqy1e/wI2LUBnFRpmmKVqZ6c3SjUqjQLvn2zNd0Jk6FhF5o5jbCrKj15EcGjKlP4IGRMC0FPophwd2I2/e3zX8BJ85B2pNn5pkQcuBJwjijYJTaMvF7wGrAchWgN3mfJzB9h3H7j3REr4Kp/Wv7WNU0wQE3ksdx44gsLtKM3KaHpUm5n0ay3XCYW6llHxS0sMa67EKOqMIxpo2Cvzeb+/K5jvDWsNMEcRwStotvbEmolqYduAQ9XsS9fBpC8qTDaEDoM2iqKU4J8c6j/3ptz4MnHXoh9hxJjJdfbMV9wtjlsjZwMMtsECGp40dS0pd1XhvWfbOr2W/s9EZ/fHQ/aspovT85uE+dL0Z3mX6QWDlDlYwr/d8UmBFtdHtJmWWggzGPwGSBdZ7i58D4iuX1s61q8aIzIE6Od4v8yHOWI+3AtAKEdT4mKs4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sambhar", 
		"option_b": "Adamgarh", 
		"option_c": "Bori", 
		"option_d": "Bagor", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110174", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hHr5YQjRhvgzOf6MSvEC2dRpnGHEqxyMGXrUefLbei+yJB0Z12bgk519jaX8+mgpwNPrYsEq637lB3pbYMnuNtKDNCwDcY=", 
		"answer": "24K5epyz0Bfut5chWxDrhf7zPGbRF2dTgwJ4I2jUT0K/J+K1Z74J/w==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH23x2q+INgRhb3hfT8MCvRBGdRom2MR61wMCCzGPeSPq3c6tdjIk+cgU9+9jbPreXxt0QOnaUb6ICbMDACd4V2iNOF3un20HQDb2kWUcgzEhhP07gNcP8i3Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cold and windy", 
		"option_b": "Dry and arid", 
		"option_c": "Humid and stormy", 
		"option_d": "Warm and rainy climate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110175", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hcjvJW7CQ1IQr36GXa99ZHnqV+fDaei+zJl1IljJjEl053jC4/SguwNf3+h5ys6jfh4NTI5u29+HjaTDzHhSc9FFicB/5YgUefAAziTtdZTMIexjjm+OIwXiZjCzHTB3mDjbi2hT6mvWKZxP2pLAIiqK657EDmE=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHGwQnv5cUQUxLzwPLzPH/YCmFRoniGEqB1fXSjQKiCb+O+zJl1Z12bgk519jaX8+mgpwNPrYsXqY2QeSwAd49mxtfJwO3jzDFAc8VMm4514doWcrRDwDSgdcDeYOphjnmBNUiwZje5RGJ1nT/Pyn9Zpoey4S60Wsl1zy+trl9sVigL0Xu1D2yXfg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R does not explain A", 
		"option_c": "Only A is true", 
		"option_d": "Only R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110176", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfxfx1/LzPH/YECIQsXrDUat1YnDgQKLQZ/7qwJQxM1OGgUg7/XCGt631t34KnKdX4JqXeSFDf4xqiOyH6+rFwXBSPMge2rR64YNfa/FSyX24Z9HfYPhh3C6IMkvkbje6RHF6kHHQg29eoY28t5zJcj8Ydn2udnETnoF35wE=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiITtmvDYONwf3TwFKnNeq370Yd9JlWHzXo5Vr0ohGx7oLgWptXHXQvw/w==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRTj9JcvXhfmze6/NHnVQ2sfp3qGVuN3eHDxVaTWa//32oN4JBydglR34TbJpeXk/1ZPoq1I5oKWZCoKfctuz9XFl/D/wWgBJMNWn8Bn958bPPJP3n2sNMLaMvdr2nfAKEOwdyyvFH9nkSKaynJZvMO3/CqyQN8zgAE91o9t49w1MtDf2KaXqEuxlQ6L0nzTL7WiBjcvsFyd5OFtc/M68w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R explains A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R does not explain A", 
		"option_c": "Only A is true", 
		"option_d": "Only R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110177", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcB/1yu+/PGWQMWMbomyXWqJ6MHniUOfDLuD3yoV+K1WdhVJ4sn/Ip7Dj40EWz5RV1YCtdSMQcYU1iPmdl/P21zFAc+tBiY9+7Y4XdfcA3zS5cZaWAfU+CEMKr8FanFssO739", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25e5b57hkRDkt7chWB/h0fX+OyvHAnFRoj+uV7B7fHj3XK7BLv733ZIxLFKGmlU79HnU46zk5BMLhrtP4ICcZCsVe8tiwdOb2Oj+0HlIMIZNlIRn944NZbgAyjS5YN3VJ756xmvAM0z9Ynm7FnF5kXHXhHgWvIy0+TT7UN8kwwc7lIJ8r2KNOTt/hXjyySQ1KEd5AVo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R does not explain A", 
		"option_c": "Only A is true", 
		"option_d": "Only R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110178", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV7zwvi/Jm7CFWcV436QEqI0ZGPiWrTLeuTxx5Z9Z0yBjEh+snTDt7L18l1Pm6Beqb6efCMGcYdm3NiA1KT2ynUBJ85B2q5365YWaPxJz32sc9HIYgYLK4FmmQMfqnJceF7Z32g=", 
		"answer": "25i9e57/2A3i/oZisL79gBoL9I6wJ13uz9j3Mw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhfz4MCeQAm4CrD+IXKxjfjHiR+fWZui+5J51I1CMzWhv/XjD44T38h9PjbpS7YmadGIXdo4vz9GZl+by0GZENsgEjoh3pLUTeLRz2DKjcZT6J/suhl6BK0T1aDW0EHh9l3iWi3JS6Jez8GeVUc138wE9mII4zM85fJ+x3Kef4VmwjwXLnF+EWrRqFhSNvce7q1OZsos3sYHNoTfU5Pj82vrW998FIhxd/5V6d0+wkugN9z02EcqhfFJY5e3cbRThITqkIgIEudnm2n1swsImUyk84RFSi41RIsF90tjitSE4NsNtVRaspkpU0pVwUw7aNKmw1Sjt7lswY3s/bIVjr206p0+IIF1t2m6OTWxBlZZu+pANnQEjam5Z3HDvkH+fiGDPfZTx4oPpifzlsrhvsqIjP0CONlnVU4MIdvPPISdmwuzbI6NTP5ZzHyvlfdQp+Xvfb8hRXruMv6lNyB8ziKZN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "me,so,li,th,ic", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110179", 
		"question": "25a0YZzyxRDpt4YoUxD1wO6/MX7CCmwW42uLV+NxfnWjW6GCeuX7iad9IlWamVR493jD46n18xMbgOhY4Y+RdycQPoJhiO+26NvI+05+c8dKnsBN26UgQ8t/8398id5ftOL7UhntaGMdA/aD", 
		"answer": "27O5fZ/ynVns+4oyU1wWswDFYtJiOWOep5gOzA/l", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH23x2q+INgRhb3hc3zMGLDF20SpnGGEq51YnrmUOfDLvnsyJliLkiAglU79GTJruXk/1ZPg6lI/c62cydDX4xqiMSGl/P21nxEIYZFlIQy6ZUNebRT2DyveNGbI/Jnw2+ULkawZDazAHlgnT7YmTAWp4Wv8Cn7Rt8xxQcgk4M4+cd8PcTfzaCWqGW3igmB2XWUCLh0HleR9fqg4lDco4o5u8qI8Tra8LT42uva99ACZAFRvohrI1Kxh6kK7Go3X4i2ZwZDsfTcYFr5YCmtI04c98Lu13gpyosvWCV0+BpHhopYZYBn2djwtDdwOtV+HD25t01PydRzWVeFe7C9kHv05VY2cGlrZIRp/Dk9pE+aJFtriGKPRCVfk8Bk+JAWgQxmb3wAqH7lkTrLg22OcpTm+My8jOawtKxx/O9nIE+GOUndWI4ZYfPIMmpzxKmIGKRPOoxzEizlOJU96Cv4NJOT1jwenJklOXLp4D+YnsHseWm/spbwgNM2ALBAItnAqc+yplnLbjPsJHOHJsTyGQn3XXX7xgJxogogiCAe7CLZBoBy9CFNmnG9TFdwmyTheHWumPx48A5NDKOViRIg+vJgxRr9", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "vegetation, animals", 
		"option_b": "animals, climate", 
		"option_c": "fauna, flora", 
		"option_d": "weather, plants", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110180", 
		"question": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhfz4MCvcAnEFpnvDQKxhd3nvTefEfOLziahOGGO2smREsmLJ45rPyGwwsJdkqay8MtfgA6b0RL9GjeHD7pVNfgg=", 
		"answer": "2+zoOMG/kU26p9ViC/nCQPekVew9NkP2ThrtNQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhfz4MCvcAnEFpnvDQKxhd3nvTefEfOLzicYhawzZ3Rtv/Tae7/WgpxMtrOhz5pmaZicRMst7wNXJxPD21mUBMshA2oV84NobfeBF332icpTPKPsu42uTKEn5czG0BzBkkSPfhXgWvoKp7Ge5TZowxRo1hIZo5cE/Pdvfy62U4UK2xiCNzjuUULxpAVic+Y6h5QO5tZA3pcjB8TvPtPb8nfndsN8ZbR1cu8YmLwvsx+gr22o5X8z0bRxP9OCQYEbiNSanZ11RqZuzllZKhqsnHVo74QtOlYZFdoBSxZHl8HI5K41oEDS7rQRB1ZtpURPWJu30gDi0oHccNXslYcposikwpU+dOltrlG/cFGABxNAr3PNZtApnPWZO3F/uhjaKzCWGaNPw+4Hyi+304Lhx/bYpLQHZeQyIBs0+RvPUKCcmhrnLXeZ+EN0a/BNsEGhVxxZWfLqACL2o", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "7000, 5000", 
		"option_b": "9000, 4000", 
		"option_c": "8500, 3500", 
		"option_d": "8000, 3000", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110181", 
		"question": "25S8aZz00Avit4wuEjPChfzxMSvyAmUesT+KXONGcXviR7PKb+O+2YV+MVWNiBt+5H/Cpqvz8hMJgLob7YGSdTEXd4hu3NmG2aT4wjFAPc9Jm4xhpJsNc+FOyH2SS+vkH8FR8S6iBAdilSVQ52fUNlYzYyMlJ6ho", 
		"answer": "zOXoOHiadzK6IJqhcZlljH2KZvE=", 
		"explanation": "25S8aZz00Avit4wuEjPzwfXmNCvgEWMVpmyLEqJ6dDHBVaDNfK33x9dDJlaInk9z83iGs7f/4VoLiuhe/4ebdSwAe8tpx8LJw+zyhHVOPsNXjolx5Y4Wc/oAwzvtddrSLf9i3S6BNUrlaT39USAkxHH0qTxCp8PopXfrFPgUgCE6k5R9rds1KNKMmaeV7kiqxgWQyXiYSbEkGFqKvMmg/1DcqYwsuo2IsCDX7bTpm+vH/8wKbkhRsItydlW1g6EM62o5X8z0fBpO+PaQcUbsIzyqJAsOtYvq2Hdl04YgU2509RFPj4JaIshmxZrlsjYiJo8ZyARrsXeW962MxXnghFgD", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 7000, 
		"option_b": 6000, 
		"option_c": 5000, 
		"option_d": 4000, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110182", 
		"question": "24GwbdHwxBX+/pMhRhf9y73wMyvAD2Mft2zDW600QnDpVbTWZuzwiZFjKFHJvlp28H7HseLjt1cKn6dI4JqMMCsQPo9u3NWNl+Xly2RPN4Z7pb9N26UgQ7Ri739jROob+0Kca3LpB3D/x6nn", 
		"answer": "2+LoOMGAh0m6p8cixAx5WXgUnmdTnbA13YV7", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHwxBX+/pMhRhf9y73wMyvAD2Mft2zDW600Q3DuVq/DfKG++5Z7Jk+dhVp1vjbPsOX38l0KnalX5ZffdCMXe48vycKGwurzhCIRY5YEuKMy0JIWb7RJ332vdcfeJL5hwC6BNUb4ZjyyCH9znTLXhjxTvoq/8Cm4UZo2zhFyhIZ85Mc/PcWd1qbT7EysjwiFnHSXCLlhAVuKvNq7q3eUpcI8tNmEvzWb5Ob2jPHX9c1LY0hVs49yc0i516EH7CV4VMmmZAsL8OPCaFf4LDy2NQ8Rudvx13d9z4EsTik1+hsGi41Sa8Nywp33/CY4PtkqATu/40VSwpU8SBaFNLK21Sjr5hUrfX9rYIt/sDR1ogqSPFFsiSuTSmxBmIFl6pAagAh3dHlBiH/vjH0ILnQrysbrOJfKB8W4gusG", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "7500-6500", 
		"option_b": "9000-8000", 
		"option_c": "7000-6000", 
		"option_d": "6000-5000", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110183", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhyKgVJ282LD47X/5EdPv6Re4J2LfyEGcI4vytWK1unyhHJOP8IEm452pJsNdfAA8DOReoaSYNNnzXyPK0zkbyr9E3VmkXHai25RrcOv+ii3R5oi0xA21oNt/8EyO5eL0a3TxUiriQqLyHOYS/1lFlHZicCU5RDV4KA5ssKf8Tra8LT42vXa88wEbgFGt498I1Kyk70a7DghEfS6XxpC8uyQblKtNCCmZw8f9t3mlmd9x5YsUGw64AwGg5FTIsl91Zf2rjczK5IozIUgMy1G4svDJ/+5rEzjAQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuq+IssS1zFcTLAp79rBM9JHXd+bJt+", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3RDn9pElEh/00fjtdX/YBiIhr3qKQbd7c3TtUeeKZ+iyiZ5/Z0iBiBtT/XrJoKD+8hMKn6dY4cffdycNe5luxNyQl+byx3BMNoZTm5J/4YhfffpEjDCiZtGbM+pvzGKFawXnbzC+DDB1mD3ZnXlS6IW052evXN93xBAkk4t3/cU5MsPf1q7T6UqqjwWX0G+EWrgkEFqd9d6t+U6droc2oY2FpD/a+rTqn+zH/NsGZwZGrLpxTlK/hacF8T4wQoi1ehcL4unRbVihYCasM04R+Nnk0zgpx4wtHX4x5hoGi41SZ8V3lpvsvSAxPNlvBzqpt01Dh5t6HwOecf2V1Xvr7FwrfXMoJYtquRE7nQGvJxg+jmOZDCVfl4957NUagURwaW5UmXvljCuYwGSdecnf5bPohPz1rbxt5uN2cwG0PVmYVYEVaLLUIidixfqPTZZQNpZ0Ay3lONsrvDv8I5eZ2nkO39Ukb3bp8GqYgMTxBWuJp5Pti9lzGqtAZIuFxMK0olPLaDfpMj2EY9nxGQTxXXv9kxpquBQ2iDQD7WaYDJxt/CMK3mq4TARJlzTvYHW1nrdfqoOJeqww1Pr+kXIcl/d5i57zlBQyBza6h35QpoyeQRAPxEeWFcMI0wduCrsTVJ/F4S2bnHXCRHAEa8b/AuiOzShdyffjlyMHF+JpiaS36iX15td9Kvdt", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110184", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhykiEh0/n/Sq6zzt1Aag7xO+4vfcicEf4Uv39md36TjzHQBN8lJn5Nm7ZkeaP1Pwn2icpTaLvdjz2KTG0vMaWv0RER8kR/ThXBfvIuy9me6U993yQZylY95/8k/KNKN0LKW7A26n0aP1XiDR7FtBVyK9cG6q1eVrpt4ocKCvSHn+sj3ybGTxNYOIgtetot+d1K/17sB8SwsQoi1bhRO8vDVZRTvLzyrZw8T8Mbi2jRoyIZpTWU1+gsGjopQZ/x94ZDtvzpwMMsqATu/40VCyIJ5HwSCdam93W3q9EZ/dGguJYlirj8wohvDavgrG8y6tPFaVob/jA94fhs=", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhf7qOX/FEWdRqmzDX6J9fn36FKTKb///yoN0NVWTiF878G+Gq7D+41oBiOha54rfdisQdoJhz5C93+G3wH5MNtVQk4Nz8JMQcrRPyn2set3WIfJ9jmeTZ0j/dTz9BWNnmzLfi2hTrMOs/DOzFM4/xVUck4h05Nw0NdTf2K+W1EOVjwWQ03eYXLV3UVWLsI6l5FGZ4IE3uMCCvz7CtPXqiffQ+d8fZwwSqI9raxuon61J1S8rXsS9fBpC8qTRZlGtFCCmZyAY9sfqwnxgxcIoWmx0/QwGgYtXcMFwwp32tSg1O41oDHOqrEhJ1Jx5W1eFYLK21Sjw71ozZjoqa44tqCUw4Q6YPlFwjiuTSmxQk5Ji/cUVgRFxeC9BknKggzGCjWSDPJv2+IL9i+ziuYVt0a8uJECUPF+YRYUVY6fTZ29zzqmaTbVVNJFuESvlPNs6vDD0MJeXy3kC3pkiIGPvtCuXm8D0NSW7vZa5nth3GqtAOtjD7If3vFnGZSrvJj2HaYv3UQn+SHnrkwdr9xAwxSAeqHHNCpp25jkIkH21CUlhhi/vaG/hl7BYqo+HeJwwx/zj0yFSqgd02W4vVHAuSQtgCrrDSw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110185", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQEGsFpmzDRapgeDH3XKLLfK3twJB/LlqAjlp18XOc4RYOBeNSszHmr2DcoGeniWI=", 
		"answer": "25e5b57hnBTj9JcvXhfmzfT8dWLeB3cCt22aHuNVdHDuU6bQZqD6xpp0NEiAjlpv+3nI46r2t1IBhqVa5Z3TMBECc4lnycLEx+j2ymUBMNNIjolk5Y4Wc/oCa74ebdQShqwZf25JsqkL/A==", 
		"explanation": "25e5b57hi1nG+IYhRhv2hfTxdVnRCWMCt3eCXO80WX/nXaaOLs//zphjZ1WazVp1sn/Ls6ri41IBm+hL+4uXeTEXcZlmy5Ca3vDyhHpPPNFK2oZ99toWaOcAwTSuZtvXKepmx23ALkv0ciqpFmk0uTjVmHNaoZez5me6Rt930xgzmos4/twzMtLfzaec5F74kg6DyDuGTa9hUViQvsuk8gOJs4c89cuCo3LT4frtk/bUsN8FZkhdq456cRu9lLwA7iMsWM2nVBxq9eXdZlX/KHLjEwYU6ovqxTRohpI7WGE95wtJkIpVItN6wp2ksD0zPtlvEXOzrQRtxpB0RhbWRK+51G336Bl/XHQvbIstlTl1qBzcO115lGKaRS9QmpQr+N8L1QF1dGtFknXlwjCNwHGHedPn5I35lvz5o7h3+6wpaU6GdV3WX4AdaaCMZ3B6w+qTTatdIZR0VyPofdwj7DbrNJeay3kexNwwb37ptCKMn8z7eWG/pZf1gcR7EbEUdsXK/sqltE+Hcib1NXGWYov4UA71c3LL0gNnvxk3kmE852HZHIx7tSQD3kyxQ0V3hi/hYjDhv7BY44PCP70w3vfk3CBQkec4lJX4wxN8QQupzXZXocSaWVVLyFrVG40IwkkrDaYNDdbB/myYgTbTXnAZdtj3FaGIzWx80urizmhu/4MHUoKHKhDYi9AyiBaiQfRtFXf/p5DwOfkGSm0i6bt2wvmy98O1YfzkKWQ4YwP3WOhL+pZEZBZuAwrRRTRdYbu6X54bUqKL0Rw+XNxsW2yWa5DuFkXC", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bagor,microlithic industry", 
		"option_b": "Adamgarh,domestication of animals", 
		"option_c": "Sambhar,plant cultivation", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110186", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQE2cDqnCHQeNjeWXrFLPKa+TsiZR9LlGImVJ4snXJraH541oAgbsBq2Yxl/brL2GeNXcauNQptWg=", 
		"answer": "24W0bZjgxRbp8oslHxfxwL3+Mm7DTyIhrGyXEpN4dXjwQKjBa+P7hIBwNVHJjFV/smTHqqvptccxjHdgWlCCCY0RwUJM+eY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3Rzj5JEvURv8wL3oNHiQDmMDqHqHEqFtMHjgUefDaejthddwKVjJjF1v92SGqrGw8l0LiqwXqZqXdWIAcoJiycSMl+byx3BMNoZTm5J/pJsReLRSzTSjbZZfQ89EYFAAw2ghQMVdhaEi", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Pleistocene,ice ages", 
		"option_b": "Post Pleistocene,warm and rainy", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110187", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQAmUUsD+UW7d8MGXrUa7QLv3swJpwNUXJnk554X/Vt6D+9FZPgq1P4YGbY3hBBgmi2ghCIvi9n8z284Maow==", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NibYFmwFqnGEHuNZdWLsWK7WZuT9hJ9kKUiAg1w783jC46P55FsGga8Xx4uQfCsXdoJshdGH3un2yDFJJtVGm4529oNdM9/uJzT3A/kuf2fNde6b8w==", 
		"explanation": "24CoeJThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NjGQN2oYsD+TV7F9f3WjXbSCZePx3pkxIVObzVp/5HfIoKD98l0bnOhS586MZC0Ne8t7x9+Fl/Dyx3lPPMpLnZky5ZQbPPVS2HHtdsHPYOpmyy6QNUz9ZiukRGNhliLfmWhTpoC+tSq+QNI4xFUgk4p55MY5OJeXzKaH4UO/xi+WnGmUWK9hAlGXod3o5E2Z4I0+9dmFtHLd/fr4lrjD+N8YZxsSsIA/d1O515gI9C83XcGgYBtIseHCYGjjHCaOIh0S9cL33n1qnMIdVWAntBpUg8NEZ9Bh04vhsiYjf8wqASG7rVdJ051zURaaNK2w0XvhoFc6YW0uYIQtqCUw4T+dJFFxlmKIRCVS1IFl+pANnQEjU2pPkH/0ijaIwFWKc4Pv7sD4kPr5rr4j5qsuOgGUPFHdFo8ZYrLOZ3N9ivqeGbJQNt9lAjamLsEn8DW5LJeG2DwByZkyKnvu8S7ZncO1MXC0p5v3iZR3GrtAMNjW4cK5t2DJXS3PJHKfb9/8UAuqD1f23Blr9xk2iDUY7SLkSqd64m0+inG+TARFlSKsUD7hgrZV+cKeepw43PGszjMH2OBwmtv20As5SRD7gnkDs4ONRl9awUDDDMhHxQcqTLUPHZvQ/i2egGXSSnIJbde2KLzH1C1bmufknGhzuNAaXYWdbA3Sh9tm3B+wFb1xQGrsppW5P/kSC2ps7r0x2ei1o8a+NferO2tqZhSjVq9Y9IdYaxd3BR7PBCgPY7ejW4gQSPRG12aKgA9NVXoJEVLJ4ugPTwG96tDAa2PMI74LAF7kbLwBU8/2SgfLOvys2yTABb6IkEP+XkosQzuRMvIiDnbjL2F5dv2d1HpWfK28", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >>  Phases in the Palaeolithic Age &  Mesolithic Age: Hunters and Herders", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Upper Palaeolithic,hunting", 
		"option_b": "Mesolithic,hunting and fishing", 
		"option_c": "Neolithic,animal husbandry", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120101", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t5EoV17QzfTyN27ECGNRsHaXV+N4f3LiQKLGMa+ytWHeUvXNM9/cIhyCg1Fr", 
		"answer": "25i5bJnq0Fna5YQkVw36h6+Ic2HJ7QY9qQXEL9fjdjs=", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sUpQV7+yv7+IW7UQ2sf42uLV+NnZHD3UefNaK3TyJN5Pl3JvUl69nPVq+cKzGZISMZMVhJzL4JTz/7I", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Madhya Pradesh", 
		"option_b": "Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "UP", 
		"option_d": "Karnataka", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120102", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt5UhWxDmwPm/J2TTCCICq3qPRqZmYzHiRqKCZ+O+6594Kl6MmVB6rTTIWoaBhv/MP5uNPS5guUwr", 
		"answer": "27qubYOzhky6tdcUigv5u+BrSrTImycE3gM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0BDk44wuVQ2yxO/6dW3fFmwV43aNEqxidWOjA/KSLv/xypwxNFSMgU9+4GWGoqv0t1AAma1JqY+RMCMRe4ovx9bJ1ub40WUBZpYEiZFn5YgaPP9JwDKgccDeMu0smvmE2/EMywPTMEpfcnzRJw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "over 300", 
		"option_b": "over 400", 
		"option_c": "over 750", 
		"option_d": "over 600", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQEHcTsHaQRqZ6c3SjW6GCW/3uzIUxF12FjF50/n/Sq6zzt0MKgLhX7NHdok9Ioae7SRrDCGfzOQ1LTg==", 
		"answer": "272tZoX63x6oXM+FFKGK47vJfa7GgVyJqQ==", 
		"explanation": "252tZoX63x6q4IQzEgr6wL3vJ2LeAGsBonPDQaxhYnLmFKjELuH335J9LlSGgl85//4Bb+g9D66WWgBv71K0bw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "farming", 
		"option_b": "gathering", 
		"option_c": "hunting", 
		"option_d": "fishing", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120104", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj0BDk44wuVQ2yyvu/ImPZAGpRoniGEqJmdTHzRqLRa+PqiZZlZ36BhFZ592LNovqyoWL/8f7ZbY+ey0RnyrbeTQ==", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NivEDCI8pmyMXqpgeHjgFilZlrEgsMwIxq4M88i4xxI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0BDk44wuVQ2y1/zxMm6QBXAerj+XWqY0RWHzUbWCXuzyyJJ+K1WdhVJ4smLJ44j15FwDhrxT4I3fcSUGPMVRkoMaaW2srnW0KbwpFqM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_b": "Neolithic", 
		"option_c": "Mesolithic", 
		"option_d": "Upper Palaeolithic to Mesolithic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120105", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q54AvQhL3hfL5dV7AE2cD40+CXqJxf33qQK/Lba3/zpIxN06Gj1p5/m+Gs7fx9EcGjK0b6JyLL2Dhl77pCpzR34wSKjBY+5ad", 
		"answer": "27C2e4Th1Fnp+Is0QBH+hfLpMHmQAmwYrn6PQeHiK7RhBoDuCylwtYRCtQnJ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyww2q+4wrVxLrhfz2OG7UQ3Ye43qNQbZmdTHgW6nWfOLyiZhnIk7JmlJ39jbHraz99l8cz65U+86XZSwXd4VoiukavQU1Qium7U67yXMHZCI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "overcome social conflict", 
		"option_b": "art for art's sake", 
		"option_c": "ensure control over animals", 
		"option_d": "for entertainment", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120106", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71FnC9pchQg7zy738OmXEBnoF7z+LXbQ0dH6jVanLY+zyiYdwLlKdhFV84TbHs7X19kFQzYXX5MGO1x/tmKAv3OUhf/0=", 
		"answer": "27a3Zof23w3j+IshXlxElc79xSUAx1siQ79MQFPT", 
		"explanation": "25S2YZzy3Vn69owuRhf8wu6/PGWQF2oU41eCQKJkYHDtFKTNYPn70YMxM0WZhFh6/nrf46H151oMm+ha54eScS4QPoJhiNHJxPDuyHhbNsIEm452pJkQcuJFwimke9raLPd0y2rAMETpJw21ATB1mjjbi3BF6IKp8Ge0Us4yzlUhnohv44grNcOXma2L6Uq/gxSDyH6VCLthEECMp8u7pwOPtYEw9cye8T7a5vP82vDc4tAYIgdA/4pwbVz8g6kA9Dl4ZcCxcVJK4+GQYFj+L2isIRoY94vw3nt+yMIgUykk5hBAi49TLoBk34zs/CY4OsR4VTu/okBTh4BpTRmTcP2s3yji4VY6NW4jYMp7tSgipB3e0N5WkHUuiW2RHgEswjRV4w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "realistic", 
		"option_b": "abstract", 
		"option_c": "traditional", 
		"option_d": "conventional", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120107", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXg2y0vjtMCvWEWcAtnqNRq9tMHXmRK7Beuj6iZ5/Z2mZnV5pskbHr6T1+F8Gm6BS6s6eYjZcPEyjYdgd2jFXu5+cbRIP0rU=", 
		"answer": "26KxZJWz0Bfj+oQsQVwtvdoQYzcJ1jwx5lDThLqM", 
		"explanation": "24O5epj8xAqq4IwsVl7zy/TyNGfDQ3UUsXrDRqtxMHziXamCffj8w5JyMxyGixtv+nPPseXx5UdPiadJqZqXdSsRPoN6xsSA2eO31nhVJsdIicIvbka/RXMVaa74J/IrDhuc", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "wild animals", 
		"option_b": "domestic animals", 
		"option_c": "birds", 
		"option_d": "fishes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4svRl7zhe/6NHjfDSIXrG3DZ7NkdWOjZKbOb+jxxZ5lL1WKzUt+/WbKpuXk+BMfnalY/YecdWICbJ8wigvwY/dX0cdzvUarULzbyk4=", 
		"answer": "26G3Z9H+xBrit5YvQhb71un2NmrECm0f4RGM7xKMp2OsG6bM07RgYxI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH61Rzrt4omEh3gwPzrPGXXQ2MDtz+FXbE0ZHnmFLTDZei+xpExJk6dzUx053rC47bl8FQKnLwb/YGQMC8WfYMv29+Z3+3k0HhCMtJNlY4wkTNWXUa2SoHmO1V5gRJAOQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "overcome social conflict", 
		"option_b": "ensure control over animals", 
		"option_c": "too much sophistication", 
		"option_d": "for decoration", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120109", 
		"question": "2523f9H10Auq/pZgcBb7yP/6IWDRQ2QDrHLDcKt7YHDvC+UXECpOWGslzU7+9rUW3svR", 
		"answer": "2+HtKJr+k5CRC73bzjgmQTorhClwWQU=", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sUpQV7hzOnqNH/VByJF9j+IX+Nnf2T3XOfNaK3cwZhhJlDLMr5qazHc6mdaR4zWCNcFdQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "25 km", 
		"option_b": "45 km", 
		"option_c": "60 km", 
		"option_d": "75 km", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjt8sUmXRL+yur6MSvEC2dRlm+TV7E0QHDvVaLNYuTqwZ5yeB6BY343AASKq0qieiaXI3pq", 
		"answer": "25i9e57/2A3i/oZisL79gBoL9I6wJ13uz9j3Mw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe1Arl+4w0Whfxhfz4MCvWDG4drGiQErd8dTHWRLfHfK3OyJtwIlOFhE9z+3WE6CEG0AP9ReW5V1SqA7TzrA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Neolithic", 
		"option_b": "Mesolithic", 
		"option_c": "Chalcolithic", 
		"option_d": "Bronze Age", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120111", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh3hrht5UhWxDmzPP4JivRFyIzq3aOUKZge3CjUb/Wa+P6iYJhZ0iGzUxz82KGt6z98gxNe1Dz2I4PW15lIcfPh8ILDQ==", 
		"answer": "26e9a5T9xVn+/oglQVyFNe0I+Qq5ixIjQ1XhwGZS", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0BDk44wuVQ2ywOXrMGXUQ2QDrHLDRqtxMETzRKLQLt3/xZZ0KFCAmVNy8TbSrOXi8lAKgbwb/YeSdTFBGE6g7dK86yFJTII23hegdw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mesolithic age", 
		"option_b": "Neolithic age", 
		"option_c": "Chalcolithic age", 
		"option_d": "recent times", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120112", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Bfj+oQsQV72yr3xOn+QAnIBpn6REqp6MGXrUefHb//ywJJiMxyOn1Ru4jbJpeXg9loBm6FV7p3fcTZDXINmxdKMw+/2mzPjwkyvpJjbbwz67iiQqFuF", 
		"answer": "24W9epL72Bftt4cpQBrhh+h+65DDDPkOaCRe+aNf4CU=", 
		"explanation": "24W9epL72Bftt4cpQBrhhen3NH+QD2sHpj+MXONzYnDqWufDfOi+x5hlZ1iMnVJ45nPC46z+t0cHiuhe6JyTeScQast/ydmHw+35w2ID0uNlWlT21TDZfS3JNGYGRg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Wild animals", 
		"option_b": "Domesticated animals", 
		"option_c": "Fishes", 
		"option_d": "Perching birds", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120113", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut60hQB/i1fzxdXjVAm4C43mRV7JhdX/3WL6CaujuwJRleB5yHiNPYtGtOUmKaBiCBeDs", 
		"answer": "25S2YZzy3QqoAV7JD7x41Sm/McNeHNkRWQ==", 
		"explanation": "25S2YZzy3Qqq9pclEhjgwOzqMGXED3tRp3qTW6BgdXWjW6mCRuzsyIdhJlLJnl56/mWE5YKOGKVVO1yJeDJpKgfJnw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Plants", 
		"option_b": "Buildings", 
		"option_c": "People", 
		"option_d": "Animals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120114", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hc3+OWrVDG4Yt3eKUeNkdX7zWKKCfv//yoN4JFmNzVpp5jbArLew41sKz7ta4ovffyRDf5l7iOyH6+rFwXBSPMge2rR67Ylfa/tVwDntZ8HcJ/t92i6UKEqwaiy+DDBnmyHeg29CoYC64S60Wpo21FUz1pF9/9F8OdaN1bHT+1m5gQPC1XXRQKhpEFrZlMCr4kaStMIQvN6ZviDCtlv/OO6gwIGkVtHuinfQIZk=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV77y/7wJ3nVAHZd436NVuNgeHSjRqLDfeLwiZ5iZ1+Gn0l+8WKEqtNjxFyU+Kepr07SZcVTIw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH61Rzrt4omEh/g0b35OnmQF2oU42yCWaY0f3ejVbXWLvrx3Jt1Z1WEnVdismLJrOX94lAHz7tU+YaWYzYKfYp7wd+Hl+XjhHBPc8NFiIxrpIkLffNFjAmlcZTLMvdjz3yZZ1f1ZiqyCjBjlSKWhnVdrY+itTO0FNk4zgEgmYs4+sEwOJee16Ge6UGrxgCNzjuZXbNwGFqe946nJZ7s194M8NqPXxHI5UE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are correct and related", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is incorrect, and the reason is correct", 
		"option_c": "Both are incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both are correct but unrelated", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120115", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcBb7yP/6IWDRQ2sC42uLV+N7fn36FLTLeui+3p5lLxybglhwsmbHqqvk/l0InOhd+4GSMDYLe8tCzcOG2+3jzHhCc8dDn8BO6qYRTvFB3zKjLpT5KPdjzGuULESwbziuRH9ikSOW3ywG6JO6/CmvUd530hoxncdr5c0wKNKNyuqPtMa7t3tw8WPuctnreZDs", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV77y/7wJ3nVAHZd436NVuNgeHSjRqLDfeLwiZ5iZ1+Gn0l+8WKEqtNjxFyU+Kepr07SZcVTIw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1Bj5+ItgVRfkwPO/PHiQF2oQtz+hWqp5cnT3X6aCZuztiZhnIk7J2AsrsmbHqqvk8ldPnadY4s6MeCcPao5925C+3+37wTFVO89X2olhpI4NafEMjDS5NN3IYPBh2i6BZ1blYT+0B3lxmiWWmHlXu4y1tTO0FNk4zhY+g4N9rdw0PcPf+6Ca5U+9kg2DnHKCCKlsFBSWu8Kxq1CVtId4osSZuXLJ+/fy2ujS+dAfawZVrMZ5cVSx17wB/WoVVNu7ZBtf+e3TIVXqJWiXLwsP/IvixHEpyZYhWHt05xZSh5AWdcln3tjiuSU1LY14GjCx41dIwphoWgWFNKmw0Xyk4VksejojZJxo/D86ogTcOFV3lH+VQitC1IZ58d1ZgQxmPUJFj3nsiyuDiWbPfZTmqV5bPBKQOj5vxhy5t3AkV+s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are correct and related", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is incorrect, and the reason is correct", 
		"option_c": "Both are incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both are correct but unrelated", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120116", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHwmNdFL1nJn1R4+TbWoqz+41oBiLsb6JrfUioKc4lq3NuIl+Hv0HRPN4ZCiI9/pI4XebR13C2oZpTrIfJvy2GMLlH4bjr9BXdxqD/qhC4WgIKp9DerVdR30xAzmpQ469o5LcKa17yf8Q28gxaL32/RSbNtHFWVpvKm103P4JI5vMOZuDzctPjwkf2fsJ4bZxpRt49xZBu7hakA9mc9UNy9ZhUL8+3CZUetNy2xIk4T9t+j33op0oosHWw15hNPh5BCItBy35bwtTw3LI1rAXOYq01NxZFoVBaqeoG2hCjN7hUrfX9rTYt/vT0loAHcK1twjm6EWGARlY5i89EV1RRidGFUlXjnkX+KkmDPdZ2j6I/yk+3+tLBs/KIrIFuFMRzPV5RcWb33L25xwqmUC+ZIO5onFiDpK9Bu7y34NJOZ2jcZw5kpPDjm5i/ZkcLnK2C5p8277lXeRsuTQzbo1klHJ9vBMw==", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNHywxyq9IoyQBvx0b/bVCnfJrbInBgzgeFaIk9o", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR2RDn9YA0WR+y1/L8PivDC2cdt3qRQeN1YnSjWKjBb/n7zdd4KRyKiFVv4HfK44z+81oOz6lV7c6cfywXf4JhiMOG2uG3y3cBJ85B2oVz9pYWeedUjCm/ddfeM75hyC6IMkjxaXmxDXZx1DjYylVYrIq6tROzUZonwRw8go526tt8PcPf+6Ca5U+9kg2DnGiBSbMkHEGVoce450bcsIcqvMKJon6b9vH+k/bd+dAMIg5AsIs/d1O5150Z6C8qEfi1ZBNO/ujZdVzkI2iiIAtd+MXnlnFx0ocnWWA6819SjcNea9Nn2YrtvzM8f9ljGDapn0pvyZE8UBHWYLW9kGvs4Uc+dm4ud4N+qCQ24QmZKUBriG6PDCNX1JRj+5AxlBZibX9BkjaojS3LqWuLaYCj3YHwie3p4Jpq5KorIFuBIVXXWMRcdrbBK3Qyw/rbGa5Zc5tiByvlKdwh8nn2JtaV0TAA0dUzb0Pv8WqMnMT2Nne085Dsgtg6VLkPJJHA8cq6oFDCLWPoMj2SJs3mXBnlSnLs3xclsx01wSIE7WaYCYd2+CwB3nG+CVBslzTlLG+kl7JPqq2ad4sjk/Ti1D8RlOc4k5L80V05SwGrhX5NppfTD05HxFrZHcgVyxorH/hBAJ/W93+F2TbRRXhNfdvwB6mLzClbmuLjiyF8s4MBFYqBORffytEoiAO5BO58FXToqYrqAfIhAmFs/7NjxuSkpN77ZfKtInEjYR2kGe5Ns7dZYQ95FB/WBGRfcrGjV48XTfkP1nDangRcB3NIF13Ju6kGVAmrpteIb2TaI6ITAxuia6YIEsC4SE7IIOOs23DmELqO1VO3UkFpDjuOYaMC5g71boX3N1O2hWdo78ThfhFPTIZXPyj9YG63seOMDUYudyllOItOdFPcRRc31DzGJPhqiOcNfwooAayuD1UEhRQPqDbbAl0FuVhZTOWlQUEjar1KYF8Uyz67GLQWShnGn3oZj0/c1Sv4IfVeJQkudHaWz0/vlYZjh+ulwoeVTceiPbEax54KKrpeBI7eHk9civb27OnpH2t5AX92J/aFW+PFuUHxQsr9sMfJhVFCzrYcdlE0MXmDiIncsDhoKqsPZn4KqXsc7M/TcAqj3JtNlUBpWVv4/E/jUlsvlx96Y5LnKs3dI5Wx+V5YBWTOWflXkPk49S32NM/BZRR/BGw7hQKIYpLL1THDMqrvxaNJFgy725DRQI4t7UZ9jt+9zVpFpS98gHLjB3/AZ+Ot3BZRYn12QrmeFk4dhwUnlTW3ylbmfZyiiLEHzqdIzL1T5BT2pSZznV+YSk6OZXbryuOMsnWK/lQ0yqIjXXXjV3J/yQlkTP85/GouTz9hRa56u/bhLbjIjSGbJpmhjY0f4BZVSrTFb7K9qdDyZbDNILLimYmNb2Lz/pVgCPDjZckMNH6NcDUaray0aoHFaRrTKH6W3L6cUj+BZSZa7XwujmqLFA5lKHe2WYs2ys0HbGAGWVQI3EZaTbm0", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only 1 and 2 are correct", 
		"option_b": "Only 3 and 4 are correct", 
		"option_c": "Only 1, 2, and 3 are correct", 
		"option_d": "All are correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120117", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHwmNdTL1WEj15v+XeK46Sw5FoIgaFd4I2efjZDf5lswNGM2Oj4w3hCMsoEiYlm4dZfdecAwDKudcDeJL46my6LKgXjaCypDDB7knH0gnNGqY+H+xu1BpoezlUHhpd9/4gMPdue3Kef4VmwjwXC3WmFBP1wGVHZtMCh5kKQs8I+p8icpDfV4Pjg2vzW4NcIdg1W/5F6cV78mqca7CYhEcy7ZRdY5e3TIVXjKSWiKx0h9/fthTRdzodpT2Y3/19Wg4pYdsl90YukvSZwHcVjGDG/t09Bh5FkSxKYcP2twCjw7xUyen4ud4QtqCQ4pBygJmhwziu+RCVcloV/9dFZnBcjfGEAiXjyhzKKkm6Ofp/mq5P1ke2wrLZg87ciLQGJOxz1V4kUfLKAF3VzzuyIBZpSG5BwVy/nM8xu7y34NJOZ2jcZw5khPXKn9yWLgMj2LTr4tEDe4sSxqhEK/g3/oi6moQ==", 
		"answer": "27q2ZIizg1smflZICr57qZZO/eLK9Nqj", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9slgU17hzPrxPG3ZAGMftz+CQKB8cXTsWKjFZ+7/xddiLkiMwRty4TbKrKbx41YLz/wOqYWSMDEMa59niN+Pl8b/y2FAP/pKpo5G7JMMPOdUzSmoedHVNL5n3S6DKFfiYjqpRFJ8nTzUj2hdqcOy5me6FM0yzBl/nYl3+sZ8PcWc0amW50G3gQ+B3XfRW7RwFBSQu46B5UeVoc54ucKOsCbe8LT4mPfG5J5fN0hZssZsbE6on+gG/moaWcekaR4HscnRZVz0IWiTNQ8Z/Njrll19hos6HW81+RBTkcNQbdIz34z3/CA/PMYqBju/r1BF1Yc8XhmSNK2q1WDt80EwZ3MoJYlsqih1sQ6VJkB3lGyPcCJ4msBe7sAch0RTfGNBmXnsiyuDiWbPfYH3p8Doje2wobdq/6IrOgGGJ1nJQ4gScb/ZZ2N32uCYGaNYc4hiBSemMNo96DXgYJKb0jwexNAjb3bp/SeYnt7JN1m0h5rwnZRlAL4UM9zA59/3uU+HaC3iLm+BY8jgGSH+D0nowwt39ygkxCAV527RHIF29m0MjGr8CVBsl2fhYnWsl7JPqpaGfppxxPD+2HIWivFpip75wBElBwC+nXZApoGbD0tK31GWGcgJwRsvALgYVIHY/mnWlHjZRn0BbIK2D6eTgyhH1+bimmh+/58AUJ/OGBHSmZ4n2gPxDvttUGmtu4PrK/kRSmU/urMx2OiiuNi/NfyibHEialqjQP9c4NVebkJ6HwLQBChcIKymV4leVuVd1zXCgglcQnsJA1Xeu64HUgCWpPDAayrMbLIXTg7jar0RGsD/XQfOIbGLwDnEBLqInkb+WlwxSzSZYaUdpRP/OoH9IBahnShw8MzgIW1VeI0jNC7gNHitpLeGBgM0a2wsO8pEdVXHThMw1ArLIrl1gqQLMAgsSKazEF4RhVFOi37wBlFIskkKVKTtQUEiaqdKNBsb2CShUaYNUxGKligPhl+P1i3+IPkLJUAufnfIz1jonosmmuf9h4CFSsHybakUkoAMOrMbVp/VGlUI2uPh/ejvFX91RmlyI/fGTfbDsVv/DM+0o4PZylJfwLAdOUooZS2ZiJvQ5DNiIeVAaTBYsnAS7MvAdkaj18hN3VUoUUfp9H3qY28ouxN2epjqKtTPapqrsEVRBCHKVqtImf502Gz3PMvUJBYwBGIhlAPQf9yK6jWHNbX6gJ0bBBynxJH3S7Zj2EBw3Zyh101UrjZwgWiiAmWaa+nu5wxGJ39sC5aXE1BfgwMp1Hq4zRPpfbqEopUqofB216cf5UzfpzN/m1+LSgrdamfvnveQsybPrQcixqRwVWKmSXZpjgMqQbAk9Dl6SChhRK5nqPb8IaHLjHWuIIj4zJ4O7VdRSavFKLS4vNm8NqrRKras0I7DBnzl+JIrZr2aPanaph7pntgSsh20Mg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "only 2", 
		"option_b": "only 1", 
		"option_c": "only 2", 
		"option_d": "only 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120118", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUsXR3z0fTwO3iQFGsFqz+XWqZ9YjHwXaDMZ+v3ypZ/JFnTzyNLUIwDxzESDwj52Zvxzg8=", 
		"answer": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sVtEi7zzPPrMG+QEW0SqD+QWqZ4ZHTxR+vgZuLuyJsxahzd2Btw/zbAsar9t3EHhqVZ7JqUcW5DVop9ycCZ1uq3iTFyNsdIicB24YoWf+BJwjrtddrSLf9i3Sz+Ah+yd7GvLueiWvpD3Wqn", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9slgXhHxxOn6MSuEViIaqnOMX6ZgdWPwFKHQYeC+659+N12FwRtz/WPVpraw9l0Mhq1V/c6NfyEIPphnzdyd0vbkhHBFPNRKn4Qy85MLdLRQ3jilfcfPL+xnzS6DJlP1Jym8DX5gnT/RmTIWnIu+5iL7RNs+zgE7mIBrrcw5LN6czeiF6V+xiRORnHqfQbBlHUfV9d2g5FSfoZExu8rNtDPJ+O25ku3e8dBLYxpGtpVralj8krAZ6i8rQsG7ZgEFsc3edVH/JTu3LgAa9dKvlmBhw5EsHWg6/RJHjsNbbdR60IukrjcjMMNrATb6tE1Uz9RoVxiFcf2+333q5BUwezoDZJhsrD00r0+PLVVyiSuaXiNc1JRj+5AwmwB2bi92nXrshybLg2yZdZ/q8YHojOf+7Plx97UiKE2JO1uYV80far3OImRmw+aVTaRZJ4hiEiymKd0rvDj3I5+R0S1NwtYjJDfm5j7Zk8PxeU27oZPpntV4VLwVOsXQ+873uVKHSC3lKHzdJHjkMNqWMZkJ5sfUZq/elfk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bhimbetka,Painted rock shelters", 
		"option_b": "Bhopal,45 km from Bhimbetka", 
		"option_c": "Harappan,Seals depicting animals", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120119", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUsXR3z0fTwO3iQFGsFqz+XWqZ9YjHwXaDMZ+v3ypZ/JFnTzyNLUIwDxzESDwj52Zvxzg8=", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NiudQ0MDtz+HV7N9c2XmUOfVZ+H6iZZ/LlGIgUg3sl7HsaTg51IBz+UbyICWfSMPPptuwd6d3urw1zFDNsVFl4Uy55URavFO2DSietXXbL5Dy32PK0zkbzC+SVZ7mD3ZnXlS6Lar5SKpFOo2zBQ3mYtx+cA1P5V7eRbRsBfw3OL+6JYUTKDu", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnf55UlQF7CxPH+MGTcCnYZqnzDV7F1PDHiRrOCaujuwJRlIljJmlJ39jbHraz99l8cw+hU74iaYisNectmxsOA0Ozj1zFIPdJL2oVz9pYGPPxVwTyjNNfOLOp73GuTaQXUciu0Cnc0gDnTylRXuoKr5Sa1FNk+1hw+n515+cEzMpvf2Kaa5Uy0xhaD1XWFQbNjAhSbsM2p5kbcocI7usCAvjyb+fvtk/6fsM0CZQZbuZ92bVz8lL0F7D8qUMT0aRxPsfTfckfkIiS6ZxwY9cLk33t81cI6VG46/RlPgYJYYcU9lqzsuXIjKs95ECKvpkpUh7l5TBiafamw2Wuk8FAtfHUvJYdsriYwpU+daEd2k22IDDheg4F5+sNZhgF3aWNFmDbsizmOk3GWcJbwq4Hygaj+pa4j4awkIESUNFCYUogKYL/PN2p3xP2IQ+Qb50P0Qm3e4tqw+YZZSPXY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Upper Palaeolithic,Art depicted wild animals", 
		"option_b": "Harappan,Animal paintings became conventional", 
		"option_c": "Mesolithic,Followed Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120120", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3ibV5LlGLiE9w8zbPsOX8+FAOm61fqYeRMDYLe8t83NGd0qT4wjFsMsJMg4Ey1IgeePFTxAGjSNqJab5MxmeNJUDkbDj9DHFn1D7Aj24W/dPrtTe6XdQjxRFyhIh75ogvNNKTza2B+3G2ugjRlTu5XbNwGFqe9dmp+AOIqId4pd+EvzHS5PX12uvc5cwIZ0hducZzak25m6EB9yU8bcaIZkYCsdDYZBTAJTusKwcJ8cLglnVuw8IvUmU4+whVwpdeZ4BGxojhrnIAPsFrEDy2qlBIzpdAUSCefb6wkGfioEE3cDoqZ4V7uW0mtQ6ILVl7lH+PDC1DkcBo8cILkAd3Ii1RBDG6qyI9TwktoTq6gx6Q", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNHn2Ryq9ocvRBuwTFEBCg9dupS5SfARl++4hA==", 
		"explanation": "25ewYZzx1A3h9sUpQV7+yv7+IW7UQ2sf42uLV+NnZHD3UefNaK3TyJN5Pl3JvUl69nPVq5n+1VsGgqpe/YWeMCoCbctg3tWbl7GnlDFRMs9KjoV2pIgQf/8A3zWoeMDeMu1SwEaVKVH5aT79E3Fn1CXejzxGuoq19i6rVdZ30xonhIR9rcc6fNuWz62f4UW3iQK+0k+ZTf1JFEeWuce840qf4IM/sI2Lvj7X++Pq2uzb9Z4+chhXrcZPYle9kqcF8T4wWMv2huWBNIPsjW9/+34gmmbLvA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1,2,3 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120121", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ3IEsW+MQaY0f3ejUqjQY+TwztdzJlKNnhty/DbSq6Cw51Icm/cZu333HhVJJc5pZ6RR46ykFQ==", 
		"answer": "272tZoX63x6oXM+FFKGK47vJfa7GgVyJqQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e5ZpXgkQ7v5YBgQgz7yPztPGfJQ2QesXKGVuNyf2OjXLLMeuTwztUyBVVQerqWwAZE2mlXHNcP", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "hunting", 
		"option_b": "rituals", 
		"option_c": "marriage", 
		"option_d": "communication", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120122", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt4wuVhfkzPnqNGfDQ3YIs3aAU694aTHgW6rSfOTtzJMxJhyLjFV/rTRM6AifAcdBH0Cv1maLa2lj", 
		"answer": "27SqZ4T91Vm4oscHQ2DhYuKtjo8BRsrMXw/J", 
		"explanation": "25T4apD91Vn99pZgRgfizP7+OWfJQ2QesXKGVuN7djHiRqjXYOm+m8IxLlKNhE1y9mPHr7aybDTIzTlzmIaELHV5Ohw2dw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "around 50", 
		"option_b": "around 25", 
		"option_c": "around 10", 
		"option_d": "around 100", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120123", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV1731un2OGrEBmZRrn6bW65hfTHtQarAa/++wJkxJhyFjEl892SGpLf/4kNPjqRX4I+RcydDcY0vytGH0/eohlGkUqlYV4WGY9iV6Oe14LY=", 
		"answer": "27SqZ4T91Vm/p9ViQfQiwty6DurNBvTdAh295A==", 
		"explanation": "25S2KJD/3RDr+YYlEhz30er6MGWQFWMDqnCWQeN2cX/nR+fEYf++xIJlMl2FzVpy9jbRrLD88xMBgLwb4Y+JdWIGZohqzdSM06T21n5UPcIEz9AipJcacfZF3i7vcePOG6sDXkZ3c31rU/IBRQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "around 250", 
		"option_b": "around 100", 
		"option_c": "around 750", 
		"option_d": "around 500", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120124", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q+oAtUBvg1r3wMyvRQ2EdonHDQaZ4dXL3FLPKa+TsiZpwNU6AjFx+smbHsbH+8kEc0OrWV9vxjMTkJHUuXTn9AAdp", 
		"answer": "27qtfIL61Ryq440lEh3+xPO9MURq776qdRQkBbNxTD5hhw==", 
		"explanation": "25i9ZZP2wwqq+INgU17xyfzxdXzfFm4V436PRaJtYzHuVbXQd63x3INiLliMzU9z9zbFr6T+tWFuLckJsD0dmOhRMRwLPVo=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "within the clan", 
		"option_b": "outside the clan", 
		"option_c": "within the alliance", 
		"option_d": "within the same band", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120125", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwRXr7oAkEh/8hfTyJWTCF2Mftz+RXa9xMHjtFKzHa/33x5AxN1mGnVd+smLJpKDk/1Ydz6xO+4eRd2IXdo4v/cCZ0va39HBNMsNLlolm7JMcPORIzS6oK5ZtgXUqq3E0toiZvuIVaHxU", 
		"answer": "27a3ZZzm3xDp9pEpXRCwdpw9FmsQbDhCOSRmpXCp8g==", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZZzm3xDp9pEpXRC+hfv+NmLcCnYQt3qHEqFtMGXrUefXfei+xpExK12Hik569XOK47X89koKi+haqY2NZSEKf4cv2t+F0qT+yjFKNsNUk451pIoac+RMyX25e9PeNPZr3CzakpX0cK9qWwvNlikIqP5l", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "rituals", 
		"option_b": "hunting", 
		"option_c": "mutual aid", 
		"option_d": "communication", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120126", 
		"question": "25Gtepj91ln9/4wjWl7izfzsMCvUCmZRt3eGEqB7fnLmRLOCYeu+yptwKRyMgF5p9XOZ4UrovVCMwAu/HOp8gIW8FMk=", 
		"answer": "25u9Z536xRHj9MdKVHU3t28HIbIUTLDyEys9", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hfp8pU0EhH0hfy/NmfRDS5RomzDU600dWnsU6bPYfjtiZBjKEmZwRt+/3PUpKD0t1canaFV7s6LeCdDUI5gxNmd3+30hGFJMtVB2PxQo4kQptpiYanaOpS0bTE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Palaeolithic", 
		"option_b": "Mesolithic", 
		"option_c": "Neolithic", 
		"option_d": "Harappan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120127", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnf55UlQF7CxPH+MGTcCnYZqnzDQqt1Y3SvFLDKb/m+3pZiZ0iBiBt582XPsOX/8RMcgKtS7JqGL2Bbt0X1EEbKWiZ6rK1Rze+A", 
		"answer": "272tZoX63x6q9oskEhj9yvm/MmrEC2cDqnGEEKJpH45S/6/RVU9KRjHuONE=", 
		"explanation": "24a3a5j2xQCq/otgRhb3hcjvJW7CQ1IQr36GXa99ZHnqV+fSZuztzNdmJk/Jj1po93KGrKuw/0YBm6FV7s6efiZDeIRgzJCO1vD/wWNIPcEGI7E+HNJ4RP3rCKhK1Rn35g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "agriculture", 
		"option_b": "animal husbandry", 
		"option_c": "trade", 
		"option_d": "hunting and food gathering", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4ouV179w73rPW6QD2sapnOaErNhYmHsR6LRLuL4iYV4M0mIgUg7+3iGt631t1IBjKFe55rfYy0Ad4570Y/LDMNB40mgf7cE83IrEK21kA==", 
		"answer": "26e5fJj1yFnr+4kpUxDxwO69OQkGlUC6F4k4vV68hOJQlg==", 
		"explanation": "24exfITy3Qqq9Io1XhqyzfzpMCvSBmcf43yMXKdhc2XmUOfWYa3syIN4IUXJjFd3+3fIoKDjt1EKm79e7IDfciMNepgt5E9PcztAWph/0V8D2gH2LQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "hunting rituals", 
		"option_b": "marriage rituals", 
		"option_c": "communication rituals", 
		"option_d": "ratify alliances", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120129", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z2Aqq440lEhHgzPr2OyvfBSIdonGER6JzdTHhUavLa/v7zddlKByBjE1+snnFoLDi5VYL0Opu2v0V+9+39GS+C+3DdxhJ", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkSnr+4QlXRL70fX2NimBBVvzhA30bn2/RHhcB277", 
		"explanation": "25m5Zpbm0B7vt5YlVxPhhenwdWPRFWdRrG2KVap6cWXmUOfLYK3qwZIxEkyZiEk7wnfKoqD/+1obh6FYqZ6XcTEGPG80nCfG2j2BSIwDeaOmyF0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Neolithic", 
		"option_b": "Upper Palaeolithic", 
		"option_c": "Mesolithic", 
		"option_d": "Bronze Age", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120130", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEhzzy/nsdWTWQ3YZpj+2QrNxYjHTVavDa+LywIN5Ll/JnVN64XOGsK3x5VZPm6Be4JzfYicQcZ59y9WaiKYEnApGNtFeFFrTPN+CAMqx", 
		"answer": "27CpfZD/3QCo3mT1aTEdYpwDYo8LMd9bYg==", 
		"explanation": "25i9ZZP2wwqq+INgU17wxPP7dWLeQ3YZpj+2QrNxYjHTVavDa+LywIN5Ll/JnVN64XOGsK3x5VYLz7xT7M6ZYjcKapgvx9bJ3/H50HhPNIZFlIQy4pUQeLRHzSmlccbSLvkuy3+VJkn8fnm8CX96k3HCgnlb6hBFR+GtVXrMfrqTfxl3O9A=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "based on hierarchy", 
		"option_b": "based on age", 
		"option_c": "based on skill", 
		"option_d": "equally", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120131", 
		"question": "24GwbdHx0Bfut4A2VxDm0PzzOXKQF3AQrWyFXbF5dXWjXanWYa3/x9dOGGO2smREzTbBsarl5xMGgehP4YvfXicMcoJ7wNmKl/T/xWJEceQdrahdWMmNldsuLkei2+I=", 
		"answer": "27CgZ5by3Bb/5MdQG9PyOAdf1al/EA3QQtBh", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71FnE8oosWwr6zP6/JWPREGdd42uLV+N2cX/nFKLUYeHozJMxLlKdght6/DbDu6r39l4Amrsb7pyQZTJDfYpjxNWNl+W3x31APYTpDZWTARxK3r6eLMp3Y0xg", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "exogamous", 
		"option_b": "endogamous", 
		"option_c": "extended", 
		"option_d": "mutual aid", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120132", 
		"question": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgbSHN+sLACivgAm4QpnCPW7d8eXKjRK/DfeiyiZp0Kl6Mn0g7/XCGouXy9l0Lz7tT6JyadGIGb55uxNyQl+b213RFc8lK2ohn6o4WcvMAzTOpNNLUL/ouyW+UL0Dibje6Rry6/qyt2l54qW4UTkVfKY0=", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThk4/dCN/vcMGgT10liLSLfGo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1Arl4pcjVw2+hfjsJW7TCmMdr2bDVLF7fTHrQanWZ+P5iZZ/IxyPglR/snHHt6315VoBiOQb/ouNdWIQdop9zdTJ0vXixX1NKoZFl49849oLdPEAzjyjcJTWJfNsy3yTZ0HldTCzAzBgnDjFymxeqZC+t+wWCTtQbN2f464drEcNT7s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Up,per,paa", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120133", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV7hwPjyJivEDCIZommGErN4cWjmUOfDLub70NdjKFCMzVJ1sn3DprX5+VRPm6BeqbuPYCcRPrtuxNGM2Oj+0HlIMIZXlYN74Y4GPOBPyzi5fNHJYqEmrj7KVbGtML1XlN6grW4=", 
		"answer": "27a3ZZzm3xDp9pEpXRCwdpw9FmsQbDhCOSRmpXCp8g==", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZZzm3xDp9pEpXRC+he3+J3/ZAHcdom2PS+NjeWXrFLPKa637xJJjIFmHjl47/XCGr6T+8EYOiK0XqZmeY2ITd51g3NGFl+35hHxAOshQm4l87ZQYPOFOxSm0NMPSNPZnwC6UL0CwdDa+DXVgjXMkCWDtIFxH/G7ou8ZjsB8T", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "co,mm,uni,ca,ti,on", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120134", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU5Vx/g1r3rOivEC2dRsHaEXKpyeXLiWrOCa/v7x4MrZQl+IyEG8EzzAOmXd3xYGCs=", 
		"answer": "2+HuOMGz3Fnz8oQyQV6/5Pr6dWTWQ3YZpj+mU7FgeD2jB/eCY63nzJZjNBzErEtr93fUoqvz8hMAiehP4YvfdSMRcoJq28TJ3/H6xX9Sf4YW6dEnpJdfZfFB3i7gVcTLJf98z2CDIgX/YXmVC3171DnXiHVaoZD3tXDrBIpElkVixspL+ckuKJeQ3+iD5Ey2kkaByXeFQatlBV2Wu46h5QO1roYxtI/1DvCPkvO+7mxu+OHPRTlf", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW0Av+/8UpQV7zx/LqISuEVSITqnOPW6x6MGjmVbXRLuLyzddFL1nJiFpp/n/DsLGw/0YCjqZIqY+PYCcCbI5riNGb2PH5wDESY4ZJk4x+7ZURPO1FzS++NNXcL75GwWOPZ03xZTCxDWM41CXejzxQoZGo4We2Udc1xQdymYE4+cA5fNCa172AqGW3iwnOnHqBWLhlA1Gd9c+65FaSpMJq7Y2AuD7X/fv32uHW8cwYIglVsMZLa178hLwI6j54Xs70eB5K//CQYkHhNCG1JhoU9sWj33op74wtVGh0/QwGhoJCZ8QzwpekvSA/KsNuVWTq8xQNkcQsD1e0V/8jcX177Ja/03MTfTwQYChM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "4600 m years,Age of the Earth", 
		"option_b": "30 m years,Appearance of the earliest humans", 
		"option_c": "2â€“15 m years,Appearance of Homo habilis", 
		"option_d": "7000â€“6000,Start of plant cultivation in India", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120135", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUkWw3xyuv6J3KQF21Rt3eGErd9fXS5FmwRtHIl9Fti+HzZcbgmxXY=", 
		"answer": "2523ZZ6zwhj6/oAuQV7hxO32MGXDTjNA9i/TAuNtdXDxR+uCQuLpzIUxF12FjF50/n/Sq6zzt1IIiuhS586+djAKfYoimpCEl/3yxWNSf4Z3kZV+6Ilfc/IA/jygdcTSNPZrzXuTZ0T+Y3mODWZ1hDjCgnlVvZD2p3X7WZouxRQghcs4y8EuOZeb0LuQ51u9lAOGkSrJO+wyUVnZrMup+VDemmG4tKlyD3bi5OQMoV/MSA==", 
		"explanation": "25C5a5mz1RD59Io2VwzrhfLtdWrAE2cQsX6NUaY0c37xRqLRfuLwzYQxM1PJjBto4nPFqqP59BMbhqVeqYeRMDYLe8towcaM2aTjzXxEP89Kn8hA4ZxFXfpDxTijYJTzKe16wXyZawXEbzz9LGV5lT+Wj2pZpJav/Ci1FNUxgDw8ko55pIo1VvsPGlqXYv9G9oYuaSJW", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Homo sapiens,sapiens-115000 years", 
		"option_b": "Lower Palaeolithic age in Africa,2 m years", 
		"option_c": "Skulls of Ramapithecus and Sivapithecus,22 m years", 
		"option_d": "Fire discovered,18â€“16 m years", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120136", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUyVxn7yvO/IWSQCnYC42yKVa19dnjgVanBa7e8T3Fh4GWuEjz3wn+eR05xbw==", 
		"answer": "27C5e4X2wxeq9oskEg390On3MHneQ0MXsXaAU+5VYGHmVbXDYO77iZh3Z3SGgFQ7+nfEqqn55B9Pv6dP/o+NMDIPf59qycXJ3uq39HBKOtVQm457pKoKcv5BznCef8HXLO0uwWjAFUT9Zim0EHhxlyTFyn1YrMOI/DG6RNMjyBAxg5Q0reY9Ltqe3anT/ky0igObkU+ZTf13GkGVuY6n7QOdsoEwtMSO8RrU+fu5ifnD+dsFcUQSjJR2I3e9maMItQw3Qtu9ZAEL/uKQSVvgL2iwJh4U/MXwlmdo1ossU3p2qJcnVGluaZOYNIP8M1G/jA==", 
		"explanation": "25C5a5mzwxzt/oouEhbz1r3+dW/ZEHYYrXyXEqJmc3niUajOYer3ypZ9Z1ObzUt6/nPJrbH/+1wIhqta5c6MeSUNd41my9GH1OG3xWIBPsNKjol96p8bNMZFymeMetfSJfB6jkaJNFH/dSDxRER8kXH+n3FXpsO+4yi3Qc4+zxtymYE4xMY4NdbWm6HTatxf4Y+4ybDLwphV3FA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "eastern and southern Africa,Appearance of Homo habilis", 
		"option_b": "Potwar plateau in Pakistani Punjab,Skulls of Ramapithecus and Sivapithecus", 
		"option_c": "Narmada valley,The skull of archaic Homo sapiens", 
		"option_d": "Sri Lanka,Fossils of Homo sapiens sapiens", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120137", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy3iaN5IhyKglV492bS46r2t1JPjKRa58LfcTFDf4UvzciG0OX6y2RSc8FWlZViqNoacfFSyzipNNDOMvdgyS6UL0CwSTyyCHlgnDjVymxeqZC+ySmHWoh+gCY9lY59+dF8NdnfzaCWqHiolgOQnEuQRLxhHliQocah6AOMqIMrsI2asCGb9vXqn/yT/9BLah1cq49xZBu9maxJ/iU3VYizaQZD9PbZb1PRLhStdEdd1crt0WFowYdpTmwx+QwGlowWasFl09jrrjs3NsNrATa+401Oh4B0WlejZK29wijU4Vk+cHUnbJ5ltS51sQedO1FClFyURS9Z1I9tvsQRkERif2BWmTbzlj6fhWiKcofwq4HugKjzr6tx96AzdgNFoGObaQZXoC8AFlZog1p0", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNHn2Ryq9ocvRBuwTFEBCg9dupS5SfARl++4hA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hfp8pU0EhH0hfy/NmfRDS5RomzDU600dWnsU6bPYfjtiZBjKEmZwRt+/3PUpKD0t1canaFV7s6LeCdDUI5gxNmd3+30hGFJMtVBpo5B65kWeeBZjDSjNMDTJb5b3n6FNQXAZjW8AX94nSXeg38WuIu65iL7Q9skgBczhYJ8rccyfN+K17ya5kr4hwiGnH2eR7kkFlWNvcu64k2bnIwUtMOKpDPc8bTqn/3e454fbUhavpB6I1Sunq8A9issVMz0YRwL5ezVIWH9MC2xZz4c9crm2Xhg0oogXikk/B5Vh8HQ7+iz+inc8sLrBOvM5K7/", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Human Evolution: The Old Stone Age >> Art in the Old Stone Age &   Earliest Human Organization", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1,2,3 only", 
		"option_d": "All the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130101", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRoniGEqFxd3jtFK7MLuy+3phjK1jJjlR15nPet/qy/ufwYk9EzxfO7c5MDrJ/UQ==", 
		"answer": "2+zoOMGz8zqobwMgmZZrL2ee/VaWE0HNBg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH03Rbo9olgfBv9yfTrPWLTQ2MWpj+KQeN5cWPoUaOCb/6+2oNwNUiAg1w79GTJruWppwNfz4p4q2bTvE5TbbFL4qKAD5mUylg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "7000 BC", 
		"option_b": "9000 BC", 
		"option_c": "4500 BC", 
		"option_d": "5500 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130102", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t6glWgz1xO/3dWffAGMFpnvcECp2OasOufxcw/Nu2w2P4LI=", 
		"answer": "25e5ZITw2RD544QuEKGbWuATy4NJVkK2AsTHZjk=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEg370ej+IW7UQ2sf412CXrZ3eHjwQKbMIq3/iYdjKEqAg1h+snnA45Xx/Focm6lVqyQdoHMYTHkCP8bJpb7v6jU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Punjab", 
		"option_b": "Sind", 
		"option_c": "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa", 
		"option_d": "Baluchistan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130103", 
		"question": "25q2KIb72Brit5cpRBvggu6/N2reCCIYsD+uV6tmd3DxXOfRZ/nryIN0IwPLNPlEN3UDKWBA0OhD136IDg==", 
		"answer": "25e3ZJD9kQvj4YAyECwW0mqDFu7yT81/H9z/5ZY=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEhL9xvzrMG+QDGxRt3eGEqF1fnqjW6GCeuX7ibV+K12HzUly5HPU4b9LliirYFBzYR6+YFq5WK8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Indus river", 
		"option_b": "Bolan river", 
		"option_c": "Brahmaputra river", 
		"option_d": "Ganges river", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl72zPm/G27fD2sFq3aAErNxf2HvUefNaK3TzJ9jIF2bhRt//XvDsLH59FIbiuhS54eLeSMPcpIwijzgxbgHXOt1ywKduiaOQT0=", 
		"answer": "25K3aYXgk8cAY6rj1i3EMPbVFhi415U=", 
		"explanation": "25y2YYX60BXm7slgVRHz0e6/JXnVB20cqnGCRqZwMHjtFIrHZv/5yIV5ZVj7ww96mnSqmR+C1cBPqpI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cattle", 
		"option_b": "Sheep", 
		"option_c": "Goats", 
		"option_d": "Horses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IlgUBv1xPO/IWSQAWdRqHGMRa00cXf3UbWCOriumddTBByAgxtW937UpKTi/wxNts8nSxZugwlJZCf1Cvoisw==", 
		"answer": "24W3fIX2w2D5t5IoVxv+h2Wy7kNhwPBj4hEXlMy+cww=", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkU2/p9VgcD2+hen3MCvADHYFpm36QeNjeHTmWOfVb/6+wpl+MFLJhFU733POsaLx5VtNcqZRTu3tCZLgfUQJ34eHDQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Stone axe", 
		"option_b": "Potterâ€™s wheel", 
		"option_c": "Granaries", 
		"option_d": "Hoe", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130106", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhz48sU0Whuy1fjwJWfVQ20X41KGWrFzcWPrFKPLffnr25V0IxyLlBt9/nnJp7avtUXiwQgbwz7UWWCTve7uFHA=", 
		"answer": "2+DtOMGz8zqoPt384J9Kt20fs6GpNerAmg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1A3++4AtVxDmhfTxdUbVC3AWom2LEqV1c3TnFKPLffnr25VwKV+MzV1p/XuGpan/+Fccz6lJ5puRdGJWK9s/iPKqlTcxUJZoiY1pioBxBjiXWDI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "4500 BC", 
		"option_b": "7000 BC", 
		"option_c": "5000 BC", 
		"option_d": "5500 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130107", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Bj+8pcpUxKy0vjtMCvEC2dRpG2CXKJmeXTwFK7MLsD7wYV2Jk6BzVZ04WLKuuX99lcKz6ddtsxjEpr5zsVzjd6T5alRRF9M", 
		"answer": "25itbNHxwxDp/JZiVM1xFLpxTPq+ikWONX5Qtw==", 
		"explanation": "25KqaZ/ywxDv5MUpXF7fwPXtMmrCCyIGpm2GEqRxfnTxVavOd63zyJN0Z1OPzVZu9jbEsazz/EBNyHbC/gznnXtsFkzSOWchfw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone", 
		"option_b": "Wood", 
		"option_c": "Mud bricks", 
		"option_d": "Clay", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130108", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyFQ2y0e/2N37EAnAI432CQap6MGLiQ+fEYf/q0NpiIkqMgxtX82LDseXe8lwDhrxT4I3fYycXaodqxdWHw/eohnMF9ZNnmR21PgibGs0yYrM=", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgkwft0vCTUmY+HgPjdVQpsqE=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnu5YwlVl7wxO72OyvfBSI5onSRU+80cTH3Rq7Ae/n/244xKFrJmVN+sl/Ip7DjuxMJgLpP8MOMdTQGcMtDycSMxaTZwX5NOtJMk4My958LaPhFwTijYMebKP94yy6CIkD+Jz+yEX5w1vJFr/pOm9WLY7QNLZJENxI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Brahmaputra", 
		"option_b": "Ganges", 
		"option_c": "Indus", 
		"option_d": "Yamuna", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130109", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxRbl+8UpQV7CxO/+JmPFEWMcoj+FU657ZWLvTefDff7xyp5wM1mNzUxy5n6Gqquw9l0Mhq1V/c6TdSUGcI98l5K7jhYaw8YFPDwTJhR0+7LJ", 
		"answer": "25SgbdNjJdFnufpbudgs/BMwIkZQ", 
		"explanation": "25S2a5j23w2q+4AnVxD21r3tMHvCBnEUrWvDYqJmcWLrQbXDY+y+yIQxJlLJhFZr/WTSoqvkt1IXiuVM4IuTdCsNectnzcKGlVaikVhidSuFierNeeNxBtg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Sword", 
		"option_b": "Bow", 
		"option_c": "Axe", 
		"option_d": "Spear", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTfv+IkpRhb7xr3rOmTcQ2UDrGqTEqpnMHziRqzHaq380NdjIl+djFV853rHseXx71Ycz79S/YbfcWIAa5l5zdTJ1PHj0HhPNIZBnod3u9j4al4e6bPmG6v4ks1OCRti", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nA7v5JElQBCw9Gub0V45aP4GevtyuFGfgw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH93gv+/8g3Vw3mwO/xdWzCDHcB43CFEo1xf33qQK/Lba3qxph9NByAnht4+nfUoqbk8kEGla1fqYyGMDAGfZ9uxtec2+XlhHBZNtUEjYlm7NoePPdV3iuocJTYNep6x2CHZ0D0YDz/8uNLkX95garxQWqS1eTtUg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "North-eastern", 
		"option_b": "Southern", 
		"option_c": "North-western", 
		"option_d": "Central", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130111", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRoniGErBgcWP3FK7MLuDx2oMxN12bmUg7/XCGsKrl41tPpqZf4I/AMq9TFPGcOfe4Gm1oOEh5BIw=", 
		"answer": "2+ftOMGz8zqovlsdHqVxyggrDT5kC/Zx/Q==", 
		"explanation": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUzVwrmyfjyMGXEECIXrGqNVuN9fjHwW7LWZq3Xx5N4JhyIn1479XPIprfx+18Wz6ZU/c6QfCYGbMt7wNGHl7ailCEBEeUG/rRs7i9Q6Dc4kHQ7jtqT+g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "7000 BC", 
		"option_b": "5000 BC", 
		"option_c": "2500 BC", 
		"option_d": "1000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRj48oRgVhf2hfPwISvYAnQU42uLV+NxcWPvXaLReq3QzJh9LkiBhFg74XPSt6n1+lYBm7sb4IDfZCoGPqJhzNmI2aTk0XNCPMhQk4536o5AProGiJwAYWy1TS3PuaOPo5c=", 
		"answer": "24a3fYX71AvktcINBgVI4mSfIlIcYzTVIYk=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wuEjzzyej8PWLDF2Mf42iCQeNgeHSjUabQYuT72oMxLFKGmlU73HPJr6zk/1oMz7te/ZqTdS8GcJ8jiNSIw+HzhHBTPNNKnsAltMpPPNZjjgEhCP0mUvMuesadwKjexbY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "North-western", 
		"option_b": "North-eastern", 
		"option_c": "Southern", 
		"option_d": "Central", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuywfT7dX/YBiI9omuGQONadX7vXbPKZ+6+2pJlM1CMgF515mWGs6Tm8hMbh60b/o+GMCQMbNQtqFxXlyg6TGaAs1lkj9NLFw==", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjkt4Y1Xgrn1/i98yq23wsPgxjNxfhSXxn2vw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHf0A3v5cUOVxH+zOn3PGiQEGcFt3OGX6Z6ZGKjUbHLaujw3ZtoZ0yIm15/smLOpuXn9kpPiadJqZqXdWIRd5hqiN+Pl/D/wTFpMtRFipBz6tocafhU2S+oNhQO/ynYanwxXx+S6t2b5nA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Vedic culture", 
		"option_b": "Harappan culture", 
		"option_c": "Mauryan culture", 
		"option_d": "Gupta culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq2oAoQBnz1/W/Om3EBmxRsXqFV7FmdXWjQKiCb/6+y5JlMFmMgxtv+nOGiqv04kBPjqZfqZqXdWIue49m3NWbxeX5wXBPbIRtwLw+tYR3+09Cloc0/sFL", 
		"answer": "25q2bdH811n+/4BgXh/gwvjsISv+Bm0dqmuLW6A0Y3T3QKvHY+jw3YQzTifPWhvVtiKRHCSS/G0BqA==", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEh3zyfH6MSvfDWdRrHnDRqtxMH3iRqDHffm+55J+K1WdhVJ4smXDt7H88l4KgbxIqYyaZDUGe4Uv3NiMl835wGRSc8dKnsBm7J9fUfFExSmoZsbaLvtvwCxHB2w3vrMeOzMswOD30k2R", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "The bread basket", 
		"option_b": "One of the smallest Neolithic settlements", 
		"option_c": "One of the largest Neolithic settlements", 
		"option_d": "The granary of Baluchistan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl730/jxIX7RD24I43CWRq1hfXPmRqLGLvn2zNd+M1SMn0g7+3iGjqD45VQOnaAEqwlvibMkEN5nT/1nq9YrO6I=", 
		"answer": "25a5fIX/1FsFaKo2jl4yS9sXSdd+FnB8", 
		"explanation": "25a5fIX/1Fnv4YAuRgvzyfHmdWTFF2wErn2GQKZwMGXrUefNeuX729dwKVWEjFdosn/I44j1/0EIjrpTq2XdwFHvNq2hw5XX50H4IwU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sheep", 
		"option_b": "Goats", 
		"option_c": "Cattle", 
		"option_d": "Horses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130116", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5clVRf9y73oMHnVQ0wUrHOKRqt9czH3W6jOfa36wIRlLlKOmFJo+nPC46fpt0MAg6FI4YubMDEXcYVqiNGR0ve303hVO4ZF2pJ3544ecvNVwDy/NNbONOoxjMeUEdLTHLjA8jtxOo4xERs=", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nBzr5JElQBCwO1tIVdjLxlZHSZkRlZ7O9A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH93gv+/8glUw3mwO/xdWzCDHcB43aQEq51YnrmUOfAd63uxpt4NFSMiRto5nnIpuXx71Ycz79S/YbfcWIRe4h7yd6Owuj21jFDJtJQ2Ix+InfwvhEyQ/MdKQA3+jA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "North-eastern", 
		"option_b": "North-western", 
		"option_c": "Southern", 
		"option_d": "Central", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130117", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut4QnQBfx0PHrIHnRDyIQrXvDXbd8dWOjVaTWZ/v33Z50NBybiEhu/3OGqquw2lYHna9a+4bfcSQXe5kvytWA2eO3wHhSJ9NWmIV2pJgGPPJMwzKpZ4uZN/FbYantlg2aqdQt9nsojg==", 
		"answer": "2+DoOMGz8zqogQx4mp4MnViP/2A/y3DUUA==", 
		"explanation": "25S7fJjl2A3j8pZgRRvgwL3tMHjFDmcV436RXbZ6dDG2BPeSLs/diZ5/Z3GMhUl882TO46T241Ydz7xT7M6beTEXa5ltyd6K0qTx1n5Mc8BIlY9299hyylrgNxoG8au/onG9kBuV", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "6000 BC", 
		"option_b": "5500 BC", 
		"option_c": "5000 BC", 
		"option_d": "4500 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130118", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRD5t6sPZl7zhdP6OmfZF2oYoD+QV7dgfHTuUanWLuzszJYxJV2aiF87/XiGt631t0cWn61IqYGZMCMbe5gv3cOM07u1eYW4NLkKmIXyTM8ddmFwIQ==", 
		"answer": "25a9ZoXh0BWoe5ENMyy4D/CoE6giIx1cKQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEhP3y+n2OmXDQ2wesWuLH7RxY2XmRqmOLuPx24N5almInk9+4HiK46T+8xMcgL1P4YuNfmICbctu2tWIxKT4wjFvNslIk5R67Zlfb/FU2DGoedHVNO0uzG+TIkGwaDf9EHhx1CXPmnlF6Iy9tSajUcl1nTyHLw7D38p6NAQE2KHbeA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "North-western", 
		"option_b": "North-eastern", 
		"option_c": "Southern", 
		"option_d": "Central", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRj48oRnQV7cwPLzPH/YCmFRt3CMXrA0cWPmFKPLffn3x5BkLk+BiF878G+Gor315BMYhrxTqYGJcS5DbYJrzcPJ1urzhGFOOshQn4Qy5o8LaKsCsTfbupwd5Kky3VAOhJyWow==", 
		"answer": "24a3fYX71AvktcINBgVI4mSfIlIcYzTVIYk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg3gz+/4AyXF711/LqJSvfBSI/pnCPW7d8eXKjQKjNYv6+wIQxKl2bhl5/snTf46To8kBPmKFP4c6QZiMPPphmzNWal+X5wDFRPM9KjoV2pJgKaOAC3AJUcvxGIO5WKbffF0Xv7A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "North-eastern", 
		"option_b": "North-western", 
		"option_c": "Central", 
		"option_d": "Southern", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130120", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRs3qMQq9xMH7lFIrHZv/5yIV5Z0ybiF90/3/Ioqvk+0pPn7pU7ZucdX1BdkA2oWbS8zw6ibho6vnrZw==", 
		"answer": "24KwbZDnkRjk88UiUwz+wOS9HSPUlzIi/GKG2q8zClbuAw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1fjwJWfVQ20X41KGWrFzcWPrFLfQa+nxxJ5/JlKdgUI74mTJp7Dz8ldPmKBe6JrfcSwHPolu2tyMzqYFDkvkSQcyh0Nx11sHOrQP", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Rice", 
		"option_b": "Wheat and barley", 
		"option_c": "Lentils", 
		"option_d": "Fruits", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130121", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfxv61/r+J2OQCnFRrHGGEqxyMGXrUefOb//5zIRlZ3KMgldy5n7PoOXj8kcbg61W7ICLY2I/cLdh+tWIxOv5njFsNs5WnYFg7NoTdfFTjD+oYMPeJfAu2maFZ2z+YyyuRHF6kHHCgnkWhYa//DO+Rsg2zhAzmMUri0669ggG56YZW3ED5xXo", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddDIl2aglU7+2WGt631t1AAnbpe6prfdToTcophycSA2Oq3y3cBEtVXn5Jm7ZURPpj8mlgY8S9+7q+6nUJOO0w=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEh39y+72MW7CBmZRrHGGEqxyMGXrUefOb//5zIRlZ3KMgldy5n7PoOXj8kcbg61W7ICLY2IPcYhu3NWNl+by0GZENsgEjoh3pLMReOFTjDyjcJTPKPsu42uELlH1dSu8CnV1mnO0NtD8pxpqXRMi8VT63wKa", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130122", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfBv9yfTrPWLTQ3EUt2uPV7FnMHjtFIrHZv/5yIV5Z0maiF878HnSq+Xj41wBiuha54rfci0Ne8t7x9+FxKTLyk1PAcNFiY98vtosaPtOyX25e9vXM755y3yFZ1DjYj39EH80liTfhngWr5G6+yapXd8kgjzXOMZKD1IrxYBK89iaG+I=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddDIl2aglU7+2WGrarkt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8lC2qFh958NaP1Pwn+UijOOtp2FKh4b3JkFo0I5", 
		"explanation": "24asZ5/2kRjk88UiXRD3henwOmfDQ3UUsXrDR7BxdDHhTefsa+LywIN5Ll/Jnl5v5nrDsbaw8Vwdz75a+4eQZTFDf4h7wcaAw+3y1z0BMdNQ2olmo4lfcvtUjC69cdfSJvdryi6UL0TkJyqpC35x1CXZhXBF6JS+5yL7QckyxFUmmcd6+MEwOJeYy6md6V+xgxXA7Qn5Y9gD50gqhqjVDMVyMQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130123", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYhHm1r3oMHnVQ3IDrHuWUaZwMHjtFIrHZv/5yIV5Z12PmV5psiKT8/Ww1XBPs6Zn57yacTEMcNEv/NiMl/T40GVEIb9X2pd64Z8TPONB332metvMLr5vyHqFNQWkMmntRFJX1qJ9YZSiEq/zqukbGfK0/kg=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddDIl2aglU7+2WGt631t1AAnbpe6prfdToTcophycSA2Oq3y3cBEtVXn5Jm7ZURPpj8mlgY8S9+7q+6nUJOO0w=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH43xb9+4AkVRuyyvu/IWPVQ3Iet2uGQNpnMGbrUaLOLuz43ZJjZwjc3Qs70FWGr6D0t0cAz7xT7M6PYi0Ha4h7wd+Hl+vxhGFOJ9UGpTfW5dLN6h/ZMf8tSLYJWw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130124", 
		"question": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEhL9xvzrMG+QCmxRnEC8bZxLTz2jVefSfOLowJlyIhyGixtL833PsLHx+REtOtRjRiXKSnQKT6f8ght+", 
		"answer": "25e5ZITw2RD544QuEKGbWuATy4NJVkK2AsTHZjk=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEhL9xvzrMG+QCmxRgX6PR6B8eWL3VamAK+FBDFybJcYJPRAybXnLdA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Ba,lu,ch,is,tan", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130125", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7hwOnrOW7CECIYrT+uV6tmd3DxXOfVa//7iZN4NEicn1l+9jbEuuX2+1wAi7sb6JyQZSwHPrRQ9++26Nu35lIDlPSJdqJgiWPoDPe4daUvDQ==", 
		"answer": "zODoONUeDTP8Cq8xPVjzcueerA8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13Rbl85ZgWxCy6Pj3J2zREWpRrHyAR7FmdXWjVbXNe+P6icIkdwzJr3g5g+pOGCSyKT0pO/V2/VLBVQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 5000, 
		"option_b": 5500, 
		"option_c": 4500, 
		"option_d": 6000, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130126", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy0fX6dUXVDG4Yt3eKUeN1d3SjXamCR+P6wJYxMk+MiRto5nnIpuXPyGwwsJdkqYeRMC4CbIxqiN6c2uby1mIDieT8NQWB0Iaq4/9h+m5/UQ==", 
		"answer": "27SgbYKxB/GV4RfL7mVFLUuKu12zLg==", 
		"explanation": "24asZ5/2kRjy8pZgRRvgwL3qJm7UQ3UYp3qPS+NwZWPqWqCCeuX7ibl0KFCAmVNy8TbHpKCyr7K1dOwA7KzrEi2XBgE8lQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "ax,es", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130127", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1vjrIWfVDmcftz+MVONZdXnxU6bQZq332tdiLkicjE9+9jbJreXk/1ZPjalV4s6QdmIXdo4v9++26NvI+zFTOtBBiMJDWPbLcmQpRtEi7d2CaoR0", 
		"answer": "27e3ZJD9k59nUWW0KxHNGxUXjicBNto=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit4wzEhL9xvzrMG+QDGxRt3eGEqF1fnqjW6GCeuX7ibV+K12HzUly5HPU4b9LliirYFBzYR6+YFq5WK8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "bol,an", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130128", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofEhngyujvdWTWQ0wUrHOKRqt9czH3W6jOfa332td1Lk+dhFV853/Vq6D0t1EWz7pe6pqefiUWcop9iNGR0ve303hVO4ZF2oNn9owaeLRD2Sm5fdrcYPtqyWvCT3m3okX/CkLYjprUKG+KCw==", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nA7v5JElQBCw9Gub0V45aP4GevtyuFGfgw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH93gv+/8g3Vw3mwO/xdUXVDG4Yt3eKUeNgf37vR+fKb/v7iYV0JEiIg1xu/nfU46To8kBPmKFP4c6eMCEWbJ1qzJCKwvDjzX9Gc8NAnYUwQyANXt6ijJSAV8xzMvwadA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "No,rt,h-,we,st,ern", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130129", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUOVxH+zOn3PGiQF20erz+EQKxhYDH0XbPKLuTq2td1Lk+dhFV853/Vq6z+8BMJiqlP/JyaKmBTlXghbbws+1lzXWrhtxOV", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nA7v5JElQBCyiM3wOWLDC2cV42yXXa1xMHD7UbSCeeTqwddwZ06Mjk96/HHTr6Tit1Eam7wXqaCQYjYLM45u28SMxeq3iVBZNtUEjYlm7NoQavVMjC6kcNHIYP9gyi6QKEz+czy5RHJhgCWayk9ZvZez8DW1FJcFxRYml4l/+MQ9Lpeewa2AqFqxkg7C3TuSXa9yFFDZttu8/0qSp8I9scqI/XL3++P8iLjj8dIKZwdetpJ3alj8lq8MuCM2EemyehtI8KmCIVmtOS2iNR1fHsbC+kqH9uglKBrMWOwxbw==", 
		"explanation": "2+TxKL/8ww3iupIlQQr31/O/eCvxQ1Ier3aQWqZwMGL3W6nHLuzmzIQxMFWdhRt6smTDoLHx+VQag6lJqYyKZDY/cNkmiP6GxfD/iXRAINJBiI4yqdo9PNVYyS7tY93PKL5h2G+MZ1b5YzyuRHF6kHHGhXVYvIa/tSWuQM4LzkZ71rR3+Nw0OcWRmeXTy3+9hRKD0nyERLx2UVWBsN3o/EqIqMI59c6YoyTe8LT6j+zH+dAMIg1WuIM9KvTbHYpEsN7v7xr34qBWCg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "North-western,Polished stone axes with a rectangular butt", 
		"option_b": "North-eastern,Axes with oval sides and pointed butt", 
		"option_c": "Southern,Rectangular axes with a curved cutting edge", 
		"option_d": "Lower Palaeolithic age in Africa,2 m years", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130130", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUOVxH+zOn3PGiQAmEFqmmKRro0Z3j3XOfLev6+3Z58IlCAg14hsFxla4Hwu4GKKKpOQDChFbs=", 
		"answer": "25Gxe4Xmwxvr+YYlEhzrhfvzOmTUECJc9irTAuNWUz3RUbTXY/3qwJh/Z1OPzVp84H/Ftqnk4kEOg+ha6pqWZisXd458iJ3ch7SnhFNif/ZWlYRn544Wc/oAwzvtZNvPM74jjk+GM0DiJ23oVCA0thKa3ioG+MO2tT6+VcgkjTQ1k8d364goNNLf/KmB/EX6Cmkhmn5X39s5h6LPl4KGIA==", 
		"explanation": "25Gxe4Xmwxvr+YYlEhzrhfvzOmTUECJc4yrWAvM0UlLfWpXHffjz2YN4KFLJgl0783HUqqbl+0canalXqY+cZCsVd59mzcPJmqSilCERc+Rnpo5C9pUbafdUxTKjNNvdYO5h2n3AagXRYS24FjAgwWGGyl516qCUcz/wglskCCHl2lJvTJg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Disturbance by floods,5500 BC", 
		"option_b": "Resumption of agricultural activities,5000 BC", 
		"option_c": "Production of pot,After 4500 BC", 
		"option_d": "4600 m years,Age of the Earth", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130131", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUsXR3z0fTwOyvHCnYZ43aXQeNwdWLgRq7SeuTxx80z8N8MpEYCr/u4GF96lBFZHw==", 
		"answer": "25i9YIP00Avit8hgfh/gwvjsISv+Bm0dqmuLW6A0Y3T3QKvHY+jw3ddzIkieiF51sl/Ip7Djt1IBi+h27IqWZCcRbIphzdGHm8z2z2NAc4tgiIl34NodfedJwn26fcDTYNJv2muSZ2v1aDW0EHh9l3HFj2hCpIa28CmvR5YByRs2np55/ohxEtiNzaCW+kP4lRaXzmjRX7RwGRS3sMGk4leUqYF4psSZtCGX1fD4l//S4tZGZgdfupVrali9g6EG9mo3V4i1ZhtG8OjDI+svOQ9GkgxPVvQsYkveO7w=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit8hgfh/gwvjsISv+Bm0dqmuLW6A0Y3T3QKvHY+jw3ddzIkieiF51sl/Ip7Djt1IBi+h27IqWZCcRbIphzdGH6+rfxXpTMoYJ2qRg7Z8bPPZB3zSjNMPSNPYu4m+UIlewSTyyCHlgnDjVym9TvJe38Cq+Ws4k/BsEn4l85dE9L5fSmei951+sjgOQ0juCWKh2AhSOvNqgq22Zr44xocWEsnLI/eD8ibo+gzDq8NEs1KOEbi1061Fl", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mehrgarh,Largest Neolithic settlement between Indus and Mediterranean", 
		"option_b": "Hakra,Dried basin with Later Neolithic settlements", 
		"option_c": "Vindhyas,Northern spurs with Neolithic sites", 
		"option_d": "Adamgarh,domestication of animals", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130132", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgXxvzy+6/TX/YBiIBr36AV+N7djHhXbXBZpShi9/him8+8obveA9QjsoGL1A=", 
		"answer": "25eteovy2Rbntc2MShUa5QAQJnrqShQYckE=", 
		"explanation": "25eteovy2Rbnt5EyUxDhyfzrMHiQF21R5GuLV+NkfHDgUefNaK38wIVyLxvLQDMDzqSCTnD8WcaLiWKmjA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Burzahom", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Chirand", 
		"option_d": "Koldihwa", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130133", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5AuWw/nwL3+N2TFFyIFq3rDcLZmanDrW6qCaf//35JieB7QdUmQHVtx3DDIrmHR2Y8B", 
		"answer": "25G3ZZTgxRDpt4EvVQ2y0vjtMCvSFnAYpnvDRapgeDH3XKLLfK3zyIRlIk6az1W8fZh5m0jvfE4p5qrRQu8=", 
		"explanation": "25q2ZIiz0A2q1ZAySB/6yvCzdX/YBnAU5GzDV7V9dHTtV6KCYeu+zZh2NByLiFJ19TbEtrf58ldPmKFP4c6LeCcKbMtg396Mxfe1mnpryUVbtUe+P90B/J222g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Dogs were buried separately", 
		"option_b": "Domestic dogs were buried with their masters", 
		"option_c": "Cattle bones were found in graves", 
		"option_d": "Graves had multiple layers of bodies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130134", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5YpRhuywfT7dX/YBiI/pnCPW7d8eXKjRKLNfuH7iZt4MVnJhFU74n/SsOXy7hMOz6Ra4ovSYysHe9QtpXzKhI3ljn/MkTKIuKYjEA==", 
		"answer": "25eteovy2Rbntc2MShUa5QAQJnrqShQYckE=", 
		"explanation": "25SsKLPmwwPr/4otHl7cwPLzPH/YCmFRqnGLU6F9ZHDtQLSCYuTozJMxLlLJnVJv4TbIpqTit1JPg6lQ7MyMnwQemFvLOpY7NfkDmwv8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chirand", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Burzahom", 
		"option_d": "Koldihwa", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130135", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yyfL8NH/VByJF8j+IX+Nnf2T3XLDHffm+xpExFE6Ag1p882SZ4dmnWGtDZHON0c4lsWBpf64=", 
		"answer": "25Ktbprh0BWoQuCIktjWHDIk4rjmaBHmaA==", 
		"explanation": "25Ktbprh0BWq/pZgRhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+QW7dxMH3sV6bWa+m+ncYxLFHJnlRu5n7Rprbkt1wJz5tJ4ICedyMRPEbcE2ZjVCcukh3fm8xDlvw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chirand", 
		"option_b": "Burzahom", 
		"option_c": "Gufkral", 
		"option_d": "Koldihwa", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130136", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yzvPwImWQBW0D42uLV+N3ZX33XbHDeuTxx9d+IRybhFh+sn/I47H48hMJhq5P4c6SeS4Pe4VhwcWEl8bUmzOP0eIbVIxhLTMzH7+GYuIe", 
		"answer": "2563ZJX62Q7rt4QuVl7fxPX+MnnRQcc/L/DPS0WrurH53s+7Q/U=", 
		"explanation": "2563ZJX62Q7rt4QuVl7fxPX+MnnRQ2sf416PXqJ8cXPiUOfGZ/7q255yMxyIn147+XjJtKuw8Vwdz61a+4KGMDAKfY4vy8WFw+3hxWVIPMgGcfLo5fvqslDBecP7mbzWGg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Chirand", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Senuwar", 
		"option_d": "Koldihwa and Mahagra", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130137", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTfv+IkpRhb7xr3sPH/VQ2sC43OMUaJgdXWjV6vNfei+3ZgxM1SMzXl09n6LhKTp9hMbiqVL5YvAMhNdqXHKZmDk5cUXHXmKJX8=", 
		"answer": "24G5epD32BGolAfydQVKwnRO9EqgE5Pkqw==", 
		"explanation": "24G5epD32BGq/pZgRhb3he72IW6QD20SomuGVuN6dXDxFLPKa63cxpN5anuIlFo75nPLs6n1tW5m9XAfLrlDxo2WftZw6XU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Senuwar", 
		"option_b": "Koldihwa", 
		"option_c": "Taradih", 
		"option_d": "Burzahom", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130138", 
		"question": "25SsKIb72Brit5YpRhuy0vjtMCvSDGwU42uMXa9nPDHwRKLBZ+v3ypZ9K0XJgFp/9zbJpeXx+UcDirpIpc6beTEAcZ1q2tWNiKbdQDgwdrqI4SPdCpz9KO2a", 
		"answer": "25awYYPy3x2oCBp/RaOqoibtppuZmXlkjQ==", 
		"explanation": "25awYYPy3x2q7owlXhr3wb3xIGbVEW0EsD+BXa1xMGXsW6vRLuD/zZIxIU6GgBt6/GLKprfjtVO2/N97edvKoE+JUcikVtE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Burzahom", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Koldihwa", 
		"option_d": "Chirand", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130139", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj3g3+8pc5EgvhwPm/N3KQF2oU42+GXbN4dTHsUufge//kyJ9+KhyejEg74mTDp6r9/l0OgbxX8NHduXqyetJFGiv5RLeMXRWRYA==", 
		"answer": "25a3aYPg1Fnt5YA5Eg790en6J3KSucj7HbG9K90seZIbaO+Y3A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63xHr9Yw0UxDm1r3wMyvyFnALoneMX+NkYnTnW6rLYOzw3ZtoZ0maiF878XnHsbb1t1QdirEb+YGLZCcRZ8ma1ZajsroSFAJMiYi9kLc4", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Coarse red pottery", 
		"option_b": "Fine blue pottery", 
		"option_c": "Coarse grey pottery", 
		"option_d": "Painted pottery", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130140", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgXhf31r2rZSvbDiIGpmyXEqxyMEHiQKnDLuLwiYN5IhyHgklv+nPUreXj/lcKz6ddqZqXdWIkf4VozcPWlS8nKYPUS7Z07UiTiaA+GdA=", 
		"answer": "25awYYPy3x2oCBp/RaOqoibtppuZmXlkjQ==", 
		"explanation": "25awYYPy3x2q/pZgXhHxxOn6MSuEUyIarj+UV7BgMH7lFJfDeuP/iZh/Z0iBiBtc83jBpra3t10AnbxT7JyRMDEKeo4tkAwitBBmglcTvQ0S8I3ZEQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Senuwar", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Chirand", 
		"option_d": "Burzahom", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130141", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWh/2hfjpPG/VDWEU43CFEqF7ZHmjVaDQZ+7rxYNkNVnJjFV/snfIqqjx+xMHmrtZ6ICbYjtcPNgHIJcAswUqBN0cqvc6Jmc=", 
		"answer": "25Ktbprh0BWoQuCIktjWHDIk4rjmaBHmaA==", 
		"explanation": "25Ktbprh0BWt5MUOVxH+zOn3PGiQCmwZon2KRqJ6ZGKjRLXDbfn3ypJ1Z16GmVM783HUqqbl+0cana0b6ICbMCMNd4ZuxJCBwvf1xX9FId8GlUUuIbkLQzBUnbmpcu9lqg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Burzahom", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Chirand", 
		"option_d": "Koldihwa", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130142", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTfv+IkpRhb7xr3sPH/VQ2sC43GMRuN9fjH3XKKCYOLs3Z88MFmamV5p/DbBsarl5wxND05jTsQuUViW4YXxeZq1zw==", 
		"answer": "25awYYPy3x2oCBp/RaOqoibtppuZmXlkjQ==", 
		"explanation": "25awYYPy3x2q+oQ5Ehz3hfTxNmfFB2cV43aNErd8dTHtW7XWZqD7yIRlIk6HzVxp/WPW7+X++EdPm6BeqYCQYjYLM5xq28SMxeq3w2NOJtYG3X90ONSgOxlW2Yl1XuH5oA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gufkral", 
		"option_b": "Chirand", 
		"option_c": "Koldihwa", 
		"option_d": "Senuwar", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130143", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoVw33he72IW7DQ2sC42yKRrZ1ZHTnFK7MLvn2zNd5LlCFnht09DbnsLbx+gxNsC2Tn8h8Qkwu7Z8ygNd5qQ==", 
		"answer": "25K5ep6z2RDm+5ZiGYN5+VUI/1sqklDJssq0hg==", 
		"explanation": "25u9Z536xRHj9MU0XRH+1r33NH3VQ2AUpnHDVqpnc371UbXHaq33x9dlL1nJqlpp/TbOqqn85BMAieh6+p2efWB7gT4R9MirbMvHxBqqZozw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Garo hills", 
		"option_b": "Vindhyas", 
		"option_c": "Kaimur hills", 
		"option_d": "Mirzapur", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130144", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEh/i1e/wLWLdAnYU43qCQK99dWL3FKPDeui+z5hjZ36cn0F6+nnL/Ofk3FJICz6OAxoDkuV97XbT", 
		"answer": "2+fvOMGz8zqoTIQfhVoN20DedUFtOFJ5hg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl72xOn6dWrDEG0Sqn6XV6c0Z3j3XOfge//kyJ9+KhyAnht68HnTt+WioANfz4p4q3SMVMXPIoVG5gsgaTjkKS4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "2000 BC", 
		"option_b": "2700 BC", 
		"option_c": "2500 BC", 
		"option_d": "3000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130145", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yzvPwImWQAnFRt3eGEuR3cWfmFKjELvn2zNdhKEidiEk8rTReoKbSTTuyt3G3JNVuIISi", 
		"answer": "25Ktbprh0BWoQuCIktjWHDIk4rjmaBHmaA==", 
		"explanation": "25Ktbprh0BWq45chXA3+xOn6JivEDCIFq3rDFaB1ZnSjW6GCeuX7iYd+M0iMnxw5+6MEZr9r9N3uWr60/Z6qMA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Chirand", 
		"option_b": "Gufkral", 
		"option_c": "Koldihwa", 
		"option_d": "Burzahom", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130146", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0Whuy0fjtOCuXDmsSsXCPW7d8YzajRqLEa/++3ZgxLlLJmVN+snXJrbH170dPgK4b/YaaMAkCbYNiwcKAl8ryy31IJ85NmcBx8ZYLaeZFk3/8zUqaadqUadNpqLhej4ZH", 
		"answer": "24a1aZ3/kQr++IslEgr9yvHsdzF+7yqRV5bqTFVmL2iYuZk=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71FnB9pYoXxfgzL3RMGTcCnYZqnzDUbZ4ZGTxUefBYePqzI9laxyEhFhp/XrPt63jt0EKia1JqZqQMDEOf4djiMOd2OryhGVOPMpX2OvoqAoF4HOapZr06UP66h8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Small pottery pieces", 
		"option_b": "Small stone tools", 
		"option_c": "Small burial pits", 
		"option_d": "Small animal bones", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130147", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcAvg3/z3OmaQCnFRt3eGEq57Y2WjXarSYf/qyJllZ3KMgldy5n7PoOXj/kcKz6FVqZqXdWIof5hnxdmbl/L2yH1EKoZ4lLx81p8eb/tOln2PYcbBIfZhwy6NIkT+dHn6EHhx1CHai39T6Iy9tSWyRtk/h1dVVes66EkiIWdqGQZz6q3s", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iaV0Jk+Ggxty4TbSq6Cw9Fwdna1Y/c6aaDIPf4Vu3NmG2aT4wjFgINVBiJR765Rd67AKDYMtkmgq8yvXs2RcWQ==", 
		"explanation": "25eteovy2Rbnt4wzEh+yyPz1OnmQLWcer3aXWqp3MGLqQKKCZ+O+3Z90Z3eInlN2+2SGtaT8+1YWz6lV7c6WZDFDcIpizZCdxeX5131AJ8NX2pR9pN0LdPEA3DGsd9GbL/guzGeSJE23JS0ALAAcrgeo5O79kwj5nYw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130148", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TV6xkfHSjW6GCReztwZp4NRycnl5/smLJrKnjt14Oi60b5ojfYzYMcI4vyd6Nl+b4ynQBD8h4lLJ35YkQcq4A4TSuZtvXKepm3S6XIlf1Jzj9CXF+myOWmn1EvMO082evXN936xQhnopx/8F8EtKQ1aGH4ES7xhKN03eaQakm1KQ3sJBkPfaK9MLvW2LW8Q==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIjpn6QXa00eWKjUqbOfei8wNn6sM+nVT9RRDUmOaNTiA==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUOVxH+zOn3PGiQE2ces3OGEqd9dDH2R6KCffnxx5IxJlKNzVl0/HOGt6r/+0BDz7xT7M6LdToXPph7ycSMxKTjzHRTNoZTm5My5docc/lQwDi5cZTaIu1rwG2FZ0r2JzS0B2J7mDjCgm8UGT0hLCsuzI35LT5+WVsAjw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130149", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcRb71/zxMSvZECICqniNW6V9c3DtQOfEYf++wINiZ16Gg147+3vWr6D98l0bnOhW6IqaMC0FPoph3NyMxfe3+H99PfRBm5N96sBfSPxFjC+oc93ULr5v3GGVKUGwRDG0FnF6kHHTkmxTuoq++yS+R5o2gAczn4l+7MQwfNiZmamR51isxlfSjDuSRf9+cDUhD17kk/15ixYZN+2h", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Avvt5EyRxu+hf/qISviBmMCrHHDW7A0fn73FLPKa639xoVjIl+dzV5j4nrHraTk/lwBz6ddqa+MYycRaoJgxpKFlYSlCJSKT3wLt0+woGlS", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gVB/x0e6/NHnVQ2MSoGqRU7dxPDH3XKKCfOz3x5FwK1DJiVR+4XiBt+X0/kEKjLxX8M6aaDIPf4JhiMSB0qTn1nRSNshHn8B94todc/pFjDSgZNjeLftg2n3CpjX0NA1n2ISvX5yC7rst8Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130150", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1vTrMCvHC2sSqz+OV6J6YzGbQK/HLv3yyJR0Z1OPzVly4HXO2uX55BMwsJdkq3jhE2y6nh0XJn7A1i9/nLk=", 
		"answer": "27eteovy2RbntVul9eLb8Y9HoYp5cFSfy9I=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2A3vt4shXxv2hbrrPW6QE24QoHrDXaU0cnjxV6+FLuTtibVkNUaIhVR2sJXoRVIfbal8fhbSxOlmbcQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "bu,rz,ah,om", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130151", 
		"question": "25y2KLPmwwPr/4otHl7mzfi/JW7fE24U42+RU6BgeXLmUOfDLtLB9qhOZ12HiRt9+2XOqqv3t1YMgKZU5JfdanzYBK2NkFw44+2WlYyJPA==", 
		"answer": "272tZoX63x6oXM+FFKGK47vJfa7GgVyJqQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1fjwJWfVQ20X412WQLl1eH7uFK/Daq3/iZ9kKUiAg1w783jC46P55FsGga8b7I2Qfi0OZ8n+jNcdfcBUqQoYrJiqxCjL", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "hun,ti,ng", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130152", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg2A3vt4kvUR/mwPm/YTqQCG9RsHCWRqtjdWL3FKjELt7swJlwIF2bzVJoskn5nJrPyGxNDc3+kSmJr7eG5oghg+f2Ag==", 
		"answer": "25Ktbprh0BWoQuCIktjWHDIk4rjmaBHmaA==", 
		"explanation": "25Ktbprh0BWq/pZgRhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+QW7dxMGLqQLLDeuj6icMgZ1eEzUh052LOtKDj4xMAieho+4eRcSUCbMkOEx4eN2Mda/EZRaIXjnME", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Gu,fk,ral", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130153", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1vTrMCvTD20Cpj+XXeNgeHSjdqjGZqDZyI5wZ0iMgEt39zbPsOXPyGwwsJcZbZtCOmU/qDtrLqeDh/CKKA==", 
		"answer": "24G5epD32BGolAfydQVKwnRO9EqgE5Pkqw==", 
		"explanation": "24G5epD32BGq/pZgRhb3he72IW6QD20SomuGVuN6dXDxFLPKa63cxpN5anuIlFo75nPLs6n1tW5m9XAfLrlDxo2WftZw6XU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Tar,ad,ih", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130154", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy5+jtL2rYDG9RtmyGVuNLT07ca5iCfuLq3ZJjPh4zRLNswnXcKhvZWr8tg4lR", 
		"answer": "27a3aYPg1Fnt5YA5EO8R6X2UBXk9jJWq8jPaWg4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63xHr9Yw0UxDm1r3wMyvyFnALoneMX+NkYnTnW6rLYOzw3ZtoZ0maiF878XnHsbb1t1QdirEb+YGLZCcRZ8ma1ZajsroSFAJMiYi9kLc4", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "coarse red", 
		"option_b": "fine blue", 
		"option_c": "painted", 
		"option_d": "coarse grey", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130155", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUzWwr3her2IWOQCnYC43uGQaBmeWH3XajMNK/hMFeH7ZXUUTWISfnFy7hg", 
		"answer": "25eteovy2Rbnt8hgcBH8wL32OHvcBm8UrWuQHuNXeHjxVanGLqC+6pZnIhyGixtv+nOGs6rk41Ydw+h8/IiUYiMPPsYviOCF1ufyhH5Hc8RNiJR6qNorfeZByDSlNJmbDvtv3C6iKEH4Kh68HXE0gDTbmnBT6t3ibb6+DuTMiKklnHnBGGk=", 
		"explanation": "25eteovy2Rbnt8hgcBH8wL32OHvcBm8UrWuQbq1XeHjxVanGLqC+6pZnIhyGixtv+nOGs6rk41Yds6Z8/IiUYiMPPsYviOCF1ufyhH5Hc8RNiJR62JQrfeZByDSlNJmbDvtv3C6iKEH4Kh68HXE0gDTbmnBT6vAoOOVxBb6KmZAwKgCy5Ek=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Burzahom,Bone implements", 
		"option_b": "Chirand,Cave of the potter", 
		"option_c": "Gufkral,Place of birth", 
		"option_d": "Taradih,Near Bodh-Gaya temple", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130156", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUOVxH+zOn3PGiQE3AQoGuKUaY0Z3j3XOfLev6+2p5lIgbLK9xPX3GxdcjRt+jB+8qSSQ==", 
		"answer": "25a3aYPg1Fnt5YA5Eg790en6J3KdIXcDuX6LXa44UXbxXaTXYvnr25IxJlKNzVp1+3vHr+X44kANjqZf+5fSWy0PeoJn39HJ1urzhFxAO8dDiIE+1pMcebRD2TG5fcLaNPdhwCOnMkP7dTixSFhhmiXfhHsWqY2/tSGyR9I+zhJyk4R348cxJZq9zLqJ6UW3i0Q4hruAF7PkIAxpkF8+GubX", 
		"explanation": "25C5a5mzwQvr9JEpURuyzO6/OGrEAGoUpz+UW7d8MGXrUefRZ/n7iYB5Ik6MzVJvsmHHsOXg5VYLgKVS54+RZB4NXYRu2sOMl+PlwWgBI8lQjoVg/dpSPNZV3iesfNvWHPBPyXyJJFD8cyyvATB1mjWWi3JfpYK3tS+uR9g2zhEgj8c1reMzMNOW0b+SqEy2gkav3XOQT69lLVqrvM2tq0CJrJYxo8yZuD3VtLm5ve3V+8wKbjRcl5Nxd1KykOgI9i54V8GnYBtF9qTVYlvjLyW6Z0M/7Nn513xmy8BDaqQXKpOpuYubid5khU7H", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Coarse grey pottery,Burzahom", 
		"option_b": "Agriculture and animal husbandry,Koldihwa and Mahagra", 
		"option_c": "Rice cultivation,Gufkral", 
		"option_d": "Hunting and fishing economy,Burzahom", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130157", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kR3j88U0Whuy6/jwOWLEC2sS42+GXbN4dTHqWufRYfjqwddYKViAjBt893jDsaT8+0pPnK1P/YKaL2CprBkmn2qAxl2LQdTFiSZK", 
		"answer": "24G3eIKz3h+q8JchXBfmwL33PGfcECIesT+TXqJgdXD2R+fMa+zsiYV4MVmbzVl6/H3V4fdaIhFYz7AA6ZYKtw/OdTg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1fjwJWfVQ2sf42yMR7d8MFjtUK7DLu72xoR0Z1SAilM783jC46v19kENluhJ4JiaYmIPcYhu3NmG2fe3wn5Tc9VBjpR+4ZcacuACiBk9JPkvk2QOzQniZoRmmg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "In valleys", 
		"option_b": "Along coastlines", 
		"option_c": "Tops of granite hills or plateaus near river banks", 
		"option_d": "In dense forests", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130158", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwgzt8IAzRg2y0fX+ISvEC2dRjXqMXqpgeHjgFLfHYf3yzNd6IkydzVh65mLKpumw5FsKirgXqY+RdGIEcYp724/LwswptktwDz5t/G+SW+E4lQ==", 
		"answer": "25OxepTx0BLv88UlUwzmzfjxdW3ZBHcDqnGGQeHlzJrltfvIjKQVY67gp80i", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w73rPW7DBiIXqniWQKp6dWKjXanGZ+7/3ZJiZ0iBiEI7+nfC46bx40cDiuQb+oaadTJPPophzJCO2OXj1zOUDRtYmezhZOqGs6vtOlJq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Stone tools", 
		"option_b": "Firebaked earthen figurines", 
		"option_c": "Stone querns", 
		"option_d": "Cave paintings", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130159", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoVwey0O76dXjEDGwU426WV7F6YzHlW7WdLMzxP2hIFaHMWYfMuPWFAvg=", 
		"answer": "25KqYZ/32Bftt4YvQBCweu6Jj8QOZIsNEFzpGBBWkg==", 
		"explanation": "24asZ5/2kQj/8pcuQV7lwO/6dX/fDG4C43mMQONzYnjtUK7Maa3525Z4KU/JgVJw9zbFrLf+tZB8J+ECHcHdGiCB1mbgn0s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cooking food", 
		"option_b": "Building houses", 
		"option_c": "Hunting", 
		"option_d": "Grinding corn", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130160", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElEhr9wO6/O2TEQ2oQtXrDU+N5cXvsRufsa+LywIN5Ll/Jnl5v5nrDrqD+4xMCiqZP4IGRdSZDd4Uv3NiMl/T212JANMMb2KIUylbqV+bZzzxqbHgQBRs=", 
		"answer": "2569epD/0FtaF6BCNflIrVeOApRBBP9f", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8pZgXxv80fTwO27UQ2MDpj+iYu80W3DxWqbWb+b/hddwKVjJuVp2+3qGjaT04hFVrKaIMQ4JNupVH8J1ZjpW", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Karnataka", 
		"option_b": "AP", 
		"option_c": "Kerala", 
		"option_d": "Tamil Nadu", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130161", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt6slXRL70fX2NivDBnYFr3qOV61gYzHiRqKCY+jw3Z5+KVmNzVJ1smXJtrH4t3oBi6FatsxgsUfcNDP4ZtB2MvUF+jbE", 
		"answer": "25qubYOziUy6tUOoxSHE3eOyzo4l/9dWJSs=", 
		"explanation": "24a3fYX7kTDk84whEhbz1r3wI27CQzpE8z+tV6x4eWXrXaSCfejq3Zt0KlmHmUg5rNrYTtJdd+RX22ljUWHjOw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 750, 
		"option_b": "Over 850", 
		"option_c": 1000, 
		"option_d": 500, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130162", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yzPO/FFuPQUcqOyng7N2X0/R7mWMOppE=", 
		"answer": "24CsZoThkxXZzgkZUIwtkova3F2Nrcc=", 
		"explanation": "24CsZoThkRD5t5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRsHaXV+N4f3LiQKLGLuTwibZBZQVEjUyl28juQpJk64yPRsU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Brahmagiri", 
		"option_b": "Maski", 
		"option_c": "Utnur", 
		"option_d": "Piklihal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130163", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Bfj+oQsQV72zPm/IWPVQ0wUrHOKRqt9czHwUbPWYujs2td4KRy5hFB3+37Hr+X0+F4KnLxS6o+LdX1B+gdRpECcVzzZ0W39ZhBbeA==", 
		"answer": "25a5fIX/1FWq5I0lVw6+hfrwNH/DQTQ6spsAxiWL7PCmxuSWC5k=", 
		"explanation": "24WxY5362Rjmt5YlRgr+wO/sdW/fDmcCt3aAU7dxdDHgVbPWYuiyiYR5IlmZwRt6/HKGpKrx40BNzQ7aGpoDCaHbAYz4751Lsg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cattle and horses", 
		"option_b": "Cattle, sheep, goats", 
		"option_c": "Fish and birds", 
		"option_d": "Wolves and deer", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130164", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17hwOnrOW7CECIYrT+zW6h4eXniWOfGYa3pwZJ/Z1WdzUx64TbSqqj1t0cAz6VU/4vAMl0p6Akysi583qbW9rj7ePQ=", 
		"answer": "24a9fNHn2Ryq9IQtQhf8wr34J2TFDWZRonmKQKY2hTw764kimTXY1T6/m9fEKQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz0hXv9pclVl7mzfi/NmrdE2sfpD+CQKZ1MHP6FLTHevn3x5AxLkjJglU79H/UpuXy8lUAna0b5IGJeSwEPGjIWiQBw/o/ioxkSdqirGs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Built permanent houses", 
		"option_b": "Abandoned their animals", 
		"option_c": "Set the camping ground afire", 
		"option_d": "Stored food for the journey", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130165", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Rj88sUiVxv8hfvwIGXUQ2sf40+KWa99eHDvC+VdZdapSqrrIWuohlJ28VwY", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Arit4gvRxD21r3+O2+QC2MTqmuCRqp7fjHwXbPHfa84nFUUWrCMq0p0IgtYCol3", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxQD68pZgXRiyxO/8PWrVDG4epHaAU680dWfqUKLMbei+wZZnIhyLiF51snDJtqv0t1oBz5hS4oKWeCMPPMD9fKBl4EPFErmA0CwBMT4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only ash mounds", 
		"option_b": "Only habitation sites", 
		"option_c": "Both ash mounds and habitation sites", 
		"option_d": "Neither", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130166", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5Y0Uwr3hfTsdVvRCnsQrm+CXq99MH3sV6bWa+mhi3VPoRurv50VvkBJZt5OI30=", 
		"answer": "24G5ZZj/kTfr85BiqVhZMrkprDr+ozKpn+gfuA==", 
		"explanation": "24W5YYjy3Anr+4kpEhfhhfy/G27fD2sFq3aAErB9ZHSjXamCWuzzwJsxCV2NmBmASBlLiyNKn/D9PR40sB/U", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Karnataka", 
		"option_b": "Tamil Nadu", 
		"option_c": "AP", 
		"option_d": "Kerala", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130167", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1fX+Jm6QCmxRsHCWRqs0WX/nXaaCbeLozIV0IxyehVJ4+jbWprf5+FdQzR+/9wqluOHufFdX4Z9mn/c=", 
		"answer": "2+fsOMGzxRaq9ocvRwqylK2vZSvyICD8KLV7PxO+O2yG7RUuIHEb", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn2BTvt4MyUxP3hfvwJyvEC2dRjXqMXqpgeHjgFLfKb/77iZ5/Z0+GmE9zsl/Ip6zxt1ocz/oPud7fZC1Df4lg3cTJhrSnlDFjEIRAJa4Y6isHTR31YkFKsEFp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "3000 to 1500 BC", 
		"option_b": "2000 to 800 BC", 
		"option_c": "2400 to about 1000 BC", 
		"option_d": "3200 to 1800 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130168", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk1Avvt5EoV17xxPDvJivZDSIhqnSPW6t1fDHwQbXQYfjwzZJ1eB7N5miR963X0m+g6YTu/Hp8", 
		"answer": "25ehKJL8xgnv+ZZgXx/2wL3oPH/YQ3IesGuQEqJ6dDHwQKbJa/68wyc0G2I68/JtVbJRN/ZStw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw0BT65MU3Vwz3he7qJ3nfFmwVpnvDULo0c370RKLMfa39xpliM06cjk9+9jbTsKz+8BMfgLtP+s6efiZDbZ9uw9WalbzxHnAAeDQ9OQUJxWBf6ck=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "By stone walls", 
		"option_b": "By trenches", 
		"option_c": "By wooden fences", 
		"option_d": "By cowpens made with posts and stakes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130169", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElEhbz1r3SNHjbCiIQsD+CEo1xf33qQK/Lba3twIN0eB7ihb0lm1LmXUDfVVMvYzA/", 
		"answer": "2565ep/yxRjh9sdUluJhABTJVFtdtvqA4Sxm", 
		"explanation": "25i5e5r6kRD5t4ouV179w73rPW6QLWcer3aXWqp3MGLqQKLRLuTwibxwNVKImVpw8zRY12Gjj/P57TVKm3B2ciZq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Tamil Nadu", 
		"option_b": "AP", 
		"option_c": "Kerala", 
		"option_d": "Karnataka", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130170", 
		"question": "24KwcdH33hz5t7YvRwr6hdTxMWLRQ2oQtXrDRqtxMH3iRqDHffm+x4J8JVmbzVR9sljDrKn541sGjOhI7JqLfCcOe4V724/LrIanJUKMv5NsKqWvqRy4pw==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aYfy2BXr9YwsWwrrhfL5dXjEDGwU4d/e/HXLjCoentQdr3SvqMQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy0wzk84QuURuyyvu/Jn/fDWdRqnHDRqtxMGPmU67NYK3t3IdhKE6diF875n7D46Dj41INg6FI4YOafjZDcY0vxsWE0vb40WIBIMNQjox36Z8RaOcCXgk/yCFumbmNYwdNguZA4g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Fertile soil", 
		"option_b": "Mild climate", 
		"option_c": "1 availability of stone", 
		"option_d": "Presence of large rivers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130171", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTfv+IkpRhb7xr3sPH/VQ2sC43GMRuN4f3LiQKLGLuTwibxwNVKImVpw8ymEuEuGzVc1WwB0m5nJhOyakg==", 
		"answer": "24W5YYjy3Anr+4kpEK3Bac9UZv5B6VF9cmr7y9M=", 
		"explanation": "24W5YYjy3Anr+4kpEhfhhfHwNmrEBmZRqnHDZqJ5eX2jeqbGe69a8mn8RZTo43Jk4bpz+K/F", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Brahmagiri", 
		"option_b": "Maski", 
		"option_c": "Piklihal", 
		"option_d": "Paiyampalli", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130172", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TV6xkfHSjXamCfeLr3Z8xDlKNhFo74XPSt6n18xMBiqlJqZyWZicRbctTxuyH5eH2135PaYZwkoVrpI8MefAA3ymietGbMetr3GCTZ0P/dXm6Fnl6kDjYjTxVp5G1t9TUcFs9wXee5mKnbcTIS1s=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Avvt5EyRxu+hf/qISviBmMCrHHDW7A0fn73FLPKa639xoVjIl+dzV5j4nrHraTk/lwBz6ddqa+MYycRaoJgxpKFlYSlCJSKT3wLt0+woGlS", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gVB/x0e6/NHnVQ2MSoGqRU7dxPDH3XKKCe/77iZh3Z0+dglV+smfTprf+5BMLgK1I58mLMCYKbI5s3NyQl+Hv1H1AOsgEjoh3pIgWavFSzjyjf5TIJep6wmuNIkvkdHsbSUSgPHtjkN3wkMu5LH8W", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130173", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYRHn0fW/HGXUCmNRq36QEqI0fHDxU6KCYPjzy5JjZ1OPzXV+/XrPt6359BMcirxP5YuSdSwXbctr3dXJw+u3zWVSc8VIk41z8J9fQPp8wg+odcfULqQu/WGVM02wTje5DXE0nDDFymhercO39DW8UckjgBsnm4V9/4gzOpex3Kef4VmwjwXCz36FXLFhHFGXod3o71aZ4JY39dmFtHKKtPXvm/Hf8dwCbgFGpsZwZRuvg6cH/WivohF70TnMra9sfmAzeBvA", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIjpn6QXa00eWKjUqbOfei8wNn6sM+nVT9RRDUmOaNTiA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH72B7it4s1Xxz3173wMyvDBnYFr3qOV61gYzHqR+fAa+7/3IR0Z1OPzU9z9zbHtaT5+1INhqRS/ZfffyRDbZ9gxtXFl+r40DFVO8MEmYx76ZsLebbxAdsx8ZpMSdn3Q4AcMObu", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130174", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TWqJndTHqWufRYfjqwddYKViAjBt382XSpqGw8UEAgugIud7PMDYMPto6mIDJ9ce3+H99PfRBm5N96sBfSPxFjBOoe9jSNPZnzS6QL0TjYnm0CjBnmyTCgjx/poey9Ge4W8wy0hA21pNw6IgsOcWW1qzT7l+3i0aD3nSEXP02RQTJ9dqnq0Ker5cs9Zzd4WKb1te7c3RqcCKkkMaC9qZnNFhOIw==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIjpn6QXa00eWKjUqbOfei8wNn6sM+nVT9RRDUmOaNTiA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3gv48oY0Egr7yPi/M3nRDmdRpXCRErd8dTHNUajOZ/n2wJQxN1SInl47+3iGsKrl41tPpqZf4I/feTFDeJlgxZDbg7SnhGVOc5cUytAyxrld9duE1BXtAcm1+wGagNg1kA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130175", 
		"question": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUwVxHiyfi/PGWQEG0Et3fDe61weXCjQbTXb+Hy0NdiIkidgV5/snnI47H48hMbgLhIqYGZMB08QbRQ9+/LFAmj/thx1NJYihn83+fIRg==", 
		"answer": "27KqaZ/6xRzi/oksQVzXMLhpuCYppETbK/KR2+Ew", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH61Rzr+8UsXR3z0fTwO3iQBW0D41GGXa99ZHnqV+fRa/nqxZJ8IlKdnhts92TD46Li9l0Gm60b4YeTfDFDcZkv2NyIw+H20WIBPcNFiMBg7YwabvZBwja+NlniF2+Ml5daViFS4TQHVzg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "gr,an,it,eh,il,ls", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130176", 
		"question": "25OxepTx0BLv88UlUwzmzfjxdW3ZBHcDqnGGQeNnZXbkUbTWLvn2zNdhNVmaiFV49zbJpeXPyGwwsJdkpc6ddTEKeo58iMOB0uHnhHBPN4ZDlYFm99iyb35Vwi4fV7zFjz6tkZ01", 
		"answer": "27a5fIX/1FuTQRXBT0q9HFzn2u0+kcnv", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12B7/5YwuVw2yzPP7PGjRF2dRt3eCRuNadX7vXbPKZ+6+2ZJ+N1CMzVB+4mKGtaTi/lwanOhX4JiaYzYMfYAvwd6K2/HzzX9Gc8VFjpR+4dhgtlygMlOpX+BuqA4EuEX8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "dogs", 
		"option_b": "cattle", 
		"option_c": "chickens", 
		"option_d": "horses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130177", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1vTrMCvvPF0unEC8EqpnMH3sV6bWa+m+wJkxBmzLMed4axlnznqMWmflkHcuXw==", 
		"answer": "24CsZoThkxXZzgkZUIwtkova3F2Nrcc=", 
		"explanation": "24CsZoThkRD5t5EoV17/wPPrPGTeBmZRjXqMXqpgeHjgFLTLeui+xZhyJkiMiRty/Dbnk+ewP4Yj1GS317jitzpl/iX/", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "utn,ur", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130178", 
		"question": "24qHV67M7iaq/pZgU17cwPLzPH/YCmFRsHaXV+N9fjHXVarLYq3QyJNkZcXD22En8SxxECD/r6RonK4=", 
		"answer": "24W5YYjy3Anr+4kpEK3Bac9UZv5B6VF9cmr7y9M=", 
		"explanation": "24W5YYjy3Anr+4kpEhfhhen3MCvDE2cSqnmKV6c0XnTsWK7WZuT9iYR4M1nJhFU7xnfLqqmw2VILmurQrxowVPak2WqqOAMB+lKp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Maski", 
		"option_b": "Brahmagiri", 
		"option_c": "Utnur", 
		"option_d": "Paiyampalli", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130179", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1fX+Jm6QCmxRsHCWRqs0WX/nXaaCbeLozIV0IxydhV474nPUqqr0t1UdgKUb6IyQZTZDQbRQ9++26KTjyzFAMclRjsAjtMpPPNZjju2CM+IpAEXnrtn7JidgCW4=", 
		"answer": "y+HoOJB+vvZ5f25/P/i61Skr9hk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+1Bf+/oouVxqy0fTyMGfZDWdRsGuCQLdnMHfxW6qCPLmumddTBB4uwZakscQgidcsftlGxR7w", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >>  Earliest Rural Settlements in Baluchistan to  Neolithic Settlements in South India", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 2200, 
		"option_b": 2400, 
		"option_c": 2600, 
		"option_d": 2000, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRsHqXRq9xYmKjQbTHLvnxiZVjIl2CzU9z9zbBsarl+VdQzUkkbA5HzNQ92ePwTEkYkXE=", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kRHl8pZgUxD2hfn2MmzZDWVRsGuKUahnMv4FDPXEcZj/QCMKibQiSaM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1A3++4AyQV7n1vj7dX/YBnEU42uMXa9nMHfsRufWZuj329d3Jk6EhFV8snfFt6zm/kcGirsZv2APD0pLl0KlZCWlSbCQMw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Metal spades", 
		"option_b": "Wooden shovels", 
		"option_c": "Stone hoes and digging sticks", 
		"option_d": "Hand ploughs", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sUmWwb3wb3+ISvEC2dRpnGHEqxyMGXrUefGZ+r5wJl2Z0+dhFhw4SmEMO7TlJ++SA5UHm9Oo7nzpg==", 
		"answer": "24exZpazwg3l+YAzEMO2ktwxeSwAAf/Ujnoa3EQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQr++IslQV76wPHvMG+QCmxRs22MRKpweX/kFLDHZ+r23dd3KE7JiVJ89X/IpOcVJaJgC3PxxUdK7zQ+RPHR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Blades", 
		"option_b": "Ring stones", 
		"option_c": "Metals", 
		"option_d": "Feathers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140103", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk1Avvt6slXRL70fX2NivYDHcCpmzDQrF9fXDxXavbLv72yId0IwPLnlyRhxCMgMioadDGpIbMgg==", 
		"answer": "25axepLm3Rj4t4oyEgz3xun+O2zFD2MD4UVdVz9Rq7BHY9jTdr0fiuY=", 
		"explanation": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUoXQvhwO6/PWrUQ3YZpmyGErdjfzHzRq7Pb//niYR5JkyMnhkmUxszdOXpsR4I58qHvjk8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Square or triangular", 
		"option_b": "Hexagonal or pentagonal", 
		"option_c": "Circular or rectangular", 
		"option_d": "Oval or diamond", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140104", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUsWwj7y/q/PGWQAGsDoGqPU7E0eH72R6LRLv7rzpB0NEjJjFl052KGjaD/+1obh6FYqZ6afzIPe9QtGPwh2CMNV4KCqDsvDBb58Q==", 
		"answer": "25qvZpT3kQn4+JUlQArrhfTxdWjfDm8erT3d0X6AW7KvAdTiTuHQE3z0", 
		"explanation": "25ysL4Kz0xzm/oA2Vxqy0fX+ISvABm0Br3rDXqpieX/kFK7MLv7ryp8xL1Ocnl5osmXOorf18xMfnadL7JyLaWCEOJAG20SbZeX9KmRNrDMq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Were hunters", 
		"option_b": "Lived solitary lives", 
		"option_c": "Had monarchs", 
		"option_d": "Owned property in common", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrv5YAhXl7lxO6/O2TEQ3IDrHuWUaZwMHP6FLPKa63QzJh9LkiBhFg74nPJs6n1t14KgbxS5oCadGIKcMt7wNXJx+Xk13BGNpkGoTAaWm+iJjI3cQDIUgi0RA==", 
		"answer": "25i5YYv2k9QHopdo20/VUoow9aRlI54=", 
		"explanation": "24e5b5i/kRHl5ZYlEhngxPCzdWreByIDqnyGErRxYnSjWaLMeuTxx5J1Z12azVl++3jB47Xi+FcajK1fq0DVqvgySqsQF87L11yoF0w=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Ragi", 
		"option_b": "Horse gram", 
		"option_c": "Rice", 
		"option_d": "Maize", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140106", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTfv+IkpRhb7xr3zOmjRF2serT+UU7A0cXX1VanBa+m+wJkxM1SMhEk79HfUrqz+8BMbiqtT54eOZScQIcn2HQCOpcyBh/FlNGA9GfM1", 
		"answer": "25i9YIP00AvitcEjxmki05yh+VPloeNGkhk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy6Pj3J2zREWpRs22MVrZ3dXWjQ6/Hb/m+yJl1Z16In1d+6zR9JONNTVhroqtZVQKI3vk9", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chhotanagpur", 
		"option_b": "MP", 
		"option_c": "Mehrgarh", 
		"option_d": "Upper Deccan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140107", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q440lEjD3yvH2IWPZACICpmuXXqZmYzHtUaLGLv3x3YN0NUXWz+Q/wn6lR7V2Czl4CjVaHCc=", 
		"answer": "25O3etHgxRb49oIlEh/8wb38OmTbCmwW4Rn1fwqpEsb6JYw+j/1J/bM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3xzv84AkEg790e6/IWSQEHYesXrDVKx7dDHkRqbLYP6+yJl1Z1qGnxt05n7DseXg4kEfgLte+s6TeSkGPohgx9uA2eO3xX9Fc8NFjol849ikzhkfGo3BSFJ2jarmrU89", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "For decoration", 
		"option_b": "For selling", 
		"option_c": "For rituals", 
		"option_d": "For storage and cooking", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140108", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5UvRgr31+S/M2LCEHZRom+TV6JmLzP7C2rNiT2PXtI+6r4TOLy/", 
		"answer": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUwWh/hwL9ZNKNBChbjSHx2jpAyWRr1", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxbu4oY0WxH8hfL5dXvfF3YUsWbDUKZzcX+jXamCeuX7ibl0KFCAmVNy8TbWq6Tj8hFRrBQ9eYylpdY9pFloc9tq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mesolithic phase", 
		"option_b": "Paleolithic phase", 
		"option_c": "Iron Age", 
		"option_d": "Neolithic phase", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140109", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk0Aqq8oQyXgey6/jwOWLEC2sS42+MRrdxYmijWabGa7K8qTC1kyHkCycNfSyfF2vGgQ==", 
		"answer": "2525ZpX+0B3vtaPXUAOqBSBLTlhCqBQ9Tu0=", 
		"explanation": "25C5ep3qkQnl45ElQAeyzPO/IWPVQ0wUrHOKRqt9czHzXKbRa63pyIQxL12HiVZ69nOEShh8zhyCTCNVFjBaIQsSzA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Using molds", 
		"option_b": "On potter's wheels", 
		"option_c": "Handmade", 
		"option_d": "With machinery", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140110", 
		"question": "25OqZ5yzxhHv5YBgVhf2hen3MCvADHYFpm36QeNjeHTmWOfSYf7twJV9PhyKglZ+smLJ44fx+0YMh6FI/Y+RL2Auye4ZDHGu8cg249+9DmcV", 
		"answer": "24K9e4X2wxeq1pYpU1wECpPiyXiWe2BQ3W6SGM2V", 
		"explanation": "25ysKJjgkRvv+4wlRBv2hen3NH+QF2oU42+MRrdxYgjwFLDKa+jyiYRhNVmIiRtv/Tbkoqnl9FsGnLxa586ZYi0OPpxq28SMxeq35WJIMoSv8B77q5lajovZ82ieMdWB", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Eastern Asia", 
		"option_b": "Western Asia", 
		"option_c": "Africa", 
		"option_d": "Europe", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140111", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiy6/jwOWLEC2sS42+MRrdxYmijQ6bRLuPx3dd8IlKdhFR193KGqquw41sKz7ha+p2edydcPPpyylJJ2ldPW9FNsZF8tQQ=", 
		"answer": "24e9bNHk0AvvtS9tLhJbngGVgVhMlJEZH9c=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+1Bf+/oouVxqy0eTvMHiQFGcDpj+BXqJ3ezzhQbXMZ/72zJMxMF2biBc79WTDuuXn9kEKw+ha54rffSMXd4Z/2tWaxOHzhGZAIcMG1AAeMNwXMn/YL2iQlO0gbA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Black-burnished ware", 
		"option_b": "Grey ware", 
		"option_c": "Matimpressed ware", 
		"option_d": "Red ware", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IlgRR/hhfPwISvdBmwFqnCNV6c0cWKjVefsa+LywIN5Ll/JmVR0/jbPreXk/1ZPn6lI+o+YdX1B/4MUoKsr/k1c6lposhZlfg==", 
		"answer": "24aobZDhk/zHBPDLjkDnl3ZbFXniLd4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEhP3y+n2OmXVByISpnOXQe80cWnmR+uCb+nkzIQ9Z12HiRt4+n/VpqnjtQ1AEtXUkI9RskMbIISsD1g=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Celt", 
		"option_b": "Adze", 
		"option_c": "Chisel", 
		"option_d": "Spear", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF7+xP70JivDCmUfqnmKUaJ6ZDH3RqbBa/6+xpExCVmGgVJv+n/F47b140cDiqVe55qML2Bw3JNqQ+djw1VDpJDBRWOQ", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkT3v9IYhXFxnY9a5jVCLUjiOY0lb9byI", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHmwQnv5cUEVx3xxPO/IXnRAHYC436RV+N5dX/3XajMa+m+yIQxL12fhFV8snDDtOXe8lwDhrxT4I3fYycXaodqxdWHw/e1zvN0qp8aZntCERl6bB0BhA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Orissa", 
		"option_b": "Mehrgarh", 
		"option_c": "MP", 
		"option_d": "Upper Deccan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140114", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR749owuEgnz1r3vJ2TUFmEUpz+BS+NgeHSjeqLNYuTqwZ5yZ0yMgkt39zbJpeXd8lsdiKlJ4dHdpnHq0UsYIqnuJtFGHzIJXQ==", 
		"answer": "24KwbZDnkRjk88UiUwz+wOS9HSPUlzIi/GKG2q8zClbuAw==", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit5UlXQ7+wL3vJ2TUFmEUpz+XWqZndTH3Q6iCbejszJZ9NB4sLRb+YW1ZsS5a4OXEIn5+", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Ragi and rice", 
		"option_b": "Maize and barley", 
		"option_c": "Wheat and barley", 
		"option_d": "Horse gram and rice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoVw33henwOmfDQ3UQsD+WQaZwMHP6FInHYeH33Z94JByaiE9v/nPUsOX2+EFPi61P6IeTdSZDaYR9w4/LIup6yGvLfdrGxq7Yk+Rg+w==", 
		"answer": "25ixa4P83RD+/8UiXh/2wO693wc2Io/knkktDSLJgzhjEQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxArv88U0WhvhwL39OWrUBnFRpXCREqV9fnTxFLPDfebti8e7uVLZWPmuvB3ovuFTsT8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Large stone hammers", 
		"option_b": "Wooden sticks", 
		"option_c": "Metal knives", 
		"option_d": "Microlith blades", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140116", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TV6xkfHSjWqLHauj6iYd+M0iMn0I78HPForDj8hMbh61CqZ2LcTAXe48vydeb3ufiyGVUIcMEpo5O6qgafedPwmftRNvPNPt81y6XJlawdTysEXlmkTWWjHNE6Jez8GeoQNUlwRI31oh+rc4zM9Pf3rqS4UOrxgeM2DuSR7JvGFqe95TtlMQaCrp/qsScOEhYTG8=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Avvt5EyRxu+hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDW7A0ZHnmFKTNfP/7yoMxIkSZgVp182LPrKuw+FVPrrtI7JyLeS0NPO39SieICF6J1lk94kQfp34=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy1Q/v+ZFgXRiyxPrtPGjFD3YEsXrDX6Z1fmWjVamCZ+P925JwNFmNzVV+93KGparit0AbgLpa7ovfcSwHPohgx9uA2eO30nRSIMNIicIKOpm85EN0tWhEWGbF7HKt", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140117", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TV6xkfHSjW6GCQ+j225BwNVTJml5p9zbHp7Px+VAKi+hZ7I2eZTEGPp9nzcnJ2+3hwXUBOsgEl4Vm5ZZfdPtV3zi+NOjVHPBcy2+TKEuqJw21AWk0mDjAj3gWoY37+DK/GdglyRY51o93+Ns5L5ee16zT+F+3ghOB2X/RX7VhEEDZtMCsq0Gdso49rI9/NRRKa7U88edAO0IrrfaS", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIjpn6QXa00eWKjUqbOfei8wNn6sM+nVT9RRDUmOaNTiA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/PGXTDHADpnyXCeNgeHSjeqLNYuTqwZ5yZ0yMgkt39zbJpeXd8lsdiKlJ4c6TeTQGestmxpCEwuC6xmNIMM0Eko9n958MPqFK5FklrwOl8bZvK5EJFkk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140118", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdx/gyeS/G27fD2sFq3aAErN7ZGXmRr6CeeztiZpwI1nJmEhy/HGGrqTz/1oBirsb1YCjfhAGf5hgxorJ8uXlyGgBI8lQjoVg/doWcrRUxDjtWtHULPd6xmeDZ1X4Ziq4RGd1h3Hei3JSpYK/8GUc2AA8AnbLqQn1TstmC3+c", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIjpn6QXa00eWKjUqbOfei8wNn6sM+nVT9RRDUmOaNTiA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3gv48oY0Ehjzxum/PHiQF2oQtz+GU7F4aTHNUajOZ/n2wJQxN1OdmV5p6zbRoraw/1IBi6Va7YvfcSwHPoVg3JCE1uf/zX9EfstFnoUw3xjLh4ptljsX958FxuLV4Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140119", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1vjrIWfVEXFRtmyGVuNLT07ca5j9LvnxiZVjIl2CzU9z9zbBsarl+VdPiadJqYieYi8KcIwtfbwIrEI2i9z0qKApXEMiBQ==", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kRHl8pZgUxD2hfn2MmzZDWVRsGuKUahnMv4FDPXEcZj/QCMKibQiSaM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxArv88U0WhvhwL3vJ2LdCnYYtXrDRqx7fGKjUqjQLuv/25p4KVvLPzD2q7hldDH0ceKmzhL5JQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Metal spades", 
		"option_b": "Stone hoes and digging sticks", 
		"option_c": "Wooden shovels", 
		"option_d": "Feathers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140120", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy+sLAClTvPCIGpm2GEqJwZnDtV6LGLuzwzddhNVONmFh+9jbRq6Dx4xMOgawb64+NfCcaPAB+cmdxE2LSrdmrn0OIQQs=", 
		"answer": "25i9YIP00AvitcEjxmki05yh+VPloeNGkhk=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit5IhQV75y/LoOyvWDHBRqmuQEqJwZnDtV6LGLuv/25p4KVvJmV54+njPsrD15BGvXAV12KE2Wa6yadO6JLbI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "me,hr,ga,rh", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140121", 
		"question": "25C5ep3qkTfv+IkpRhb7xr3vOn/EBnAI42iCQeNkYnjuVbXLYvS+9qhOGGO2shm4ENhPXcda4yE+vpoJy/ee", 
		"answer": "2525ZpX+0B3vtaPXUAOqBSBLTlhCqBQ9Tu0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63xD+/oQsEg790en6J3KQFGMC43yRU6VgdXWjVr6CZuzwzddzIlqGn1475n7D46z+4VYBm6FU586QdmIXdo4v39iM0ui1v0PbbDfseW6iSIQ7PObBFg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Ha,nd,ma,de", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140122", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2y1fjwJWfVQ20X41KGWrFzcWPrFKvLeOj6iZ5/Z2O2smREzUmGq6rl5FYczSH/0oPDsgW8kD3EruayMU0=", 
		"answer": "27itbNzxwxDp/McoGWZdv/drvr5edZwUHgtV", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz0wzj+5FgRhb3zO+/PWTdBnFRtmyKXKQ0fWTnFKXQZ+712tVjlO4+ahsb02pwbUXSxbo6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "mu,d-b,ri,ck", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140123", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj3g3+8pdZQV7lzfj6OSvADHECqn2PS+NnYGPmVaOCeuK+65Z9Ml+BhEhv83iGpbf/+hMwsJdk1rGgMocOGvOFpwavEa/bFxOeQRo=", 
		"answer": "24K9e4X2wxeq1pYpU1wECpPiyXiWe2BQ3W6SGM2V", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzwxzt/oouEhfhhf/6OWLVFWcV42uMEqt1ZnSjXanWfOL63JR0IxydhV474nnSt6DijkBPmKBe7ILfZC1DXIpj3dOB3vfjxX8DtdpPWt/6y2Z8/lUW/7GLSw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Eastern Asia", 
		"option_b": "Europe", 
		"option_c": "Africa", 
		"option_d": "Western Asia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140124", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUjQBHi1r3oPH/YQ3YZpj+tV6x4eWXrXaSCYuL9yIN4KFLTzQo7xX7DorGw9l0Lz6pa+4KaaW5DLMtdydeAl+X5wDFJPNRXn8B19psSPgI+sbCKJ6PQkdY3lmNqiNk=", 
		"answer": "2+T4RZT7wx7r5Y1sEkyy4vjxMHnRDyI/pnCPW7d8eXKjR6LWeuH7xJJ/M0/LwH6eDWcAhTxGbBtpgHxP4g==", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Avit5IhQV75y/LoOyvWDHBRtHeGU7c0cX/nFKXDfOH70NsxMFSAgV479XPIprfx+xMhiqdX4JqXeSFDbY573NyM2uH50GIBI9RLnpVx4Z5fbvVHxX2setCbKPF83WvAIFfxanvQk96CkG2xu/oJqRDoYAdf", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 Mehrgarh, 2 Chhotanagpur", 
		"option_b": "1 Upper Deccan, 2 General Neolithic settlements", 
		"option_c": "1 Mehrgarh, 2 General Neolithic settlements", 
		"option_d": "1 Orissa, 2 Chhotanagpur", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140125", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwXQrmwO/mdWbRCGsfpD+XV6B8fnjyQaLRLvr33Z8xM1SMhEk75n/Lpqn5+VZVz/kbwY+RdC8Ceo4v2N+dw+Hl3T0BYYZ0lZRm4YhYb7RXxDioeJZUzQlpCRY29ziIH3i4n4R7", 
		"answer": "2+T4TZDh3QCq2YAvXhfmzfT8eSuCQ04Qt3qREo1xf33qQK/Lba/7uaJJG9tVqUUYRRhMhfLP", 
		"explanation": "25y2YYX60BXm7slgQhHm0fjtLCvHAnFRq36NVq51dHSvFKbMaq3yyIN0NRydhV474nnSt6DijkBPmKBe7ILfZyMQPoJh3MKG0/H0wXUDTG80MyPb9GHYqBgmMkF3qw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 Early Neolithic, 2 Later Neolithic", 
		"option_b": "1 Later Neolithic, 2 Early Neolithic", 
		"option_c": "1 Mesolithic, 2 Later Neolithic", 
		"option_d": "1 Paleolithic, 2 Early Neolithic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140126", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRoniGEqFxd3jtFK7MLvn2zNdYKViAjFU74WPEoKr+41oBiqZPtsyIkFmFl01nnhf4LWXtdOpb", 
		"answer": "24a9fpT9xRGq+owsXhv8y/TqOCvyICC7egGqAHP27/N16SubCVte", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2yxPr6dWLeQ0sfp3aCErBgcWP3UaOCb//x3Jl1Z0iBhEg75n/LpuflaBTrfSDrjdMae7zJ+97f", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Fifth millennium BC", 
		"option_b": "Sixth millennium BC", 
		"option_c": "Seventh millennium BC", 
		"option_d": "Eighth millennium BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140127", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IkzEhr71un2O2zFCnEZpnvDRqtxMF/mW6vLeuX3ytdhIlOZgV4ksIWQ5K10lzrCp1B8jq0mbzc=", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kRrv+5EzEJbJMwzg3ejmh5TBVJzP5pc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxhz48sUlVhn3wb3+O2+QE20YrWuGVuNgf37vR+fXfej6iZF+NRydhFd3+3jB4TAjB1S0YMmmQwmDUAqigKI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone knives", 
		"option_b": "Stone hammers", 
		"option_c": "Stone spears", 
		"option_d": "Stone celts", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17h0fLxMCvTBm4FsD+TQKp5cWPqWL6Cfejs35IxJk/Wz66tRGKQF7vBkYU9L0vOyYA=", 
		"answer": "24GxZJ363x6q44ovXg2w3zC2KdKngcAS4KCD1qTyUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQ3l+IkzEgn31/i/OG7RDXZRpXCREqd9d3bqWqCCeuX7iZBjKEmHiRt6/HKGsKrn/l0Iz7te7IqMMivOJGErouJDbKSrjQpU7Ug=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Hunting weapons", 
		"option_b": "Decorative items", 
		"option_c": "Ritualistic symbols", 
		"option_d": "Tilling tools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140129", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRp3aHEq17ZDHzRqjUZ+n7iZF+KFjJi1RpsmLOpuXe8lwDhrxT4I3fYCcMbodql5LL93MCqPJ7VMgJhPzPDbkE", 
		"answer": "252tZoX63x6oyuY642CebOxOjT38wdswOg==", 
		"explanation": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUwVxHiyfi/OGTGBmZRomiCS+NyYn7uFK/XYPn3x5A9Z06MgUJy/HGGrqri8hMAgehY/IKLeTQCaoJgxpCI2eC3x3BVJ8pB2ohn95gecvBS1X8bn22HKWpW3pE3XHmkgaAn", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Cultivation", 
		"option_b": "Cattle husbandry", 
		"option_c": "Fishing", 
		"option_d": "Hunting", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140130", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRrl4okkEgr6wL3vMGTAD2dRrHnDRqtxMEL3W6nHLsz5zNdiIkidgV4ksD3lnu8FqV5ItOoZOLDcbSw=", 
		"answer": "24a0Z4H2wlnl8cUoWxL+1r32OyvCDGEa42yLV69gdWPwFKbMaq32wJt9PhybhE1+4DbQoqn88koczePKoaKAB+nO9X3hOjGKiOs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3xzv84AkEgr9hf/6dWXVAnBRsGuMXKY0YnTwW7LQbejtiZF+NRydhV5y4DbSrKr85BMOgawb/oueYC0NbcnYClaneYAJtxNBEMJvHLD/", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Open plains", 
		"option_b": "Deep forests", 
		"option_c": "Deserts", 
		"option_d": "Slopes of hills in rock shelters and hilly river valleys", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140131", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5ElURb8yvHwMmLTAm5Rs22MVbFxY2KjW6TBe/++wJkxMFmamV5p/DbnsKzxt1EKm79e7IDfZyoKfYMv2NWb3uvz1y4DdEorXf+0EwCUDcnWcRdTkw==", 
		"answer": "2+zoOMGz0Bfut9ZwAk6y5969C3f+nc5ySnMYcNwRKUX0kg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzwRz4/ookEgn70fP6JnjVByIDpnKCQKh1cn3mFLfQYerszIRiZ1WHzUx+4WLDsauw1kAGjuoWAApOT65h9ZYGGy1aT0hM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "8000 and 2500 BC", 
		"option_b": "10000 and 4000 BC", 
		"option_c": "7000 and 2000 BC", 
		"option_d": "9000 and 3000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140132", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17cwPLzPH/YCmFRs3qMQq9xMHP2XavGLvr33Z8xM1SMhEk75nnJr7avtWXE5R12CnRJ445G5iAngyQ=", 
		"answer": "25GvbZ3/2Bft5Me6WU2BTXJmrQamCPOog5cI", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxA3j+4w6Vxqy0fX6PHmQF20er2zDVKxmMHP2XavGZ+P5iZ9+Klmaz1d+4VxCD1pE3Icsmlnfkac=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Roads", 
		"option_b": "Temples", 
		"option_c": "Boats", 
		"option_d": "Dwellings", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140133", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Bjj+cUjQBHi1r3oMHnVQ2EEr2uKRKJgdXWjXamCeuX7ibl0KFCAmVNy8TbHpKCw/l1Pm6BeqaeRdCsCcMt83dKK2OrjzX9EPdIb2Iiuf85fYD40jIWK+USnAtk=", 
		"answer": "24KwbZDnkRjk88UiUwz+wOS9HSPUlzIi/GKG2q8zClbuAw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kRr4+JUzEhz3xvzyMCvDF2MBr3rDW600ZHnmFLXHaeTxx9d1Mk6Ag1w75n7PsOXx8FZNeS3jFoW1xkGNl67x4PKiAg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Rice and maize", 
		"option_b": "Wheat and barley", 
		"option_c": "Ragi and horse gram", 
		"option_d": "Millets and pulses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRj448U3Uw2yy/LrdW/VFWcdrG+GVuNwZWPqWqCCeuX7iZp0KUiAglV+9jbWprf5+FdPhqYb/ouMZCcRcMtO29mIiKZif+GeY16R3IOHPPqDTP4A", 
		"answer": "24a7fZ3jxRDk8MeEeVwpHTrkNzQO27UR936j", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEhP3y+n2OmXDQ20Fq3qREqV7YnzwFKjELuzs3YQxJUmdzVV05jbVoLD850cGga8ZU1UsU4TKevvqiGNe9t7oTg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cultivation", 
		"option_b": "Potmaking", 
		"option_c": "Writing", 
		"option_d": "Sculpting", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140135", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoVw33hfTxMWLTAnYUsD+XWqY0fX71UefWYfr/25NiZ1+Am1J3+2zHt6z/+RMGgehP4YvfXicMcoJ7wNmKl+XwwS4D91MBVrT/xucN717cO2QHFA==", 
		"answer": "25u9f9H+1Bjk5MUvVF70yvL7dWreByICq3qPRqZmMsxSsBD7kTEdOkAdN16x94s=", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKz0hHr+YIlEhPz1/b6MSvRQ3AUtXCPR7d9f3/iRr6Cffn72ddlKEuIn19osnXPtaz8/kkOm6FU58w+zvSpIq3f1j+Cegf9IFr4", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Trade and commerce", 
		"option_b": "Use of metal tools", 
		"option_c": "Advanced pottery", 
		"option_d": "New means of food and shelter", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140136", 
		"question": "25ehKIb70A2q+oAhXA2ywfT7dUXVDG4Yt3eKUeNkdX7zWKKCYOLqiZhzM12Agxtv+nPPseX2+FwL0Orsl3k5WEHAraP6VHOhJQF5", 
		"answer": "25K5fJn2wxDk8McVkGzdVtfBmNO/6GugOrYX", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3Bjj+Yk5Ehr31fjxMW7UQ20f43yWXrd9ZnD3XajMLuzwzddyJkidgV47+mPVoaT+80EWzWX+f909MFpYivs3CB8bSps=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cultivation", 
		"option_b": "Cattle husbandry", 
		"option_c": "Fishing", 
		"option_d": "Gathering", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140137", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy9unwO26QImUU43eCVuNgfzHnUbfHYOm+2YV4Kl2bhFdisnnI47L4/lAHz6Va/YuNeSMPPo1g2pCd3+H+1jFVPMlIid8wwzcPtM5y7g1nv3SKzmMfxQ==", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kxoo4HS7aNPtskm2n4aq3P4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3Bjj+Yk5EgvhwPm/Jn/fDWdRpXCRErd8dXjxFLPNYeHtiZZ/IxyeiFpr/XjV4Xm2y0oMZ5x4ME5SJU+6rNI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Metal", 
		"option_b": "Wood", 
		"option_c": "Bone", 
		"option_d": "Stone", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140138", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwQvv4YAuRhv2hen3MCvjF20fpj+iVaY0YHTsRKvHLuvsxpoxIVOcg19y/HGGsKDk418Kgq1V/Z3fdiMRPop4ycnJ0fb4yTFVO8MEkol+6INffeZFzS7yNtUSz75D1K4wJb5w4reeZu8=", 
		"answer": "25G9eJT91Rzk9IBgXRCy1unwO26QF20er2zB2vT6G6YyI8THx+jg40e9Ng==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3xzv84AkEgr9hf/6dWXVAnBRsGuMXKY0YnTwW7LQbejti27k33iIGMptBlD2zEisl9M=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Fear of wild animals", 
		"option_b": "Lack of agricultural skills", 
		"option_c": "Dependence on stone tools", 
		"option_d": "Harsh climate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140139", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5clVRf9y737PG+QF2oU41GGXa99ZHnqV+fDaei+y5J2LlLJgVpv92SGt63x+RMYirtP7JyRMAMQd4owihioiX/5kWpNtcfYzMtxb6k=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjyk7ZqZKivw9rSb214+RXRxvc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxbp8pYzEg3mxO/rMG+QD2MFpm3DW600ZHnmFI7MauT/x9diMl6KglVv+3jDrbGyy+NHdIVlp+YKNT9oFjUIvg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Europe", 
		"option_b": "Africa", 
		"option_c": "India", 
		"option_d": "South America", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140140", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17gwO7qOX+QDGRRt3eGEo1xf33qQK/Lba3szIF+K0mdhFR1sn/I47H48hMCgKxeqYGZMDEWfJhm28SM2efymzMmAqottDLZqzW63fmP4j/5", 
		"answer": "24awYZfnkR/4+IhgWgv80fTxMivEDCIStnOXW7V1ZHjsWufDYOm+ypZlM1CMzVNu4XTHraHi7hFwNOCECBXgCWHpTqF6Tg8X", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKz0hHr+YIlEhPz1/b6MSvRQ3EYpHGKVKp3cX/3FLTKZ+vqiZ5/Z1SGmhtr93nWr6Cw+1oZiqwb6ICbMDEMa5lszdTJ0ev4wDPBzFDJEj0EtgAqlseVUOa5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Increased trade", 
		"option_b": "Urbanization", 
		"option_c": "Rise of kingdoms", 
		"option_d": "Shift from hunting to cultivation and cattle husbandry", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140141", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TV6xkfHSjQ6LQa63xx9dlL1nJmVNp92XOrKn0t1wJz6tS/4eTeTgCaoJgxpC12dj59nRAIMlKwMBG7J8GPPxByH2jccObLftvwH3AKEOwYTayADB1mjWWmXRTpJe+52WMyBL90fdpnBiZ1QZn2YFC", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Avvt5EyRxu+hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDW7A0ZHnmFKTNfP/7yoMxIkSZgVp182LPrKuw+FVPrrtI7JyLeS0NPO39SieICF6J1lk94kQfp34=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2Rjk8IBgWxCyw/LwMSvDDHcDoHqQEqJ6dDHwXKLOeujsiZpwNVeMiRt6smXPpKv58VoMjqZPqZ2LdTJDaoR4ycKNxKT0zWdIP89em5R765RdPus4ynjYCAztuppr9HcO0g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140142", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he36OnvcBiIepT+XWqY0Q2XsWqKCT+r7iZR+MlCNzVR1/m+GsKDk418Kz6dVqZqXdWIQcoR/zcPJ2OK3zHhNP9UEpo5O6qgafedPwmftQNzeOb5my2+WLknpJyu4CHlxkHHZhDxFvIy18GevW9U701UzmIM44805ONKbmbycqE+9xgiH3WnRW6lrH1HZp8u75FaOo4cr93Wax1u+KV+pWQ20ZjGDCUE=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Avvt5EyRxu+hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDW7A0ZHnmFKTNfP/7yoMxIkSZgVp182LPrKuw+FVPrrtI7JyLeS0NPO39SieICF6J1lk94kQfp34=", 
		"explanation": "25e9YZ/0kRfv9pdgQQr9y/i/J27DDHcDoHqQErR1YzHmR7THYPn3yJsxI0mMzU90smLOpqzit1cKn61V7YuRcydDcYUv28SG2eG30H5OP9UGw+iYD8/i8iLcgpyzoUk3vA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140143", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+CVaY0eX+jfanGZ+y+2oNwNUiMiRty/DbSq6Cw5FYZiqZP4c6SeS4Pe4VhwcWEl8bUhE1PD8h2n4Fh65RFPN1UjD+oc9XVYPJv2muSZ0z+JxCzAHl11DLZh2xXuoa/tTO0FM0y0wE3hIk4zNs1PZU08kUV7xk1Fr/qs7cyTEWj", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Avvt5EyRxu+hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDW7A0ZHnmFKTNfP/7yoMxIkSZgVp182LPrKuw+FVPrrtI7JyLeS0NPO39SieICF6J1lk94kQfp34=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjykQ7j44slQQ33wb3rPW6QDGwCpmvDXaU0ZHnmFInHYeH33Z94JByIil47/nfSprew41sOgehM7J2LdTANPqp8wdHL3et0QyT+9eOIF8LPHy8Zfg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both are true, but Reason is not the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140144", 
		"question": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2yxPr6dWLeQ3YZpj+qXKd9cX+jR7LAbeLw3Z5/IlKdzVl+9XfI46Ti+EYBi+hP4YvfTx08QbRQ95JtUsXy4d8D0gUseRLAhEfO", 
		"answer": "24a9fpT9xRGq+owsXhv8y/TqOCvyICC7egGqAHP27/N16SubCVte", 
		"explanation": "25ysKJzywxL5t5EoV17iwO/2Om+QFGoUrT+tV6x4eWXrXaSCfv//yoN4JFmazUhv82TSpqGw/l1PpqZf4I/dMxzWte2fczA1e+SynQA7Lw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Fifth millennium BC", 
		"option_b": "Sixth millennium BC", 
		"option_c": "Seventh millennium BC", 
		"option_d": "Eighth millennium BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140145", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+0BDkt4YyXQ7hhf7qOX/ZFWMFpnvDVrZmeX/kFLPKa63QzJh9LkiBhFg783HD46z+t0cHiuhI/IycfywXd4VqxsTJwOHlwTF+DPl7pb9Npv42kPztAJY/BCNQUmIt3hw=", 
		"answer": "24KwbZDnkRjk88UiUwz+wOS9HSPUlzIi/GKG2q8zClbuAw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQ7v5YBgRhb3he3tPGbREXtRoG2MQrA0d2PsQ6mCavjswJl2Z0iBhEg783HD4Yo8/t2qae2WkBAUS+M0xbw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Rice and maize", 
		"option_b": "Wheat and barley", 
		"option_c": "Ragi and horse gram", 
		"option_d": "Millets and pulses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140146", 
		"question": "25u9Z536xRHj9MUwVxHiyfi/Im7CBiIVqmyXW61zZXjwXKLGLu/niYN5IlWbzU5o9zbJpeXPyGwwsJdkq1+uNZlOA6NTihKMJR4b4CI=", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kRrv+5EzEJbJMwzg3ejmh5TBVJzP5pc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQ3l+IkzEgn31/i/IGXZEncU42uMErd8dTHNUajOZ/n2wJQxIk6Izx82MJYtzERao9jOJT0Tk94=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone hammers", 
		"option_b": "Stone celts", 
		"option_c": "Stone knives", 
		"option_d": "Stone spears", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140147", 
		"question": "24KxfJmz3xz9t4glUxDhhfL5dW3fDGZRonGHErB8dX33UbWOLsP7xpt4M1SAjhtr93nWr6Cw4FYdiuhU586LeCdDaoN9zcOB2OjzhH5Hc/l7pb9N26Vd8ObyW5YtTxEXscENHgVhzA==", 
		"answer": "25axfpj/2APr44wvXFxBVgiDy90Fuk7c5O3lH0by", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKz2Bfu/oYhRhvhhen3MGLCQ2MVtX6NUaZ5dX/3FKbMaq3u25h2NVmanhm25QSFJ/X29+MOFR6Z5Iiz", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ci,vi,li,za,ti,on", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140148", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy0fX6dVjEDGwU416EV+N3f2TvUOfRa/nqxZIxN06AgFpp+3rf46r+t0cHiuhI5YGPdTFDcY0v9++26NvI+zN8cOixeberdCUTp6c0oTjD", 
		"answer": "252xZJ3gkRDkt5cvURWy1vX6OX/VEXFRonGHEqt9fH36FLXLeOjsiYFwK1CMlEg5v3N2gHGFhlzVAK8leOji8Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzxhj5t4E1V17myr3rPW7ZESIVpm+GXKdxfnLmFKjMLv7qxpl0Z0iGgldosJywKGXOd2gpCfeaJ2gYW1k=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Plains", 
		"option_b": "Forests", 
		"option_c": "Deserts", 
		"option_d": "Hills in rock shelters and hilly river valleys", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140149", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwVwz7yvm/ImLECyIFq3rDQKZzeX7tFLDKa//7ibl0KFCAmVNy8TbWsaTz41oMirsb+pqeYjYGetEvmZDQh7SniSIRY5YEuKM+pMhfT/FWyTO5fJTWKfJiy2COLlD9JxueRqRiw2pxqjQRBgUaK3yMY7w=", 
		"answer": "2+T4X5TgxRz4+cUBQRfzib2tdULeB2sQ4c+2M/nLLc4rB4TmumF4JGQ=", 
		"explanation": "24K9e4X2wxeq1pYpU17wwPr+OyvVAnAdqnqRErR8eX3mFI7MauT/iYRlJk6diF87+3iGt631t2AKma1V/YbffSsPco5hxtmc2qTV5zOKAnGYSt3zkCqbHOfkIm9C", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 India, 2 Western Asia", 
		"option_b": "1 Europe, 2 Africa", 
		"option_c": "1 Western Asia, 2 India", 
		"option_d": "1 South America, 2 North America", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140150", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUtVx/81r3wMyvDFmACqmyXV613dSujBefsa+LywIN5Ll/FzQk7wWLJraCw1lQKzcjK8trIO1jOjUXmE/e74kw=", 
		"answer": "2+T4S4T/xRD89pEpXRCyxPP7dWjRF3Ydpj+LR7B2cX/nRr6OLr++4YJ/M1WHihc79H/Vq6z+8B9PjqZfqYmeZCoGbIJhz5IRotQyvPVaZDxUaAYk0kjP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1Bbm/pEoWx2yxPr6dXjRFCIQ42yLW6VgMHfxW6qCZvjw3Z5/IBydght69WTPoLD840YdiuqZ3wzAG4w0Zsv8ByD0xYE7", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 Trade and commerce, 2 Hunting and gathering", 
		"option_b": "1 Nomadism and trade, 2 Agriculture", 
		"option_c": "1 Cultivation and cattle husbandry, 2 Hunting, fishing, and gathering", 
		"option_d": "1 Urban life, 2 Nomadism", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140151", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vx36y/LzOmzZAGMd42+RXaRmdWLwFLDLeuW+3Z90Z06MilJ0/CyG8uXH8lIZhqZcpc6PfzYOf4BmxtfFl/PlzWVIPcEI2tIy0YkaPPtGjC65e9reYP1rwnqTZW7Vzclm51m4ufj2M+959W4=", 
		"answer": "2+T4X5TgxRz4+cUBQRfzib2tdULeB2sQ4c+2M/nLLc4rB4TmumF4JGQ=", 
		"explanation": "24K9e4X2wxeq1pYpU17hxOq/MWLGBnACpj+XV6B8fn7vW6DLbezyiYdjKFubiEhovjbRq6z88hMmgaxS6M6IcTFDeoJ83NmH0PH+13lEN4ZGg8Bh8JURebRDyTG5Z5Zt5vQbzagOVkAlZ7Tqb0Mi", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> The Neolithic Age: First Food Producers and Animal Keepers >> Farming and Cereals to  Progress in and Limitation of the Neolithic Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 Western Asia, 2 Europe", 
		"option_b": "1 Africa, 2 India", 
		"option_c": "1 Western Asia, 2 India", 
		"option_d": "1 South America, 2 North America", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150101", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTv44QsEgnz1r35PHnDFyIEsHqHEqJgMGXrUefHYOm+xpExM1SMzXV+/XrPt6359BMfirpS5orAMo/5myhePbYCmrUY4461Oc0=", 
		"answer": "25a3eIH2w1ss4E7Bmp7yV+mSGHObK4DH", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH23x2q+INgRhb3hdP6OmfZF2oYoD+TV7F9f3WjWabQZej6iYN5IhyLiFxy/HjPraKw+FVPm6BeqZuMdWIMeMtsx8CZ0va1Qz6pTUuoWUlQ4cDJfV2Qhg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Bronze", 
		"option_b": "Iron", 
		"option_c": "Copper", 
		"option_d": "Gold", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUcED36xPH8OmfZF2oYoEPBEq5xcX+8Fs+T3f68V0wiVo71di7E6UY=", 
		"answer": "25a3eIH2w1T544ouV17izfzsMCkf/gyiPVpSLDB7PVqqfcDd", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt8IDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFW42yKVa19dnjmR+fDLu7rxYNkNVnJj1po93KGrKuw41sKz71I7M6QdmIBcZ9niNOGx/Ty1jFAPcIEiZR96p9fdflQwDigcdrPM7yQOj5PuJRsH89oo8y1Q6hm", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone age", 
		"option_b": "Copper age", 
		"option_c": "Bronze age", 
		"option_d": "Copper-stone phase", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuyw/LzOWTHBmZRt3eGEoFmf3/5Uefjaei+4ZZjJkyZjBt453rStrf1t1oBz7ha+5qMMC0FPqJhzNmIiKbqRJlOfBSnjeyrIu0PPnis", 
		"answer": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7x0PHrIHnVECA6rDRVPErK5umtvRoB781K", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJL2ww3r/otgQBv1zPLxJivfBSI4rXuKU+80U3niWKTNYuTqwZ5yZ1+cgU9u4HPV47bl9FAKiqxe7c6LeCdDXJlgxsqMl8XwwTFpMtRFipBzpJkKcOBV3jjvXUMfL6iCXmvjGzLOBbsB9w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Vedic", 
		"option_c": "Chalcolithic cultures", 
		"option_d": "Bronze Age", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150104", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRDkt7chWB/h0fX+OyvREWdRt3eGErdjfzHAXKbObeLywIN5Ll/JnlJv92WGr6rz9kcKi/cZxjKCX1N3JYhSFByb6F4fDw==", 
		"answer": "25SwaYOz0Bfut6IpXgv8wb9NxtPw+KtTK9N6bLUrdgN3", 
		"explanation": "24GvZ9HQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JmLEBnFRqnHDQaxhZHnmVbTWa//wiaVwLV2amVN6/DbHsaCw1lsOneha54rfVysPa4Vrin3WPb6IgvZ7iKVuYD/g61U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Eran", 
		"option_b": "Gilund", 
		"option_c": "Ahar and Gilund", 
		"option_d": "Kayatha", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150105", 
		"question": "25+3eob2kRr/+5E1QBuyzO6/O2rdBmZRonmXV7E0Z3nqV6+CevTuzNpiLkiM0hnwey1UEzj8ok3jp7Mrea21", 
		"answer": "25+3eob2k79awppGh2oqS7px7t1OXf8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dWLDQ2wQrnqHEqJyZHTxFLPKa63q0Id0ak+AmV472HnUtKCw+1wMjrxe7c6QfmIXdo4v+MKIweXlxTFTOtBBiMLH8guEZvNMP+wlkWKWyk5I", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Nevasa", 
		"option_b": "Inamgaon", 
		"option_c": "Daimabad", 
		"option_d": "Jorwe", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150106", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t5EoV17Yyu/oMCvTFm4Ftm2GErB9ZHSjR67We+zqzJMuZexKiOlUAdV/pyjHhbx5/KU=", 
		"answer": "25q2KIX71Fnm8oM0Ehzzy/a/Om2QF2oU40+RU7V1YnCjRq7Ua/+8l+mmYjk7Ies1DfMzscxJhQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUzWwr3hfTsdXvfEGsFqnCNV6c0f3+jQK/HLuH7z4MxJV2Hhht09DbSq6Cwx0EOmalJ6M6NeTQGbMcvyZCdxe310WVAId8ElYYy8JIaPNNPyDy7dcbSYk4pm0XuJveRZrv+Lh1x9+8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "On the right bank of the Godavari", 
		"option_b": "Near the Indus valley", 
		"option_c": "On the left bank of the Pravara river", 
		"option_d": "At the southern tip of the Godavari", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150107", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDQqZ7YH3mFLfQZ+D/2559Phycnl475nmGrqT78hMbgKdX+s6efiZDaY5u2N+HxLu1D9VGes/56QJFK9YFLmdfeA==", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kxoo4HS7aNPtskm2n4aq3P4=", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV77y/n2I2LUFmMdsD+OU6p6fGijQbTHaq3t3Zh/IhyPgkk78WTHpbH5+VRPm6dU5Z3fcSwHPpxqycCG2fe1j2rgPioWlhngHAfolb7N0g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Iron", 
		"option_b": "Copper", 
		"option_c": "Bronze", 
		"option_d": "Stone", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150108", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yyfTxPm7UQ3Ye42uLV+N6cXzmFJPDY+//35ZlLgPLcWaO4XLvMRqWkNCmAaa/mg==", 
		"answer": "25SwaYOxuI2io5uM7OnwUKq7SxmYow==", 
		"explanation": "25SwaYO0wlnl5YwnWxDzyb3xNGbVQ2sC40uCX6F1ZnD3XeuCZ+P6wJRwM1WHiht6smbKoqb1t0cHjrwb4Y+MMCEMbptq2pLSUyn6YPlj3eEn9QsFlbac", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gilund", 
		"option_b": "Jorwe", 
		"option_c": "Ahar", 
		"option_d": "Nevasa", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150109", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhrz0fTxMivfBSIFq3rDc6t1YjHgQavWe//7ltWUSdHWl4aeseMjgmVuIKE2", 
		"answer": "27b4OsCjgVn++MVxB06ihd/cd92ZzittjvBdhJssLGzp3Xw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHS2Rj4t4Y1Xgrn1/i/PHiQB2MFpnvDUKZgZ3TmWufBLr+vmccxJlKNzQouoiaGgYayZQK7XeS13u/mfcIDOEu2FQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "c 2100 to 1500 BC", 
		"option_b": "c 1200 to 800 BC", 
		"option_c": "c 3000 to 2500 BC", 
		"option_d": "c 1700 to 1200 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IlgXx/2wL3wMyvTDHIBpm3DRaJnMHfsQanGLuTwibR5JlKNgldyrTRKYmrUqcbltF/gdpon3UCV", 
		"answer": "25awYYL23Qqo3go9MGb0nm/cWbs2mbVndw==", 
		"explanation": "25a3eIH2w1np/4wzVxLhher6J26QB2sCoHCVV7FxdDHqWufhZuzwzZh9Lh5bxzKdXcyVR8qtvU6N2LA8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Axes", 
		"option_b": "Bangles", 
		"option_c": "Chisels", 
		"option_d": "Sheets", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150111", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwRb+44AyS17m3O36dXzRECIBsXqVU69xfmWjUrXNY62smcchZ36qzVR15XfUp7avteHkIRFrij4WP31MM9rpeZo=", 
		"answer": "25e0aZL4nBjk88gyVxqwdPxyqNEkIXe8SZWpjWLvTQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZL4nBjk88gyVxqy1fLrIW7CGiIGomzDQrFxZnDvUanWLuvsxpoxKVmIn1disiSW8/Ww1XBPgKZM6JybY2C70qyHaCiLUqsQNslSr4uN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "White-and-blue", 
		"option_b": "Red-and-yellow", 
		"option_c": "Green-and-brown", 
		"option_d": "Black-and-red", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWxCy5PXyNG/eAmUQsT+HW7BgYnjgQOfLfa3szJtwM1mNzU90smLOpuXa+EEYiuhY/IKLZTAGIcn7Cob3hNH2ulbZp1l+8JaH", 
		"answer": "25G5YZzy0xjutTbolbD7joI/nFH9pTOTfrw=", 
		"explanation": "25G5YZzy0xjut4wuEj/6yPz7O2rXAnBRp3aQRrF9c2WjXbSCYuTwwpJ1Z0iGzU9z9zbsrLfn8hMMmqRP/JyaMlTz1Rn/3Ssmiwx/Knz5zdI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chandoli", 
		"option_b": "Nevasa", 
		"option_c": "Daimabad", 
		"option_d": "Songaon", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF76xO6/FmPRD2Eer3aXWqp3MGLqQKLRLuTwibZ9K12BjFl69jbCqrbk5VoMm/cZWvQ644mYHsDRzr4z1pAO1A==", 
		"answer": "24OxZpX7yBjktS6DiGnv7xjwgr6JZ91rVXI=", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7hzOn6JivREWdRr3CAU7dxdDHqWufWZui+/55/I1SQjFU74HPBqqr+t1wJz4lX5Y+XcSACestrwcOdxe300DOg3H8fTCWHnD8ma2SkixSq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Himalayan", 
		"option_b": "Deccan", 
		"option_c": "Vindhyan", 
		"option_d": "Gangetic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq9osvRhb3173xNGbVQ2QesT+XWqY0U3niWKTNYuTqwZ5yZ0yBjEh+rTRdbLlnuShrl5AfkEC1kGwN", 
		"answer": "25a3eIH2w2r544ouV17izfzsMCnSa5CWQx2BLf8GUSJuieTa", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt8IDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFW42yKVa19dnjmR+fWZui+yphhN1mbwEhv/XjD47X49kAKzU4Wau9F5km1HsBHKx25vrU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Iron Age", 
		"option_b": "Copper Age", 
		"option_c": "Stone Age", 
		"option_d": "Copperâ€“stone phase", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuyzO6/EWrZDmMTonvDU7Bnf3LqVbPHaq3pwIN5eB7fnRhtpzTJZSSf4wS8LhZT", 
		"answer": "25+3eob2kRr/+5E1QBuwH+aZnwIg8eP0qRhTPdyV7A==", 
		"explanation": "25G5YZzy0xjut4wzEgz3yfzrMG+QF21Rt3eGEol7YmbmFKTXYvnr25Iz5ITXoqcLucAkMdNZOlIecA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Malwa", 
		"option_b": "Vedic", 
		"option_c": "Harappan", 
		"option_d": "Jorwe culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150116", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ2oQoXaXU7c0f3ejQK/HLsD/wZZjJk+BmUl6slXOoqnz+F8Gm6BS6s6MeTYGbdQtVg9sszbpRFeIbxIJ97VJYA==", 
		"answer": "24a9ZZi+0Avj88UhQBvz1r8fDtpaVzGBt9hxx+tMSNtY", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JmLEBnFRqnHDf6J8cWPiR6/WfOy+3pJjIhyahE9u82LDp+X5+RMciqVSpI+NeSZDf5lqycPL3KRdsrp8OtXB1chqmU/3Fg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Coastal regions", 
		"option_b": "Rainforests", 
		"option_c": "Mountainous regions", 
		"option_d": "Semi-arid areas", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150117", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IlgRR/hhev2J3/FAm4duj+CULBxfmWjXamCT+X/28gzNnHk8+MoQfoJ6XbfWim3rQ==", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kRjy8pZgXQyyx/H+MW7DQdqyZjo6pTZhIeRWpB8tXiU=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KLD70Aumt5Y0XRD3hfznMHiQDHBRoXOCVqZnMGbmRqKCfv//yoN4JF2FgUI7/HnI7qDo/kAbiqZPqwX47Moq2pxhwGE81boYWvc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Chisels", 
		"option_b": "Microlithic tools", 
		"option_c": "Stone axes or blades", 
		"option_d": "Copper sheets", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150118", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTri9okjXRL70fX2NivTFm4Ftm2GEqpnMHLsWrTLaujszJMxM1SMzUly8X7DsLGw/l1Pm61J5J3ffyRDfY59yd2A1PeohtNlO+RdhPkKdc+WoLWqNaw=", 
		"answer": "25i5ZIbykTri9okjXRL70fX2NivTFm4Ftm2GEM6sym3bi7tUAojbrZbnn2g=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe0BX99sUDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFRoGqPRrZmdTHsUufBa+Pq25Z9Z12HiRts92XSprf+t3oBi6FaqYeMMCYGe4ZqzJCd3+G31nhCO8NXjsB76toLeeZN332icpTYJexvw2eDNAez65qhBlTVMKxjINsk8Egw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappan", 
		"option_b": "Ahar", 
		"option_c": "Malwa Chalcolithic culture", 
		"option_d": "Jorwe culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IlgWw2yxvLxJmLUBnAUpz+CXONxY2LmWrPLb+G+zJt0KlmHmRt09DbSq6Cw1FsOg6tU5YeLeCsAPptqx8CF0qPkhGVOPMpPk5Qtpmow+VXQDyL8xEoAPUw6RaI=", 
		"answer": "24asZ5/2kRvm9oElQV7zy/m/N2fRB2cdpmuQENQ+RtJN+Q2mhZcdLxDqI7k=", 
		"explanation": "24asZ5/2kRvm9oElQV7zy/m/N2fRB2cdpmuQErRxYnSjR67FYOT4wJRwKUjJiFd+/3PIt7aw+FVPm6Beqa2XcS4AcYdm3NiA1KTnwX5RP8MDicBm65UTd/1UjmLggQTw72xrnr7FOzm49pM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone chisels", 
		"option_b": "Copper bangles", 
		"option_c": "Stone sheets", 
		"option_d": "Stone blades and bladelets", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150120", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4EpQQrgzP7rdWLDQ1IQrXuWEpF1enDxFIPKZ+/3iZt+JF2diF8ksGf7vApvcO+lKTaid/AvGKc=", 
		"answer": "25etepXk0Beq84wzRgz7xum9rARF46HtTvnVJ41PRUs0LQ==", 
		"explanation": "24W5ZpXmkSvr/YQyEjr6zP/2dWLDQ3EYt2qCRqZwMHjtFLPKa63c3IV1MF2HzV9y4WLUqqbkt1wJz61a+pqaYixDV4VrwdHLxA+7P/GUa4gJqqWpM0aYSw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ahmadnagar", 
		"option_b": "Pune", 
		"option_c": "Allahabad", 
		"option_d": "Burdwan district", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150121", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXg2y0vjtMCvTDG8crHGPS+Nwf3zmR7PLbezqzJMxI0mbhFV8smLOpuXT/1IDjKdX4JqXeSFDf4xql5KYVVCeYRzHKnmQaQt+U++l", 
		"answer": "25a3f4K/kQri8oAwHl71yvzrJieQE2sWsDPDU61wMHP2UqHDYuL72tVfdV4I7wlGBwT4kQovpE7v", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxhz48sUhXxH8wr3rPW6QE3AYrn6RS+N1fnjuVavRLv/7yIV0IxyLlBtY+nfKoKr8/kcHhqsb+YuQYC4GPBr1n/D3Cs/YH8cbItJarEU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cows, lions, tigers, and buffaloes", 
		"option_b": "Cows, cats, dogs, and goats", 
		"option_c": "Cows, sheep, goats, pigs, and buffaloes", 
		"option_d": "Sheep, goats, lions, and tigers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150122", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhDt+YwmWx3zy+m/J27dAmsfsD+UV7FxMHfsQanGLuTwibNwLlGIj1p/rTRroZGX01bOeOTrhV9kWobw", 
		"answer": "25eqZ5/p1Fnt+IokQVxBXgeNPZTqYfwp+pgceC7d", 
		"explanation": "25G5YZzy0xjut4wzEhjzyPLqJivWDHBRt3eGErFxc371UbXbLuL4iZpwKUXJj0l0/GzD46L/+FcczX/EIPgZ0ECHXtSX9oI89II=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Pottery", 
		"option_b": "Stone houses", 
		"option_c": "Mud-brick structures", 
		"option_d": "Bronze goods", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150123", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4RgURH/yPLxdWnFCm4VqnGEEq51ZHTxXabOLunr255/IBydhV470X7Hr6b/+1obh6FYqY+YdX1Bh3cYae6sM8rIGBGvDNmnZw==", 
		"answer": "24K5fIX/1Fnr+YFgVh/nx79mZv45d/QQDunu/wZc4Eev", 
		"explanation": "25i3e4Wz2Rb/5IAzEhrn1/TxMivEC2dRgHeCXqB7fHj3XK7BLuz5zNdmIk6MzVh0/GXSsbDz41YLz79S/YbfZyMXaodqiNGH06TzxWRDcRJ6CdwMfwLPLpDyWxoyr0Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Burnt bricks", 
		"option_b": "Wattle and daub", 
		"option_c": "Stone", 
		"option_d": "Metal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150124", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr4+JVgRR/hhf7qOX/ZFWMFpnvDW600Z3TwQKLQYK3Xx5N4JhyNmEly/HGGt631t3AHjqRY5oKWZCoKfct/wNGa0ru1Iwp2SMoONKuh+eAOo7BquA==", 
		"answer": "25e5ep32yFnr+YFgRRb3xOm9KpI8o6F7vgtoKfS69hrmBQ==", 
		"explanation": "24K9e4X2wxeq3oskWx+yxujzIWLGAnYUpz+BU7F4dWijVanGLvr2zJZlZ1icn1J19TbSq6Cw1FsOg6tU5YeLeCsAPptnycOMlQ5BX9SeZeUvFnHvMp5oWNs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Rice", 
		"option_b": "Millets", 
		"option_c": "Barley and wheat", 
		"option_d": "Bajra", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150125", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2hDk88UvVF70zPrqJ27DQ3EEpHiGQbdnMGXrUefUa+P725ZlLlOHzVR9smLOpuX9+EcHirob7oGbdCcQbdQtFEXK/YDv+R8j3U4bqLunvg==", 
		"answer": "24G9eoPy0hb+44RgVBf10O/6JivfBSIGrHKGXOGbLZitruLgSq0lrtNKNGRY", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U42mGXKZmcWXmUOfWZui+xJhlL1mbzVx09nLDsLa8t1oBi6FY6JqadGIBZ8t7zcKb1uf40GVAc8BNnZVg4Ylfc/IA2zKgcdqZqTTcwjmPkeIWUjWTBHGE2g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone figures of men", 
		"option_b": "Bronze figures of animals", 
		"option_c": "Terracotta figures of women", 
		"option_d": "Mud figures of children", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150126", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr4+JVgRR/hhe3+J3/ZAHcdom2PS+N1Y2LsV67Deuj6iYB4M1TJiFpo5nPUreXZ+VcGjuhf/JyWfiVDaoNqiPOB1uj0y31IJ85NmcBi7JsMeasCyIa0Rsh6OjP4EHKOu7rN6Q==", 
		"answer": "24exa5Sxb4884U9gNqJ0m+eAy2HyFA==", 
		"explanation": "25C5e4X2wxeq3oskWx+y1e/wMX7TBmZRsXaAV+NwZWPqWqCCeuX7ibR5JlCKgldy5n7PoOXg/1IciurO2dWmLdrSC5r/bC1T2OSA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Wheat", 
		"option_b": "Barley", 
		"option_c": "Bajra", 
		"option_d": "Rice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150127", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWw2yw/zyOn7DQ2QesT+KRrA0dHjwV6jUa//niZh3Z1KcgF5p/WPV46b15VYOg7sb7ZuaMDYMPo53y9Gf1vD+y38ecfXzuEEolv+QtH4kIXQFdME=", 
		"answer": "25u5fpXyxRbm/sc2iLiyiA/VeusKFdK6TXwg", 
		"explanation": "25u5fpXyxRbm/sUvXF7mzfi/N2reCCIepT+XWqY0XnDxWabGb6332td/KEiIj1d+snDJseX540BPirBP7ICMeTQGPo9m29OGweHl3TFONYZHn5J35ZYMPkhsGsG+JmoOjo+0p2T+sJM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ahar", 
		"option_b": "Inamgaon", 
		"option_c": "Daimabad", 
		"option_d": "Navdatoli", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDQqZ7YH3mFK7MLuj/2oN0NVLJpFV/+3eGr6z78l8Wz6RS/4vffyxcPMcOf85E1Bshd/e0QK2FTBs=", 
		"answer": "25Oxe5mz0Bfut5cpURuw5cnT+dd1tSLz9q6wFP+5LA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w735PHjYQ2oerHSQEqJ6dDHxXaTHLv7rzpB0NEiazU9z82KGpazj/xMOgawb+4ecdWIUe5lqiNHJx+vn0X1AIYZAk4VmptMfAWzPIJ2YeLhA9tlwmuA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Meat and wheat", 
		"option_b": "Fish and rice", 
		"option_c": "Berries and barley", 
		"option_d": "Lentils and lamb", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150129", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk1Avvt4gvQQqyyvu/IWPVQ0EZonOAXa99ZHnqV+fSa+LuxZI2NByBgk5o92WGoKr+5EcdmqtP7IrAMqDZyFTGGA7Lc9hQSlH8Xsk=", 
		"answer": "24K5fIX/1Fnr+YFgVh/nx79mZv45d/QQDunu/wZc4Eev", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+0BPl5Yw0S179w733On7DBnFRp2qRW61zMGXrXbSCfujswJh1Z0uMn147/3fCpuX/8RMYjrxP5YvfcSwHPo9u3dLFl+vx0HRPc9FNjogy8JIeaPdIyTntZtvUJu0sKxMXasZBQo+/df3pQKO93w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Stone", 
		"option_b": "Burnt bricks", 
		"option_c": "Wattle and daub", 
		"option_d": "Mud-brick", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150130", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Bj+8pcpUxKy0vzsdX7DBmZRpXCREq51fmijU6jNav6+z5hkKVjJhFU71nfPrqTy9ldQzVqrCu9UJuiMsb9EOsbRae8=", 
		"answer": "25eqZ5/p1FuIIa/tKEpd2nFLhiBLoPaZ", 
		"explanation": "25G5YZzy0xjut4wzEgz3y/LoO27UQ2QesT+XWqY0YnTgW7HHfPS+xpExKl2HlBt54HnIuaCw/kcKgrsXqZ2QfSdDd4VpxMWM2efywDFDKoZQkoUyzJsNfeRQzTPtd8HXNOt8yywc82VZ3KLBxj1ibGG3O7JO", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Iron", 
		"option_b": "Stone", 
		"option_c": "Clay", 
		"option_d": "Bronze", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150131", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4EpQBvx0fTwOyvHBnAU42uLV+NwdXDnFKXXfOT7zdd4KRykjFN64HfVq7Hi9hMLmrpS54nfZCoGPqhnydyK2Oj+0HlIMIZUkoFh4cVdzDiSoQ7HysvknWKDtgH4xw==", 
		"answer": "25u3eoX7nA3lupYvRwr6h+xvhBeDodQQQ1P9y1thGzQ=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KLzy2Rj49pYoRgzzib3vMGTAD2dRoWqRW6ZwMGXrUa7QLun7yJMxJVmHiFpv+jbSq6D55RMHgL1I7M6ZfC0MbJgvwd7J1qT5y2NVO4tQlc1h648LdLRQwy6kYN3ULrw6V1N52aGqfdQ2ctHywaYZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "East-to-west", 
		"option_b": "North-to-south", 
		"option_c": "Diagonal", 
		"option_d": "Circular", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150132", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTri9okjXRL70fX2NivDBnYFr3qOV61gMHniUOfNeOjsiZYxL0mHiUl+9jbOrLDj8kBPjqZfqYCKfScRcZ58iNeb1vLyhGJIJ8NXxcL2EV6/B6EKCtF5mgE4qsA7", 
		"answer": "25y2aZz00BbktTbxA6OA1n8Y7ZVa27ci5WU=", 
		"explanation": "25y2aZz00Bbkt5IhQV7zhe72MmXZBWsSonGXEoB8cX3gW6vLeuX3ytdiIkidgV5293jS47L541tPgqlV8M6XfzcQe5gvyd6Nl+PlxWdEc9VNjoVhqNoZc+ZUxTukcdCbIfBqjn2VNVf/cje5AXQ0liiWizxbp4Kvt9VkPoYEKUi7rQH1X8LE6L0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Navdatoli", 
		"option_b": "Daimabad", 
		"option_c": "Inamgaon", 
		"option_d": "Ahar", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150133", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDQqZ7YH3mFKrDYPj4yJRlMk6MzVl+83LV46Pi+F5QzfVaIKi+Lls+6RDy31Fgf1s=", 
		"answer": "24a9ZZi+wQvv9IwvRw2y1unwO27DQShgZHGgq7Jwfuh4CBKZGBo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3Bju8sUiVx/21r35J2TdQ3EUrnbOQrFxc3jsQbSCffnxx5JiZ1CAhl478XfUraD8/lIBw+hI/YueZCsXe8cvyd6Nl/XixWNVKYZHiJlh8JsTPgWmrgpzIvpyyKYqPwSMYbI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Wood", 
		"option_b": "Bone", 
		"option_c": "Clay", 
		"option_d": "Semi-precious stones", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRtH6QEo1bRDHiFKTHfOj/xddhNVONmFh+9jbEuuXk/1ZPrKBa5Y2QfCsXdoJsiMCM2PT7wS4DSHvktMXdXhAAECA6KRoc8w==", 
		"answer": "25ixZJ32xQqoKX9f7DrozLEIASObLnABcg==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQrv4YAyUxKyxvjtMGrcECIGpm2GEqRmf2btGOfPZ+HyzINiZ0uMn1474nfUt6zz4l8OnaRCqY+MYy0Ad4p7zdTJwO3jzDFVO8MEvoVx55sRPOZFyzSiepajX9J6vJE2b/3tVcuxfcQu", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Wheat", 
		"option_b": "Barley", 
		"option_c": "Rice", 
		"option_d": "Millets", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150135", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/JnLdAW0dqmWGVuN9fjH3UbXQb+7x3YNwNByPgk519jbPreXd9l8Yjuha54rfQiMJf5h7wNGHm6Tk0XZGNtVQk451pJtfbvFMxTqke8HIYP17wnrfZW0nFO7w58NDKA0SM9uX3IE=", 
		"answer": "25etZJ2xali7AlIjVMwwhi59p3mlZw==", 
		"explanation": "24ascZ36yxzut4c1XhKy0fjtJ2rTDHYFomzDW600XXDvQ6aCb+P6iaVwLV2amVN6/DbVq6rnt0cHjrwb/YaaMCAWcocv39Gal/D/wTFSKstGlYwy65xffbRSyTGkc93UNe0uzXuMMwfNhewuXbtFhmfmwveLmRyH", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Lion", 
		"option_b": "Goat", 
		"option_c": "Horse", 
		"option_d": "Bull", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150136", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t6IhXBvhzer+JyvcDGEQt3qHDeEOXNRQH6spG5Jg2if5c1Xo", 
		"answer": "25a0Z4L2kQ3lt5EoV17gzP73dWjfE3IUsT+OW61xYzHsUufWZui++p56Jk76p1Nu/HzOtqvlt1IdiqkZVVTv6qHm7p45apFkTlTltg==", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cUpQV75y/LoOyvEDCITpj+NV6JmMGXrUefBYf3uzIUxKlWHiEg7/XCGt631t2AGhKlJmqSXZSwJdp5h3ZCb0uP+y38BOsgEjoh3pLEXeeBSxX2ue8TLJewuzGuMMwX/YXmPBXp1hyXei3IULnrQPZz0RjDHilCT/H8mcQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Near the Ganges River", 
		"option_b": "Close to the rich copper mines of the Sikarâ€“Jhunjhunu area", 
		"option_c": "In the southern plains of India", 
		"option_d": "Near the Himalayan region", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2hDk88UvVF79x/f6Nn/DQ3UUsXrDV7t3cWfiQKLGLuvsxpoxAF2HiEhz5XfU/OcMhyE6iACX2Shw8+AgEqAK", 
		"answer": "25Sqep7k2Rzr85ZsEg3iwPztPW7RB3Fd43mKQas0eH7sX7SOLu//x5B9Ik/FzVhz+2XDr7a8t1YbjOp9m/NYA9ivyq9lXMD18Gl3", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cUpQV7hzPrxPG3ZAGMftz+FXbE0ZHnmFLHDfOTx3IQxJFOZnV5psnnEqaDz40BPiadO54rTMCsNfYd6zNmH0KT21mNOJM5Bm4RhqNoMbPFB3jWoddDIbL5vwGrAKFH4Yiv9BWJgnTfXiWhF6sBYKjAh/RLd6ZQaGtX1moc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Terracotta figurines", 
		"option_b": "Stone tablets", 
		"option_c": "Gold jewelry", 
		"option_d": "Arrowheads, spearheads, fish hooks, bangles, chisels, etc", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150138", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuy1fjwJWfVQ20X41iCXKZneGbiRuDRLv3swJpwNUXJglh452bHt6z/+QxN8EMt8DPwwDXMbbFZiETDbg==", 
		"answer": "25i5ZoT10Br+4pcpXBmyyvu/NmTAE2cD43CBWKZ3ZGKhCEZ2PVdLeHOmn1wecOg1gg==", 
		"explanation": "25G9e4H6xRyq9YApXBmyyfL8NH/VByIfpn6RErF9c3mjV6jSfujsiZp4KVmawRtv+nOGhKT+8kAHmKlJqZ6afzIPe8t/2tmE1vb+yGgBNclHj5N34NoQcrRNzTO4ctXYNOt8x2CHZ0b/dym4FjB7ljvTiWhF6qy7rrZR6jJQZm+2sK0lmjg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Farming", 
		"option_b": "Hunting", 
		"option_c": "Weaving", 
		"option_d": "Manufacturing of copper objects", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150139", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hHr5YQjRhvgzOf6JivEC2dRjFyzDeFiXLs3OqInUgfwsJs/GRhc", 
		"answer": "25T4epT3nArm/pUwVxqy0vztMCvfBXYUrT+TU6p6ZHTnFK7MLu/yyJR6ZYlvBdW5LuChlfkzabqP6wQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHc8imqv6ojWgz3iN7wOWTFEWcV40+MRrdxYmiqFK7RLun72pRjLl6MiRt64TbH47f18x4cg6FL+YubMDUCbI4vzsKMxvHyymVNKoZUm4l88J8bPP1OjD+hddfQbL5jz2eOK1ywbjf9EnFnkXHQhW5bu8E5nVlDuGKE2SYfE0zZLwnU", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Clay vessels with inscriptions", 
		"option_b": "A red-slipped ware often painted in black", 
		"option_c": "Blue and green glazed pottery", 
		"option_d": "Pottery with animal motifs", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150140", 
		"question": "2565cZDn2Riq9JAsRgvgwL32JivUAnYUpz+CQKxhfnWjQ6/LbeW+2ZJjLlON0hmCVCie9iNfg9kVIAJWTZMc", 
		"answer": "2+foOMG+gEG6p8UCcVyhB1kiBhlbpvv6G2SK7g5T", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHY0ADr440hEh3nyenqJ26QBnoYsGuGVuN1Yn72WqOCPL2umdogfwzZzXlYvjbSrLLx5Vccz7xT7M6afiZDcY0v3NiMl8z21nBRI8dK2oNn6I4KbvECVifCGKTAIj1oW6oVa3sGsg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "3000-2800 BC", 
		"option_b": "2500-2200 BC", 
		"option_c": "2000-1800 BC", 
		"option_d": "1500-1300 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150141", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuy1u3+O2XVByIXsXCOEvIjICGuBfWSPq3c6sgz6jTVjUl2yp1YpSabnpbjow==", 
		"answer": "25i5ZIbykRr/+5E1QBuwtAkAMmZtWX5PPcHOH0VT9A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe0BX99sUjRxLm0O/6dXzRECIBsXqVU69xfmWjVqLWeej7x9cgcAzZwAopoiaGgYaw/l1Pna1c4IGRY2IPd4BqiP6IweD20H5NOooEv5Jz6tZfffpEjBOsc9DaYs6zFsfGOcTEnwBnxXjx7G4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Jorwe culture", 
		"option_b": "Harappan culture", 
		"option_c": "Malwa culture", 
		"option_d": "Ganeshwar culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150142", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt6YoUxLxyvH2IWPZACICqmuGQeN8cWfmFKXHa+O+xZhyJkiMiRty/DbSq6Cw+loLwo9a54maZCsAPp1uxNyMzru1byivPV0HnobomtI4Zr05cA==", 
		"answer": "yObg4RCCSrC88AbG1Dmux+aFfQ==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnn/oFtdR/8wvjrPGiQFWMdr3qaHuMlIymjd6/DYu7xxZ5lL1WKzUhy5nPV463x4VZPja1e586WdCcNaoJpwdWNlQELTjNWBB2/3YihIBrYbfU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 854, 
		"option_b": 138, 
		"option_c": 97, 
		"option_d": 215, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150143", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTri9okjXRL70fX2NivTFm4Ftm2GEqp6MHLmWrPQb+G+yJl1Z0uMnk9+4HiGiqv0/lJPg6lI/YubMDYKcocvn4DZl8bUmzNgJeIe4q/44BiwXbTYusUE", 
		"answer": "25+3eob2kRr/+5E1QBuwH+aZnwIg8eP0qRhTPdyV7A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dXvVEXEYsGuGVuNhfmXqWOeVPr2+67Q9Z1OcmVd64WLPraKw+EcHirobyoaefCEMcoJ7wNmKl+fiyGVUIcNX2ol8pJkacuBSzTHtddrfYOlr3XqFNUuwTje5DXE2kFy7BNPjT1O9i0+zID1TpA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganeshwar culture", 
		"option_b": "Malwa culture", 
		"option_c": "Harappan culture", 
		"option_d": "Jorwe culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150144", 
		"question": "24GwbdH31Brm/oslEhH0hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeN8cXPqQKbWZ+Lw2td4KRyeiEhv92TI44z+81oOz6lJ5puRdGJSLNs/iPKql+3khHBVJ9RNmJVm4Z5faPsA2zWsYIuZ50HU1lMVS84lRh6NWmMM6g==", 
		"answer": "25T4bJTw3RDk8sUpXF7gxPTxM2rcDyCYUNLY4aHU1CUwgfO+5Uni", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arr55UlUwzzy/76dWTWQ0EZonOAXa99ZHnqV+fRa/nqxZJ8IlKdnhty/DbRprbk8kEBz4FV7YeeMCMRcZ5hzJDYhbSnhFNic89X2oJ36JMaavFEjCmiNNbeYPp7yy6UKAXxJz24B2JxlSLTynVY6JG6/Cm9VdY7gkgiQYjkMrLVOMwpI0f0RDE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Invasion by foreign tribes", 
		"option_b": "A decline in rainfall", 
		"option_c": "Economic downturn", 
		"option_d": "Rise of another culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150145", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit6wuVhfzy73tMGzZDGxRp3aHErd8dTHAXKbObeLywIN5Ll/JnVN64XOGp6zi8lAbg7Eb/ZyefjEKaoJgxpCA2fD4hGVJNoZNiI98pIoXfedFk39ug28b7qaI3XpEL/K8bn5V", 
		"answer": "25C5e4X2wxeq3oskWx+wuAeB2sexY43jXXE7bCHfYQ==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJTywg3v5YtgexD2zPyzdX/YBiIyq36PUax4eWXrXaSCfuX/2pIxMF2azVJ2/3PCqqTk8l8Wz7tO6o2adSYGestt0ZCd3+G3zWNOPYZUkoFh4dZfaOZBwi6re8bWKfBpjn6FKFX8Ynm0CmR71DfDhnAbro++8SC+UJo2xwc7lZJ0+d0uPduWyryAqrE5cspWog1kyI53UnnyYS8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Northern India", 
		"option_b": "Western India", 
		"option_c": "Southern India", 
		"option_d": "Eastern India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150146", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3l+IlgRR/hhfn2M23ZAHcdtz+XXeNhY3SjXamCeuX7iZV9Jl+CzVh382/DuuXj+FoDz6lJ7I/fdDcRd4VoiMSB0qTUzHBNMMlIk5R67ZlfbPFSxTKpK5Yw7as1YfYzs3vOqkndlgcD", 
		"answer": "25Gxb5b63x6q5JEpURWwxfEY3IA0z84UBBRfe1IwQg==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fno+4QjWV7xyfzmMHKQEG0Yrz+CQKZ1PDH3XKKCauT5zp5/IByamVJ4+TbRoraw41waiKAb/YHfZTEGMstq28CM1O32yH1Yc89K2pR64dobbu0A3zisZ9vVYkcE0ClhybpEuT4bxWX6zHQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Plough", 
		"option_b": "Digging stick", 
		"option_c": "Hand hoe", 
		"option_d": "Sickle", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150147", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWxCy9/z1NHjEC2Mf42yLXbRnMHCjRLXHI8X/25ZhN12HzUtz82XD46H55EcGgatP5ZffUyoCcohgxNmd3+30mzM+UUNQnNueLaHMquD1HdXk", 
		"answer": "2565ZJjx0Bft9otiNV9t58I93QsSwoCP1bfULg==", 
		"explanation": "2565ZJjx0Bft9otgWxCy9/z1NHjEC2Mf43eCQeN1MGHxUerqb///2YdwKRyFjEJ+4DbSq6Tkt1ocz6tT6JyeczYGbIJ83NmK1uj73TFiO8dImY9+7Y4XdfcC0Pc7ke1NHiJ/mk2cKA/hiA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganeshwar", 
		"option_b": "Kot Diji", 
		"option_c": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_d": "Amri", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150148", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuyzO6/PmXfFGxRt3DDV613f3zzVbTRLuzyxJhiMxyIgVc7/XCGjqT49kEOnKBP+4/fdToAe5t7iMCIxfDkhH5Hc/BNnoFg5pIePPVOyH2Ge9rQIfAxjBfgks8EdkXAhUXdhMIDH0Q=", 
		"answer": "25+3eob2kRr/+5E1QBuwH+aZnwIg8eP0qRhTPdyV7A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dXjAAmwC42uLV+NxfmXqRqLWd63xz9dcJlSIn1po+mLUoumw8ksMg71f4ICYMDEMc44vycKM1ve3yHhKNoZyk4Rz9pgXfbRBwjntX9vVK/9gjCHOn08pdoDH8BWTuWQvO7s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Malwa culture", 
		"option_b": "Ganeshwar culture", 
		"option_c": "Jorwe culture", 
		"option_d": "Harappan culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150149", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhDt+YwmWx3zy+m/JmPZBXZRrHyAR7FmdXWjXamCa+zt3ZJjKRygg19y8zbWrLbkt0cHiuh44Y+Tcy0Pd59nwdPJx+z213QecYKQu7UokQiVbV2KFQxF/qg=", 
		"answer": "24GqaZ/g2A3j+ItgRhGyw+jzOSbWD2cVpHqHEqJzYnjgQavWe///xZ5iM0/Lc5XZUTxubPWxhl6Wm1rNSg==", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkQ3i8sUDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFRs3eCQaY0eX+jUabReujsx9dYKViAjBc75n7DsaCw4FIcz6kb+oaWdjZDaoR4ycKNxKT1wXJOPs9KncB08ZYTMfJMyTmqcdCbIfl8x22VK1HldTixDWNgh3HBg2he6Jez8Ge6UMwyzgFymYE4+cA5fN6N1qbT+EW5lQPAgokwEQQUZKAgdKKCZsA1yw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Urbanization", 
		"option_b": "Nomadic lifestyles", 
		"option_c": "Transition to full-fledged agriculturalists", 
		"option_d": "Establishment of trade routes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150150", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44AzEhf8hcr6Jn+QIWcfpH6PEqJmdTHrXaDKYuT5wYN0IxyAgxtv+nOGs7f/4VoLiqwb/YuHZH1BAnpSHIXeaE8Bx94RIyhaAw==", 
		"answer": "24W5ZpXmkSvr/YQyEjr6zP/2dWreByI8oneKQatwcX2heBs3+LEXwaEYr8trHzLBSQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1AH+t4glXAr7yvPsdVvRDWYE402CWKJmMFXrXaXLLuzwzddcJlSAnlN/83qGoraw/l4fgLpP6ICLMDEKao58iNmHl9Py12UBEcNKnYF+po7cj+F/6DAo2zrj6HZ3g5Q=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganeshwar and Kalibangan", 
		"option_b": "Amri and Kot Diji", 
		"option_c": "Pandu Rajar Dhibi and Mahishdal", 
		"option_d": "Navdatoli and Eran", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150151", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdfwJ3zVQ2EEr2uWQKY0c371UbXHaq3/xZp+NEjJjFd3snnA44jx/1IdjrtT/ZyeMB4NQoVdzdGa2OqthEVJNoZulZJl4docafhU2S+oNMPaM759x3qVJlH1Y3myCnxt1D7YymhercOp/CCzQJo1wRs51oh+rdw0OZevy6mF6V+5xhSLyn6DCvsvoWoLG4F1d9KLocoTV7M=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIFq3rDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuv/xYR0ZfW2VL4gqzdENcdDFQAnRXE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dW/ZByISrGmGQON1fHzsR7OCb+HyiZh3Z3GIhVpp82XOt7fxuxMNmrwb4JrfZyMQPphm3MWIw+HzhH5Pc9JMn8B+4ZwLPPZBwjbte9KbNPZrjl6SJlPxdTj9FnlikSOaynJZvMOv/SL7RtMwyAFwgQLUO79c8FVDyNFcaLnYUw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150152", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcRbzyf7wOWLEC2sS43yWXrdhYnTwFK7MLsTwzZ5wZ0uMn1478HfVpqGw+F1Pm6BeqZuMdWIMeMtsx8CZ0va3xX9Fc9VQlY53pJMSbPhFwTijYMebHPBSwFyFJlb/aWP9MHhx1BLei3BVp4+y4S+yV5onyBQhk8d85No5P8OTwOiV50G0iRGH2DuFQLgkM0aWu9Stq2KbpcIQtN+MoSLatPfsluzG4ttLZx5XrZ9oa16ukugA9moRX8y9aVD4pfPqm628SFT26mAJqh/g", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIFq3rDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuv/xYR0ZfW2VL4gqzdENcdDFQAnRXE=", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7x0PHrIHnVECIVqnvDR7d9fHj5UefBYf3uzIUxJlKNzUhv/XjD7+Xy4kdPm6Be8M6Zfy4PcZxqzJCd3+G35mNOPdxB2qF14do3feZB3C2sNNfOLOp73GvAKEv8fnm0CjBnhDTVg3pfq8Or9DWvR5o4xlUbmINx7IR8MtiLma2F7V+hkQ6Hzn7T1Ir1xn4Vax14a4QGp8Lcaw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150153", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYRvkwO/+OSvzC2MdoHCPW7d8eXKjR67Wa/6+3pJjIhyPgk519jbPreXd9lsOnalI4ZqNcWI/cLdh+tWIxOv5njF1O8MEiYlm4YlfdfoA4TyldcbaM/Z63G/AMEDiYnmuDWRhlSXTjjxfpsO9+Si0UJonzBQ7mJQ4/sExNduey+iH5w2sjgPC9HqDSa10EFqK972VLlAE7mnGQLYq2IB869Y=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIFq3rDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuv/xYR0ZfW2VL4gqzdENcdDFQAnRXE=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRTr+ZxgcRbzyf7wOWLEC2sS42yKRqZnMGbmRqKCZ+P6zJJ1Z1CGjlpv93KGqquw2lIHjrpa+oaLYiNPPp9nzcnJwOHlwTFIPYZXn417qZsNdfAAzS+odcebLfF92mKZZ0r+JzuvC2d62TPai39d6JC0/Cv3FNQ41FU0moh36YgsMNaW17vT5ESzg0aW1H7RYLx2EESJtMC7qXe9egH6tDS2gJfDWMswA+0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150154", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeNkdX7zWKKCYeu+6J9wNRyFhE1+9jbPreXj41wBiuhT5puMdTFDQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBANJLlIUy85sMPPUAzzWodcSbIfBqjmuBNEz8fnm8EnF9mDDUhnkWuoao+jKpV993yRtyt495/4q8ae18Y24HpNsEKEJNhpBg", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIFq3rDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuv/xYR0ZfW2VL4gqzdENcdDFQAnRXE=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFRs3qMQq9xMH7lFIbKb/++wJl1IlmNzVdy5HPC46z+t0AbgKZeqYaQZTEGbccv3NiMxeG3zWIBPckEnolg4ZkLPPlFwimke9qbL/gu3XqPKUCwZTy0Cnc0lXHVgnlXuMOp8DS0Qcg0xVU7mMdZ5ckufjwheaO4mALxOUZ8RG+BjcI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150155", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gexCywPzsIW7CDSI4rXuKU+80ZHnmFITKb+H9xpt4M1SAjhtr93nWr6Cw/1ILz6kb7YeaZGIAcYV8wcOd3urwhH5Hc8BNiYgy5ZQbPOZJzzjtSNrnLsxrz32PKR+wQTCuDDB8mz7dmTxBrZG+tSG0QdQzgBw81qVx5ckufNaR3eik7V6sxiSH0nyQRP+G6cY8XrDmvbjIdRMoGI+C", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddDIl2aglU7+2WGt631t1AAnbpe6prfdToTcophycSA2Oq3y3cBEtVXn5Jm7ZURPpj8mlgY8S9+7q+6nUJOO0w=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/M2LDCyIZrHCIQeN9fjHmVbTWa//wiYV0IFWGg0g74WPWs6ri40BPm6BeqYieczZDaoNu3JCP3vf/hGZAIIZF2pBz9o5fc/IA2DWofcabJPdr2i6BK0r+YHmqDWR81CPfiXkU81nyH6GakzCRMY/MQqSsFw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150156", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdh/7yPz9NG+QCnFRpX6OXbZnMHfsRufWZui+25JyKEqMn0I7/XCGobf/+UkKz69U5oqMMB4NQoVdzdGa2OqthFVAOstFmIF2pI0eb7RJwjuhYdHVI/tqjmyZZ1H4YnmVBWJ1hCHXhDxVvY+v4DW+Fqwei7HfP54g5fSox3b6+dQ=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddDIl2aglU7+2WGt631t1AAnbpe6prfdToTcophycSA2Oq3y3cBEtVXn5Jm7ZURPpj8mlgY8S9+7q+6nUJOO0w=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w739J2TeGWdRpHCMVrA0cWWjcKbLY+z8yJM9Z12HiRtv+nOGqqv2+0YKgateqYGZMDYLe8tHycKIx/T2yjFCJspQj5J3qNoMafNHyS65NNWbI/FgwGuDM0z/aXm/AWRjkTTYymhercOv4ij5Pbf3Ag1cSBU0wrkCneYycg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150157", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdb+LGrEC2NRoGqPRrZmdTHmTK7Reuj6iYN+MF2biUg75n7D46D+8xMAiehP4YvfWCMRf5t/yd7J1PH70GRTNoZ4lLx81p8eb/tOln2ZfNGbC/93z3qIJgXzcjWpEWJx1DnXjjxUp5eztTepUZcfwQczhpd544g5MNKS3KaH+w25iALCz3OeX7hgUXyYp8+4+0KS4Is2s8GYtDzY8bZCViFZcnmUXdcJxJ8Cphi2", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddDIl2aglU7+2WGt631t1AAnbpe6prfdToTcophycSA2Oq3y3cBEtVXn5Jm7ZURPpj8mlgY8S9+7q+6nUJOO0w=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHY0ADr440hEh3nyenqJ26QBnoYsGuGVuN1Yn72WqOCeuX7iZN0JFCAg147/XCGt631t3sOnalL+Y+RMCEWcp962tXJ1urzhGJJPNFHm5N34Nodc+BIjC2/cZnzIexv3n6BKQXxaT39LHFmlSHGi3IWoY29+TK+Wtky01fO6aBM0iZypuCb4kOURct5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150158", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeNndWX3WKLPa+Pq2td+IRydhV47xH/Ip63p9hMdiq9S5oDfcSwHPrxq28TJ9eH5w3BNc9FBiIUy6pULPOZFwDy5cdCbNPEu2maFZ23xdTitFHF61DLDhmhDuob7ySmHWugywQY9mN042cA5fP+ey6mD+Ey2xgWX0G+EWrgkBlWK9dyt+FeOqYEssMnNvjzX7bTtlbjH+NtLSwZWqpU/VVqwm60QuvkccFIaM12FQoW29YFyXoQ=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIFq3rDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuv/xYR0ZfW2VL4gqzdENcdDFQAnRXE=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFRsHqXRq9xfXTtQLSCYeu+3Z90Z2qAg19z63eGsaD3/lwBz6lV7c6odTEXPqlqxteI26TgwWNEc89KnoVi4ZQbefpUjDKrNMDTJb5Gz3yBN1XxaXm0CnZ4gTTYiXka6IqvtS6oFNQ41FUzlYRt/8koOZeL1uiA6VT4kg6HnFOQWrx0AVWX9c2951eJsod4osye8SDe5+Drk/vH9dpLcQdeuopmI0+z17wB/WoRX8yhe1J98OjcZE2vx3bJPJRjZNnpYUbuHBtuGQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150159", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdD+OXzRQ2EEr2uWQKY0eWKjV6jMfeT6zIV0IxyHglU22nfUorXg9l1Pva1a+oGRKmIuf4d4yZCKwujj0WNEc9FFicB27Ykcc+JF3jipNN3VYNBv2GqBM0r8bnX9IWJ1mn2Wi3JS6K268iO6FNsx1BAg1pNw6Ig4OdST0KaWqEK+xhKK2Tu5Sa9lAUSYu46r/k+ItZA992P3PbMug/UTZWFbnui36/Y=", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6dWnFFyIFq3rDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuv/xYR0ZfW2VL4gqzdENcdDFQAnRXE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe0BX99sUjRxLm0O/6dWLDQ2sfp3qGVuN3f3/wXaPHfOj6iZl+KRGhjEl64mbHremw9UYbz6ZU/c6ddSECa5hqiN+Pl+3j1zFFOtVHlZZ39oNfaP1NyTGketGbCep9jm2IJlfxZC24FnlngDjVmTxbqYi+tS6vFN4+0wE7mIRsrc4uM9rf8amB6V2ohwjC1XWXRKhhH1ecpoySRjkELdON99S5ThySOhaR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and Reason is the correct explanation of Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is true but the Reason is false", 
		"option_c": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150160", 
		"question": "24GwbdH12Av548UtVwrzyb3qJm7UQ2MF42uLV+NxfnWjW6GCeuX7ibl0KFCAmVNy8TbWprf5+FdPmKlIqbGgTx08QbRQirLccOMH407LC6XZRe3URd8=", 
		"answer": "27a3eIH2w1u6yfE2W4p9AG5ii0nbrDlU", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHnwxjk5Iw0WxH8hfvtOmaQF2oU41GGXa99ZHnqV+fWYa3qwZIxBFSIgVh0/n/Sq6zzt0MHjrteqYeRZi0PaI5riMSB0qTxzWNSJ4ZRiYUy65xff/tQ3Di/NpgkPdIK0GKBOhljbuMJorI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "co,pp,er,zi,nc", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150161", 
		"question": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7hzOn6JivZDSI8oneCQKJneGXxVefVa//7iYNoN1WKjFd36zbKrKbx41YLz6FVqY+NdSMQPpxm3NjJ6NvI+05+DPkEiY976NiW3od34GtORmcSDvYVSgQb", 
		"answer": "27eqZ4b9ohvm9oYrEBGExF9bUHrjWMTtC/14KQ4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2A3v5MUpXF7fxPX+J2rDC3YDoj+UV7FxMHXmR6TQZ+/7zddwNByLiFJ19TbPreXx5VYOnOhM4JqXMCARcZxhhdKF1uf8hGJOOsoGr7yLuiVR3yLwCGn0jumNZw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "br,ow,nâ€“b,la,ck", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150162", 
		"question": "25y2KIL8xA3i8oQzRhvgy73NNGHREHYZonHPEqx6dTHsUufWZui+zI9yJkqImV5/slXOoqnz+F8Gm6BS6s6MeTYGbct4ycPJ6NvI+05+DPkGX2ww8wuGjUfYPFZGF1uC+A==", 
		"answer": "27SwaYOxLqQdVFqYY753oDmBC54hMA==", 
		"explanation": "25SwaYOz2Aqq+IslEhH0hen3MCvdBmwFqnCNV6c0Y3j3UbSCeuX/3ddmIk6MzV5j8XfQorH18xMGgehI5puLeCcCbZ9q2t7J5eX9xWJVO8dK2PIgChmsBnhIXVRZf2Gi5bI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "ah,ar,ag", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150163", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj3g3+8pc5Eh3zyfH6MSvSD2MSqDKCXKc5YnTnFLDDfa3u25JnJlCMg0879GTJruX+8lIdg7Eb1rGgTx08QbQvx96e1vbz1zMDGLPggPBvCP1TDaMzh32R", 
		"answer": "2+foOMGz8zqoAYqZZKQ34D27Qf/y9WxlNw==", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZL4nBjk88gyVxqy1fLrIW7CGiIYsD+HV7B3YnjhUaOCb/6+y5J4KVvJnUl+5HfKpqvkt1UdgKUb6JyQZSwHPtk/mIDJ9ce1TaZVWjliLgWVB3fTyczdgg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1500 BC", 
		"option_b": "2100 BC", 
		"option_c": "2000 BC", 
		"option_d": "1700 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150164", 
		"question": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dWTHBmZRrmqAWuNgfzH3XKKCUdLB9qhOGGPJjk535mPUpueO/+/uFJKCMCDoBb4JanpP", 
		"answer": "27i5ZIbyk4Kc5MDj3k3gd947Sb9QInQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dWPRByICqniNW6V9c3DtQOfBYePwzJRlLlOHnhts+2LO47H48hMijqRM6M6cZS4Xa5lqitYBjF8oaZ1tHnZyY77TR+8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "mal,wa,va", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150165", 
		"question": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U42+RXadhc3TnFLDKa+zqhddjLl+MwRt6/HKGoqH0/kcGgKZa5YKGMCEWcp9m3tGd0uC3+05+DPl7pb8wiZdZDKkWbXJLyq7OUAJbGQ==", 
		"answer": "27e5YoPyk0VpoBUB25YlUbaYh8uvb/U=", 
		"explanation": "25e5YoPykQ7r5MUhXxH8wr3rPW6QEHYQs3OGEqBmf2HwFKTXYvn335ZlIljJj0I75n7D44b49l8MgKRS/YaWc2ITe4R/xNXLEkwDJkLL0MzcJYeJFx/bkA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "baj,ra", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150166", 
		"question": "24GwbdH/0Avt8pY0EjT91+r6dXjZF2dRp3aQUaxidWPmUOfRYa34yIUxLk/JsmREzUn5nJqyVVeMlYbRL4ewp0ZswH3YWQ==", 
		"answer": "27G5YZzy0xjutaDBKkc6mg1oG6Fun3MUxy8=", 
		"explanation": "25G5YZzy0xjut4wzEgr6wL3zNHnXBnEF43SNXbR6MGLqQKKCYeu+3Z90Z3aGn0x+snXTr7Hl5VZNrgzyu89maCmO6CuulSb1uQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "da,im,ab,ad", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150167", 
		"question": "25y2KLj90BTt9oouHl720O/2O2yQF2oU43qCQK99dWOjRK/DfeiyiZtwNVuMzVZu9jbOrLDj8kBPmKFP4c6gTx08QbRQ95CB1vLyhHNENsgEnolh55UJeeZFyH8UUW2e+mhsose+1pUgLAZM", 
		"answer": "27qubZ/gk1lq4wMA/EfIHaIir2t/zmk=", 
		"explanation": "25qubZ/gkQ7v5YBgVhfhxvLpMHnVByIYrT+XWqY0fWTnFK/Ne/772td+IRygg1p29XfJreX04kEGga8b/YaaMCcCbIdmzcLJ9Oz2yHJOP89QkolxpIoXfedFjmujgBlxL4LtostzzFbIbVA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "ove,ns", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150168", 
		"question": "24G9eoPy0hb+44RgVBf10O/6JivfBSIGrHKGXONnZXbkUbTWLvn2yIMxM1SMzXhz83rFrKn541sGjOhL7IGPfCdDaI5hzcKIw+HzhGVJNoZ7pb9N26UgQ7RHwzmpccfIYjf0BQJig2BFP3+TA0FAdJ8=", 
		"answer": "27i3fJn2w1uCLrlLBrJ5+FmROg+xn0A7", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Av49oYvRgrzhfv2Mn7CBnFRrHnDRax5dX+jXanGZ+7/3ZIxMVmHiEl65n/JreX/8RMbh60b5IGLeCcRPoxgzNSMxPe1opoeJE9t3uJNsABcOdX8Uw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "mo,th,er,ma,id", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150169", 
		"question": "24GwbdHwwxjs45YtVxCyzPO/HGXRDmUQrHHDXqpidXWjW6mCeuX7iahOGGO2smREsnDUqqv38kBPgK4b/YaaMDEGap9jzd2M2fC1QW0DEIDwGu9YbashDx1HCA==", 
		"answer": "26K9e4X2wxeonl4e+sGddg33Z9tTa9Dy3A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHwwxjs45YtVxCy0vjtMCvDCnYEomuGVuN7fjH3XKKCeejt3ZJjKRyMiVx+4TbJpeXZ+VICiKlU58zl1MM2WnfTfxz0aK5aLRc+", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "wes,te,rn,nor,th,en", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150170", 
		"question": "24GwbdHU0Bfv5I03UwyywfjvOnjZF3FRom2GEqJnc2PqVqLGLvnxiYN5IhyZiEly/XKGnJrPyGwwsJcZe9x7UVR8UYPV52JppISUsw==", 
		"answer": "2+fgOMGAg0u6p8UCcVwfXRDL4T6dq48zQM6N7xOO", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cUkVw791vTrJivREWdRqnuGXLd9dnjmUOfEfOLziYN5IhydhFZ+snDUoqj1t1wJz/oDud7SInBTLstN65zJx/byiXVAJ89KncBm7J9fcfVU2S+oNPzaMv9+3m+OZ0blay2oFnU2fWRguB/Yhsi8hlyR8SzpIw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "2500â€“2000 BC", 
		"option_b": "2800â€“2200 BC", 
		"option_c": "2300â€“1900 BC", 
		"option_d": "2700â€“2300 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150171", 
		"question": "24qHV67M7ibVt5IhQV7zhe3tPGXTCnIQrz+AQKJyZDHsUufWZui+7pZ/Ik+BmlppsmbDrLX88hFm0zsndXr1ODdAz36qyRDi", 
		"answer": "27i5ZoT10Br+4pclEhH0hf7wJXvVESIeoXWGUbdnMhoktpO+n2rOXU7O/nnAsMk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU0Bfv5I03Uwyy1fjwJWfVQ3UUsXrDQqJmZHjgQavDfOHniYR6LlCFiF87+3iGoLfx8UcGga8b5oyVdSEXbctp2t+El+f41GFEIYTuN6diOmyLjqVjbWJ+PTBR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "pottery making", 
		"option_b": "textile weaving", 
		"option_c": "manufacture of copper objects", 
		"option_d": "wood carving", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150172", 
		"question": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dXjAAmwfpnvDVLF7fTHca5j9UdLB9tVbCH3l9rQgrMWJBg0gszyw", 
		"answer": "2+TsOMGAhkm6t6cDEHZZ+WAaR6Sm3yxVBOvrOfI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHZ3gv98sUjRxLm0O/6dWLDQ3AUoHCEXKpudXWjQKiCZuzozNd9Jk+diF879GTJruWhowNfwv8Luc69U2AXL6oPLzAuc3gqhiolpKCa", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1300â€“800 BC", 
		"option_b": "1400â€“700 BC", 
		"option_c": "1500â€“750 BC", 
		"option_d": "1200â€“600 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150173", 
		"question": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/N2fRAGlconGHH7FxdDH0VbXHLu7xx4N4KUmMiRty/GLJ46355EcAnaFY6ILfZCsOe5gv3NmF26TjzHQBDPl7pb9N26Vdt32Pka3rTJDFJhTufNI9JA==", 
		"answer": "26a9a5791Vnp8os0Rwzrhd/cd5t2LL+WJTfYNTm2h5qzqTI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/N2fRAGlconGHH7FxdDH0VbXHLv3724R4NEiMiRtv+3rK47H48hMciqtU54rfcycNap590ZCr9KZkhPSfpetJC2habZUdLsNw", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fourth century AD", 
		"option_b": "first century AD", 
		"option_c": "second century BC", 
		"option_d": "fifth century BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150174", 
		"question": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7x0PHrIHnVECIYrT+AV61gYnDvFKbMaq3pzIRlIk6HzXJ19n/H46H55FIfn61a+4ubMCAaPrRQ9++26NvIhH5Tc9JMn5J35ZgQaeACS12CC/gWowb4ou2qFJeNDQ==", 
		"answer": "2+TqOMGz8zqoKdZN/5lSHfqKeQ1RsMQrGQ==", 
		"explanation": "25SqZ4T91Vm7pdVwEjzRib3rPW6QIGoQr3yMXqpgeHjgFKTXYvnr25JiZ1WHzVh+/GLUoqmw9l0Lz79e+pqaYixDV4VrwdHJ1eHwxX8BJ8kEjYF84dgxwm+/Ti3QTmhhJ8RtDXFr", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1300 BC", 
		"option_b": "1100 BC", 
		"option_c": "1000 BC", 
		"option_d": "1200 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150175", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUjRxLm0O/6enjZF2dRtHaXWuN9ZGKjUKLRbf/32YN4KFLTz95nHJ2rtdPW4KGvfrg5NOI=", 
		"answer": "25+3eob2kVTJ+JMlQBv2hfzzOGTDFyIQr3PDXaU0XXDrVbXDfeXq25Y9BlSInxs23nnForH18xMGgehP4YvfdDAaPpFgxtWal+vxhGVJNoZmm45z99oJffhMySThV9zaLP1hwmeUL0zzJym4C2B4kXGbv29TrMOo4Si1UZo2zhFylYho/c0ufNid062Q/F76t1fEPk7qqcbRYNvhlLYs5g==", 
		"explanation": "25+3eob2kVSq1Io2Vwz3wb3+OWbfEHZRonOPEqxyMFziXKbQb/723YVwG1KohVppsjuGj6rz9kcKi+hS586LeCdDepl2iMqG2eHkhH5Hc9JMn8BQ5ZQeb7RWzTGhcc3nLt1mz2KDKEn5czG0BzBkkT7GhnkW5cOO5iK/FMkjzxs31oZ26Yg/M8eP3LrT50+ygwWWzzlo0R6ZrGYT2Ei3642ndsr7", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Jorwe,Covered almost all of Maharashtra", 
		"option_b": "Ahar,Located in the dry zones of the Banas valley", 
		"option_c": "Chalcolithic people,Used stone and copper objects", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150176", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUsXR3z0fTwOyvHCnYZ42uLV+NnYHTgXaHLba36wIRyKEqMn0IhsGUfv524KMS9ajUDoxORNoE=", 
		"answer": "25G5YZzy0xjut8hgcAz9y+f6dWzfDGYC71aNU65zcX7tFOrve+m+wZhkNFmazUxy5n6GrLP1+UBDqqlI/YuNfmIqcI9myZDE8e3kzDFJPMlPicJ9pLBG1h1dT/lF/N6J7LJ6", 
		"explanation": "25G5YZzy0xjut8hgcAz9y+f6dWzfDGYCn3GqXKJ5d3DsWuePLsDrzdd5KEmaiEg75X/Sq+X/4VYBnJRVzI+MZCcRcMtGxtSA1qS6hFdIIM4Eko9974ldtOc5FYtO1gsWpHHEYkqcbQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Daimabad,Bronze goods", 
		"option_b": "Inamgaon,Mud houses with ovens", 
		"option_c": "Eastern India,Fish hooks", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150177", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUjRxLm0O/6JivHCnYZ42uLV6pmMHDwR6jBZ+zqzJMxNVmOhFR14SyEwntQ+jXV5+i28cM4FguLMg==", 
		"answer": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cVtEizzz/zsIWPRDS47rG2UV+M5MFziXKbQb/723YVwa3GIgUx6sjvjsaT+tYJVc1vigvNk0QQMzM794yI=", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cVtEizzz/zsIWPRDV4fiXCRRaY0PTHOVa/DfOztwYNjJmCHoFp35XeG7uXe9kULjrxU5YfTMAcRf4UjiP6I0OD2htVZSEHnjwVug5lLbusauEA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganeshwar,Rajasthan", 
		"option_b": "Jorwe,Maharashtra", 
		"option_c": "Malwa,Eran", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150178", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwVwz7yvm/ImLECyIFq3rDQKZnYHTgQK7Ua63dwZZ9JFOFhE9z+3WGoLD840YdivIZyrfkrPGRjkvXy/+I0gCNxg==", 
		"answer": "2565cZDn2RiqusVxBU6ihenwdTqCUzJRgVzPEol7YmbmFOqCP7mumddlKBze3Qs70FWK44jx+0QOz+Ubu97PIGIXccs+kIDZl8bUhudoMbA/nVgLBder63Y9xR8=", 
		"explanation": "2565cZDn2RiqusVxBU6itqytZTuQIUEtrVWMQLRxMDyjBfOSPp6pmccxBX+1g3Z6/mHH4+iwpQNf39sKsd7PMAAgPAPn9ObML+JukL8dirRJ8Hg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Kayatha,1700 to 1200 BC", 
		"option_b": "Jorwe,1400 to 700 BC", 
		"option_c": "Malwa,2000 to 1800 BC", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150179", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUjRxLm0O/6JivEDCIFq3qKQON3eHDxVaTWa//32oN4JE/TzwNnKijGpxPGSFnLT3whtqs=", 
		"answer": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cVtfx/80Pv+Nn/FEWdRrHnDUaxkYHTxFKjAZOj93YQ9Z3SIn1pr4nfI4+jF5VEOgehY4JiWfCsZf59mx97Fl8741mZEc4thlIN96Yoeb+dF332AddzaMv99xnqSJgd7nHKIjlx0jwDcaS+/A/Em", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpTg2Q7r5cVtEjPzy+j5NGjEFnAU43CFEqB7YGHmRufNbOf7yoNiG1KhjEl64mbHreW9t2YdjalVqY2WZisPd5Fu3NmG2dj57n5TJMME18BX6pkQceRB3y6oZ5T2IfZv3G+TL1HiZnsXPgqnJpG7YHe8IR1/gGpr", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Chalcolithic Settlements", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ganeshwar,Manufacture of copper objects", 
		"option_b": "Harappan,Urban civilization", 
		"option_c": "Jorwe,Encompasses Maharashtra", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160101", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7v5YBgRhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeN3f3zuQanLeuT72td3Lk6amRt9/WPIp6D0qBFXAAxrRs1oMrxuL6CA+6QH", 
		"answer": "26W9Zpj9wgzm9pdgexD2zPy9/gnArT7OeV8uX4+my3hjrA==", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7xyvDyIGXZF2sUsD+FW7FnZDHmR7PDbOH32p90IxyAgxtr93jPrbbl+1Idz4FV7YeeMraIp4D2belJLemJOLwTPiM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "peninsular India", 
		"option_b": "northern India", 
		"option_c": "eastern India", 
		"option_d": "western India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7iyunrMHnJQ3UQsD+FW7FnZDH2R6LGLu/niYN5IhyqhVp38XnKqrH4/lBPjL1X/ZuNdTFcPMygl1DqAY+TkgwplnDLatI=", 
		"answer": "26W5YZ/n1B2q54o0Rhvg3L8fPPfwludc6TdmyY7lwnCr", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7x0PHrIHnVECIGpm2GErd8dTHlXbXReq3qxtdkNFnJnVpy/GLDp+Xg+EcbirpCqxLqFs6XpDmgiw4ICIqCdO8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "clay pottery", 
		"option_b": "metal pottery", 
		"option_c": "glass pottery", 
		"option_d": "painted pottery", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2hDk88UvVF7w0O/2NGeQCnFRoHCOX6x6MHjtFLDHffn725kxDlKNhFoksH9ojrn3imaDtNspT0tdiwk=", 
		"answer": "27CgfJT91Rzut4c1QBfzyb8zARiQcPzDorZV/0OtRyOZ", 
		"explanation": "24K9e4X2wxeq3oskWx+y1e/2OGrCCm4I42+RU6BgeXLmUOfHdvn7x5N0IxyLmEly83qEUG0OTpli/TCIykhS2up8eQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fractional burial", 
		"option_b": "vertical burial", 
		"option_c": "extended burial", 
		"option_d": "cremation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrv5YAhXl7lxO6/JXnZDmMDqnOaEqBhfGXqQqbWa+m+wJkxMFmamV5p/DbvraH59hMLmrpS54nfZCoGPqhnydyK2Oj+0HlIMIZUkoFh4cVdG2U5pI8ItQ/FZXNdguAbJA==", 
		"answer": "27e5ep32yFuXh65/7EKiwEAGwo06vRGj", 
		"explanation": "25e5ep32yFn99pZgU17i1/TyNHnJQ2EUsXqCXuN3ZX33XbHDeuj6iZ5/Z0uMnk9+4HiGiqv0/lJPi71J4ICYMDYLd5gv2NiIxOG19YhmBjDg3IIOtw5z01n/sg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "rice", 
		"option_b": "barley", 
		"option_c": "maize", 
		"option_d": "oats", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160105", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuy1fLrJivFEGcV43mMQON2aTH3XKKCTeX/xZR+K1WdhVJ4smbDrLX88gxN7ZyPtpBgRQO2/TiO15F28A==", 
		"answer": "27a3Z5r63x6mt4AhRhf8wrG/MXnZDWkYrXjPEqJ6dDHwQKjQb+r7i26gvf/TA2mp63ZlgPdZneM=", 
		"explanation": "24W3fIKzxhz48sU1QRv2hfvwJyvGAnAYrGqQEqd7fXTwQK7BLv3r24d+NFmazVJ18XrTp6z+8BMMgKdQ4ICYPGIGf59mxtfFl+DlzX9KOshD1sBz6p5fb+BP3jyqcZb2PPpS1fRUFDOab6pOOL5M", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "decoration", 
		"option_b": "musical instruments", 
		"option_c": "cooking, eating, drinking, and storage", 
		"option_d": "religious rituals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1xbl88UlXhv/wPPrdXzRECICqniNW6V9c3DtQOfLYK3qwZIxI1WMmRt09DbDorbk8kEBz4FV7YeeL2AQCGtffWc2+0p+2vCBMapq", 
		"answer": "27Oxe5mz0Bfut5cpURuwc+BsDhZhOnV0Bj2KVHgAvw==", 
		"explanation": "25Oxe5mz0Bfut5cpURuy0vjtMCvGCnYQrz+GXqZ5dX/3R+fLYK37yIRlIk6HzXJ19n/H5Law81oKm+pL3LvL0hGtmUgUV4k+GZBJ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "barley and wheat", 
		"option_b": "fish and rice", 
		"option_c": "maize and potatoes", 
		"option_d": "oats and millets", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160107", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg1A3++4AtVxDm1r3+ISv7AnsQt3eCEqJ6dDHGRqbMLuTwibpBZ0uMn14ksPuZOGo7xIvab8/I6X9VLak=", 
		"answer": "27O3eoX61xDv88cw6vUI91iw1SK2r3+HCVWS", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQrv45EsVxP3y+nsdXzVEWdRpXCRRqpyeXTnGOfLYOn3ypZlLlKOzUh0/3OGr6Dm8l9PgK4b7YuZdSwQe8tg2pCZxevjwXJVOslK2PI+8R1ycAU4eG7OwHR3Ew0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "made of wood", 
		"option_b": "on hills", 
		"option_c": "fortified", 
		"option_d": "near lakes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160108", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7v5YBgcRbzyf7wOWLEC2sS42yKRqZnMHLsWarNYOHniZF+MlKNzVJ1smLOpuX9/ldCqKlV7ouLeSFDbI5owd+HiKb6lf3DSSpfNPDezyk38GEg", 
		"answer": "27u9aYOz0Fnm9o4lEhHghfy/J2LGBnBRoHCNVK9hdX/gUeWTHmu7CcVD0CihNRyfJOdc", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQrj44AzEhH00fjxdWTTAHcDsXqHEq1xcWOjWKbJa/6+xoUxJFOHi1du93jFpraw+FVPnaFN7JyMMqVs9H+ghU+qWFW0gUImPNg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "in dense forests", 
		"option_b": "on mountain tops", 
		"option_c": "in desert regions", 
		"option_d": "near a lake or a river confluence", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160109", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiy1fLrIW7CGiIGomzDR7BxdDHhTefDYuDx2oMxJlCFzXhz83rFrKn541sGjOhY5oOSZSwKaoJq24/LTbQbvNPhYfuwkVDdzyXyBg==", 
		"answer": "26KwbZT/nA3/5YslVl7wyfz8PibRDWZcsXqHErN7ZGKhm78DIUwqW2FxfrznyNoZxw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz0hbn+oouXgey0O76MSvHC2cUrzKXR7F6dXWjVqvDbeazyJl1ak6MiRtr/WLV4Q/z5JEnwct9XUUeYOM7j7I=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "painted blue pots", 
		"option_b": "wheel-turned black-and-red pots", 
		"option_c": "handmade yellow pots", 
		"option_d": "metal pots", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQni9pYlEhr9wO6/IWPVQ0wUrHOKRqt9czHzXKbRa633x9diKEmdhRtS/HLPouX29lcKz6FV/YHAMt3qof9zi5ltFYD3aCaKeoU=", 
		"answer": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUVxxmsYDLCY+qtrDEKSn/Har", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIL8xA3it6wuVhfzib3rPW6QLWcer3aXWqp3MGHrVbTHLuTz2ZJjJFmZmVJ5/m+GpaT08ldPhqZP5s6LeCdDXYNuxNOG2+3jzHhCcYovlwwRY+EOTdD3aSPGtiI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mesolithic", 
		"option_b": "Bronze Age", 
		"option_c": "Chalcolithic", 
		"option_d": "Iron Age", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160111", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7v5YBgRhb3hfj+J2fZBnEF41yLU693f33qQK/Lba3tzINlK1mEiFVv4SmEWBqYCwOSlurro1VeCIJueA==", 
		"answer": "25i5ZIbykRjk88UjVxDm1/zzdULeB2sQ4bedSqhWb4tJCYfoLQGMZd4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDQaZgZH3mWaLMev6+3pJjIhyAgxtW83rRouXx+VdPjK1V/ZyefGIqcI9myZJIjH8r4/TNRb8CgIweZd02", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "eastern India", 
		"option_b": "northern India", 
		"option_c": "southern India", 
		"option_d": "Malwa and central India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160112", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuy1/jyNGLeECIepT+QRrFhc2X2RqLRLuTwibR5Lk6Ig18783jC45Xx+Vcaz5pa44+NMAYLd4lmiNmH0+30xWVIJcMElYYtpinRAlX7nSmOozP+xuLAV1U=", 
		"answer": "26W3e4W+2Rbm8pZgUxD2he/wIGXUQ2oetmyGQeGYuskxvY2uPln93jcgw1eb", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQvv+oQpXA2yzPP7PGjRF2cV42uLV+NkYnTwUanBa63xz9dhKE+dwFN0/nPV46T+8xMdgL1V7c6XfzcQe5gtYUFmAgM2kTbmEZdjMc53tA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fortifications", 
		"option_b": "square houses", 
		"option_c": "temples", 
		"option_d": "post-holes and round houses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160113", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4RgQRf1y/T5PGjRDXZRoHCOQqx6dX/3FKjELvn2zNd1LlmdzVJ1smHDsLH15V1PpqZf4I/AMi9R3KkELr3zKJ1ohjJ4srU=", 
		"answer": "27S2YZzy3Vns+IokEBB5Y46u3fs5k6VMoRIsgdc=", 
		"explanation": "25i3epSz0Bfj+oQsEhj9yvm/ImrDQ2EerWyWX6ZwMHjtFLDHffn725kxDlKNhFo5EXoHp3a+FYCsqZEKfau7oA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fruits", 
		"option_b": "animal food", 
		"option_c": "dairy", 
		"option_d": "vegetables", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160114", 
		"question": "25y2KLzy2Rj49pYoRgzzib32OyvHC2sSqz+TXbB9ZHjsWufVb/6+3Z90Z1iMjF878HnCuuXg+1IMiqwb7ZuNeSwEPol62tmI27u1YR+4lzZGKuasWHLeeE/M5g==", 
		"answer": "27u3eoX7nArl4pEoEFvBJujRzJtZaZ9ajbyg/XA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH31Bjut4cvVgeyzPO/GGrYAnAQsHeXQKI0Z3DwFLfOb+77zdd4KRydhV47/HnUt6295Fwam6Ab+YGMeTYKcYUtg/1YV6/ieHmBjXNa01QKOw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "east-west", 
		"option_b": "diagonal", 
		"option_c": "north-south", 
		"option_d": "vertical", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ39+MU1Rhv81vTzJivHBnAU42qQV6c0cmijQK/HLs72yJtyKFCAmVNy8TbWpqrg+1ZQzSDTEN1yqBApoJV/ojXm2lw=", 
		"answer": "27m3fJCz0Bfut5EoUxL7h3th81k89VbxIP1EOo0QlDg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxArv88UiXQr6hen3MCvcDHYQ436NVuNgeHDvXefEYf++3Z90Lk7JiVpy/m+Gs7Di51wcirsZ75yLwXJIEV3lKWy74PaYsQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "pan and bowl", 
		"option_b": "cup and plate", 
		"option_c": "jar and spoon", 
		"option_d": "lota and thali", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160116", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcRbzyf7wOWLEC2sS43yMX65hfnj3XaLRLvr725IxN06AgFpp+3rf47P18FYbjrpS6IDfTCw/cLlqycOG2b638HlEKoZHj4xm7YweaPFEjD+sZtjeObIu2WaFJlG8JzW4CmR9mH2Wi3JS6JGy9iL54+1BJTyK8kokeorW0B5aZQ==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV77y/7wJ3nVAHZd402GU7B7fjHqR+fBYf/szJRlZb/i+eTz9MDk+ipr/YebRWA=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFRoHCOX7Z6eWXqUbSCbfjy3Z5nJkiMiRtt82TPrLDjt1AKna1a5Z3TMDYLe5Ivydya2KT0y39SJstBnsB865RSavFHySmsZt3aLr5owWGEawX1dCm4B3l1mD3PynVY6JS+5jO+RtR36Rs2n4Y62ujO18BD1+P664UZYh37EQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is incorrect, Reason is correct", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160117", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeNkeHDwUefLYK3txoJlLxygg19y8zbRoraw81ocm6FV6prfdjAMc8t7wNXJ+eH4yHhVO89H2pB65YkaPMhO8DOfcdXIL/A0jkeOZ1b/ci21RFl6kDjXxjxCoIb72yK0WNMjyBwx1pdw7Ns5fN6Sya2B60iokg+A0GLRTrxgFFDZvMC85AOIqId4lsWMvTHU+P3tkvHQss071+1aP98HPgbxo5RoNGs=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/M2rcEGdTMGpJFXhmL/SRcvUWGeF7zw==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIL8xA3it6wuVhfzib3rPW6QLWcer3aXWqp3MGHrVbTHLursyJNkJlCFlBtv4HfIsKzk/lwBiqwb4ICLf2IXdo4v69iI2+f4yHhVO89H1sB/5ZEWcvMA2DWoeZTSLupr3HqXLkv1Y3uVuRy6Jjd/XJkPrc9IL5/q", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "Both A and R are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160118", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeN3f3zuQanLeuT72td3KEmHiV5/snXPt6z15BMzgZRV24ueYy0NJMtbwNWQl+Hk0HBDP89XkoV2pI4XebRGxS++YJTXIexpyy6WLkn8Zj64FzB9mnHGj3JfppCu+SapFPM5xBwz1I1VVVLIATvFjjiBbg7SYak=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBi5RoWqXEpE0eWKjWqjWLvn2zNdyKE6biFhvsnPes6nx+VIbhqdVqYGZMANBVpDr8DG+r/xFqySp39Hq+g==", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7xyvDyIGXZF2sUsD+GQbd1cn3qR6/Haq3yyIV2IhyfhFd383HDsOXy4kdPgadPqY2WZCsGbctbwNXJ0vfjxXNNOtVMl4V88NoQerRMzS+qcZTNKfJiz2mFNAX0aDyuCjdg1DTHn31CrcOv+me4Xc4ugBM9g4l85MY7fhkOy+Ngun2zpn1v4U54q50=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false, but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160119", 
		"question": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7xyvDyIGXZF2sUsD+KXONjdWL3UbXMLsTwzZ5wZ0ybhFZ64H/KuuXz+F0cmqVe7c6gTx08QbRQiNGal/T21mUBPMAEjoh37YhfeP1F2H+KCJ2dwrsJ+7MuQWxYbHrd", 
		"answer": "27S2YZzy3Vns+IokEBB5Y46u3fs5k6VMoRIsgdc=", 
		"explanation": "24K9e4X2wxeq3oskWx+yxvLxJn7dBmZRrnCRV+N1fnjuVauCaOLxzddwNByZjElvsnnA47H48lodz6xS7JrdJD8IvHLiuwqKhw8TDtunmQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "an,im,al, fo,od", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160120", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg1A3++4AtVxDm1r3wMyv7AnsQt3eCEqJ6dDHGRqbMLuTwibpBZ0uMn147zUn5nJrPyGxN5Y6vvRI0fCs5OWSqSY3uVw==", 
		"answer": "27O3eoX61xDv88cw6vUI91iw1SK2r3+HCVWS", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQrv45EsVxP3y+nsdXzVEWdRs22MRqZ3ZHTnFKjQLun7z5J/I1mNwRtz93jFpuXk/1YWz79e+4vfdi0RaoJpwdWNlTAZKpYp/PueP4IxJigSImk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "for,ti,fi,ed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160121", 
		"question": "25y2KJTywg3v5YtgexD2zPyzdW3ZEGpRonGHEpxLT07ca5j9Luvx25p0IxyahFx1+3DPoKT+4xMKg61W7ICLY2IMeMt7wNXJ0+3y0DNDiCK+Bwc9D3QZv/ARgQoH", 
		"answer": "26exa5Sx+aaDFo50ufXza3S6i+ZLhw==", 
		"explanation": "25C5e4X2wxeq3oskWx+11r37PG7EQ3IDrHKKXKZ6ZH36FKHHb/nr25J1Z1qAnlM783jC47f59FZNWOZ10lHWATSY5Oixyh15KA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ri,ce,gr,ins", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160122", 
		"question": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7hzOn6JivZDSIFq3rDX6pwPVbiWqDHeuT9iYV0IFWGgxts92TD46b/+l4AgaRCqYiQZSwHPoVqycLJ1qTI+05+DPl7pcLsni3GTC16jNMwm+2LmZQY", 
		"answer": "27m5Y5Sz3guq9sUyWwj31738OmXWD3cUrXyGEA/e2eyVQa7ZF7T7+c0xMRU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQrj44AzEgn31/i/IHjFAm4duj+PXaB1ZHTnFKnHb/++3pZlIk7JnlRu4HXDsOmw5EMKjKFd4I2efC4aPoduw9Wal+vlhGZJNtRB2pJ78p8Nb7RNySnvvUADrlM87sgqdfRYO4+98Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "forest", 
		"option_b": "hill", 
		"option_c": "desert", 
		"option_d": "lake or a river confluence", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160123", 
		"question": "24GwbdH31Bjut4cvVgeyzPO/GGrYAnAQsHeXQKI0Z3DwFLfOb+77zdd4KRydhV47zUn5nJrPyGxPn6dI4JqWfyxDep59wd6Ol+bi1nhAP4QS7tbmDG7VHA5ZxFABtmL0", 
		"answer": "27u3eoX7nArl4pEoEFvBJujRzJtZaZ9ajbyg/XA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHxxAvj9olgRgzzwfTrPGTeQ2sf41KCWqJmcWLrQLXDLvr/2tdlKByZgVp49zbSq6Cw9VwLluhS586LeCdDcIR93NjExOvi0HkBI8lXk5R765RdKAvwl7lOfqTnNKdz3DRo3w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "no,rt,h-so,uth", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160124", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUyVxn7yvO/ImLECyIYt2zDVqpxZHDxTefSfOj4zIV0KV+M1xsqskHDsLH15V1PpqZf4I/fImImf5h7zcKHl835wHhAcQ4epT3QDscpAHn3M2H5RMg=", 
		"answer": "2+T4SZ/63Bjmt4MvXRqyl73ZPHjYQ2Mfpz+RW6BxMlcnX9lEWw/v8t4XNoKxI8I=", 
		"explanation": "25Gxbpf2wxzk48UyVxn7yvPsdWPRByIVqnmFV7FxfmWjUK7Heuzs0NdhNVmPiEl+/HXDsOXy9kAKi+hU586eZiMKcoptxNXJxeHky2RTMMNX2oF84NoLbvVExSmke9rIYt9mmD8DyC3j7hZPkRB8A+c=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 Dairy 2 Barley and wheat", 
		"option_b": "1 Vegetables 2 Fish and rice", 
		"option_c": "1 Animal food 2 Fruits", 
		"option_d": "1 Animal food 2 Fish and rice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160125", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUzVwrmyfjyMGXEECIGqmuLErd8dXjxFKTKb///yoN0NVWamVJ44SyG8uXb9koOm6BaqY+RdGImbIphiILJ9Oz+1nBPN4ZFlIQy1JsReOEA/jyndcabBPZnzGfCt/Ez2UZEw51pokRrwmQ7vQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4Tp7hxRDs/oAkEkyy9fLsISbYDG4UsD+CXKc0Yn72WqOCZuLr2pJiZbK7Qvc+svcdVoyHWB7h6zQ=", 
		"explanation": "25Gxbpf2wxzk48UzVwrmyfjyMGXEECIZonvDR619YWTmFKbQbeX33ZJyM0mbjFc79HPHt7Di8kBPm6Ba/c6beTEXd4Vo3dma3+HzhGVJNssGaP+99PvMI8zDKD5gyjoFOA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 On hills 2 Near lakes", 
		"option_b": "1 Made of wood 2 Fortified", 
		"option_c": "1 Fortified 2 Post-holes and round houses", 
		"option_d": "1 In deserts 2 Near forests", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160126", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUyVxn7yvO/ImLECyITtm2KU680YGPiV7PLbeikicYxCl2BjEl64X7SsaSwpRM8gL1P4c62fiYKf8mzTygpzBXgOjWjOXhQamqv", 
		"answer": "2+TxKL/8ww3iurYvRwr6he3wJmLECm0f4y3KEoZ1Y2WuY6LReq3uxoR4M1WGgxkzuiRi40Y1riqXTMP7ngqb", 
		"explanation": "25Gxbpf2wxzk48UyVxn7yvPsdWPRByIErXaSR6Y0cmTxXabOLv3syJRlLl+MnhkgfdzvsKC8zEWWdiTTCU5J", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1) North-South 2) Diagonal", 
		"option_b": "1) Circular 2) East-West", 
		"option_c": "1) North-South position 2) East-West position", 
		"option_d": "1) Vertical 2) Diagonal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160127", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b3+N2TFFyIFq3rDcat1fHLsWK7WZuT9iZR+KlGcg1Jv+3PV5OXk+FwDnOha54rfZTYGcJhmxMPJ3ve3xXJCJtRFjoUtpk5h0JNdAEWLE5cLprM071w=", 
		"answer": "24GwbYizxArv88UtWx3gyvH2IWPDTyICt3CNV+Ngf37vR+uCfeLzzNdyKEyZiEk75nnJr7a8t1IBi+hM4YuafG8Xa5lhzdTJ1ej2x3oMMshA15J34NoPc+BTjrR8DbbqiKjxVFdUFnZOzm8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/NmTdDncfqmuKV7A0Y2TzRKvHY+jw3ZJ1Z0iBiFJpsmXSrKv1t0cAgKRIqZmWZCpDfYR/2NWbl/D4y31Sc8dKnsBl4YgaPPVM3zLtf9rUN/AuyGGSZ1H4YjCvRHR9hyXfhH9CoZW+tTe0QM4y0gxwdk+wiPDvE6WpNChO7pRHVg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They exclusively used copper tools and no pottery", 
		"option_b": "They used microliths, stone tools, some bronze tools, and hand-made pots", 
		"option_c": "They used only stone tools and no pottery", 
		"option_d": "They used microliths, stone tools, some copper tools, and wheel-turned black-and-red pots", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160128", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b39MHjEQ2YUsHyRW6FxYzH3XKKCTeX/xZR+K1WdhVJ4snXJrqjl+Vobhq1Irs6beScXf5l2iNiI1e3j1zFIPYZAk4Z04YgacuAA3Dy/YMebL/gu52CELkSvJWQuPt9G2J+vzVlOieTRiKo=", 
		"answer": "25y2KIb2wg3v5YtgexD2zPyzdX/YBntRoHCNQbZ5dXWjWajQa63/x558JlDJi1R09jqGtK35+1ZPhqYb7I+MZCcRcMtGxtSA1qi3wnhSO4ZFlIQy9pMcebRXyS+oNMfSJ/BnyGeDJkvkJzyxAX1xmiXFyCCcJtkKwo3K8ofQ8KapN18=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Bz+9pc5Ehbzx/TrJivGAnAYpnvDU6Bmf2LwFLXHaeTxx4Q9Z0uAmVM75XPVt6Di+RMmgaxS6M6TdSMNd4VoiN2GxeG30H5WMtRAicBz6pMSffgAyjKicJTaLvouy2+TM0DiaXmUCnR9lXHTh2xeqZCy7y61U5oxyQY61oZ26YguNdSam9uQTANtEageSarE8+br8ME=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They primarily consumed only rice all over India", 
		"option_b": "They were vegetarian throughout India", 
		"option_c": "Only fish was a significant component of their diet", 
		"option_d": "In western India, they consumed more animal food, while in eastern India, fish and rice were significant elements", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160129", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCRQKZ3ZH36FKPHfe7swJV0NBydhV478GPUqqT8t0MdjqtP4I2aY2IKcMtrwdaP0vbyymUBIcNDk49899obaeZJwjrtYNzeYN1mz2KDKEn5czG0BzBknDDFjyMUdwW2qaxa613qKJTDkjeh3A==", 
		"answer": "25y2KLzy2Rj49pYoRgzzib39Om/ZBnFRtHqRV+NkfHDgUaOCZ+O+3Z90Z1KGn09zv2XJtrH4t0MAnKFP4IGRPGIKcMt8x8Wd36TeynVIMoZNlMBm7J9fefVT2HC6ccfPYO5h3WeULkr+K3m8CnQ0gDnTmHkWv4KotSKjQN85xBA21oVt/8E9MJeW1+iE7V6sgxSMnFKfTLRlU8Cr+Nkw8C+MefBYcPqmiFw=", 
		"explanation": "25Gxbpf2wxzk48UyVxn7yvPsdWPRByIVqmyXW613ZHj1UefAe//3yJsxN06Ijk9y8XPV47H49kdPna1d5YucZCcHPp9nzdmbl+fiyGVUIcdI2oJ36JMaeucAzTOpNMDJIfpn2mePKVayTs09oXa5jpOVnnLC+ueWHA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bodies were universally buried in the east-west position throughout India", 
		"option_b": "There was no specific direction for burial practices across regions", 
		"option_c": "Fractional burial was prominent in both western and eastern India", 
		"option_d": "In Maharashtra, bodies were placed in the north-south position, in south India in the east-west position, and there was extended burial in western India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160130", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDQqZ7YH3mFLfQZ+D/2559Phycnl479nnLprbk/lAOm61fqY+ReS8Ccpgvzt+biKaFkZ2KM46a+ElBCqtNvGWy", 
		"answer": "25O3Z5WxXkEzKI8CJOPijlbf/vOAgA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U42+RW651YnjvTefRYuzrzp9lIk6MiRt//XvDsLH59FIbiqwb6ICWfSMPbctpx8LJ0ev4wDFAPcIEnol2pJQQaLRV3zjtYNzeLb5owXzAKkz8bHm8CnQ0kDDfmGUWuJG08TK4QMl1BwnS1zxzHdBZU+siRxPpFA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Food", 
		"option_b": "Milk", 
		"option_c": "Ploughing", 
		"option_d": "Transport", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160131", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q5IotV17m1/T9NGeQE2ces3OGEq17ZDHuXavJLvn2zJ5jZ1+ImU939ymEX+6LNmpLayAkReCI9nEqWw==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz0xzm/oA2VxqyyPTzPivHAnFRrnqCXLc0f3/vTefEYf++0JhkKVvJjFVy/3fKsOdGtrsObh6bCwfTOdE1sLfK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHx1BXj8oNgRR/hhen3NH+QDmsdqD+UU7A0fXTiWrOCeuK+x5hkNVWahRti/WPIpOXx+VoCjqRIpc6XdSwAe8thx8TJ0evlhHlUPsdK2oN96okKceRUxTKjNus/lVp8V5pc0DwIaG40VjM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cultural reasons", 
		"option_b": "To sell milk", 
		"option_c": "Fear of depleting resources", 
		"option_d": "They believed milk was meant only for young animals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160132", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0gzm44w2Uwr7yvO/OG7EC20V42iCQeNkf2LwXaXOd63r2pJ1Z16QzXhz83rFrKn541sGjOhL7IGPfCdcPB46zcYa4jfPnjwRkvMlTfQ=", 
		"answer": "24a0aYL7nBv/5YtgXQyyz/XqOCvTFm4FqmmCRqp7fjNycVJuU424DMPb+rJZiY3p", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYizxArv88UkWxn1zPP4dXjECmEasD+UV6pzeGXmUOfVZ/n2iYRlKFKMzV9y4XXV7+Xn/1oMh+ha+4vfYzcKaoptxNXJ0evlhGJNMtVM14Jn9pRfc+YAxjW4eZTYNfJ6x3iBM0z/aXsgSHDp4LO49fuPlTs8L+Ue", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Terracing", 
		"option_b": "Intensive farming", 
		"option_c": "Slash-burn or jhum cultivation", 
		"option_d": "Irrigation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160133", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTv44QsEgnz1r3tNHnVD3tRpXCWXKc0eX+jd6/DYu7xxZ5lL1WKzVhu/mLTsaCw8Vwdz65a+4OWfiVcPB9epi5eZAPQhB/GW338sw0=", 
		"answer": "25yqZ5+xM/FwQkrenY6NyQi+fslUTw==", 
		"explanation": "25y2fJT9whD88sUhXBqywOXrMGXDCnQU43yWXrd9ZnD3XajMLv/72IJ4NVmNzU9z9zbTsKCw+FVPhrpU586WfTIPe4ZqxsSam6TgzHhCO4ZTn5J3pIgebvEAxTPtV9zaLP1hwmeUL0zzJzqoCGRhhjSUCOhXQ632RQMkXg0ey62QIA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bronze", 
		"option_b": "Copper", 
		"option_c": "Gold", 
		"option_d": "Iron", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160134", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4RgQRf1y/T5PGjRDXZRoHeCXq9xfnbmFKHDbej6iZVoZ3+BjFd4/XrPt6359BMMmqRP/JyaY31B72ZKdZeEktIvqYWJzIvFMA==", 
		"answer": "252xb5mzwxj+8sUvVF77y/v+O3+QDm0Dt36PW7dtMsvAHzGUbmEYXpv3ARnU9WE=", 
		"explanation": "25G9e4H6xRyq9YApXBmyw/LwMSbAEW0VtnyGQLA4MGXrUb6CZuz6iZYxL1WOhRtp82LD46r2t1oBialV/c6SfzAXf4dm3MnJx+vk13hDP98EnpV3pI4QPPpV2C+kYN3ULr5qy2iJJEz1aTq0AWM0myOWhn1Vo8O082e2Ud4+wxQ+1ox24t8wOdOY3Oqwd8qO65th9BNHo7aj23mU", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Invasion by outsiders", 
		"option_b": "Lack of water sources", 
		"option_c": "Crop failure", 
		"option_d": "High rate of infant mortality", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160135", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk0Aqq9IowQhvghe3tPGbREWsduj+WQaZwMHP6FLPKa63dwZZ9JFOFhE9z+3WGs6D/518K0OqNSEzmPxeCUxmBWxn2g1Fz", 
		"answer": "24G3Z53gk7cqQtgcCfSGAuAGfnUAYoA=", 
		"explanation": "25a3eIH2w1n99pZgXx/7y/HmdX7DBmZRt3DDX6J/dTH3W6jOfaG+y4JlZ0iBiBto52bWr7yw4FIcz6RS5IeLdSZDf4VriMeIxKT5y2UBMtUEiZRg65QYPPVTjD+/e9rBJbzDKdMFAVJ8tFF0dmlZXVZ2", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Jewelry", 
		"option_b": "Cooking pots", 
		"option_c": "Currency", 
		"option_d": "Tools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160136", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTv44QsEhjzxvTzPH/RF2cV42uLV+NmeWLmFKjELuzwyp50KUjJjlJt+3rPuaTk/lwBnPcZloH1auxEH6jMyniHjIkKsg==", 
		"answer": "25eqZ5/p1FuIIa/tKEpd2nFLhiBLoPaZ", 
		"explanation": "25eqZ5/p1Fn++IosQV7lwO/6dXjZBGwYpXaAU61gMHjtFLPKa63swIR0Z1OPzVhy5H/Kqr/x41oAgbsb5YeUdWIXdoR8zZCA2aTSw2hRJ4oEuZJ38J9TPNlF3zK9e8DaLfdvgi6BKUGwczG4RFl6kCTFykpXpI++7GV+ULFryjC4V63rN7yweYHR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gold", 
		"option_b": "Silver", 
		"option_c": "Iron", 
		"option_d": "Bronze", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4RgURH/yPLxdX/CAmsF43CFErd8dTHAXKbObeLywIN5Ll/JnV504nrD46Tz5VwcnOhy54qWcX1BQWef+/ulQcw/tkQuYVFk9Q==", 
		"answer": "24GwbYiz0hb/+4FgXBHmhertPH/VQbbzLmv//wOXPuyuvXptli8=", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUV7x0PHrIHnVECIQoG2MQbA0WX/nXaaCYuz9wpJ1Z13Jmkly5mLDreX89l0Imqlc7MLfZSwPd4BqiMSB0qT2wGdAPcVBnsBQ9pURZvEA7TqoNNfSNvdix3SBM0z/aSr/etBX1f89abNVwUe3RnS6cA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "They lived in big cities", 
		"option_b": "They could not write", 
		"option_c": "They used iron extensively", 
		"option_d": "They had a robust trading system", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160138", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q+oozRl7RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDUbZ4ZGTxUbSCbeLz2ZZjIhyehE9zsmLOpuXZ+VcanOht6IKTdTtDfYJ5wdyAzeXjzX5PbIQeobKHBySjZdgZ3lP2IPdB", 
		"answer": "24GwbYizxhz48sU5XQv8wvjtd+DtixBnp6aMdTqSFLxGXJY=", 
		"explanation": "25i3e4Wz8hHr+4YvXhfmzfT8dWjFD3YEsXqQEqp6MHCjR67FYOT4wJRwKUjJnVpp5jbJpeXZ+VcGjuhM7JyaMDsMa4VozcLJw+z2yjFVO8MEs4528YlfSvVMwDi0NNfSNvdix3SBM0z/aXtyPNMm8FmEG3eGj/veOMXX", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "They were older", 
		"option_b": "They were contemporary", 
		"option_c": "They were younger", 
		"option_d": "They had no contact", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160139", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxRbl+8U3Uw2y0O76MSvWDHBRoGqPRqpicWXqW6mCZ+O+3Z90Z3+BjFd4/XrPt6359BMfirpS5orAMs+6XjUz2Kf45BXlAgeE2NM=", 
		"answer": "25Gxb5b63x6q5JEpURWwxfEY3IA0z84UBBRfe1IwQg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U42qQV6c0dHjkU67Maa3t3Z5yLE/Jml5y9X7SpqGw4Fobh+hL7JyZfzACao5riMOd2OryhHVIIMVX2I7LohYckWXfjRKroWOuu9I=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Plough", 
		"option_b": "Hoe", 
		"option_c": "Harrow", 
		"option_d": "Digging stick", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160140", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuyx+jtPGrcQ2QYrXuKXKRnMHjtFLDHffn725kxCl2BjEl64X7SsaSw/l0Lhqta/YeJdWIMeNQt7X9NR4EEe8woMeog9d0lPA==", 
		"answer": "252xb5mz2Bfs9os0EhP91+n+OWLEGiA8m36Pofopt42ZHw/aAACU", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHxxAvj9olgXRiyxL3zNHnXBiIftnKBV7E0f3ejV6/LYunszJkxLlKNhFh65nPV46Sw/1oIh+hJ6JqaMC0FPoJhztGHw6T6y2NVMspNjpkwx0XaULHLDAENJCBXUn4q+w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Migration patterns", 
		"option_b": "Trade relations", 
		"option_c": "High infant mortality", 
		"option_d": "High population density", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160141", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTv44QsEgnz1r3sIXnfDWUUsT+CXKc0fX7xUefXfej43JsxM1SIgxt4/WbWprevtag5mr5rSUgqyT1z/VWyWpE=", 
		"answer": "25eqZ5/p1FuIIa/tKEpd2nFLhiBLoPaZ", 
		"explanation": "25eqZ5/p1FWq+oQkV17w3L3yPHPZDWVRt3aNErR9ZHmjV6jSfujshddmJk/JgFRp9zbUrKfl5EdPjqZfqYOQYidDa5hqzsWFl/D/xX8BI9NWn8Bx64oPeeYCzHs6j9KGNPNe3RSUukBO6Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gold", 
		"option_b": "Silver", 
		"option_c": "Iron", 
		"option_d": "Bronze", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160142", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrl/olgVhf2hen3MCvzC2MdoHCPW7d8eXKjRKLNfuH7iZ5/Z1mInk9+4HiGiqv0/lJPg6FN7M6Wfn1BZ2DuwdTAHG4B57MckzPAmg==", 
		"answer": "24e9bNHg3hDmtZtt47EO0D4maCp7HG74OZY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYiz3RD88oFgWxCy0fX6dXnVByICrHaPEqJmdXDwFKjELuj/2oN0NVLJpFV/+3eE6mu2fVqqxcH+VJscnJgBRQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sandy soil", 
		"option_b": "Loamy soil", 
		"option_c": "Black cotton soil", 
		"option_d": "Red soil", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160143", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDUbZ4ZGTxUeDRLv3swJpwNUXJj1p4+XHUrLD+8wxNYoQ4z7tMVZMMzhgHWQDjWA==", 
		"answer": "24etepD/k5G/gB+v3AgeFTdUPSmpbIA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3gn68pdtQQr9y/i/Nn7cF3cDpj+LU6c0cX+jUbTRa+PqwJZ9K0XJn05p83qGoaTz/FQdgL1V7cxbVzKxpyTuVtxaWXNuqN4T", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Urban", 
		"option_b": "Nomadic", 
		"option_c": "Coastal", 
		"option_d": "Rural", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160144", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4svRl7zy73+NmPZBnQUrnqNRuN7djH3XKKCTeX/xZR+K1WdhVJ4smbDrLX88gxNwDINVihgZDu/Un0wceFmFg==", 
		"answer": "25mxfpj91lnj+cUjWwr7wO69ur3Y+Um7Sbl+3u5ZIwmEUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U43uKVuN6f2WjWK7Ua633x9dyLkiAiEg3smPIr6z78hMbh60b+YuQYC4GPoRpiMSB0qTV1n5PKcMEu4d3pmKBd9EZ89UT1OljN/Rw0JY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Domesticating animals", 
		"option_b": "Using copper for tools", 
		"option_c": "Farming", 
		"option_d": "Living in cities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160145", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeNkdX7zWKKCZ+O+ypJ/M06IgRt6/HKGtKDj41Ydgehy54qWcWIHd48vxt+dl/TlxXJVOsVB2ol88J8Rb/1WyX2rdcbWKfBpjlKOG0vCYjiuC34u1BjEhXIWoY6r+SK2UdQj01lyk5Rr6MYoNdaTma6c+g2rkwWKnH2QWrBtH1PV9dmt+UbcsoMqsI9cVX+qLhmCPnrgfgQ4tSfF", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfmyiZZ/IxydhV47wHPHsKr+t1ocz7xT7M6cfzARe4h7iNWRx+j2ynBVOslK2oZ99toLdPEA7S6+ccbPKfFgjB3HsV2Wyam/lhN6ddyFSAQ=", 
		"explanation": "25y2fJT9whD88sUhXBqywOXrMGXDCnQU43yWXrd9ZnD3XajMLuLwiZV9Jl+CzUh0+3qGsaDh4lodiqwb4JyQfmIKc5tjzd2M2fDkiDFWO89HksBl4YgaPOZB3jjtfdqbNPZrjk2IJknzaDW0EHh9l3HVn3BCvZG+twkdWDg606NB4zII7dE0R4o=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160146", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he7qJXvcGiIepT+AXbNkdWOjUqjQLvn2zNdSL12FjlR3+2LOqqaw51YAn6ReqZmeY2IPd4Zm3NWNl9j5+H9zNsdXlY4opK4XeeZFjCqoZtGbLvEuzWGQN0DiJzS0CnVn1DjYylVYrIq6tSOuRtM5x1UmnoZsrdg5Lt6Q3eqPG2OhNCvkoNxn/gHmVuiR", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7xyu/tMGjETyITtmvDYKZ1Y37tFK7RLuTwyphjNVmKmRn5LTdgcDgk+ptIIVXowem3", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUzRw7iyeS/Om2QAG0Bs3qRErR1YzHvXarLeuj6iZF+NRydhV470X7Hr6b/+1obh6FYqZ6afzIPe8cv3NiMxeG303RTNoZHlZBi4Yhfcf1OyS7tfdqbJf992muSKQXZaT20BTLN7H69ytuT5ZbqFp82fGvB", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160147", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hd73NGfTDG4Yt3eKUeNkdX7zWKKCbeLrxZMxKVOdzV9+5HPKrLWw9Fobhq1IqYKWeydDaoNqiPKb2OrtwTFgNMMEmYlk7ZYWZvVUxTKjZ5TnLsJg/GuBNEr+PXmJDHVt1D3XiXdTrMOv/SL7QN80yBs9moh/5Ms9MJee3b6S5k69iwOMyDueTv1wGVHZnMCs/lDcloM0uciU8THS4v31k+LS5NcEbEoMfInAPow46Kqi6a7mGz95", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfmyiZZ/IxydhV47wHPHsKr+t1ocz7xT7M6cfzARe4h7iNWRx+j2ynBVOslK2oZ99toLdPEA7S6+ccbPKfFgjB3HsV2Wyam/lhN6ddyFSAQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/Nn7cF3cDpmzDVqpwMH/sQOfKb/v7iYN5IhyIiU16/HXDp+Xk8lAHgadX5omWcyMPPoBhx8eF0uDwwTFNOs1B2pR64do2cvBV332bddjXJecuzWeWLkn5fTipDX962HHBgnVVoMOz9CP7V9MjyRAh1AAm4UgJvroIkPZ/yNZ7tL4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160148", 
		"question": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U43uMX6ZnZHjgVbPHaq3/x558JlCazVlu5jbCqqGw+Vwbz65O5YKGMDcXd4dm0tXJw+zyyTFHPNQEl4l+79oecvAAjAKSS+vkH8FRjCnLqZ8Qo2PSpNDYdm0a9g0=", 
		"answer": "27G5YYPqkQn4+IE1UQrhhxe5zToIMmhpfIo86ArcniA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U42+RW651YnjvTefXfej6iZZ/LlGIgUg79HnU46P/+FdPjqZfqYqWdGINcZ8v3cOMl/D/wXwBNclW2o176JFfffpEjDmsfcbCYO58wWqVJFHjJRp3gmUMOs9PYHqNos9i1nM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "da,iry prod,uc,ts", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160149", 
		"question": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/JW7fE24U42qQV6c0dHjkU67Maa3t3Z5yLE/Jml5y9X7SpqGw4Fobh+hr7JyZfzACao5riO+26NvI+05+cU7AS8U0PBtLumT9YcU2lPY=", 
		"answer": "26asZ5/2kR3j5IYzEHZrWhVf47eRrayom+mx/Io=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYL2kQ7v/oIoRhv2hfn2MmzZDWVRsGuKUahnMGbmRqKCffj33ZZzK1nJi1RpsnzOtqiw+EFPnKRa+obScjcRcMts3dyd3vL20HhOPYSUWbnSktn1hQeFJouTH80B", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "sto,ne di,scs", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160150", 
		"question": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUDWh/+xvLzPH/YCmFRs3qMQq9xMHniUOfDbe772oQxM1PJjlRr4nPU7+Xk/1YWz6Ra6oWadGIXdo4vw96GwOjywHZEc8lC2o17/JMRe7RDwy29ccabN/d6xi6/GHrPWAaCOzBgm3Hbi3dT6IGp+imhUZhIazGEIdOXUNuP00u+qKcR", 
		"answer": "26GxZtMjfpJxY+0Was7AUjtnZEg4", 
		"explanation": "25eqZ5/p1Fnj5MUhXF7zyfHwLCvfBSISrG+TV7E0cX/nFLPLYK+GONZJJBhfnCfhc9/duLkF", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "t,in,im", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160151", 
		"question": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Ehzzxvb4J2TFDWZRrHnDRqtxMFLsRLfHfKDN3Zh/IhyKmFdv52TD47Lx5BMwsJdk1rGgT2CIDK/6INVd6IBKJzQgIX32", 
		"answer": "26etepD/kweWP+huyIdJksfHB2ku1RM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/OnmQIG0Bs3qRH5Bgf3/mFKTXYvnr25IxN06MiVR2+3jHrbH87hMHjqwb6M6NZTACcsttydOC0Pb40X9FcZEy2d+CLDRDDo7BiDhPpmk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "rur,al,ur,ban", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160152", 
		"question": "25i3e4Wz8hHr+4YvXhfmzfT8dWjFD3YEsXqQEqp6MFjtUK7DLvr725IxGGO2smREzUmGoKr951Idiqwb/YHfZCoGPqJhzMWal9L2yH1EKoZHk5Z76JMFfeBJwzPvmoE92fFPcRTyGwTuJ9ZZpQ==", 
		"answer": "26y3fZ/01AuooHuF8+IFlilHg3UdyfGolQ==", 
		"explanation": "25i5Zoiz8hHr+4YvXhfmzfT8dWjFD3YEsXqQEqp6MFjtUK7DLu7/xJIxJlqdiEk75n7D44z+80Ycz55a5YKaaWIAd51mxNmT1vD+y38DZyVVKnA7m84kUazoUiJaww==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "you,ng,er,yel,der", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160153", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUtVwrzyb3oPH/YQ2sFsD+WRqp4eWX6DuVMQy0sqr2J1MoyZBljRFEf", 
		"answer": "25a3eIH2w1mnw4ovXg2+5+/wO3HVQy8wrXyKV61gMHLqQq7OZ/f/3Z5+KU/Jn1Jo9zrvsar+tx4mgbxe552WZidDeIp9xdmH0KbBxvkBGW+wUQ1mbDebVvxQ", 
		"explanation": "25a3eIH2w1mnt7EvXRLh+fPdJ2TeGWdR7j+iXKB9dX/3FKTLeOTywI1wM1WGg0g74H/Vppn+3kEAgegWqaeRZCcNbYJ5zZCP1vb6zX9GceqGQ+T/5xasiTMHKG8VFfc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Copper,Tools", 
		"option_b": "Bronze,Ancient civilizations rise", 
		"option_c": "Iron,Intensive farming", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160154", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUyVxn7yvO/ImLECyIYt2zDQax9fDH3TbfHNK3/gNdSIlKdn1p3snfIp+Xn8kAbirpVqaeRdCsCPokmiPWIxPDy1n8BGshAk4EwL7XlJRk3RPrNW7s3Ji0sbw==", 
		"answer": "27TxKLP/0Brht4YvRgr9y73sOmLcQ2BY402GVuNnf3jvFueBprvhwTHQaCfecsuTm+4=", 
		"explanation": "25a9ZoXh0BWq9oskEgn31un6J2WQKmwVqn7DWqJwMHPvVaTJLu7x3YN+KRyaglJ3smHOqqn1t1YOnLxe+4DfWSwHd4ovwNGNl/bywDFSPM9I2F+QH7I+Oxah2igpjIrtDYg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "a) Loamy soil b) Sandy soil", 
		"option_b": "a) Red soil b) Black cotton soil", 
		"option_c": "a) Black cotton soil b) Red soil", 
		"option_d": "a) Clayey soil b) Rocky terrain", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160155", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUhVRuy0vTrPSvEC2dRoGqPRrZmdSujVe6CTeX/xZR+K1WdhVJ4snSP44z+80Ycz55a5YKaaWBbzL0CWcYeosxkaErpjWYl", 
		"answer": "27TxKKj8xBft8pdgUFey6vH7MHmSbzDYpg8TXpByoSnMIFH2vQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ2Rjm9IosWwr6zP6/Nn7cF3cDpmzDRaZmdTH6W7LMaejsiZ5/Z1+GgEt64H/VrKuw41xPm6BeqaeRdDcQPr1uxNyMzqT0zWdIP89em5R765RdlbeFJu16Uh9yQjNozWypIA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "a) Older b) Contemporary", 
		"option_b": "a) Younger b) Older", 
		"option_c": "a) Contemporary b) Younger", 
		"option_d": "a) Distinct b) Advanced", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160156", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRtH6QErd8dTHvVbXFa/7qiZR+N0yMnxtz/XfUp/qyHN6EvRokIrX28FbxBdoDfw==", 
		"answer": "25KtZpb2wxDrt4wuEjPCh9cKy2suTdNp2TRN9CJ0Nv0=", 
		"explanation": "25KtZpb2wxDrt4wuEjPChfX+MSvRQ2oeom2HEqB7fWHxXbTLYOq+ncUlZ1+GnUt+4DbSrKr85BMOgawbuN7NMDYLd4Uv29iM0vDkhH5Hc9VNlpZ39toQfv5Fzym+Nrl+bvyeCEwWtT5fgVj2ZyM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gungeria in MP", 
		"option_b": "Gujarat", 
		"option_c": "Haryana", 
		"option_d": "West Bengal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160157", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ39+MUzRh/mwO6/PGWQF2oU43qCQbc0eHD1UefEYfjwzddyKEyZiEk7+nnHsaHjqBFWRzEShPGOcgJYCmswgosl", 
		"answer": "24K9e4Wz8xzk8IQsEh/8wb3QJ2LDEGNTgTJZwJFvZnSs8ceW+NX0lQ==", 
		"explanation": "25a3eIH2w1ni+IQyVg2y0vjtMCvWDHcfpz+RU61zeX/kFKHQYeC+/pJiMxyriFV883qGoqv0t3wdhrtI6M6WfmIXdo4vzdGaw6bYQe9qz/+NOgTzoAxYq7EK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Tamil Nadu and Kerala", 
		"option_b": "West Bengal and Orissa", 
		"option_c": "Maharashtra and Goa", 
		"option_d": "Bihar and Jharkhand", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160158", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQnl45ElQAey0vzsdWrDEG0Sqn6XV6c0Z3j3XOfRYeD7iZh3Z0iBiBt4/WbWprew/1wOnawb5oyVdSEXbdQtSqENSVILqGNyErlWeNVNMg==", 
		"answer": "25q7YIP2nDrl+4o1QBv2hc3wIX/VEXtTDBW5kCY+MgALQ0gTZA2+sw==", 
		"explanation": "24a3ZZSz0hb654AyEhb9xO/7dWTSCWcSt2zDRaZmdTHlW7LMaq33x9d0P1+Im1pv+3nIsOXx+1wBiOhM4JqXMC0AdplqhdOG2+vi1nRFc9ZLjpMw2JLbppNlNFwNxQ8to/jn2g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Red Pottery", 
		"option_b": "Black Pottery", 
		"option_c": "Ochre-Coloured Pottery", 
		"option_d": "Green Pottery", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160159", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hy3Bbk8MU0Whuyw/LzOWTHCmwW42qQV6c0c37zRKLQLuXxyIV1NByIg187/nPC46Sw5FYbm6Re7c6TeSQGIclCGfVdlNCFuIwOmntreIWx", 
		"answer": "24a9fIX/1B2q9oIyWx3nyenqJ2rcCnEFsD+CXKc0cWP3XbTDYP68d2ovA28g8x1+627VXLfHGw==", 
		"explanation": "24a9fIX/1B2q9oIyWx3nyenqJ2rcCnEFsD+CXKc0cWP3XbTDYP6+3IR0IxydhV47+3vWr6D98l0bnOhU786LeCdDfYR/2NWbl+z4xWNFIIZFlIQy6J8bPPUA3zi5YNjeJL5ix2iFZVY24A+ejCEIqK1LuuTTmBQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Nomads", 
		"option_b": "Merchants", 
		"option_c": "Settled agriculturalists and artisans", 
		"option_d": "Fishermen", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160160", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5clVRf9y73oMHnVQ28QrWbDfaB8YnSud6jOYfjszJMxF1OdmV5p6zbVqrH15BMJgL1V7dHddKoKuMbuQEVhYz/nBur2RQ==", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkQnl5ZEpXRCyyvu/IWPVQ2Yeon3BZPPPqa5kuiInFyqGZqj5vA==", 
		"explanation": "25i5Zoiz/hri5YBtcRH+yujtMG+QM20Ft3qRS+NneWXmR+fKb/v7iZV0IlLJi1Ru/HKGqquw41sKz71L+YuNMDIMbJ9mx97J2OK30HlEc8JLm4Iw55wgQW1gyxwNNbJXmxXI4A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Lower plains of the Ganges", 
		"option_b": "Coastal regions", 
		"option_c": "Western desert", 
		"option_d": "Upper portion of the doab", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160161", 
		"question": "24GwbdHj1Avj+IFgXRiy0fX6dUTTC3AU7lyMXqxhYnTnFJfNevn7244xJEmFmU5p9zbPsOX15EcGgqlP7IrfZC1DfI4vytWdwOHyyjF+DPl7pb9Npk9YQbUpWBD0mt8zOcNzFYQ=", 
		"answer": "2+foOMGz0Bfut9R1Ak6y5969ZkQ18nHEiKpggjhrXcdG3Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzwRz4/ookEhvh0fTyNH/ZDGxRqmzDUKJndXWjW6mCb63tzIV4Ik/Jgl0793/Bq7Gw5FAGiqZP4IiWc2IHf59mxtealc0IelTBORMs0/UJhjTQ9es=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1000 and 500 BC", 
		"option_b": "3000 and 2500 BC", 
		"option_c": "2000 and 1500 BC", 
		"option_d": "1500 and 1000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160162", 
		"question": "24GwbdHg1A3++4AtVxDm1r3wMyvEC2dRjHyLQKY5U37vW7LQa+m++ZhlM1mblBt453rStrf1t18OnLxe7c6ZfzBDf5t/2t+R3un20HRNKoZMlZcy6JURe6sC3QWGFRrAXSRzGFwXZ+ALdQ==", 
		"answer": "25T4a5T9xQz47sUvQF7hyr8QvvzIsYxrargtD0fwX/I1", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1A3++4AtVxDm1r37PG+QDW0F43OCQbc0dn7xFKjUa/++yNdyIlKdmElisB2IYHve/YftjKKI0JUCf9s=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A millennium", 
		"option_b": "A few decades", 
		"option_c": "A century or so", 
		"option_d": "Five centuries", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160163", 
		"question": "25T4e4T01hz544AkEgz3xO7wOyvWDHBRt3eGEqZ6dDHsUufWZujtzNdiIkidgV5293jSsOX55BMwsJdk1rGgMreS+S7R+mjfsUpgPRkKNlA=", 
		"answer": "25y2fZ/30A3j+ItgVBH+yfLoMG+QAXtRtH6XV7E0fH7kU67Maa/uyaKMH3cg4gY710I6OuZH", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzr5MUtUweyzfzpMCvSBmEernrDR61yeWWjUqjQLuXrxJZ/Z0+MmU9393vDrbHjt1caiuhP5s6IcTYGbMtjx9eO3urwhgi+/f06JN2NMyd/HEFqve0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Foreign invasions", 
		"option_b": "Economic collapse", 
		"option_c": "Disease outbreak", 
		"option_d": "Inundation followed by water logging", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160164", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1AH+4pclEhH0hen3MCv/AGoDpjKgXa97ZWPmUOfyYfnqzIVoZ16MhFV8smXJpbGw+loIh7wb64vfcicAf558zZCG0aT+0GIBDPl7pb9N29hKKAJ1bEw0OyjGCPmbb4be", 
		"answer": "25Sre57w2Bj+/oouEgn70fW/ImrEBnBRpXCREqI0fH7tU+fWZ+D7izjH4GLizEW5DIp8cW7whLg=", 
		"explanation": "24a3ZZSzwhri+IkhQA2yx/jzPG7GBiIFq36XErd8dTHzW7PWa//njoQxNFOPmRtv927Strf1t0EKnL1X/YubMCQRcYYvwcSal/Tly31OPcFBnsBz94kQf/1B2DSiepTMKepmjnmBM0DiJchrrhYsox6pdFtOAHXrrew=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Poor quality clay", 
		"option_b": "Rapid production", 
		"option_c": "Association with water for a long time", 
		"option_d": "Lack of baking", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160165", 
		"question": "24GwbdHc8imq54AvQhL3hfD2MmPEQ2oQtXrDWqJwMHjtQKLQb+7qwJh/NByehE9zsmHOqqb4t1IBjKFe55rfcysVd4dm0tGd3uv5mzPenZ3a14n9Enc2n13KSbxE", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjk5McAQA9YxWgQkeJVD4eXz8WZ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHc8imq54AvQhL3gu6/NHnVAiIGomzDXKxgMHfiRufEfOLziYN5JkjJgl075n7D443x5VIfn6lV+sLfYzcEeY583NmH0KTny2VEPdJNm4wy7ZQLeeZBzymke9rIYn5NHoJu9Xxc1V273G/JMiM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Mesopotamians", 
		"option_b": "Egyptians", 
		"option_c": "Greeks", 
		"option_d": "Harappans", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160166", 
		"question": "25+3bJnjxAvrt4wzEhL9xvzrMG+QDGxRt3eGEqF7YnXmRufNaK3pwZ5yLxydmlQ74WLHt6DjqBHndqmes6aWOVWbm8HNom68", 
		"answer": "2525eojy3xiq9oskEizzz/zsIWPRDSC/JhRM43Fpzaoqk+9Cj6QM", 
		"explanation": "25+3bJnjxAvrt4wzEhL9xvzrMG+QDGxRt3eGEqF7YnXmRufNaK3WyIVoJlKIzVp19jb0oq/x5EcHjqYZQE3Te9uW04oXXV95fYp7EA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Punjab and Haryana", 
		"option_b": "Haryana and Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "Rajasthan and Gujarat", 
		"option_d": "UP and Haryana", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160167", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3hvg8oY0QV7lwO/6dW3fFmwV43aNEqJnY37gXabWZ+LwiYB4M1TJolhz4HOLgKr8+EYdiqwb2YGLZCcRZ8tmxpCMz+f20nBVOslKid8wm1QC0O56gpj0VF5+H1LUXw==", 
		"answer": "25q7YIP2nBrl+4o1QBv2he3wIXiQAmwV42yMX6Y0fWTnFLTWfPj93YJjIk/Ls6vZnaG26GNZEAzGwECshQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2yRrr4YQ0WxH81r3tMH3VAm4Upz+XWqZndTHsVq3HbfntiZZ9KFKOzUxy5n6Gt631t0MAm7xe+5fdeerwqy6wRDv8tk7cRQZ2Sg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gold ornaments and jewelry", 
		"option_b": "Ochre-coloured pots and some mud structures", 
		"option_c": "Beads and terracotta figures", 
		"option_d": "Seals and tokens", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160168", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7iyunrMHnJQ3UQsD+WQaZwMHP6FLPKa63uzJhhK1nJjF1v92SGt631t1cGnKlL+YueYiMNfY4vx9bJw+zyhF5CO9RB16N96JUKbvFEjA2iYMDeMucuzXuMM1DiYmb/bJ7BwaqoltBxf/Wl2o42YQ==", 
		"answer": "25e0aZL4nBjk88gyVxqy0vztMCn9JrW1vlN0V/VXUpwbEjFu", 
		"explanation": "25e0aZL4nBjk88gyVxqy0vztMCvHAnFRtmyGVuN2aTH3XKKCfujx2Zt0Z1WHzU9z9zbCrKTyt1IJm61JqZqXdWIsXbsvy8WFw/HlwTOCbqEBTPLM3Lx04briqcQe", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "White-and-blue ware", 
		"option_b": "Green-and-yellow ware", 
		"option_c": "Black-and-red ware", 
		"option_d": "Pink-and-brown ware", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160169", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQnm9oYlEhbzwb3rPW6QF2oYoHSGQbc0X1LTFKPHfuLtwINiZ1OPzQoqsnuZ4VF1u9kdWri/vclLjhG4nUs=", 
		"answer": "25+3bJnjxAvrtZdBtbE9nVpa1ezzT5ZRzZg=", 
		"explanation": "25+3bJnjxAvrt40hVl7mzfi/IWPZAGkUsGvDfYBEMHXmRKjRZ/nthdd0MVWNiFV4+3jB4/Sht15NpPG3iKTF1RMGntqC/9NpZw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gungeria", 
		"option_b": "Haryana", 
		"option_c": "Rajasthan", 
		"option_d": "Jodhpura", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160170", 
		"question": "24GwbdHxwxbk7YBtRw37y/q/NmLGCm4YuX6XW6x6MHzmWrPLYeP7zdd4KRydhV475nPet+Xi8lUKnbsb/YHfZyoKfYMvy9mf3uj+3nBVOslKxcLUscYlivSb5j46BD0eBanD", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjk5McAQA9YxWgQkeJVD4eXz8WZ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHxwxbk7YBtRw37y/q/HWrCAnIBonGQErRxYnSjWaLMeuTxx5J1Z1WHzUl+/nfSqqr+t0cAz7xT7M6wUxJDbo5g2NyMlbRC5q3GsmjMcDz+dd9w6HI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Mesoamerican", 
		"option_b": "Sumerian", 
		"option_c": "Egyptian", 
		"option_d": "Harappans", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160171", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdL8PXnVTkEer3CWQKZwMEHsQLPHfPS+2ZJ+N1CMzUh+5mLKpqGw/l1Pm6BeqYqQcSBDQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBHsdKg8Bd55INebljwzGiYcbeJL5ewXqUIlfpJyq0EHVn1DnXnHkWqoa++2e/Xck0zwM3hIJ8rcEyfMOX3OiG+F29lEaS02mFQbJqUVuf9dqg7gOYr4M690e5vaXANLZ0WTiOvdyh7Tg=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfmyiZZ/IxydhV47wHPHsKr+t1ocz7xT7M6cfzARe4h7iNWRx+j2ynBVOslK2oZ99toLdPEA7S6+ccbPKfFgjB3HsV2Wyam/lhN6ddyFSAQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/OGreGiI+gE/DQapgdWKjXamCeuX7iZN+Jl7JjlR19H/Urraw41sOm+hP4YvfXwEzPptqx8CF0qTkwWVVP8NA2pR64YgaPlKugdhqQxX0+8CcRa2ZPqY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160172", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdLcBSvDBnYFr3qOV61gYzHnXaOCYOLqiZtwNEjJi1RpsneGtaDi7hMDgKZcqZqWfSdDQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBGshRlIRz8JMQcrRGwzGhe8PeJL5s1y6XJlH1dXmxC3dznT/RynFfr4uvtS+6Qt93zRQ2k8ds5c18PcWa2LvT/UO+jxLC2nSDCLVxHFWX9cap6UqIoZYxusPPdqJEzAv0Z7+f9GYkY5ad7Q==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfmyiZZ/IxydhV47wHPHsKr+t1ocz7xT7M6cfzARe4h7iNWRx+j2ynBVOslK2oZ99toLdPEA7S6+ccbPKfFgjB3HsV2Wyam/lhN6ddyFSAQ=", 
		"explanation": "24K5fJThkRXl8IIpXBmyyPT4PX+QC2MHpj+OU6dxMGXrUefQa+r3xpkxMlKamFJv83TKpuX2+EFPg6FN4ICYPGIPe4prwd6Ol/D4hGVJNoZXko9g8NobaeZB2DSiepTUJr5B7V7ANEDkczW4CXV6gCKUoEoT3pV9VWUIUAE/3XPcuA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are correct, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct, but Reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160173", 
		"question": "24GwbdH/0Avt8pY0Eh391e36JyvYDGMDpz+UU7A0dn72WqOCZ+O+9qhOGGO2shlZSlZmW18hpnfvPyEDCt8u", 
		"answer": "27KtZpb2wxDrtRSk5NQCy4V8X5kb57FNiuc=", 
		"explanation": "25KtZpb2wxDrt4wuEjPChfX+MSvEC2dRrnCQRuNneXbtXaHLbezw3ddyKEyZiEk7+nnHsaGy+9QbiyTXSjVyYEuDyqPpvQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "gun,ger,ia,it,tr", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160174", 
		"question": "24GwbdHc0hH48sgDXRL90O/6MSvgDHYFpm2aEqBhfGX2RqKCa/X32oN0Ixybgk58+nrf46f140QKiqYb1rGgTx08QcndZ/VDRxBqM/wqp7AcR2Wc", 
		"answer": "2+foOMGz0Bfut9R1Ak6y5969ZkQ18nHEiKpggjhrXcdG3Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzxRDn8sUmQB//wL32JivVEHYYrn6XV6c0cnDwUaOCYeO+zJ52L0jJnlhy93jSqqP59BMLjrxS54mMMld90wMLcXIbKPZ6DnhBTuY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "3000 and 2500 BC", 
		"option_b": "2000 and 1500 BC", 
		"option_c": "1000 and 500 BC", 
		"option_d": "1500 and 1000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160175", 
		"question": "25+3bJnjxAvru8UsXR3z0fj7dWTeQ3YZpj+BXbFwdWOjW6GCUdLB9qhOGByIg187zUn5nJrPyB9Ph6lfqZqXdWIXdoJsw9Waw6TY50EBN8NUlZN78Ild4qQXNPxkDsYeRgvWMx2cBg==", 
		"answer": "2525eojy3xiq9oskEizzz/zsIWPRDSC/JhRM43Fpzaoqk+9Cj6QM", 
		"explanation": "25+3bJnjxAvrt4wzEg370ej+IW7UQ2AUt2iGV600ZHnmR6KCevrxiYRlJkiMnht6/HKGq6T0t0AGiKZS74eccSwXPqRM+JCN0vT413hVIIRm9r/FqT65VqE647MmGFb9", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Punjab and Haryana", 
		"option_b": "Haryana and Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "Gujarat and Rajasthan", 
		"option_d": "Bihar and Jharkhand", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160176", 
		"question": "25S+fJThkQ3i8sUPURbgwLDcOmffFnAUpz+zXbdgdWP6FKTXYvnr25IxI1WajEtr93fUpqG8t0cHiuhf5o+dMCoCest82NGbxOG3zHBDOtJFjol96toKcuBJwH2sdtvONL5R8VG/GHrPJVNUPBDQoM7AV4VZddZIQg0=", 
		"answer": "2+ToOMGz8zqo2wlPZGYuDLJ/AXJYg2AjYg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzwRz4/ookEhf8wfT8NH/VECIQ43iCQuN9fjHwXaDMZ+v3ypZ/MxyBjFly5nfSqqr+t1IJm61JqZqXdWIsXbsvy8WFw/HlwTP93/y8b2SggSWMuEaUfZj6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "500 BC", 
		"option_b": "1000 BC", 
		"option_c": "1500 BC", 
		"option_d": "2000 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160177", 
		"question": "24GwbdHc8imq54AvQhL3hfD+LCvYAnQU43eCVuN9fmXmRqbBeuTxx4QxMFWdhRtv+nOGnJrPyGwwsOrG6q5WikTCM/5q4aYZWEkR", 
		"answer": "2725epDjwRjk5MeWabCvBHyfxmWlnL3XSHwK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxby/ogpRgeyyvu/IWPVCnBRsXqEW6x6YzHwQaDFa/7q2tdhKEiMg09y83qGqqvk8kEOjLxS5oCMMgd9+T4Q4GS5iWRB1WpQwps=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ha,ra,pp,ans,ams", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160178", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUhQAr7w/z8ISvHCnYZ43aXQeNkZWPzW7THNK33ib9wNUyGglVosn/P44T+41sdgLhU5IGNYCoKfctpwdecxeHkhHhIOoZllJR36pQeebRT2zK/cMebKegu7WGQN0DiJzq4CGRn1sbPNeBMMQSUzNwx+TfIxVY=", 
		"answer": "27z4Tpjg2RDk8MUpW17T1+n2JmreAm5RqnaKEoV9d3n3XanFLuToibZ2NVWKmFdv52THr+fGooaKkf0+S5G+IW4csWS0", 
		"explanation": "2525eoH83hf5t4QyV170yu+/M2LDC2sfpDPDVKpzZWPmR+fDfOi+yIVlLk+dhFg3snfIt6D++VIKz7tM5pybY2ICbI4vzt+bl+L+w3lVOshD1sBz6p5ff/tQ3Di/NNfeLOp9jm+SIgX2aCv9BXdmnTLDhmhDuob5WFb30Inso55aDSVoyozQmg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "i Fishing ii Hunting iii Fighting iv Artisanal", 
		"option_b": "i Artisanal ii Fighting iii Fishing iv Hunting", 
		"option_c": "i Hunting ii Fishing iii Artisanal iv Fighting", 
		"option_d": "i Fishing ii Artisanal iii Fighting iv Agricultural", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160179", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUyVxn7yvO/ImLECyIFq3rDVKp6dHjtU7SYLEti3OS32KuYzFRGCOs1hxc=", 
		"answer": "24CoeJThkQnl5ZEpXRCyyvu/IWPVQ2Yeon3DH5BgYnD6FKTNfv3729d5KF2biUg3slzOorf7/1IBi+hL5Y+LdSMWPop9zdGal6m363JJIcMJuY9+648NefAA/DK5YNHJOb59x3qFNAmwTDG4EGJ91CvZhHkWp4X7xyaxVckjyBQ81spb4tgsOcXf2q2f/F76qt8BsyOS4pxdJJ/mWJFtOg==", 
		"explanation": "24CoeJThkQnl5ZEpXRCyyvu/IWPVQ2Yeon3DH+NHZGPiTefBYf3uzIUxL1OIn19oznjsq6Ti/FsOgawb+YKeZCcCa8tu2tWIxKS663JJIcMJuY9+648NefAA/DK5YNHJOb59x3qFNHn+TDG4EGJ91CvZhHkWp4X7xyaxVckjyBQ81so4zscsLNKNmauW5FmrxKVRwDYP2qAqQEozbXTXuig=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Upper portion of the doab,Stray copper hoards", 
		"option_b": "Jharkhand plateau areas ,Ochre-Coloured Pottery sites", 
		"option_c": "Khetri zone of Rajasthan,Copper celts", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "160180", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwVwz7yvm/ImLECyIFq3rDUbZ4ZGTxUefNfK3/24N4IV2KmQE7+zaU8/WgugJa3/gby63feStDX4lg3cTJhrSnlDFjEISXKfx3vaUzhLRRlBd+UVEV", 
		"answer": "27zxKL7w2QvvuqYvXhHn1/j7dVvfF3YUsWbDUbZ4ZGTxUefLZ6S++odwNU+MzVN68H/SorH5+F1PhqYb7YGecmB0bUUgOzmJqfaKzRS+0Y7o", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHc8imq9JAsRgvgwL32JivVEHYYrn6XV6c0cnT3Q6LHYK2smcchag3c3Qs70FWK46T+8xMbh60b+p6eYjEGPo9gydLJ3+X1zWVAJ89LlMB799oebvtVwjntJYSLcL5M7SzrvdUKm8udQ6dCn8UF/DeC", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Chalcolithic Cultures >> Importance of the Chalcolithic Phase to  Copper Hoards and the OchreColoured Pottery Phase", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "i) Sparse habitation in doab ii) Ochre-Coloured Pottery culture", 
		"option_b": "i) Ochre-Coloured Pottery culture ii) Sparse habitation in doab", 
		"option_c": "i) Harappans ii) Sparse habitation in doab", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170101", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H12Av548UuXQr7xvj7dWqQK2MDom+TU600Y3TiWOfLYK2vkcIieB607rOK2ZWZtzXpa7Fg+PrF", 
		"answer": "25T4S4T93xDk8I0hX1xWRS0v5Jf1Qtd88pmBxA4W", 
		"explanation": "25S0bYny3x3v5cUDRxD8zPP4PWrdTyIQ412RW7d9Y3mjVbXBZuz7xpt+IFWamRt6/HKGparl+VcKnehU786LeCdDX5lswNGM2Oj4w3hCMsoEqZVg8p8GPPtGjBSjcN3abL5n3S6DNUD0bi24ADBjnSXeynJZvIq4/Cm8FNt36BQgl5do7MZ8L9Ke1eia5g3p3lPRnE+ZQa4kFV2KtsG+7lGF4I85p8aItXLU+vG5lf6T5NYOIg1TrYpmI16ylKcc9j49Q9v0fxtf+aTRc0DkJimgMx1d/9ns2zR9zodpXGc3/RpIlsN/bMRmxdjSvT48OtQqNjqsqkhJ3ZVoVhiYNglJ2EJWPC6VduLCpAgGKSw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "A Cunningham", 
		"option_b": "RD Banerjee", 
		"option_c": "Daya Ram Sahni", 
		"option_d": "Mortimer Wheeler", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTl84AyXF7xzOnmdXzRECIFq3rDQapgdTHsUufWZui+4ZZjJkyZjFU78WPKt7Di8hQcz65S+52LMCYKbYhg3tWbzqT+yjEQapQVxcI83nWyPBbrcPBcm5TK5FxC", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRio09QyX7lsU5NfCmpYW9Yc5A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+3h3v5YtgURfm3L3wMyv9DGoUrXWMH6d1Yn6jXamCXeTwzZ89Z2yIhlJo5nfI7+Xn9kBPm6BeqZ2WZCdDcY0v3NiMl8z21nBRI8dK2oNn6I4KbvEH332rfcbINL5jz2SPNQX0biq+C2ZxhiiWg3IW+drppGeeTNk21hQmn4h2/ogpMsGa0KSW7A25xhGH0HfcWLFlH1qcsY69+UGdrsI7sMOZtCCb4/3tkrjS9MgKbAtXu8Z2bV2ulrsd6j87Rd2mbVJK/+CQc1HgITqoJgwR/IvixGBgwIMqSXp2mo1e3tyPAZEFberuU2OBVg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_c": "Lothal", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEhL7y/b6MSv4AnAQs2+CEqJ6dDHOW6/HYOfxhJNwNVPWzwQBVtO8QfcjY8lIcw2iP10=", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgkwft0vCTUmY+HgPjdVQpsqE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3/5MUSWwj3173sMHnGBmZRomzDU+N3YmTgXabOLuH3x5wxJVmdml5+/DbSq6Cw9l0Mhq1V/c6ceTYKe5gvx9bJ/+XlxWFRMoZFlIQyyZUXefpKw3CpdcbUYMpmx33ANUzmYiv9AnF3nT3fnn1CrYf74TW6UN97gAEgl4lr/ccuKNaL0KedpA25iALC33ScRahqGFeYocen5Q/co402od+EsyfP/fr+2uzcsMoDZ0hVrYlod1P8mK5J7CI9Qs30fQBJ8OqQYlHjNC2xNEystdugNT2EFhglqZEK3JvI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sarasvati", 
		"option_b": "Hakra", 
		"option_c": "Ganges", 
		"option_d": "Indus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8he72IW6QCnFRsXqFV7FmdXWjQKiCb/6+3Z90Z2DLgFRu/HKGrKOw41sKz6xe6IqjMn1BAOkPxPJCHtQTV4zftMIj9g==", 
		"answer": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXVzhL0u3C5plOXgmdqok5zRZ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxri9oAvXhH1zP7+OSvDCnYU43CFEpB1fnD2WK6CZuztiZJwNVKMiRtv+nOGrqr+/lgKnehnq4OQZSwHPoRpiMSB0qTzwXBFD4QEsoVg4dZfb/1HwjSrfdfaLuoux2CTLkL4cyr9DX5gm3HUn25fqY/75TW6V84+wxAh1oZ26YguNcOK2KSAqEK+xhKK2Tu5Sa9lAUSYu4647kyMrId4vcybtHLZ8fH32u3d9d8ZdgBXu8ZLa178lrod8Sw5UtynKBRE5OrUIVX5YDyrLh1d6sL30zR6zoctHWU98xdSwoxYItR709j3rDsiNtl/FD/6okpEh5dpUwODZry0kGzt7VAxZnMka5ktsyt1tQeZaFd3jGKQRTZQgIlk8JLJx/IPw7IP2h5Qa8s/0k34", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_c": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWh/2hf/wIWOQE3AU7leCQKJkYHDtFKbMaq3WyIVwN0yIgxt453rStrfx+xMfh6lI7J3AMmZgBBtseHqaujxDjLdUfFA=", 
		"answer": "25e5ZpDk0BXjtQZx/6lNlYcc8ZUg3/+enwc=", 
		"explanation": "25e5ZpDk0BXju8UhEg7gyvD2O27eFyIQsXyLU6Z7fH7kXaTDYq3twIN0axyBgld/4TbSq6Cw81ocm6FV6pqWfyxDcY0v29iGwOf213hPNIZGlZR6pIoNeblozS+sZMTaLr5vwGrAD0TiZimtBX40lyTanmlEqY/75S+6R98kgCE6n5Q46d09MJeQ2quG+Ey2hR/CzGmeXrRgFEfZtI695UqNtYd4ut2dviDP4frwjuGT5NFLdhpTvIM/d1O517wb+SQrV8emZRNf+OveIVXjJGizNQEa687wxX1myMImWykn+xxPh5dXboB22p3puTwkLI19HCeyqkoA05x5HwWTc7S33iojaEjGv+jVs3OJnwCZbrQ3", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Lothal", 
		"option_b": "Banawali", 
		"option_c": "Rakhigarhi", 
		"option_d": "Sutkagendor", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170106", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5UyXQj7y/76dWLDQ0oQsX6TQqI0Y3j3QabWa+mhi2YmT7lJd+xVR/+E35MlTDc=", 
		"answer": "24WtZpvy01nj+cUQUxX71un+OylPTYK10s2u48FGqkQJpj6N", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Eh370eS/Om2QK2MDom+TU+N9YzHtUbTWYuj6iZ5/Z0iBiBtL53jMoqew50EAmaFV6ovffyRDc4RrzcKHmuD23TFxMs1NiZRz6to+b7RBjD6iZtGbKOtsjmGGZ1H4YnmVBWJ1hCHXhDxVoZWy+S6hVc4+zxt+1q95/8ksLNbYyuiS+k6whwON0HSWQb5lHRSLsMOp4k2P4I0+s8if8TvV5/3+kuzAsNcFdgcSq456I0izlKEI9GZ4VMu7Zh1G+OecIVXjJGigMgIJ7Nni2jRvx4A7VGp0+xkGlotfcYBy0o7lsjE1O41/BzG7rQRTyJd1WgOPNosM3Ffuu61I94h3DA7DPtU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Punjab in India", 
		"option_b": "Sindh in Pakistan", 
		"option_c": "Baluchistan in Pakistan", 
		"option_d": "Punjab in Pakistan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170107", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt4ghRgvgwL3vPWrDBiICqmuGQeN7djHLVbXDfv3/x9dyMlCdmEl+sn7HtaCw9VYKgehS7YuRZCsFd45rl5JxcONnmEgAH4+Nn8VJ418d", 
		"answer": "25u9aYP/yFm4r9VwEGfS/ECYyEgzzz9S8MnsQnQ=", 
		"explanation": "25S0ZZ7gxVm4r9VwEjbz1/zvJWreQ3EYt3qQErFxfHD3XanFLvnxiZN4IVqMn1515jbWq6Tj8kBDz6FV6oKKdCsNect7wNXJ2uXj0WNEc9ZMm5N3qNoXfeJFjD+ocdqbKfprwHqJIUz1Y3tPulI+mAUKjFWmXMPKaBNW", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Nearly 500", 
		"option_b": "Nearly 1500", 
		"option_c": "Nearly 2000", 
		"option_d": "Nearly 2800", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170108", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8he72IW6QD2sUsD+CRuNgeHSjXKLDaq3xz9dlL1nJqk539DbJpeXT9l4NjrEEq6ouZhjEHNDzsU+/2DYQz1U=", 
		"answer": "25m3fJny3VuYITpxP058N53oQPuySFN1", 
		"explanation": "27qsYJD/nVn5/pE1Uwr3wb3+ISvEC2dRq3qCVuN7djH3XKKCSfjyz9d+IRyqjFZ582+K47bk9l0LnOhU/JrfcTFDf8t8wdeH3uL+x3BPJ4Zsm5Jz9IoecrRTxSmoNOPSNPYux3qTZ0T0cTizB3Vw1DXZiXdPqZG/tSa1UJo6wQc7go516Ig6PdSW1aGH4Uirykau02+ZSbEkEECNsN28+AOIr8IsvcjNsjvN/fjwgPnH+dEFJRsSr5RwdF6vhOgA9mosQ8mwbVJK/+CQb1X7KS+iMwcS94ej0GF70oosTykx+g1PgYtfbMcz2Y32/Cc+O8h4Bie7rUBJyZM8UBHWYLW92Xqk5VYwe3UmbIktvS4hqBmVPF17iSl8V5Mo+Uad0kjzwYO4NM6C", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_c": "Lothal", 
		"option_d": "Harappa", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170109", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrj45xgWxCy0fX6dUPREWMBs36NErNxYnjsUOfKb+m+xJZiNFWfiBtr82TSsOX08kAbnadC7IrfcjtDeIdgx9SaiKauG+skAyomoZ5+nhXJw11e", 
		"answer": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXVzhL0u3C5plOXgmdqok5zRZ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+0B7k/oMpURv8xvi/Om2QLm0ZpnGJXe5wcWPsGOfVZuTyzNdjIlGIn1B68HrD7+X29lAKi+hP4YvfZzACaoMvx9bJ2uXk13hXNoZClo994IlfeOFFjCmiNN3PM75+3GGYLkj5cyD9EH80gDnTylVYrJaotRWyQt8lgCE6k8d75Nwle8Tf3a2A/F+thRKL03XRQLRjGViQssa8+AOIqId4tsWMvT7e+vP8ibjD/80OZkhQpsZ2d0j8m6cK+T4xXsb0aRxPsfDYZBTjITy2NQ8Ruc3sxHds1cI9VWggtBZLkoJVdsV3lozsuXIzNttjGTqgolBJyJo+dhGen4gCAHrSDWY621x25Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Lothal", 
		"option_c": "Dholavira", 
		"option_d": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8he72IW6QCnFRsHaXR6JgdXWjXamCRuTt2pZjZ1iAnk9p+3XS46z+t3sOnbFa54/AMvGd+6nnEcn872dqPE/A3ds=", 
		"answer": "25e5ZpDk0BXjtQZx/6lNlYcc8ZUg3/+enwc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7hzOn6dWTWQ0AQrX6UU699PDHtUbTWYuj6iYB4M1SAgxtv+nOGi6zj5FIdz6xS+pqNeSEXPoRpiPiIxf32ynANc8lCnIVg99oePOJBwCisdtjeYPlix2OQNECwbjepCzBgnDSWon1EqZOr9Cn7RMgy0xA8lYI45MZ8KN+WyuiB7UqxiQjC9W+CCLx2BV2ftM28+AOdroZ4ptmfpDHP4eb8ibjQ/9AfcAFQqpJ6I0+z16lJ/C89Qc2mKBFE/PTCZFzoLjuqKABd9s2jwnxshoEgS2A4/QVHlopZbIdglp38rDM+LMRlG3O7rUAA1ZF7VhiYdbH4xmn26VQrfHUldsj4x72RwR4lBT/hTEHV/mPp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Rakhigarhi", 
		"option_b": "Banawali", 
		"option_c": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_d": "Lothal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170111", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5UyXQj7y/76dXzRECI8rHeGXKl7PXXiRqiCfeTq3JZlIljWz8H97bzNb6rpNLJ9CD0DZhU=", 
		"answer": "24axZpX7k2KA1yRUu5/EGln5h4EJNwY=", 
		"explanation": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXVKyxPO/PGjfDSIepT+XWqY0WHDxVbfSb+O+yp5nLlCAl1pv+3nI7+Xn9kBPn6dI4JqWfywGestmxpCd3+G393hPN84EipJ98pMRf/EAwzvtRNXQKe16z2DADlHjJymxBX56kTWWhn1Pp5avuWeoW8o/yQYmn4R5+c04fN6R37qS+1mqkwWWyWmUBP1lH1DZtNy84lCIqYF4tN+ZuDTa9+Dq2u3d9NsZcQtdrYM/ak+v17sA/yQxV8G3aRxI9KTZbxT5KC3jJgAe8M7twjR+yZAlWStnrN4H/l2v4A5wy28Iuk29", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Punjab", 
		"option_b": "Gujarat", 
		"option_c": "Sindh", 
		"option_d": "Rajasthan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8he72IW6QDmcQrWzDbuF2fHDgX+fAb+P5xZJiGx7Wz9caDQAZ5CIgyACcFnJlw/Y=", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/7xFTu9pcvENy3GtMJRrMeJzKlSFKBjzo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxri9oAvXhH1zP7+OSvDCnYU43CFEoB8cX/rQerGb//xiZV0Jk6azU9z9zbPrbHi/lQahqZcqYCefSdDQsltxNGK3KT1xX9GP8NXpsIy0JIWb7RTxSmoNNzaM753x2uMI0D0Jzj9EGJxlSLDmHkWvJG04yL7W9x3wQcmn4F57twvcJeW16uf/UmxiAHC02mfSbBhH0CK+Y6740aYpIs2so2BuDXT4LT2lLjH+NtLYw1Bq456d1K/16kH/Go7RMSgfQBK/aTVeUT/JTuwLgET6ovs0DR9zodpdWgm9Q9Wg40WcsV8xpTh/otGIJK7T6SYqlNtkOu5yAQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Banawali", 
		"option_b": "Lothal", 
		"option_c": "Chanhu-daro", 
		"option_d": "Kalibangan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8hf72IXKQAG0Hpm2GVuMhICGjXKadLMYw11bzZlMrUgBfsRK+Ct8=", 
		"answer": "24e5Y5n61hj4/4xiEb+ixzfldbMow0//YxkG4Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgwQvr4IkpXBmy9/z0PWLXAnAZqjPDUaxidWPqWqCCb+O+zI9hJlKahE1+siOW8+X48lAbjrpe+sLfZyMQPopix96Ol/D/wTFNMtRDn5NmpLIebvVQ3DyjNNfSNPdr3S6pM1awdDG4AWI0hzjMjzxDpoe+5zS4W8gy01UmnoI4+No+PdnfyaSS5kOxiAHC3XiERbhqUVuf9dqg7gOfqZQxucSXsCbS+/q5m/bXsNcfcUhTvY9zak+l17wGuDktQty1YRwL/eXCZlGtMCezMgIc7cLs2GcrzdKkZE3AxpTMYR2Bco/B+w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_c": "Dholavira", 
		"option_d": "Rakhigarhi", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170114", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrj44BgWh/2hdX+J2rAE2Mf43mMQLd9dnjgVbPLYeO+yJl1Z12FgRtv+mTDpuXg/1Icirsb5ojfWCMRf5t/yd7J1PH70GRTNpkGnxKTZpTrjH06kvd0KBZ/Ag==", 
		"answer": "25GwZ53yxxD49sczZN8LbTMagG6YTUfsV9UP", 
		"explanation": "25GwZ53yxxD49sUzRh/8we6/NHiQAiIDpnKCQKh1cn3mFLTLeui+3p5lLxyhjEl64mbHreX2+EEbhq5S6o+LeS0NbctuxtTJxeHn1nRSNshQm5R765Rfc/IAzTGhNMDTMvtrjn6IJlb1dHmyAjBgnDSWon1EqZOr9Cn7V8871AAgk8dM5cEvfMWey63T60K1hA+M3W+YR7MkHlKfsNy7q0Lco401pd+IuTfV5/3vn7jF+dscIgdU/5J3Zhu/nr4A9CMiUNy9ZxwM4qTVd1vhNTyqKABd+MXnlmdmxYssSWg4tBtfjIJba8NglDxrGkVbsyHjFoajrkP7Fj8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Lothal", 
		"option_b": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_c": "Harappa", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8he72IW6QCnFRsHaXR6JgdXWjW6mCeuX7ibB5JluOjEk7+3iGi6Ti7lIBjuha54rfeTFDcop9z9Wbl/D/xX8BF85LloFk7YgeI7bD/KRCyWIe1awC1jjCP7EV", 
		"answer": "24e5Y5n61hj4/4xiEb+ixzfldbMow0//YxkG4Q==", 
		"explanation": "24e5Y5n61hj4/4xsEg370ej+IW7UQ2MdrHGEErd8dTHEXKbFaezsiaV4MVmbzVJ1sl7Hsbzx+VJDz6BU5YqMMDEKeYVmztmK1ur0wTFAIIZF2qhz9psPbPVOjC6kYNGbLP98yWuSZ1H4Zjf9IHh7mDDAg25X6Lez/DT7QdQzxQchlYhq6Nt8KN+ambiB50CxiAOM337RR7skBVyc9emg6kSboZB1ncyGozOb5vH+k/fdsNcFIhxausZ8bFWokrAduCU+Edy8bVJj8PbRcUTsLmigLhgU9cL512BgyYxuTikz8RBBkIJGaslw15SkryIiOsxuVy6i2U3vZybIhLBDY/tnB98=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Rakhigarhi", 
		"option_c": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_d": "Lothal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170116", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geh/gxO3vNCvHAnFRt3eGEqV9YmL3FKPLfe7x35JjIljJnlJv9zbJpeXk/1ZPp6lJ6J6PcSxDfZ5j3MWb0qTLyk1PAcNFiY98vtordPEA5Dy/dcTLIfAuzXuMM1DiYnm0FzB6lTzTjjxXrpe+52eTVcg20AUz1JwLKlaLFjjNIO2QDPamqas=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMAieh6qx3MKmUMESRqkHocmat8tyk=", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRiq4IQzEgr6wL35PHnDFyIVqmyAXbVxYnTnFLTLeui+xpExM1SMzXN64HfWs6T+t1Aag7xO+4vfeSxDL9I9mZCI2eC3zHRPMMMEjoh3pJkKcOBV3jjtfcebLv9jy2rAJkPkYiv9DWQ2R6PJnvdLxKbte/cCyhdejg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170117", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdTxMX7DQ24YrXSGVuNccWPiRLfDLuzwzddcKFSMg1F0v3LHsaqwy10zgZpe6J2QfnhDVop9ycCZ1qT2ynUBHslMn45469cbfeZPjDy/cZTZL+pmjn2JM1Dxczy5RHF4mz/RymhercOS+yOuR5oFyQM3hMWl31dAqHtZhE/GtIJSI3k0", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMAieh6qx3MKmUMESRqkHocmat8tyk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3/5MUSWwj3173zPGXbBmZRt3eGErdjfzHgXbPLa/6+xpExD12bjEtr8zbHraGw2lwHiqZR5sObcTAMMstu25Cd3+HuhGZEIcMEmI9m7NoMdeBVzSmocJTaLPFgyS6JM1awZTizD2M2i1f9aBVmNlIaN1qAW8k5ug==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170118", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdhb9yfzpPHnRQ3UYt3GGQbBxdDHiWKuCeuXszJIxN1SInl5osnnA443x5VIfn6lVqY2KfDYWbI4v9N612dbyxWJOPZwEvoh96JsJdeZBjDWscJTzIexv3n6BKQX2aCupDXZ9lzDCg3NY6irHGi9EpCQ6gR5NCjWow5A=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiITtmvDYON9YzHtW7OCeuX7iZR+NU6Mjk87927Wr6T+9kcGgKYb5ojfUWD+EWo9SHvOp9e7QgxzX71L", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gQQrz0fjyMGXEECIQsXrDRrFhdT2jQK/HLuv/yoMxM1SImRtf+nnKorP55VJPh6lfqaaeYiMTbophiNaGxfD+wnhCMtJNlY4y4JUab7ROwyntZ8TeI/dox22BK0npJzylFHx1nT+WnXRP6IqvtTCyQNQy0wY3ksd54cR8KN+N3K3T+EW5lQORnHSXCKlsFBSxtNyp+1OdrsI7oMGZpCDetmdobIq6GkayFDD4QW3IkTc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170119", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVQ3UQsD+FW7FnZDHnXbTBYfv725J1Z1WHzQoioCeGorGw41sKz6VU7YuNfmIQd59qiN+Pl9vI+05+DPl72JPB6MzL2k+mDQy1H4GutUY=", 
		"answer": "27i3YJT92xbu9pcvEB8XbKMS90WA7+Jjr3oyuCw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVRHFR8ibRA+NweWLgW7HHfPS+yIMxClOBiFVx/TvCorf/t14OnaNe7c6eMDIKaIR7ydzJ2uv6wX9Vc89K2oFg55IeeftMwzq0NODTJb59x3qFYFawZj2rBX53kTWWn25UqY375Su6WtQ+zhJyl4l8rckuKN6Z2KuH+w2olAmU1X+UTP1nA0GavM+kq0qSs4s/vdme8TvV4Pu5jvDWsN0CdAFetpx+d1Kzme8auCk3XNi4bQpC5f2SD70TQ+LW/6Zy6fpSlXserg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "mo,he,nj,od,aro", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170120", 
		"question": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXV7m1/zxJmfRF2cC42uMEpxLT07ca5j9LuTwibJ/IFCAnlM50HOrX1TIGk5hcB8T13cySA==", 
		"answer": "25i3fZ/3kRbst5EoV17WwPz7dz/SjpnLwulczBu0rB/aZvY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA2Bfu/4xgRgzzy+7zNH/ZDGxRrHnDf6x8dX/pW+rGb//xiZZiZ2DLoFRu/HKGrKOw41sKz4xe6IqjMmIRe41jzdOdxKT+0GIBMtRHkoF365YQe/1DzTHtZ93cLvdox22BKUb1K3myAnZxhjjYjTxfppCy8i+vR5o+zgE91oZ27sE5MsPf272B4Uy0xhaQ3XiFQb5hAhSYu8ro+UqItYM0po/KBrojbQphI5j+3Kny7lRG", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mound of the Dead", 
		"option_b": "Ancient City", 
		"option_c": "Land of Rivers", 
		"option_d": "Place of Worship", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170121", 
		"question": "25m3fJny3Vnm/oAzEh/mhen3MCvYBmMV43CFErd8dTHca5j9UdLB9tW0rt0OB2Fs63hYG/Xtdlez", 
		"answer": "25KtZJez3h+q1IQtUB/rh1KoOmHFb7uQpUpDhnNy0X0=", 
		"explanation": "25m3fJny3V75t5Y0QB/mwPr2NivcDGEQt3aMXON1ZDH3XKKCZuj/zdd+IRydhV471WPKpeX/8RMsjqVZ6JffdiMAd4dm3NGd0uC3yXBTOtJNl4Uy8IgeePEAzTOpNNraNvdpz3qJKEu8Jyq1C2d3lSLfhHsWvIu+tQ+6Rtsn0BQ81oRx+8EwNc2ezaGc5gqrxguDznKFQbBhUVWavcet/UaRpYwspo/vki/jDr4OMAIC+Q6XNiZL", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Arabian Sea", 
		"option_b": "Indus River", 
		"option_c": "Gulf of Cambay", 
		"option_d": "Bay of Bengal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170122", 
		"question": "2565ZJjx0Bft9otgRgzzy+7zNH/VECIFrD+8bZxLT07ca+fLYK3bx5B9Lk+Bz/OWxwdMMeBUb4Xdq65Uqk4=", 
		"answer": "25e0aZL4kTvr+YIsV1ztzgj9O0u/1EEmXW+MKvF6", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHnwxjk5IkhRhf9y73wMyv7Am4YoX6NVaJ6MHDwFJuATOH/ypwxBV2Hild+zjSGtqv08kEcjKdJ7J3fZCoGPoJi2N+bw+X5x3QBPMAElZJ85ZcacuBTjDyjcJTYMv9o2n2NJkvjbzCtSDBmkSfTi3BfpoT73SapVconwRtyl4Jr+cA5KN6cmbuW5l6xhA+O1W+YTa4kEFqd9cOp/0aOqYM09c6YvSbO5vG7q/PVRHsUwvVPkMhxp5/bXA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Bla,ck Ba,ng,le", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170123", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2zsDU4YsGvOe+M0MDGjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMA4KbZ8i4fm12cW37HBTMtZUm8AypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9VTBEgT/ci35qpqH72CizUdQ9z1g2l5V3rYh8fJffmejTqA34xkbCnDvDCI5tH1CRicCLq2CUoYwwoICJsCDUtLS52riTsJ5LIkgS/8Y/Ixv81/tJ3z80V4i7blJo8OnSYE3RLgzjCwEJ8crvljQphsJpHSl0tF8GwsMWIoAzltik/HJwf40qVXPu42VCyIFoH0bFJP2z3Sj370ArfTokY8pAsyUwrwWTZVB/iGTcRSIRp4ll+thbWKw0b7532/nlXwBxPrp6qw==", 
		"answer": "25T4JdGinVnIt8hgAFKy5r2ydT+cQ0ZR7j/QEHIbtOI7nEbethXgl6/uuig=", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRiqv6RpEhfhhfHwNmrEBmZRqnHDYrZ6enDhFO+TJ9Hw5Jh5IlKDghZ/82TJ4+3SvhMGnOhI4JqKcTYGestmxpC63urzzDEJYY94lKN65ZQXablEzS+iNJz4ab5n3S6QKFb5czCyCnVw1DDCymhercOc4Cu9FNUxgDYzm4V59Ih0b56j14Sc/EW5ikbK+DLRQa4kF1uMu8ro6kGTtZZ45J7d8TnWtOf2j+zbsNENIiVdt4NxaVTxk6kb92oxX4iHYRxP+aSYNR2vtmcye+aouu58LIxSjvgd8Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "A - 1, B - 2, C - 4, D - 3", 
		"option_b": "A - 1, B - 2, C - 3, D - 4", 
		"option_c": "A - 2, B - 1, C - 4, D - 3", 
		"option_d": "A - 4, B - 3, C - 2, D - 1", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170124", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2zsDU4YsGvOe+M0MDGjFOeCLq2+idcxZxzJzRs7sjaG4+WwtxNPz+gbqc7fMGJDPssviJDJl6TbzWJVfu9tpo5TpLEecP1CzTOqddqbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWyjwW+cOT/DSoVch3xBwhgpVx7tx8Ndnf8amB8Uy2hzqM/juzSbNlBlWVvI7oqwPc4MJ49Y3N8XKbtLS52riTsJ5LIkgS7cY/QVe9lKNJ+is2VsSxey5F0qT0aVvhIT6qNQ9duYujljQphsJpHSl0tF8GwsMWIoAzltik73IbKtlpHXO7sUFBh5t6HzCDfryq0XzY7nF/WHUjYIRns2AxoB2TaBQ+2ivcDGwR1MArvpBZ1UQ3PUJFnXjzwgPJlG2KPJ7s/o74xef24K1r9+MjLECEd/INFpEJMEEGHiiuQTkYmvw=", 
		"answer": "25T4JdGhnVnIt8hgA1Ky5r2ydTicQ0ZR7j/XELcfY8AHVrix8iy33pIzR4s=", 
		"explanation": "2565ZJjx0Bft9otgGj+7hentNGXDD2MFpmzDRqw0TDPhWKbBZa38yJl2K1masRk7uieP7+X4/lQHg6Fc4ZqWfiVDd598iMOA0Or+wnhCMshHn8B76toLeeZN332icpTUMvBvw2uOM1awZje5RHNmlTfCmXFXppCz/DeHWvg2zhQll4txrYAedZeWyuiA4VmthxKH2DuYRv1wGVHZnce7+EKO4IYxptmfuDHPtP332tDS4scKbAkS99Q2X1WYn6cF+TwxQ8n0IDECse3DIVjiIym3Igpd8MWjwnxshqk8SWo8tB5Uh4IWbcYz8Y3uvSAxK40iRnqGrWlPz5FyVRjbcLyq3yisxBx/eH8qa5ktgG8hqQrcJVtrlG/cQyoRgIhuvtQclABfPy8IyD+swi2OhmmKf4fq5Ye8jPzj4Lhx8asmLE6MOlvRVYwQJaDJIGl7zOCYDKhfNt9mGSamNNs99T7xNIXU1jcZ35khIXTu8SSN0s/gK2y7v9LpnNV1ALYDM8KHzLx/jqkYJ+XJRzp4g1IDtg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "A - 3, B - 4, C - 1, D - 2", 
		"option_b": "A - 2, B - 1, C - 4, D - 3", 
		"option_c": "A - 2, B - 1, C - 3, D - 4", 
		"option_d": "A - 4, B - 3, C - 2, D - 1", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170125", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2zsDU4YsGvOe+NjeWXrFOfuZ/7qhL5YZTannjDqVteuDBrPqvumeBI=", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjkt4Y1Xgrn1/i/eCv/D2YUsT+XWqJ6MFLrVavBYeH33Z94JByKmFdv52TDsOmw1kEKjuhY5piaYicHPol2iPiIxeXn1HBPc8VRlpRn9p9fMbQRnmT0IoSLYO1/jmWNawXdZi2oFnU0hDnXmXkWu4qv8DT7GZofwQczhpd5rckyOJey1qCW5ke3ywKDznTdCJVlA1WJpc/opgO4qZE7utuIozfftPLwiOvHsNcFIlkL7dc9p0I9h01km6fN8QwoalHTSg==", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRjkt4Y1Xgrn1/i/fUqZQ2sC43KCRqB8dXWjQ67WZq2vicY9dQXQwQ0rojbVsuX7+hNHm6BeqY+NdSNDfYR5zcKM06T13TFVO8MEsoFg5YoPffoAzyihYMHJJbcuz33AKkD+czCyCnVw1DjYymhercOr9DSoVd0y/BsGnoI47No5PZec1r6W+ki8xgSbnFOQWrx0AVWX9c2951eJsod4/e/E8TvItPn4jvvb9dpLdQFGt8YtI3Swk60buD4wUMb0SxpK/effbV35KCGgZw0I9d/2xHF6hrYhVHp0/RFCi4BXdsVglozsvSZwK8VvVRu7sUVQ15VyHxSDeKmtwm2k8Ec6cXs/YJktqCUw4SyUKVh9lWeVWCRYl8Bo69wNgBZmblNOsXf0ly2OwHWHfYDmq5P1ke3j4PFAu+MmO0TAOF3MVYUZYfPXLnN6irrbJadOMo93FmLnM9Fu0TbxJZie0HQJ0csvb0Pv8Tmc0tniNiWpuob8nZRkEa8SM8LA59/3pFTCIS7gNWiBY4vkUQnjSjz31U5xvx1l4CAC6XLICYc/9jgBimuiTAgkkzSgf2iggrtYqouAP5o51rX83CEDmfN9o5Xf1Q89VxS6zTdn+8SWXBxCzEDVFsgDhB4nGLxBQNb1+36VmmDVWXkJP8j/E7uTgyVGmrKo3DA9i5gHRsydJQ3eyskn21elCfg5U27/u5K5KfNVCGFs/rtiyeK3sti+cbOlImFqbgmkVuxQ8oFUbEJsGB/VRTBHZfiGV48fUfBO3DXJggtcUm1MRVPCu/lRD1XobclTaRuY26SfZtiw5OSZtA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappan culture,Older than Chalcolithic cultures", 
		"option_b": "Area covered by Harappan culture,1299600 sq km", 
		"option_c": "Mature phase sites,Harappa and Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_d": "Harappa,Discovered first in 1921", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170126", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk1Avvt5EoV176yujsMHiQCmxRt3eGEot1YnDzRKbMLu733Z50NByIn0l6/HHDp/qyPKpbAZcU7ZnblB+q8hQgEw==", 
		"answer": "25O3ZJ38xhzut4RgVQz7wb3sLHjEBm9TvSfc7CxvvzyG3klUbjBhZQ==", 
		"explanation": "2523fYL2wlnj+cUIUwzz1e3+OyvTCnYYpmzDRaZmdTHiRrXDYOr7zdd4KRyIzVNy9X7KuuX/5VQOgaFB7IrffSMNcI59hJCb0uL7wXJVOshD2oF28psRf/FEjCi/dtXVYO5iz2COLkv3Jw21AWk0gzTEjzxXpIq8+yK/FNU5gBRykZVx6YgvJcSL3KXT/0SsjkaRyGmUTal3UV2Xocu6+EaftIs2so2MpXLJ/fPxjrjS/tkHZxse/4VtZlqonqYOuD82WM67eh9H6KTDaE7oJGihKwEe8tij13pthowsVG489hBUioxZZtMxCllEmnqpHllrLckduF8LUw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Randomly", 
		"option_b": "In circles", 
		"option_c": "Followed a grid system", 
		"option_d": "In clusters", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170127", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrj45xgWh/2hfDwJ26QCm8BsXqQQapidTHwQLXXbfnr25JiaxyhjEl64mbH46rit34Ah61V44HSdCMRcdQtS3mhwW6svVwCJriZ51LEJQ==", 
		"answer": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXVzhL0u3C5plOXgmdqok5zRZ", 
		"explanation": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXV7h0fLwMSvfFnZRtHaXWuN5f2PmFK7Pfv/72oR4MVnJnk9p53XStrf15BMMgKVL6JyadGIXcctHycKIx/T2hFhVc8BBm5Rn9p8bPPpP2DyveNGbIextxmeUIkbkciu8CDB1lznfj2pTpYa14TT7R880yFUzhcds5c18NdSQ16GQqGqqgweWnFmQXLUoUVmMudqhplCIr5Ah9c+YuD7f/fr+ibST8dAPIgtdspZzZkP8k7oI8SQ5Vs30ewtY5eHdchZT/QB4bhQoGofkhthROpCN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_c": "Both equally", 
		"option_d": "Neither", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7w1/T8PniQFGcDpj+TQKp5cWPqWL6Ce/77zdd4KRyhjEl64mbHreXz/kcGirsEq9ODvrZcGXM/8A8hPoXVSi8=", 
		"answer": "25etep/nkRv4/oYrQVy47Nf1BlP59ADNBmiDxT/y", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7xzOn2MHiQE3AYrn6RW69tMGTwUaOCaOTszJMxJU6AjlBovjbFsaT241YLz65J5oPfcWIOd5N73cKMl+vxhHJNMt8Em452pJULdPFSjDCsYNHJKf9i3SLAME35ZDH9E3VmkXHCgnlY6IWy5yK/FNM5gB47molrrfw0NcTfy62A/UGsgwLC1XXRW6lxA1CA9c+m7wOYtZA5t8GI8THU+uftiO3Q5NcEbEhfvpJ6cVK9m7tLkPHpHOwKhe5n/5u0SDZPOw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Dried bricks", 
		"option_b": "Burnt bricks", 
		"option_c": "Clay bricks", 
		"option_d": "Stone bricks", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170129", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ28Qt3qRW6J4MH7lFLPKa634xZh+NRyGixtv+nOGpLf19kdPjalP4dHdgCSWsII+UrTbmGlBTkpB6A==", 
		"answer": "25etep/nkRv4/oYrQVy47Nf1BlP59ADNBmiDxT/y", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5EhPz0fjtPGrcQ20X42uLV+NTYnTiQOfgb/n2joQxIVCGgkk7+3iGjqr48l0FgOVf6JyQMDUCbctiydSMl+vxhHJAIcNCj4x+/doTff1EjD+/fdfQM759y3rALkuwYCCtF2V52TPXmXlS6I605zO6RpZ30x09gYR5/sEyO5eL0a2a+g29iAGL0n6UWrRqFhSKvsek51DcoYw89cyZpTfV4P32lLjH/54PZxxTtoo9WCaaGAn4bGmh/JmdCf7rXQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Marble", 
		"option_b": "Burnt bricks", 
		"option_c": "Clay", 
		"option_d": "Wood", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170130", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7r5MU3Uwr31737J2rHDSIXrG3DRqtxMHbxUabWLu//3Z8uZZP6+kaXqylou3lndqsAzYQ=", 
		"answer": "25T4ZJDh1hyq4IAsXl77y73+OyvRB2gQoHqNRuNmf37uFh7Z3htN3T1eq97/cgZW3xM=", 
		"explanation": "24K5fJThkR/l5cU0Whuy4u/6NH+QIWMFqz+UU7A0YH7wR67AYvS+zYVwMFLJi0l0/zbIpqTi9UpPmK1X5Z3ffzBDbI58zcKf2O3l1zF1O8MEmIFm7N0MPORV3i2iZ9GbLf93jmaBMUCwbje+CGVwkTWWmHVCvYK3/DSvXdl3whQmno526oR8LMKN0K6a60ysjwmMkDueWv13HleQtMLo7EKIqIcqvMOKon6b5/z2jfvS49cFZUhGt4N2cRu9k74I9ik9VYihZhZO4/fEYFrpKSakZwEbudziwnF7ho8oU2gz8RJDjJcUIZFSaa8N6yYacEw0JkbZrA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Rainwater", 
		"option_b": "River", 
		"option_c": "A large well in an adjacent room", 
		"option_d": "Aqueducts", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170131", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrj45xgWh/2hfzxdWLdE3AUsGyKRKY0dGPiXanDaei+2o5iM1mE0hmJ2unqsBEOSbym/RK32Saq", 
		"answer": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXVzhL0u3C5plOXgmdqok5zRZ", 
		"explanation": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXV76xPm/NGWQCm8BsXqQQapidTHnRqbLYOz5zNdiPk+diFY75X/Sq+Xz+EUKna1fqYqNcSsNbctsx96aw/bix2VEN4ZGn4535Y4XPOBIyX2+YMbeJep9gi6ILkL4azC6DGR9mjaWnnRToZH79COtVdQ0xRFyg5V67MZ8LNue16aa5kr4hwiGnGiQRrRwEECQusDo+1Gdo5Yxtsie88I9fjBdtADgszQ3YXezI2Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_c": "Banawali", 
		"option_d": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170132", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hb88pclVl7mzfi/MXnRCmwC43aNErd8dTHLVbXDfv3/x9dyLkiAiEgksJqhbFOaFI0s5KJrQvI2h6Y=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0wvj9I4zEh/8wb3sIWTeBiICr36BQeFuuW1mla0hITU3OGGK08e3", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH3wxjj+ZZgWxCy7fztNHvAAmxRoHaXW6ZnMGbmRqKCfeLzzIN4KlmazVh05HPUpqGw4Fobh+hZ+4ecezFDf4VriNGdl+vjzHRTc9JNl4VhpI0WaPwA3ymietGbM/JvzH3MZ0D+dCyvDX5z1DCWjmlEqYG38Ge6Wt53xRM0k4Rs5N45fNON2KGd6Uq9xhWbz2+URf8ocsb69jJPWE2rdQTmkWah", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bricks", 
		"option_b": "Stones", 
		"option_c": "Wood", 
		"option_d": "Both bricks and stone slabs", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170133", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut4A2VwzrhfXwIHjVQ2sf42uLV+NccWPiRLfDYK39wIN4Ik/JhVpt9ymEtv3+pL1XeNMjee3KBfEp7Q==", 
		"answer": "25a3fYPnyBj488UhXBqyx/zrPXnfDG9TEsEIFFO1O54FUILLiYeMTQ==", 
		"explanation": "25C5a5mz2Rb/5IBsEhfg1/jsJW7TF2sHpj+MVON9ZGKjR67Ya6G+wJkxD12bjEtr83iGoKzk/lYcz6Ba7c6eMCEMa5l70dGb06T2ynUBMoZGm5R69pUQcbgAxDSqfNjSJ/Z6x2CHZ1H4Ynm+DWZ9mDjMi2hfp4385me9W9ki01U9mMdo6NovM9me1eiA+Ey7g0aD0n/RQKRjGFGXsIyMtcer4hit7mh9Vgc4t6jk", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Kitchen and bathroom", 
		"option_b": "Courtyard and bathroom", 
		"option_c": "Courtyard and kitchen", 
		"option_d": "Bedroom and kitchen", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRb+/4AyEh370eS/PWrUQ2NRt36NWeNgeHD3FKTNe+H6iZV0Z1+GgEt64HPC47H/t0cHiuhc+4ueZGIBf59niN+Pl8n4zHRPOckJnoFg68Vdxsqurlbv/xz3f9KwqlG4Xg==", 
		"answer": "25GwZ53yxxD49sczZN8LbTMagG6YTUfsV9UP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/0Avt8sU0UxD5hfvwIGXUQ2sf41uLXa91ZnjxVefBb+O+y5IxK1WCiFV+9jbSrOXk/1ZPiLpe6JrfciMXdstgzpCk2OzyyntOfsJFiI8+pIkKe/NF3ymketObM/djx2KBNQXzcjWpEWJ1mHHGmH1VvIq48DT7VdklzwYh1oRx+cE5L5UfOF7vg7f9r8wr1k8llhMF", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Banawali", 
		"option_c": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170135", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gdwj31+S/PWTFEGdRqnHDeqJmcWHzVamCbeTqwJJiZ1SIiRty5mWGrLL+t1AAmrpP8I+NdGI/cLdh+tWIxOv5njFpMtRFipBz6tocdeJJwDS3dcDSL/Au3nyJKFf5czCnAXQ0hDTEmXNYqY/75je6V993wRs21o9h6sE5MtLdzR2E1tdkzQs8mNgUiyRDfA==", 
		"answer": "25b4ILP8xRGq9pclEh391+/6Nn+ZQSQnKuX4QQxBtQee2c8MOBk=", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6MHDxUefDbe7r25ZlIhyIg187+3jSprf8/l0EiqwXqZyadi4GfZ9mxtfJw+zyhFlAIcdUioF8pJ8SbPxB3zS+NNvVYPdgymeWLkHlZjX9F2B1lzSWi3JS6IC38Ca1WNM5xQYh1CmMmZuTTM03Z1tKPJMC66U=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "A (Only Assertion is correct)", 
		"option_b": "B (Only Reason is correct)", 
		"option_c": "C (Both are correct)", 
		"option_d": "D (Neither is correct)", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170136", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+3gr+t4wtQhHg0fzxISvAFmAdqnzDQq91c3SjW6GCQ+L2zJl7KBGNjEl0smHHsOXk/1ZPsJdk1rGgTx08PPM3Ijz10YXWljcmPJ/UMQs=", 
		"answer": "27KqbZDnkRvr441iC6Gl0dBKUoatYAFBnix0xw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+3gr+t4wtQhHg0fzxISvAFmAdqnzDQq91c3SjW6GCQ+L2zJl7KBGtjEl0smHHsOXk/1ZPqLpe6JrfUiMXdscvyZCK0urj1nBNc9VQiJVx8I8NebRQwy6+fdbXOb573WuEZ0P/dXm+C315gT/XhjxUqZez/Cm8GJon1Qc7kI577Nw1M9nfy6GH/Uy0lUrC3XWVCK5rEl2YuY6v6leUpZAxu8qe/XLI/fP3k/7K+dAMIgFGrMZ8dleogroI9Go5X8z0ehdH+OPZbkH+YDuqIAAU/8Lg13pqw8BObqjWOcbAXf8rfJHUXvu4", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "gre,at ba,th,to,wel", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170137", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV79w73SOmPVDWge7nuCQKw0Z3DwFPOXOby+xNd9KFKOzVp19jaX9vejt15PmKFf7MyCqEux6jfbZiCI1jx5Ni6v", 
		"answer": "27KqaZ/ywwCoiTkjIHwuJAftPa+e6ndwBg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzr48UCUwr6hfL5dUbfC2cfqXDOVqJmfzHuUabRe//7zddwN0ybgkNy/3fSpqnptwda2Pkb5IuLdTAQPoJhiNyM2ePjzDFAPcIEy9Ugt9oSeeBF3i7tfdqbN/dq2mbMZ1D+YzyvCHl6nT/RynVCu8Oo4CWoQNs51Bwzmsdr5NI5fNaR3eia5V23lBKD0niUCLx3UVXZvsuxq0KOo4oxociOpSfJ9fi5nP3S5MsZZ0ogFBiurjdaLne68tOpk3jv", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "gr,an,ary,ere", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170138", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7xzOn2MHiQFGcDpj+HW7BgeX/kQa7RZuj6iZVoZ0iBiFJpskn5nJrPyGwwz6ddqZqQZyxDboduxt6A2eO1PsJPGuiv9KHoSwIQlTvNjA==", 
		"answer": "26ahe4X23FvE5cYcSNknhS/lYS9ajRV7", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7xzOn2MHiQFGcDpj+HW7BgeX/kQa7RZuj6iZVoZ0iBiFJpsnHUqqG9+1oEiuhP5pmRMDIPf4Vhwd6Om6TxwXBVJtRNlIcy944Nff1HxCntZ8DJJft63S6JKVH1dSq4B2R9mjaWi2gWuoq8/TP7VdQwzBAh2sd7/809KN6R3uiSqFi2jwCNznbRSbNgUVuLss+m4lmZpMItp8+Mv3LX9e32j+yRUPNKStxnpohxJrljoysjuw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "sy,st,em,er", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170139", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV7h3O7rMGaQDGRRi36RU7NkcTHqR+fDYuDx2oMxMlKAnE5+sM0Ea6Zu2EVzkwhk0ANgzNc=", 
		"answer": "27GqaZj90B7vtdO7AtxEp97D2RLhhhWjdm8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH3wxjj+YQnV17h3O7rMGaQDGRRi36RU7NkcTHqR+fDYuDx2oMxMlKAnE5+snLTpuXk+BMGm7sb6IqJcSwAe48vzNWa3uP5hH5Hc8VLjIVg4Z5feOZBxTO+NNXVJL57wGqFNULiaCyzADBnkSbXjXkWpYK19CC+Wd851FlyhIJ+4c0/KN6R3uiH4EixlEaL0nWeXrxwGEKc9du66UKS4Is2s9+MoibJ4fftj+rWsv0afRoPARoJc4x1E9S12LU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "dr,ai,na,ge,go", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170140", 
		"question": "24e9b5Dh1RDk8MU0Whuy1untIGjEFnAUsD+KXONccWPiRLfDYK393JtlMk6MwRts+n/Fq+Xj41IbiqVe55qMMCMRe8tuy9OcxeXjwS4BD8gV08Bf65Iacv5PgTmsZtubKP9qjmiFMEDiJyqpFmV3gCTEj28WvIu6+2eTVcg20AUz1rt20cZudZer0a3TzEW3igeU1WmQCKllH1/Zvc+sq0LcpIs+s8iftDzPtOTsiOjc49tLdgBTscZra178kLoM+T54U8mgYFJE96T9blzoLiKsagoc68Sj6npVyNFgHU4m9RFHkIpTcYBj2pn9uTZwPo16HCW1t0VMh4ZzUxLWfbP4+Gn24UUvdHRrZoN5tSgm4TOSFFoq0yuoRCkRk5Ju/8RZlwV3dS9JkjbNjTeOjm+AMZfi+Y+8kunj4LRi+60rMAGJO0jdWIkZYfPGKHUy2OyYH6NdJ5ZoGSPqfcU77in2M5OHnWHk86tp5aLvUjxiEUujIMU=", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn2RD488UzRh/mwPD6O3+QCnFRoHCRQKZ3ZDHiR+fLYOn3ypZlIljJj0I75n7D47f/+1ZPgK4b7pyefiMRd458iNmHl+niyGVII8pB2oN78JMab7R0xDjtct3JM+ou3XqBM0D9YjepRHln1DjYiXNEuoa44Wv7Vcl37Ro6k4ly4oU4PcWQmaCS7A21iRSHnGiFWqhnBUGLsN3o30uZ4JE9tsKDtXLI4PXtn/XW/spLaxsSuYdzcF78hKEH+y94RcCxKDZD/ujRd13/IWi3JgAWudzixTR51I0rXGs47V9TkYZSIsZ8xNjwtDdwLMxnEHOqtlZQyId5HyOecf2+33329F1/Zm4qcY9guSMh4QaPaFpxjiudTy9EhoF/+5AYhkR3dWoAm2TlgyvLgmSbdNP06pO8g+fi4Ktq5rYmJQGCNEjQX4MbJ2M5e6BFLArjGLzm2e7lxNM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "3 only", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170141", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+sl7HsaTg51IBz6tS/4eTeTgCaoJgxpCAxKT0y2NTNsVQxcBO6stfSPxFjBSjcMHIYO5rwX6MIgXgdTa5EXNxkHHVhWhCp4379yK9W8gygBQ8j8d3+cA5Lpec0L6a5ESihxKL03XRdLNYHwbZgcatq2qSpJcr9d2IviLX8bTxm/yT/tFLaQZdqIp6Z1y516cPuCgqXsaubVJ3/9jeMhTZKC3jDw8P+Nvz13p6hpI7Um0h9xpCwpFfYcUz35akmyc6Pt9rAXO7sARFxoZwRleXZ/3piDi0oHccNUYlWYQ5/Bk9pE+1JlBriSuMSSNBmIUr7tEQkUR3dWpJjjb3gziOkyWGctPx4oP5x7mUXOoWK9gWVPK9sk18/Jo=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMKxBijdVcljHShlKS8xxVQvAg==", 
		"explanation": "25e5e5T3kRbkt5EoV177y/vwJ2bRF2serT+TQKxieXXmUOfLYK3qwZIxM1mRmRc75n7D47bk9kcKgq1V/c6LeCMXPp9nzZCg2eDi1zFRNslUloUy9IgQeOFDyTntd9vPNPFgjmyFIUriYnm8Cmk0myXej24Wq4qt/CuyTtsjyRo81o5rrcszLsWa2rzTwEKvgxCHzjfRXLVhA1HZvN3o5UzcrYc2ocSCv3LU8rTtkv2T/8oDZxoSrJJ+d16xkqYd62o6VMG6b1JK8ufFc1X5JWiXLwtd0crx12R5x4w6HW098F9Og5VTIst92Y/ouTY3Oo1lE3O4sUtO3ZE8FxiGYLS33ii2qRl/d28/JZ5luT8w4QaPaFFok2+ZQi9U1I9tvsQRkAkjbX1PmGPjizGMwHeGf5aj4o68ov36oati5uMmOgGFNE7UT80ddvORfzciisu4Te5TI4tuGCymbpxsZv7EyfFVhCkG1WEEUHImgg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1, 3", 
		"option_b": "1, 2", 
		"option_c": "2, 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170142", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i0O/vOnjVQ20X42uLV+NzYnTiQOfAb/n2iZ5/Z3SIn1pr4nfI47b541Yc0Oq5ty127JkbgRV5W8dzh5FB", 
		"answer": "25S6ZITn2BbktW1UzG0jPIiUNTpBO+rfW44=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzr48UCUwr6hfvwIGXUQ2sf41eCQKJkYHDtFLTLeujthddiMl+BzVposlvJq6D+/VxCi6lJ5sLfYycRaI5riMKAw/H2yHhSJ89H2oF84NoPc+dTxT+hbZTYL/Nj22CBKwXgciutC2Nxh3H/nm8Wq4Kp8CGuWNYugAU+l4l26Mx8P9iRyryB/U6sjwmMkDuGSalhAxSUtMCp7EaRpYws9d6Uoibe+bi5m/bXsN0ObBxAvoo/b1S/lrwA9yR4Qt2zbxdY5aTZdUetNTumZwgS64vzw2ZgwIsqXH09+xEGkIpCd8F/xdSkvz09MthkFD/6oUVUz51yWFvWe6/4wm3o6VI2em84JYlorig4rgGVLUc8/bNpnLjSGFZAi8eGQV+AOw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ablution", 
		"option_b": "Religious ceremonies", 
		"option_c": "Swimming", 
		"option_d": "Storage", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170143", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17zy/PqNGeQCmwErXuCRqp7fjHsUufVZuT9wddjLkqMnxto52bWrLfkqBHVW1xZIGrGHY0mHEEBe+1I", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgkwft0vCTUmY+HgPjdVQpsqE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xf/9olgWxDny/n+IWLfDSIepT+XWqY0WX/nQbSCfOTozIUxJFOHmUly8GPSpqGw41xPm6BeqYiaYjYKcoJ70ZCG0aTjzHQBIcNDk498qNoMaedUzTSjfdrcYPd63S6BIFf5ZCyxEGVmkXHXhHgWu4av4Su+Wd851AZwP9V9r9QHM+IflibJzozNTA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Nile", 
		"option_b": "Tigris", 
		"option_c": "Euphrates", 
		"option_d": "Indus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170144", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17V1/j6PniQAGMdrz+XWqY0WX/nQbSCfOj5wJh/Z1iciBtv/TbPt7aw9Fwbm6dVqZ6NfyYWfZ9mx97WlQmS4GKUBdyAPgOVsYRyTU4=", 
		"answer": "24axZpX831vyMxJtaU34RFTpvZaSiTUS", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUwxzv/JZgXB//wPm/IWPVQ2MDpn7DYap6dH7tGOfGa//335J1Z1qbglY7wX/Ip628t1Icz7xT7M62fiYWbct/zd+Z2+G303RTNoZQkoUy4ZsNcP1F3yntYNubMOxhynuDIgXzaC2pC342LYNuHgdhv2IpbHYX0cRtNg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Sindhure", 
		"option_b": "Sindon", 
		"option_c": "Sindia", 
		"option_d": "Indusia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170145", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/L9NGncBiIDpn6QXa00dn7xFLPKa63/x5R4IlKdzV1+4GLPr6zk7hMAiehP4YvfWSwHa5gv2tWO3uv5mzMQRAw3L6KGSzyqYftY6Gh7", 
		"answer": "25S2ZoTy3Vnj+ZAuVh/mzPLxd2grWxNivdqCxDXUfQcto1Q=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xf/9olgWxDny/n+IWLfDSIepT+XWqY0WX/nQbSCfOTozIUxKl2NiBtv+nOGsaD3/lwBz65e+5qWfCdPPphmxdmF1va30H4BO8lT2pR64doxdfhFjC64ZMTUMupryi6lIFzgc3t/xunGnU0tEWnL72MVhror", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Annual inundation", 
		"option_b": "Heavy rainfall", 
		"option_c": "Natural vegetation", 
		"option_d": "Trade activities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170146", 
		"question": "25+te4Wz0Aqq440lEjD7yfi/NnnVAnYUpz+mVbpkZD2jQK/HLtLB9qhOGGO2zVhp93fSpqGwxFoBi6AZ3WYblIi4e9v8B79eCwgBDw==", 
		"answer": "27y2bITgk5HEbQdSRulpmfNwTxSuCzI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3/5MUyWwj3173vOWrJBmZRoj+QW659fHDxFLXNYui+z5hjZ2+Ag19zsnfV47H48hMhhqReqYqWdGIFcZkv7deQx/C3zX8BJ8NWl5My65xfevFS2DShfcDCYhwEk7U6TKI3kVfbeTUXhAU=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ind,us,ha,rapa", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170147", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1e/wN2rSD3tRtmyGVuNgeHSjQ6jNaujwiahOGGO2smREsnLUorL+t1EWz6dD7IDfdi0RPopo2tmKwujj0WNEcYmSDHafGnzYFtR46aGE6X8=", 
		"answer": "26W0Z4T02VvOHX89AgBjrlBNH9znuK09", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yyfT0MGfJQ3cCpnvDRax7dHTtFLfOYfj5wYQxI06ImlU78G+GrL31+RMJgLob/YaaeTBDf4x9wdOc2/Di1nBNc8dHjolk7Y4WeecC82SJoYqjzDmlz6hT1xNQlg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "pl,ou,gh,gu", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170148", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yzvP6IivRAW0Etz+UWqp3eDHkRqbLYK3qwZZlZ1WazVV05jbLpqvk/lwBiqwb4IDfZCoGPrlmz5C/0uD2mzM0NES6kYCohfmCcfxKUXBX", 
		"answer": "24KwbZDnk9eM9XNUu7JonZmUAOrDo4o=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y0vjtMCvRFGMDpj+MVONmeXLmGOfDLursyJ5/Z1KGmRt293jSqqr+8ldPhqYb/YaaMBAKectZzdSIl9P/zX1Ec8RFiIx3/doecvAA2zWodcCbN/t8yy6NKFf1JymvC319mjTYnjxfpsON8COyV5ojxQ0mhcs4/8E/OZeczKSH4Vu5kg+N0juGSa4kAUaYttqh6EaY4IAh9dmFtHLz9eb4iujS/s1LawYSvINtd1q1megb/S0xXsanJFJY+evHYlX+KSakZxoV/MLxlnBg0Ic7Tmx09RhUi4BDbtRmxJno/CIiPs5+HDC/sAZALE7EfKc9K47Jh+jrULpB", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Barley", 
		"option_b": "Ragi", 
		"option_c": "Rice", 
		"option_d": "Wheat", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170149", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl771r37On7SF2QErz+XXeN8cWfmFKXHa+O+ypJ/M06IgRtv/TbSq6Cw31IdjrhL6IDfczcPap59zY/LXv4tyaQRwSSFbmZSZWqiGg==", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58slgRhb90Pr3dWbVDXYYrHGGVu80dH7mR+fMYfm+yIdhIl2bzU90snTD46b1+UcdjqQb/YHfWCMRf5t/yd7J1PH70GRTNoZFicB84ZMLdPFSjDS5Z5TZL/Br3S6OKFewdTytFnVnkT/Ci2hfp42otSapUZoxzwA8ksd74sUxM9mTwOoUY+YKnbF6H7qHOm8B34jI", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Buffalo", 
		"option_b": "Goat", 
		"option_c": "Elephant", 
		"option_d": "Horse", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170150", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/O2TEQ2YernqQRqp3cWXmUOfAd63qwZIxClmagkt05nfLqqT+5BMNmrwb65ffZCoGPqNu2tGZx+X51zFIPYZjj4pz9psLI7YePl2u+I3wKxoP+51cLXXz", 
		"answer": "25C0bYH70Bf+5MePlAHMFHiRbjRRc7PPijoM", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yzPO/En7aAnAQtz+HXa5xY2XqV6bWa+m+zJt0N1SIg09ovjbRq6zz/xMYjrsb54GLMCYMcI4vysnJw+zyhFxEIMlUlZRz6ZMecucCc0jII1vpCvNNKGoJP+3rdQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Goats", 
		"option_b": "Elephants", 
		"option_c": "Pigs", 
		"option_d": "Horses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170151", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+sl7HsaTg51IBnOhS586LeCdDbI5owd+Hl+vxhFZUOcdWm5Qy4I8NdfpHjCmlcZTyLvp73S62Jkn8YiD9J3linT3fkH1CoYy1tS6oFPQY9FUmhJJ9svQyANm+l+in4EihxhaQ1XaQWrRoCBSdsN6t5UeZpMI3u42AsCDS+vG5nPHA+NcFZUhUsJQ/d1O5nrpJ6z8rRc26aRxI9Krsb2jjAmbjEwYY4Iv002ZshoknUn46tBlJkMNCasV6xNjluCQxMc5vEXOvsUZBydRsUxaYerS21ybY7mkxVjRrUYJopW0xrgKZO0B3mWqISSgRgIhuvvEfhw1gfGEAuXrlkjeKjnHBQJ3f5aSyxdziob1msrQmOgGBOxzRWJkZYqHBKydiy/uPTalac4tvEiv0fdAt8zf2LY/ana1mgiIWuCN8c2Uqg4EcvIA=", 
		"answer": "27q2ZIiz8Fnr+YFgcVzkT1/wOUCk1it43/xEMTqB", 
		"explanation": "25T2XJn2kTHr5YQwQh/81r32Oyv3FmgQsX6XErRxYnSjRLXLY+zswJtoZ1qIn1Z+4GWGtK3/t1Qdir8b6pyQYDFDbZ5swJCIxKTgzHRAJ4oEmIFg6J8GMLRBwjntZt3YJbAu+maFPgXxayqyRHR7mTTFnnVVqZe+8We6WtM6wRkh1pRt7sB8PcTf2qmH/EG9ykaR1H6UWPEkEFqd9cmn6leP7sIMvciftHLS57T8jPHX9dAIZ0hGt4drI0+0krFJ+SYrXoixZhVK9uHUIV3jYC6qNAYU98yvlnZ80sIgSSkj9QwGjIxCItR705H2/CIiNsBrByr6sEtV1Zd5HxiQNLu332yq3FsdOzofbY90/DowswrcI1pxjWXcSiND1JRj+9kL1QVna25On3PkwiqZgmSBPIPv6o7yjOb37vlX+qZnAUCSNEzIV4MPJaTFNWIy2eKSAapZN99yBSDnM5U+8Dj3LpOGzHka2NZgLWLu+D7ZkcThMGCp84Xwmtw2A7oMOpzJ6MKz/VPSdWPyNW+WY9/nFUj0XX3x3Q9islg20TIE7W/LRMl++ylNjX++QFBlhi7vYjynl71V5ouadosinbXY1TcZirR7lo/+0Q58UAGpiD9CvpeQD1pA30DfGMQCwEk5BaAJVIHQ/mGF1XfeTzwZcNnzE7vJ/yJrlKPFhmRk/5QBWImdOBDYi8ojzFelCfg5dGH/oYX4M7wwBmE88rN/3qPhg8K+NdulPmQ6fxu5Sq9d/JhUexZyEgrJACAPdLCrFrwNSOFBklDGkhdARnFdSRrC9LxISQyv6uXOfGPdYr9cKxLnc7sEHdq2DnPHMLGIziLABb6S1WKyWlQtTzSJYbkepQnxboXkIVOnnChF/9PsMVAXBJQfNSv2NH+xoOOiGA87cWwAJI9XckbbX1Ath37NJu1um6JAZBdtYLuuGB4qmDUB3wrAD1xA8FsfTOWsThMuJL1AJ0kQwXelELILHBPMxi4Ci1+OgifvJvREPFBtO1CbigzImoBnj+/ojJ3BHsbjKbgfkpoKPL4bS47eGklcmfry5u3pC20tD2J5PbjBUKLFuEq2EM3zq8zUiRxY3L0Adl4oZRSOmpDJ/y5sIqxOL3FEuTMpqdjBawfkmbxR0EkoREft8UTgAWAuuRVgLoD+adWcK4jl8lVeEjeLF6pGmfBrkWznOs/BYQhzR2I7lUeZYN3Y3nYe4rhAATUiI3cpXW/WVg0P", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "only A and C", 
		"option_b": "only A and B", 
		"option_c": "only C and B", 
		"option_d": "only C and D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170152", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gfxH6wPP1OibUAnAe43eCVuNnZWHmRq7NfK3t3YVkJEicn15osmLOoquw31IdjrhL6M6jfh4NTI5u29+HjaTay3lEPcxL14Rz9pVfa/VTjD6he8feMr56wS6XJlH1dXmuC2VmlzTFyA6SKLzEot/NdnE3ZL9H1I8=", 
		"answer": "25T4IL793QCq1pYzVwzmzPLxdWLDQ2EesW2GUbc9MmQeGdQ/YMyaEBlXclIpI+M=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUhQQ331+n2OmWQCnFRt22WV+80ZHnmFLXHb/7xx9dhNVOfhF9+9jbPsOX++EdPm6BeqY2eZTEGPo1g2pCk2OzyyntOfsJFiI8199oMaeRF3jSiZpTINOx7zXqVNUDjJW/uYMgRXAQiGGU6d6XGD4k=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A (Only Assertion is correct)", 
		"option_b": "B (Only Reason is correct)", 
		"option_c": "C (Both are correct)", 
		"option_d": "D (Neither is correct)", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170153", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdX+J2rAE2Mf43yKRqpxYzH2R6LGLu/r25llZ16bhFhw4Tb6rZn+xVYOnKdVs866dzsTastu3JCd3+G313BMNoZQk413pIoNdflB3jShbZTOM/tqjmqSLkD0JzuvDXN/h3PqJVHqv9toropffi7H6hyu", 
		"answer": "25T4IL793QCq1pYzVwzmzPLxdWLDQ2EesW2GUbc9MmQeGdQ/YMyaEBlXclIpI+M=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gQQrz0fjyMGXEECIQsXrDVKJ3ZGTiWOuCeuX7iYV0Jk+Ggxt//XPV46v/4xMLhrpe6pqTaWIGZptjydmHl/D/wTFAINVBiJR765RdfPImqYKajkKsx8vQOBKuHQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "A (Only Assertion is correct)", 
		"option_b": "B (Only Reason is correct)", 
		"option_c": "C (Both are correct)", 
		"option_d": "D (Neither is correct)", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170154", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71FnC9pchQg7zy738PH/ZBnFd42uLV+Nmf3DnR+fBe/m+yJRjKE+azV568X6GrLH48kFPjqRW5p2LMCMXPrRQ9++26NvIhHBPNMpBicJUNn2/Icz12lEOwJwzW3lc", 
		"answer": "26exb5nnkxIPX9k85n5UKWZ5YmMRJ5A=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71FnC9pchQg7zy738PH/ZBnFd42uLV+Nmf3DnR+fLYPn724R0JEiMiRt65jbHr6j/5EdPn61J74ucZGIRd4xn3JCI2eP7wWINc8VWn4Fm7ZQYPPUAyy+kcJTLIep6y3yOZ1H4Zi39AnF3nT3fnn1CrYf78CG9Xdk+xRsm1op3+80xOdmLmamd7A2rjgmV33qCTbkkBVycvNzo5kaIqYEtucKYonLO5vb4lLjD/N8FbAFcuMTYr2WtwZtWvRDHzEC0aEZb", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "rig,ht,le,ft", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170155", 
		"question": "24W9eoXy2Bfj+YJgRhGy0fX6dW7dE2oQsHaQEqx6MGLiWq7Wb/n3xpkxLlLJpVpp82bWoquw9Fobhq1Ipc6IeCsAdstu2tXJw/biwS4BD8gV08BX8p8NZbRIwyi+cZTSLr5DwWaFKU//Kj28Fn80nDDSyn0Wu4ar9DW6QN93wxonhJNh7No4fNaR3eiR6VmwlAmN0TutRoFqQx3Zgcatq0eOoYs2tMqI8SHC5+D8l7ja/p4pYwZTqIdzahurlrtJ6CU3Q8StKBZO5+HcbkToJGifKTITqoKj/nV7x5I5XGd09xZQi49feMFn35fq/DY5O8MtAXOqsU1P1Z1oVg2TNLW90WTw6BU+e35rZoZovSM5qAGZO0c+m3jcQTlSnMBq7ZAWgQxmby9ijnnumDrLoWKKPJDq/YnwjPLxtLBs/LBnFU+8OwiRFqQSJZjBK25wy+ecDKgQc4xiASf0PNlu9Db0JYXU1zgJkNAuK37x/S6Mk8G1LmC2v4G7nfuSLWrKUEA3zpmVnkv4LA==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kU2q+IssS1zVbDoKf3IKA2NImUSncxP/", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12Av548UzRh/mwPD6O3+QCnFRsGqTQqxmZHTnFKbRLujozIVoZ1SGmEh+sn7Hp+X540BPgL9VqY2QZTAXZ4p9zJCI2eC3xnBVO9RLlY0y0JIaPPJP2S+5fJTINP96y2OFKVGwbir9BXxnm3HXiX9DuoKv8Ge6R5o6wRsr1o93+Ns5L5eW1+i46UGxhAeM23qfCLVlFRSNvcuh+QOTt4x4osiBvSGbwPz82uvW89EFZkhBq4drZla5mbxJ8Tl4X8egKBtF9e3TYEDoJGiqKU4J8c6j0nF9x4slTiV09RFCwpdeZ4Bn3pH2uHIjK8x+ED6/rVAAzoc8XBiYYK+51GHn9FA7NXgyJZ5luW0wrB+UKUd3iSuTQmxZkYFn6thZlApnPWxMmXfujjaFhXacPkdyHHobeJrCeGBWgIerWIc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170156", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvv8IwvXF771r3sIGzXBnEFpnvDRqw0eHD1UefSfOLowJN0IxyKgktr92SGt6qw41sKz4Ba+4+PYCMNbdQtPRjZE9Qc04QW7knsDouMAg==", 
		"answer": "256wbYXh2FWqxYQqUw3mzfzxdzKpwL9GBfPABOoebYovT5A=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63An/5Yw0WxvhhfTxdX/YBiIesXqQErBhd3bmR7OCeuX/3ddyKEyZiEk752XDp+Xy7hMnjrpa+Z6efjFDfYpizZCPxev6hFpJNtJWk8Bx64oPeeYAwTSjccebKfAu/G+KJlbkbzizRkmAGZQnC5ICaNteKUgS9xg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Baluchistan", 
		"option_b": "Khetri, Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "Afghanistan", 
		"option_d": "Gujarat", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170157", 
		"question": "25OqZ5yzxhHj9I1gQhLzxvi/ImrDQ2ADrHGZV+Nkf2LwXaXOd633xId+NUiMiRt56zbSq6Cw31IdjrhL6ICML2CCg33coXP38yVymmd7/cHh", 
		"answer": "25S+b5ny3xD544QuEAT62kEevP3ioKg1yXSd//I=", 
		"explanation": "25S0fJn8xB7it4osVl7lyu/0PGXXECIQsXrDVKxhfnWjXamCRuzkyIV4JV2OhRt6/HKGgaTj41Idw+hP4IDfdi0RPoZuw9mH0KT11n5PKcMEjYFhpIoQb+dJzjG0NNbJL+tpxnrAMEzkb3m5DXZynTLDhmhP6IWp+ir7ddwwyBQ8n5Rs7MZ+sZs/ewRPIg+6xpEBxBo/2Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Hazaribagh", 
		"option_b": "Baluchistan", 
		"option_c": "Khetri, Rajasthan", 
		"option_d": "Afghanistan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170158", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geh/gxO3vNGXDQ2kfpmjDUKx1ZDzuVazLYOq+9ZlNKW6MjEh0/CyGl6317hMBjr5S7o+LdSZDaoNqiNOG1vfjhH5Hc9JMn8BT9psddfVOjA6odZbQM7WZUpgjjhpmUTmDx/kA", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMAieh6qx3MKmUMESRqkHocmat8tyk=", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRjk5MJgWRD90vH6MWzVQ20X432MU7c5fXDoXanFLuTtiZJnLliMg0879GTJruXk/1YGnehV6JiWdyMXd4RhiNGKw+3hzWVINtUEm4x96p1faPxFjD6idcfPYPFojnqIIgXRdTi/DXF61ALTiz6O83CVRLqyJKjyQFBIrtqd", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Assertion is true, Reason is false", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is false, Reason is true", 
		"option_c": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_d": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170159", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdX+J2rAE2MfsD+UV7FxMGbmWKuCb+7v3JZ4KUiMiRts+2LO47H48hMCjqZO74+cZDcRe8tgzpCLxev53nQBD8h4lLJ35YkQcq4A+DWobZTOM/tqjmOBKVywczayCGM0lT/SynVbuI+++CK1QMl3zxNyhZN3481+MIa21Do+folA1EVOKNzh+Q==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiITtmvDYON9YzHNe5OCeuX7iZR+NU6Mjk87927Wr6T+9kcGgKYb5ojfUWATvbJIqXxky3Fqe8jzsxW5", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRD+sJZgRgznwL3rPWrEQ3YZpj+rU7F1YGHiWrSCeejszNd3JlGAgVJ64DbRqrH4t1EdgKZB7M6ScSwWeIps3MWb0qi30HlEOtQEj5N3pJUZPOdUwzOoNMDUL/J9jmeTZ1D+dTyxBWRxkHHChTxCoIqotSy1W807xRE1k8U2mi24TDUha5xIQU1lJXxs", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Assertion is true, Reason is false", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is false, Reason is true", 
		"option_c": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_d": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170160", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt4IyUxDz1/T6JivHBnAU43mMR61wMHjtFLPKa639wINwI1mFzVR9sl7HsaTg51JQzRq/LBV9KZYzjuMPQHksxkk=", 
		"answer": "24axcNNZOlVr6ziA4eM6FbVLNoyX", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnp/pEhVhv+hfL5dUPREWMBs37PEqJkYGPsTK7Pb/n7xY4xdQvJikl6/HfUqqDjt0QKna0b7YeMcy0Ve5lqzJzJxPHww3RSJ89KncBzpIkLbvtOy32oecTTIe1n3S6PKQX1YT+0B3lxmiWWjHNZrMOo4SipVd0ygBQ8ksd17MY9O9KS3KaHqj1nrWflEqUVwFOeJcYrS6c=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Four", 
		"option_b": "Five", 
		"option_c": "Six", 
		"option_d": "Seven", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170161", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt5cvXRPhhfn2MSvEC2dRoX6RQKJ3e2KjVbOCRuzsyIdhJhyZgkho+3TKuuX49kUK0OoZgHuGKM0Xfsr5XhxuQ80G", 
		"answer": "24GvZ9zh3hbn8oFiwxo1yxgyixfnYDgjA7UE9A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHx0Av49oYrQV7z0b3XNHnRE3IQ42iGQKY0cnTvXaLUa+m+3ZgxL12fiBt64HnTraGwpgFPnadU5J3TMDEWeYxq28SA2eO303RNP4tLiIdz6pMFefAAwDS7fdrcYO1+z22FNAXkbzipRHN7gT3Syn1Vq4y2+Ci/Vc4ygBRylYh2/sE4OcWe26SWqEOtiwSHzjueTv1tH1CQo8es/kKQs8DIaogsdF6KOD2HAMgXJZwY", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "One-roomed", 
		"option_b": "Two-roomed", 
		"option_c": "Three-roomed", 
		"option_d": "Four-roomed", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170162", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrj45xgWh/2hfy/MnnRDWMDuj+OV6JnZWPqWqCCOripmNd8Z1CGg1w783jC4/SlpQBPguhM4IqaL2AfxCko6g5frJm8xb26VFPr", 
		"answer": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXVzhL0u3C5plOXgmdqok5zRZ", 
		"explanation": "25i3YJT92xan84QyXV76xPm/IWPVQ24QsXiGQbc0d2PiWqbQd63zzJZiMk6Ag1w7piOR8uX9t1oBz6Re54mLeGICcI8vmYXbhKT6hHhPc9FNnpR6qNoNefJMyT65fdrcYPd63S6SKEn1JzCzRHdmlTjYym9Cp5G68iL5wb6wD8kTjqWf7jO6iWre7w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_c": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170163", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7v5YBgRRb3xOm/NGXUQ2AQsXOGS+Nyf2TtUOfLYK3WyIVwN0yI0hl41nwdUddFhSANTObTen4t", 
		"answer": "25aqbYf60hz5t4omEgr6wL3rPXnVEGoYrXjDVK97f2PwFgTPvCwCiW1iTM/MDF8JB0M=", 
		"explanation": "24KwbZDnkRjk88UiUwz+wOS/Im7CBiIVqmyAXbVxYnTnFK7MLvn2zNdyNVmfhFh+4TbJpeXk/1ZPm6BJ7J2XeSwEPo1jx9+bxKT20DFpMtRFipBzqNoWcvBJzzy5fdrcYOpmyy6HNUT5aSr9FGJ7lzTFmXlS6Jez8DW+FviTHoorHF/uS89qCVYyskY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Granaries", 
		"option_b": "Houses", 
		"option_c": "Crevices of the threshing floors", 
		"option_d": "Bathrooms", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170164", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk1Avvt5IhVRvhhfH2Pm7cGiIBonaHEqp6MFzmR6jSYfn/xJ5wKRyKhE9y92WZ4UJz0jQtT5O70+K8ql7yOts=", 
		"answer": "25y2KJPywxXv7scesIlk43f1T3gRv8EsU0QN", 
		"explanation": "25GqaYb63x6q9otgUxDzyfL4LCvWEW0c41KGQaxkf2XiWa7DYK39wIN4Ik/FzUx69XPV47L15VZPn6dI+oedfDtDbopmzJCA2aT1xWNNNt8I2oEy9Igef+BJzzjtYNzaNL5jx2mIMwX4Zi+4RHJxkT+WmXRXuoa/tSWiFM4/xVUbmINt/oqC/360vTf3kdu0gV7GmYBO", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "In silver", 
		"option_b": "In barley", 
		"option_c": "In gold", 
		"option_d": "In copper", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170165", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0Whuy1e/6Jm7eAGdRrHnDQKZzZX3iQKLGLvr7wJB5M0/JjFV/snvDorbl5VYcz6FVqZqXdWIqcI9625Cb0uP+y38BINNDnYVh8MVdnMCB9lX3FrAWOodQz+j3iw==", 
		"answer": "25y1eJ7hxRjk9IBgXRiy0e/+MW6Somse16G8YaSr8vi58jxogg==", 
		"explanation": "24e9b4T/0A3v88U3Vxf1zensdWreByIcpn6QR7FxYzHiV7XNff6+yNdmLliMzVpp93eGqqv0/lAOm60b/YaaMDEKeYVmztmK1ur0wTFONYZQiIF24doWcrRUxDjteN3NJe0uwWjAM031JxCzAGVn1CHThWxarcFUXtx0NOkrkfJhjv/Rshgf", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Importance of trade", 
		"option_b": "Religious practices", 
		"option_c": "Artistic preference", 
		"option_d": "Construction standard", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170166", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF73xvLxOmbJQ3UQsD+BU7BxdDHsWuf9UdLB9qhOGBDJjkl69GKGs7f/80YMm6FU58LfcSwHPo533NWb2eX7hGVTMsJB2Hwoi3UF8X1nxWGrA0o2gis=", 
		"answer": "27S/epjwxBX+4pclEC5I1c6ueA1sw+Rc4DaMAHI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13gzk84Q0WxH8xPG/JWLcD2MD43CFErd8dTHLVbXDfv3/x9d0JFOHglZismHHsOXx8EEGjL1X/ZuNdW5DbZ5/2NyM2uH50HRFc8Rd2oNg5ZwLb7RBwjntYMbaJPssqZgmFXN0lPJcH3xiwwe3QQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ag,ri,cu,ltu,re,mu,de", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170167", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddZJk6InUt6/DbSsaT08hMOgawb6oGSfScRfY4vwcPJ1uf00WNAJ8Mb2rx8tdordPFZjCi+cdCbLft6z2LAKkr+YiD9An9m1CXEi3hT6L+1ySnpFO4/xQxylYZq/8E5OJeawaub6UO/gxXCyHODR6hjGRSY9cyp+VeZssIrrN6ZtD+byPrFlKuTxNYOe0hWtoI/bVSo16MH9z14RcCxKAdY9KTfZxT6KC2mK04h9/ftgjRdzodpdWgm9Q9Wg41FIshy0tjnsz89Ot9pHDK240hJyZ9vHwCfYLX44mnu4UYrfXslJYtjuG0UpwiUKVp3iX+dQm7RazYAcFIu1YMjVTOScbBf", 
		"answer": "2+f0KMWxyVfkW42bD52aFMevDcekaQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yzfz7dWjfDm8UsXyKU680fHjtX7SCeeTqwddDJlaInk9z83iGoqv0t3IJiKBa54eMZCMNPoJ8iNGK1PHlxWVEc/JMn5J3pJMMPPpPjDCoesDSL/AuwWjAM031JzapDHVm1CLCi2hTpYa14TT7Vt8+zhJyl4R7+No9KNLf7aCWqGW5lAeSzHqfW/1gGFDZu8G8q1aPpcI1sNmMvXLW+/r8g7ib/84fawdc/9c2I1mpg+gI6i94U824YRdd9OCQdVutKCm1Ik4I6s7nlnUp1Zs6SWw5tBBAwoFXcNR2xNjisyBwOtVpHTK0pEFTh9xzTwOfe7P4giGkwVE7fG4iaoRssCEs7U+IIFFsnyuVX2xfm8Bm+94NnAttPWBG3GLohzLLjmqbPJjt5Jf1i++wtLFmsrY0LAGPMxzMXohccrvFImsyguaLGa9TPd80XmDSQ3iOnIiXbBGop6akhElB", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "2, 3", 
		"option_b": "1, 2", 
		"option_c": "2, 4", 
		"option_d": "3, 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170168", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5UvQQ37x/HmdWTTAHcBqnqHEqFtMHzmWaXHfP6+xpExM1SMzUlu/n/IpOXz+1IcnOhS5863cTACbptuxpCK3vD+wWIecXHeg7yqTk6pwalasI2sCRQ=", 
		"answer": "25axfJD31BWq+Jdgcx3gyu3wOWLDQeFgeCa1oeZx1+GWhlgtBh0=", 
		"explanation": "25i9ZZP2wwqq+INgRhb3he/qOWLeBCISr36QQeN9fjHLVbXDfv3/x9dyLkiAiEg7/n/Npqnpt1wMjL1L4IubMDUGcocizNWa3uP5wXUBO8lRiYVhpI0WaPxJwn25fNGbI/d6z2qFKwXxdTy8SDBnnD7BiX1FoY28tTOzUdMlgBA+k5F5+c04fMSQ2qGS5A2rkgeWyWjRfLVhAlHZp8u74keZroE9po2LtDPP4eb8nrjR9cofZxoSvIlxcE+ugqsd8SU2HYi4aQBM9PaQcl33JTvvZw8T/Yvu2WZshosnSXs99x5Sh8NXcMN734zhvyYlLcxmVTa2pklFyYBvHxSZea25wm3goEEwNW4jYMpusyA4rgHcIFtriW6PDmgih6Zo3S11yRne73J5qDQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Houses", 
		"option_b": "Citadel or Acropolis", 
		"option_c": "Granary", 
		"option_d": "Bath", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170169", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17i1/TyNHnJQ3IEsW+MQaY0f3ejQK/HLurszJZlZ16ImVM782KGjqr48l0FgOVf6JyQL2ChayMuxBAnCJxx/X+hviJD", 
		"answer": "24exfITy3Vno9pEoWxD1h9Z50S0nQt6FYaL55tXERhs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Eg7n1+3wJm6QDGRRt3eGEoRmdXD3FIXDeuW+yIMxClOBiFVx/TvCorf/t0EKgqlS553fdCcBf59qzJzJwO3jzDFVO8NLiIl399oNffpHxTOqNNLJL/Muzy6DIlf1ajazDXF41D7Eym5TpIq8/CiuR5ox1Rsxgo5344goM5eembif6U69xgCNzjuSR7BpBFqYuY6q6leUqYw/9cyDtXLL4ebwnPHQ8coCbQYSrY9rdlqwhOrfO9aHrWgkWk19yl13V/Lp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Leisure bathing", 
		"option_b": "Ritual bathing", 
		"option_c": "Water storage", 
		"option_d": "Fishing", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170170", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sU0Whuywu/+O2rCCmcC43aNEot1YnDzRKbMLv733ZJiZ1CAhl536zbTsKD0t1UAnfcZ9FiQrpvR+hZlTLKzxA2CxQ==", 
		"answer": "24asZ4P63x6q8YovVl711/z2O3iSYkH0fFC2rnoDHvCdPPUWvg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH0wxjk9pcpVw2y0vjtMCvFEGcV42uMErBgf2PmFKTHfOj/xYQxM1SImRts92TD46n5/FYDluhJ7I2aeTQGestu25Cd1vzy1zFAPcIEj5N34NoZc+YA2zyqcZTLIedjy2CUNAXxaT39AX1xhjbThH9frZD5NrVMyreXkXqKECwbrbiBxg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Storing gold", 
		"option_b": "Storing weapons", 
		"option_c": "Storing food grains", 
		"option_d": "Storing tools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170171", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdX+J2rAE2MfsD+LU6c0c37uWaLQbeT/xdd9LlKCnhts+2LO44j15FwfgLxa5IeeMB4NQoVdzdGa2OqthFxAPd8EsoFg5YoPffoA3ziseMebN/t8yy6ELlbzaC+4FnVw1DjYylFTu4yr+jO6WdM2gkSAa0uJNB1D7EBuGr0rGOA=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMAieh6qx3MKmUMESRqkHocmat8tyk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/HWrCAnIBonHDQaZ1fGKjXamCQ+jtxod+M12EhFo7+2WGouXj40EAga8b4ICbeSECaoR9iN+Pl/D/wTFCPMtJn5Jx7ZsTPPhJwja+NNbeNOlry2DAM031Jy2qCzB3nSffhnVMqZey+imoFi1Jz8FbwI3qPJvh6Plc9Bs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Assertion is true, Reason is false", 
		"option_b": "Assertion is false, Reason is true", 
		"option_c": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_d": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170172", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjn+IsnEgr6wL35OmfcDHUYrXjDRaZmdTHiWq7Pb+HtiZN+KlmamVJ482LDp+Xy7hMbh60bwY+NcTITf4V8l5C12bW34X1EI85FlJRhpNojcqYA5DK/Z9HIYMJgnS6jJlHjJwWzUDBGnDjYhX9Tuoyot5C4i5saKvU8b0+HkD5RUJc=", 
		"answer": "2+f4Z5//yFuwo8gtRcpR5VdHb9SvxQyG", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2ywfLyMHjECmEQt3qHEqt7YmLmR+f2ZujszNd4NByHght293jSqqr+t1wdz61N4IqafiEGPoRpiNWF0vT/xX9VIIoEmYFm99Zfc+YA3jWketvYJexh3S6CIkz+YHm5C31xhyXfiX1CrYf79z77QNIygD0zhIZo/ckyL5W3i3QECAnXXPNNsYsooCef", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1, 3", 
		"option_b": "1, 2", 
		"option_c": "2 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170173", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVQ3UQsD+AXa1neWL3UanWLvn225hkIFSGmE875X7PoK2w51Ydhqdftsw04x7bHX36WG6te+6vAd7P", 
		"answer": "2+ftOMGzxRaqptxwAl7Q5r8yT6aDqu291E3A+XsTZljV", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7x0PHrIHnVQ3IUsWyKQbdxdDHuVa7MYvS+zYJjLlKOzU9z9zbrorHl5VZPp6lJ6J6PcSxDbo59wd+Nm6Tx1n5Mc8dUipJ9/JMSfeBFwCTtJoKLcL56wS7RfhWgJxueITBAnDjFymxTuoq08WesVcl3wx0zhIZ7+c0uNc2a3eiR8Q2sjgPC2neeXa9tAlyQu8no5EXctZA6tMPNsjfV4PHribST8dodYwZRuoI/alW6haka7DgtUtyhehcHseXeZRTpKTu3LgAe7cL10zRo1JYgW2g34AwKwpFTZMx21YztsjVwK8VvVTCvr1BV1ZE7TFeVe7Os2Wbx6UEmNXslYcppuTswrQCMJVFwjimUxlBxFgT7s/A7MsvDA+v8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "3000 to 2500 BC", 
		"option_b": "2500 to 1900 BC", 
		"option_c": "2000 to 1500 BC", 
		"option_d": "2200 to 1800 BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170174", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geh/gxO3vNGWQAHcdt2qRV+N8cXWjVamCa+DuwZZiLk/JglU78XnLrqDi9FZPs6Zn57yacTEMcNEv4NGb1vTnxTFWMtUEio9h95MdcO0A3iihcdCbIucuzy6DK0TjdHmyAjB5kSPVgn1YvJD5C0FiCvIjt5yYl7bgh31fyw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z0iBiBtp93fVrKuw/kBPm6BeqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgEnI9gpI4XebRB3y6oZsDSL/Asb6tWEpnisVTnhAjPqlynnA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7xzOv2OWLKAnYYrHHDRaJnMHLmWrPHfOj6iZZjKEmHiRtv4HfCpuXx+VdPjKdW5IuNcydPPophzJCd3+G3w35XNtRKm45x4dodZbRNyS+ufNXVNL5twm+TNAX2ciupDHVm1CLDmmxZupeotTOzXcl3xRginoZr5Nt+fDW5QDUGWUK225HiBXcuXg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are correct and the reason is the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are correct but the reason is not the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct but reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both assertion and reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170175", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofEh/mhdDwPW7eCW0Vom2MEq51aTHrVbHHLu/7zJkxMk+MiRt9/WSGoqf84kcGgKYZXrqufy3kFa2V4LiSNaF8Fw==", 
		"answer": "25KqbZDnkTvr441iYseeQpUTLfiVZ1NvUfxKpA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHPkz748oQ0Ejzz0fXDdyvRFyI8rHeGXKl7PXXiRqiOLuzwiZJ9Jl6Gn1pv9zbRorH15RMbjqZQqZmWZCpDbZ9q2MPFl+n+w3lVc85FjIUy5p8acrRV3zipNNLUMr5vzGKVM0z/aXX9FGVmnTffiX1CoYy1tTWyQM82zAZ+1ohqrcszMdqK16mfqE+5kg6L0nzRTKhhUUCW9ce8+AOdpJQ5u86ItXLM9eD8iLje8dAKZQ1fuohrI1qyk+gK/SQsQ8m4KB5E8uXEaFvjYD+qMwYU94v33nEpxYs9RCtTSgfXQcgyjP4LrxXWhAik", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Granary", 
		"option_b": "Citadel", 
		"option_c": "Great Bath", 
		"option_d": "Assembly Hall", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170176", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fLfaL/25IxM06ciBt68HnTt+XY9kEOn7ha5868ZS4Xa5lql5C12bW58HlEc8VNjpky65xfVPVSzS29dZTTIfou2nmPalf/aDS4ADB8myTFj28WroyptSWuRt821RYgl5NrrckyOJeS3LqQ4Ey2khW+0jutRu8qUXyYp8+4+0KS4JAtucifonLM8eb82ujB+dMKcAFepsZ5bFiphK0NuCU2Ecu7ZgNe9PfEXVrRLmjwaToV/Ivu12B81IdpdWgm9Q9Wg40WYdV/wo32uXI9PsRkATKzrUFEh5U8ShmfcrKq3Sjo6VM6Zm4yaY8vSojbNNZJPwaeiauI3ii2Og==", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7xzOnmdWPRByIFtHDOQKx7fXTnFK/Ne/772tdhKE+ahFl36zbArLew9kEbhrta553fcSwHPoduyt+b0vbkhENUP8NWicBl4YgaPPlP3jjtd9vVI/t8wGuEZ1L5czH9B395mTTEiXkWvIu6+2e4W9Qm1RAhgsdM5c18MdaLzLqWqGW5lAeSzHqfCL5xHUCMp8vo6lOMpYMqpo2ZvnLT9eL82vXS+dAfYwFcuoI/YhupmaEP9zg1EcS9bhdY5f3cZBaBOkDQo43hC7W8AtZp0rOv", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170177", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5UvQQ37x/HmdWjfD24UoGuGVuN1YzH3Vb+CZ+O+4ZZjJkyZjFU78WPKt7Di8gxNR1SRWeLNDKPNw6RYiB/+1g==", 
		"answer": "25KqaZj9k8wGsKsr0AXEbSyvbR6s9+o=", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRjk5MUwXQ3hzP/zLCvTDG4dpnyXV6c0cXbxXaTXYvnr25Z9Z0ybgl9u8XOK47H170cGg61Ipc6efiZDaIpj3dGL2+G31nRSPNNWmYVhpJsMPPUAyjK/eZTUJr56z3bAE035dHmvAWN7gSPVjzxVp4+38CSvXdU5gAYnhpd3/9w5OJeL0a3T7li2hRKL03WYRrokHlLZtsum/1GdrIsisMnNsDbW/frwiezB8coCbQYe/49xZUm9hLwb7SksRNqxKBZO5+HcbkTgJSa3a04c98+jxXtqz4c9XGV0+hpDhpAUFSNtzA/2sr5uBWI2Z5Hy4A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Money", 
		"option_b": "Jewelry", 
		"option_c": "Grain", 
		"option_d": "Livestock", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170178", 
		"question": "2525epDjwRjkt5c1Xhvg1r3oMHnVQ28esXrDVKx3ZWLmUOfNYK3pwZZlZ1WHnk9+83KGrKOw9FwBnr1e+pqML2B9ZuIh4yUf62fz2WTx3sId", 
		"answer": "25a3ZZz2wxrvtTeYZ3n5oq/O6hx3q574VkQ=", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRjkt5c1Xhvg1r3vJ2LfEWsFqmWGVuNgeHSjQ6LOYqD8zJ5/IByGixtv+nPPseXg8lwfg60b6ICbMDYLe8tiydmHw+H5xX9CNoZLnMBm7J8WbrRDxSmkccebKfB92muBIwX/YXmtEWJngTjYjTxboY+y4SapTZo0zxsjg4Jr+dt8CN+amaua/kS0jxyDyHKeRvp3UVKWttu7q0yS4Jcqt8yD8SLX9fr3k/bUvJ4CbA5AvpVrcU6/g70b/WZ4UMawKBVE5+HCb1XjIy3jJAET7dnq1GF9w4ZpSWZ0/QtVwpBCY8J62pHwpXIxMckqBSG1sFRF1Z1oRlXmByuteP7zgNWjdEVG7TVM", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Religious rituals", 
		"option_b": "Arts", 
		"option_c": "Agriculture", 
		"option_d": "Commerce", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170179", 
		"question": "2525epDjwRjk5MUtWxn60b33NH3VQ2Eer3OGUbdxdDHca5j9UdLBiZZiZ13Ji1Rp/zbJpeXk9ktNVaOVngAkEZrltWVrWy3X4Q==", 
		"answer": "27KqaZj9k1ovD1zqxIqT6tw8V14rTnk=", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRjk5MUwXQr3y+n2NGfcGiISrHOPV6BgdXWjV6jPY+L6wIN4Ik/JgVJw9zbBsaT5+UBDz7xe8ZqWfCcQMstg2pCb0vf40WNCNtUEm5My5doZc+ZNjDKrNMDaOLIu3XuQN0riczCzAzBgnDTfmDxXrI6y+y6oQMg21Bw9mMd548x8NdmZy6mA/F+thRKXzn7RfLVtAhSJp8+r/0qfpcI5vMmItXLI+/fwn+zS/J4YdglQtop2d0L8lqYNuC49R824ZwJG9OrEI1uTw/adV6Ja/OHMwIT8FK0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "gra,in,pl,use", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "170180", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjn+IsnEgr6wL35OmfcDHUYrXjDRaJnMF/MYOfDLuv7yINkNVnJgl075n7D443x5VIfn6lVqb2LcTYGIctTxpDYl8L41mVINc9Hm5R765QMPP1OjD6kYN3eM75SwDzABkuwaCu6BX59jjTSym9CqY2//Cm8FNslzQwOmNQ42ckkOcTf2qef5Ei7kgOGnHKfCLp2EF2XicD8q3eZrZI0sN7NsCab8eL8iOGT49cfZ0qtF5xTIV0UtZy0b27F+WgA", 
		"answer": "2+H4Z5//yFvHpGQswfmI+t/GdIBD3YAt", 
		"explanation": "25O3eoX61xDp9pEpXRCy0vzsdWqQBWcQt2qRV+N7djHwUbHHfOzyiZR4M1WMnhc783jC44H4+F8OmaFJ6M6XcSZDeIR93MPJwO3jzHhPc8BLiJRhpK4eZPFTjDCkc9zPYPZv2GvAJUD1aXm+C3x4kTLCj3gWoY378jW6XdR37hpygoJ1/cQ5L5eX2L6WqE+9gwjC2nSERrkkEEDZtMCxq2udsoMopcyD8SHS4PG74QBSfSPsYrEbtPIIRkW4+Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Introduction to Polity", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "3 only", 
		"option_d": "4 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180101", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR7l84ElQQ2ywfT7dX/YBiI5om2CQrN1fmKjRKjRfeT8xY4xIk2cjE9+smHPt62w41sKz4ZS5Yvfdy0Heo5825CgxO3kmzMJkywoC3xeHhIi3AJd7a6e", 
		"answer": "25C5eoX7kR7l84ElQQ2wu1Hy5235dWye3H0SZ+tVMw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1fLsJmLSD3tRpm6WU7dxdDH3XKKCaeL6zZJiNByGixtv+nOGjaz88h9PprtS+sLfZysXdst7wNWAxaT4038BNsdWjogy45UbePFT332ZfN3IYO17yWmFNFHjJzqoCGRhhjDayn9Zpo2+9jOyW9QkgBc3gpB96MZ8KN+amYCS+kyolgeMnHiYXrRoGE6Yocen5QOdroZ4tMOOuDfV4LTcneHD5NcKbEhQuop2Zl2v2+gB8S0wXcGzYAZC/+OQdVzoYDuqIAAU/8Lg13pqw8ImWyk1tApIi5VTcNNy2tj2uSQ1LchkFjb6pUtSh5J5TQOfeLSsySjl7lF/eXMtYMdqtTs8rwjcLltsmW6PDkRRyjeOhebqZFMXURQ4TbI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Earth goddess", 
		"option_b": "Sun goddess", 
		"option_c": "Water goddess", 
		"option_d": "Sky goddess", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180102", 
		"question": "24GwbdH31Anj9JEpXRCyyvu/ImPZAGpRpHCHEqx6MHCjR6LDYq3twZhmNByBhFY74WPUsarl+VcKi+hZ8M6efisOf4d8l5LFDvs7ph3YRdJ42MfgeNEh", 
		"answer": "24W5e5nmwRj+/sUNUxbzwfjpNCkFYTLgbWVogMuHdf1NQOJ4", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1Bjmt4ElQhfx0fTxMivRQ2oesXGGVuNwdXj3TefRe//sxoJ/I1mNzVlisnfIqqjx+0BPhrsb64uTeScVe48v3N/JxeHn1nRSNshQ2pR64doYc/AA/Dy+fMHLIepnjlqILlawdzavEGJ1jTDaynVYrIq49DO+R5o/yQZyhIh06Ig9L5eemaya/kS2g0aSznSFTb5wHkbZusjo6k2VrYM0poHNoivW9vv1k+La/tlLdgBX/65+cVqsh6kH6214Use6ZhdI5e3fbxT5L2itJhoI686j13pthpYhWGAmtA1DkZNTYdQz0Jf2/CY4Oo1rGzq3okgAzJ1yWBOZef9yxg2SgVvQJ8ND86Whbwww", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Brahma", 
		"option_b": "Vishnu", 
		"option_c": "Shiva", 
		"option_d": "Pashupati Mahadeva", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ348oBgVhf2hen3MCvABm0Br3rDXaU0ZHnmFI7MavjtiYV0IFWGgxts/WTVq6zgqBHlrQyTdmox8oJB3elcLdao", 
		"answer": "24WxeJD/kxLD32Ww2tEPsW/fDrBqwdQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy0fX6dULeB3cC422GVap7fjH0W7XRZuTuzJMxM1SMzUty4nfK47Hi8lZPx45S6puMMDAGcoJowd+a1q27hHBNIMkEkY5985RffecA2DWoNMfaI+xryi6GLkKwcyu4ATBAnDjFymhErYb7/SK3UJok0Bwgn5Nt7MR8L96Y16GV4U65iAWHkDuCUbBmHliQr8em7AObso0vocXB8SXS5/D2l7ST8dAPIg1cs494a0+5maUM9j50Ecm6bFJC5feQc1H7JTqmKQ0YucLwlnF/z4YsU310/REGi5dFIsR2xpHnqDs/MY1lG3OppkVM1NR9URPWda+s2W7l40EsNw+atYytxXq/OQlgILJzUUg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Banyan", 
		"option_b": "Oak", 
		"option_c": "Cedar", 
		"option_d": "Pipal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180104", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geh/gxO3vNGXDQ3AUtXqRV6c0ZHnmFKDNaun72oQxKFrJiFpp5n6Gn6vM+WEKjrtU59TfXjcOe5lg3cPJw+Hl1nBCPNJQm8B07Z0Kbv1OyS7te9KbN/Fjy2DAL0TmYnm/AXV61DfZn3JS6Iq1tQ+6Rtsn0BRwTnY0V+2I8KX4IUWQGS1mzA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z0iBiBtp93fVrKuw/kBPm6BeqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgEnI9gpI4XebRB3y6oZsDSL/Asb6tWEpnisVTnhAjPqlynnA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Av49oYvRgrzhfv2Mn7CCmwUsD+RV7NmdWLmWrOCeuX7iZB+I1iMnkg7/XCGpqTi41tDz7tT5pmccTEKcIwv3NiMl8z21nBRI8dK3ZMy9p8JeeZFwj6oNMDUN/98yn3AL0DiJfcS0I63ML0q4rhjIcb0cQQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are correct and the reason is the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are correct but the reason is not the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct but reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both assertion and reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180105", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yyfLwPm7UQ3cBrHHDRqtxMHTiRrPKLuztiZYxGGO2smREzTbBrKH08kAczZUf8j3zHPD4Tt0ezqM2r40=", 
		"answer": "27O9eoX63RD+7sfmzAxMHJU/Q8CrtmCOon+7", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1/j4NHnUBmZRt3eGEqZ1YmXrFKbRLuy+x4JjM0mbhFV8snHJp6H15EBDz7pe74KaczYKcIwv3NiM3va3x35PPcNHjol96toLc7ROzSm4ZtGcM75oy3yULkn5cyD9BX5w1CLDmWhTpoK19iL7YNI+01UxmYl76NgofN6R36SG7UO7gwLCyHOUQa8kA1GVvMmh5FaP4IA9ucSItyGb9fr92vnB5JJLZwVCt4dsakG1ma9J7CI9Edu9bxxC9+3TYFruJWisIU4c/tnq1WFl0pc7WCk1+hsGlotTIsV9wJH2szw9OsN+V0fVxJFkj/XRsywBBp8o+Ac=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "fe,rt,il,ity,iti", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180106", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1/jpMHnVByIFq3rDbZxLT07ca+fWfOj7iZZiZ1WdzVh6/DbEpuXj8lYBz6dVqYOefjtDbY5uxMPLqkkk5aE2c85WVUNkSqGkVw==", 
		"answer": "26WxeJD/k4TqYJJxzl5YNp9MNPDteEc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg0Br48oFgVBf1hentMG6cQ2YUs3aARqZwMH7tFLTHb+Hthdd5IlCNzUhr+2TPt7Dx+xMGgrhU+5qefiEGPo1g2pCd3+G37HBTMtZUm45hqNoPc+dTxT+hbZTIOfNswWKJPUz+YHm6Fn9jgDmaymtfu4e0+Gv7VdQzgAYin5Vx+d09MJea16Sa70WsgwiP2XWFCg/HDsiZzUKQUN/y2bKYNMA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "pip,al,el", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180107", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddjIlCAilJ052WGs7fx9EcGjK1IqYeRMAoCbIp/2NHJ3ve30GNUNpkEpo4jpK4XebRNzTSjNNDeKep3jnmPNVb4bimtAXQ0gzDFykxXu4uu5SavXZoawR0zkoJu7PQyANnNmZyb7VT4kQmQz3OYWK1hFRSY9cmn70eZs5F4psSAuD7a5rTtlbj9+dIOIg9du4J6cEj8vrsA62oxX4iRbwtb5djeXVq+YBirJgIR7NijwXt71YogTSkj9QwGjIxCItJ21ZfjsjsqOskqHD36i0VSxoRsXhnWZ7K72W3w+WkxSXR/Jb5luTR1tgCOO1x3inuZSGxFhoVu7ZxZkBdzeGxJnXrsm3+fiGDPbJrz6oy+ufw5F4avyetXbAle4WV6cw==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYP2lgqq84o1UAqyxP/wIH+QM2MCq2qTU7d9MFziXKbGa/v/joQxLliMg09y9H/ForH5+F1Pruhd4ImKYisNe8t8wN+exKT2hGZOPsdK2pd78JJffbRQwDyjYJTcMvF5x2CHZ0rlc3myAjB8kSOWj3FUupq0uWeoXdc+zBQg1pN3rdw0OZex0KSWqEq3ggKHz2jRYa5tAhSQu46N7FqMtMIIvcyBvSfItOP2iOvb+c5LcRxTrZJ6Zxu1megh+Tg5Qdi1KBNF9aTTblr5KSa2Igpd8MWj/n1nwpdpTmY3/RpSm8NiasVqlpnorz1wKMJ4Bjuzs1RFw9RoTRKTZ/202WPhoEU2ZXsnJ75Ehqz73IJGXuY5NKLUYfg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180108", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQEWcdqniKXbZnMGL6WaXNYv6+3p5lLxydhV5y4DbHsLb/9FoOm61fqYebdSMQJLdh5Nmaw6SmhGZIJ84Etolh8NpNPgSTMtHpMyShOWuvKzs5TVg=", 
		"answer": "24G9eoPy0hb+44RgVBf10O/2O27DQ20X42iMX6Z6MDyjY6jQfeX32dd+IRydhV4793fUt62w8FwLi61I+sLfXSMPe8trzdmdzqT4yjFSNsdI2s0ywJUKfuBG2THtfdDeLupnyGeDJlH5aDf9E3lgnHHmi29evZO64S77eds/wRE3gIY0rfg0PduTzLvT+1S1hAmOzzvcCI9hAkScttqp6U+Z4IQ3p8DNvjSb4/vrifDa4J4CbEh6toh7dhuvmKsA/T4hHYiQbRtf6KTRbF3pMzzjNwcN+Mej1GZoyIEhWHp0uV9ykIZTItd8xIvstSJyE6lGxKu5dYklurKqcxfNmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Av49oYvRgrzhfv2Mn7CCmwUsD+MVONjf3zmWufQa/3szIR0KUjJmVN+snHJp6H15EBPgK4b7I+NZCpDSoNqiN2I2+G3wHRIJ98ElY4y5doMefVMjDWsZ5TaYPph22yUIVD8JzC5AX5gnTffiX1CoYy1tTCyQNJ38BQhnpJo7Nw1fPqe0amX7Vu5xjaK3XedXa4kAk2Ut8Gk+AOOpZIqsN6Ivyab9bTrn+vD9d0fYwpeusZ5bEmx16cPuD03Q9u8YQIL+OqQSV3jJD3jNAEe8M73zzRdzodpWWw94AYGg45fZtNnlojtrDM8f894FD25q0FTh4Z5TwWTZ7i2xHuk9Ec6cDo8aph+tCQl4yF8lBQ3uuLuDs5PZwoy+I4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Terracotta figurines of women,Worship of the earth goddess", 
		"option_b": "Male deity on seal,Doubtful identification with Pashupati Mahadeva", 
		"option_c": "Phallus symbols,Respectable form of worship in Hindu society", 
		"option_d": "Deity amidst pipal branches,Tree worship", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180109", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl771r3yMGXECm0fpnvDAPIhMGXqWaLRLuTwiYN5Ihy7hFw7xHPCovqyLTwIRnsF058eznySeHvAjg==", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUpQV7/wPPrPGTeBmZR8S7WErd9fXTwFK7MLvn2zNdDLlvJu15/8zqGoquw9l0Mhq1V/c62fiYKf4Uv3NWRw6TWyGVJPNNDksB65YgbcO0AxzOiY9qbNPEu2maFZ1DiZTizRFh1hjDGmn1Yu8/74S++FNI40gY31o934cwvfMSW3qaa7kS7hwiWnHiERKlxA1WV9c+m7wOPuY86usGEsnLN9fjsn7ja/p4fag0SjY94I225k6EKuD49SdynKssfjGOWlWEMWcihN4jraG0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cow", 
		"option_b": "Elephant", 
		"option_c": "Horse", 
		"option_d": "Rhino", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180110", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPP8PHvRDyISsXCTEq5xfmXqW6nHaq33x9dlL1nJv1J8skDDp6SvtYL52A0iQmpBejIvOCK9Eg8=", 
		"answer": "25e5ep32yFsBrhGILVYtl8f2Ubd6Oqgw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDk9IwwUxKyxu/wJSvdBmwFqnCNV6c0eX+jQK/HLt/3ztdHIliIzVJosnTHsan17hM7h6FIqY2aYicCcsto2tGA2aTgxWIBMsgEn5Nh4ZQLdfVMjC65dcTXJb5nwC6UL0CwYzC4EDB7knHCgnkWqY24/CK1QJoezhE7l4k4/c0zLNualeiS5kn4jxKRnGiYT7NtF12atMCr7gOVs8IqsMuBtDHP8fC5k/aT+coYIg5AupdqZlWo16UM9j4xXsb0YRwL5ezVIWbkJ2iVIgoU+ovrz3ln1cDMG7kZpHJ9kR0mL6n5Whm6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Wheat", 
		"option_b": "Rice", 
		"option_c": "Barley", 
		"option_d": "Ragi", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180111", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehHg1vi/ImrDQ2EUrWuRU680ZH6jQK/HLtv7zZ5yZ1+cgU9u4HOGn6vM+WEKjrtU59TfRCoGPoNg2sOMl+3khHxEPdJNlY534NpNLaEA2DSgccebKfAu2maFZ3f5YHmLAXR11pBArgLMh3HY6jKDkVqhnTM=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iYN5Ihy7iFpo/XiGqraw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZCTYAncMtRPcncJw+BfGIhQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF1B3j9MUjWhf3w+6/MGbAC2MCqmWGVuNgeHSjXKjQfeiyiZZ/IxyAmUg74X/Braz2/lAOgbwb5IuRZCsMcMtmxpCd3+G39nhGc/BBnoEy948PbPtS2C7tYNzSM75ty2CUNUT8bi2kRHl61CXej3VE6ICu+TOuRt914OXiqLfnciUSxhgG9l/7tA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/Nm7eF3AQrz+XXeNgeHSjYqLGZ+6+yp94IlqazVp19jbLpqvk/lwBiqwbu9/KMDYKc458iNmHl/D/wTFzOsEErIV25cVdvAvLVGUXySF/q9zRD+ACKA==", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xDn9olgURv80e/+OSvEDCIFq3rDZKZweXKjV6/La+vtiZZ/IxyEiFVv+3nIpqGwpQJaz7xS5IuMMCsNPp9nzZC73uO38nRFMoZNicBm7J9fdPtS3zjtXNvJM/t9jmaFK0GwdDC6CnlynTLXhGgWu5q29yi3Xdl3wRs21pVx+d09MN6MzaGQqFu5ihOHnHKfCIthFV2a9d2n6EqZtJt09d+IoSDe5/H3jvHd954bbR9Xrco/bVS+nqQA7DN0Ecm6bFJG+OjZdVX/OWizNQEK/NjwlkBhw4s7HW8m8Q5Th41CIs122IztszxwNsMqATu/43ZJwNRKWhOfd/2wyWXq8xUtcHwnYIl5r20hqQqVOhR9j2eIWT5QmMBi88AWhxBic2xF3kGcztHaDgQjgerORIovKXE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Elephant", 
		"option_b": "Rhino", 
		"option_c": "Tiger", 
		"option_d": "Horse", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180113", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yyv/rNGLeBmZRoHCTQqZmMHfxW6qCeuX7iahOGGO2smREsnvPraDjt1wJz5pa44+MZCoCcMkHJGf/OmW7st+lqPjIYvPu", 
		"answer": "276wbYXh2FvrrEjCUJ6ek2ZjmJehYoQu", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1vLqJ2jVByIFq3qKQON3f2HzUbWCaP/xxNdlL1nJplN+5mTP46j5+VYcz6RU6o+LdSZDd4Uv+tGD1vfjzHBPcWZBXiapuo7uo2Na72ugVus=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "kh,et,ri,re,at", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180114", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUjQB/00e6/JXnRAHYYoHqHEqp6MFniRqbSfuzwiYN+MFKazUxy5n6Gt631/kFPi61I6pyWYDYKcYV8iOyH++3k0DxoaYYE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWpnVFvM6S3H37aNQWgDc3l4M44Mk3NdmYmejTqA34xkbCnDvRCP0kURTZ5I6Y+UyYtYE9sY2KvT3I5+25ivfH5NsZe0husaQ/QUm1lKMF+TMxX8/0KFILsaSQIRStYGjjZ05duYujljQ7hrc6WG108hBUwo5Xacl90djmqTs8O8RkEiD6okpEh4doTQKVYKiq1Xuk3FscNU4ufZ5ksCh1sR2TLEF9jmKTQmwR1MArvpBZ1UQwPUZOinnslDqPwGiGZJrt7MDojOawt7B3+uMkJlGQME6YaoM4JZHSKGloz6mIAK9IO5ZpEGKmfZVuvHm5YNbUi3kuwtwhO3LjtCCchcj5NWCoupfqztV4EP8JItTI+ou4thzGZSzzL3CWaN+2PA7rfNIz43KfpydE+GmP3g==", 
		"answer": "25T4JdGnnVnIt8hgAFKy5r2ydTqcQ0ZR7j/QELRDRlgVuASJClG9OPhrVPM=", 
		"explanation": "25T4SpTy1Vnn9o4lQA2yxu/6NH/VByIbpmiGXq9xYnjmR+fgLs/swJR6Z0+dn0545mPUpraw/l0Lhqta/YvfcjAKfYBjycmA2eO35zFiPNJQlY4y8J8HaP1MyS7tfNXfYPdj3nyFNFb5aDeuRFQ0tiPZhGZT6JS65me2Vd4ygBcr1opx9cEyO5eL0KbT6UO8xgWNzGuUWv8tq7EFgSLsayU9dgZqf8qm", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "A - 1, B - 2, C - 4, D - 3", 
		"option_b": "A - 4, B - 2, C - 1, D - 3", 
		"option_c": "A - 4, B - 1, C - 2, D - 3", 
		"option_d": "A - 2, B - 1, C - 3, D - 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180115", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vwz/1r3tMGfRF2cV42uMErd8dTHKWqPXfa3szJB4KFLJmlJv+jbSq6D55RMLirtY+4ePZCsMcJgv9N6l3vfjiVgbc9FNjogypLYWb+AN5RT3Ntrh/hwYQLdjp9QpQuWxXCc=", 
		"answer": "25KqaZ/ywxDv5MVtEjj90PP7dWLeQ08eq3qNWKw5dHDxW+fDYOm+3IR0IxyPgkk74WLJsaz+8BMInalS553TMBEGf4d8iJ3J4vfywDFHPNQEjpJz4JMRe7RQ2S+9e8feYP9gyi6IJkGwdDqvDWBg2HHxi35XuoG6+yOoFNUlgBszmoZrrYV8CcSa3eiV51/4lRKNznKfT/1zEECcp4Lo2FeTrod4psSOuj7e57S02tTa+9sHe0hHrIN7I12zhegB+TguVNugYRxMsefCbkT+YuuiChKuLbBRGkbh4S4kZ1k=", 
		"explanation": "25T4T4Py3xj4/oAzEhf8hdDwPW7eCW1cp36RXeNnZH7xUaOCaf//wJliZ37Jvl56/mWGq6T0t0YBhq5U+4PfYyERd5t7iNGH06TgwWNEc9NXn4Qy4pUNPOBSzTmoNPebB/9sz3yCJkv0dHm4CnN4myLTjjxUscO/9CqoFMkjzwc3ksdv7Nw5Lpe7mZuH50O9xhWL33CdTa4kBlGLsI69+EaY4IQ3p42FsCDN8eftk/bUsuBN6UZvtobMmAaItXnVQ9w=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Granaries,Found in Mohenjo-daro and used for storing grains", 
		"option_b": "Seals,Used for trading purpose and had script", 
		"option_c": "Gabarbands or nalas,Used for storing water", 
		"option_d": "Stone sickles,Likely used for harvesting crops", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180116", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR7l84ElQQ2ywfT7dX/YBiI5om2CQrN1fmKjRKjRfeT8xY4xIk2cjE9+smHPt62w41sKz4ZS5Yvfdy0Heo5825CgxO3kmzMJkywoC3xeHhIi3AJd7a6e", 
		"answer": "25C5eoX7kR7l84ElQQ2wu1Hy5235dWye3H0SZ+tVMw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1fLsJmLSD3tRpm6WU7dxdDH3XKKCaeL6zZJiNByGixtv+nOGjaz88h9PprtS+sLfZysXdst7wNWAxaT4038BNsdWjogy45UbePFT332ZfN3IYO17yWmFNFHjJzqoCGRhhjDayn9Zpo2+9jOyW9QkgBc3gpB96MZ8KN+amYCS+kyolgeMnHiYXrRoGE6Yocen5QOdroZ4tMOOuDfV4LTcneHD5NcKbEhQuop2Zl2v2+gB8S0wXcGzYAZC/+OQdVzoYDuqIAAU/8Lg13pqw8ImWyk1tApIi5VTcNNy2tj2uSQ1LchkFjb6pUtSh5J5TQOfeLSsySjl7lF/eXMtYMdqtTs8rwjcLltsmW6PDkRRyjeOhebqZFMXURQ4TbI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Earth goddess", 
		"option_b": "Sun goddess", 
		"option_c": "Water goddess", 
		"option_d": "Sky goddess", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180117", 
		"question": "24GwbdH31Anj9JEpXRCyyvu/ImPZAGpRpHCHEqx6MHCjR6LDYq3twZhmNByBhFY74WPUsarl+VcKi+hZ8M6efisOf4d8l5LFDvs7ph3YRdJ42MfgeNEh", 
		"answer": "24W5e5nmwRj+/sUNUxbzwfjpNCkFYTLgbWVogMuHdf1NQOJ4", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1Bjmt4ElQhfx0fTxMivRQ2oesXGGVuNwdXj3TefRe//sxoJ/I1mNzVlisnfIqqjx+0BPhrsb64uTeScVe48v3N/JxeHn1nRSNshQ2pR64doYc/AA/Dy+fMHLIepnjlqILlawdzavEGJ1jTDaynVYrIq49DO+R5o/yQZyhIh06Ig9L5eemaya/kS2g0aSznSFTb5wHkbZusjo6k2VrYM0poHNoivW9vv1k+La/tlLdgBX/65+cVqsh6kH6214Use6ZhdI5e3fbxT5L2itJhoI686j13pthpYhWGAmtA1DkZNTYdQz0Jf2/CY4Oo1rGzq3okgAzJ1yWBOZef9yxg2SgVvQJ8ND86Whbwww", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Brahma", 
		"option_b": "Vishnu", 
		"option_c": "Shiva", 
		"option_d": "Pashupati Mahadeva", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180118", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8hf72IXKQCnFRrXCXU6F4aTHhQa7Oeq3xz9diM1OHiAQ58ZL31GTKRMet7F+CfufChQ==", 
		"answer": "25GwZ53yxxD49sczZN8LbTMagG6YTUfsV9UP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2A3zt4omEjr6yvH+I2LCAiIYsD+NXbd1cn36FKXXZ+HqiYJiLlKOzUhv/XjD46Tjt1JPn7pS5I+NaWIAcYV83MKc1PD+y38BPsdQn5J75ZZfSPxFjDi1YNHVM/d4yy6VNECwaD/9F2R7mjSayn1ap428tTCyQNJ3zwE6k5U47No/NN6L3KuH/V+5ikaH0H6cTbNwAhjZpsan/ECds4cr9dmFtHLP8ffxlPHQ8dJLcQNbs4o/YlW4170b+is2Edi4aRxF+OrXIVvrYDyrIk41+NnixmRoyJFrq+HiSaIBs7/XpAk/PhTNDA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_b": "Harappa", 
		"option_c": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ348oBgVhf2hen3MCvABm0Br3rDXaU0ZHnmFI7MavjtiYV0IFWGgxts/WTVq6zgqBHlrQyTdmox8oJB3elcLdao", 
		"answer": "24WxeJD/kxLD32Ww2tEPsW/fDrBqwdQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj1Bb6+4BgXRiy0fX6dULeB3cC422GVap7fjH0W7XRZuTuzJMxM1SMzUty4nfK47Hi8lZPx45S6puMMDAGcoJowd+a1q27hHBNIMkEkY5985RffecA2DWoNMfaI+xryi6GLkKwcyu4ATBAnDjFymhErYb7/SK3UJok0Bwgn5Nt7MR8L96Y16GV4U65iAWHkDuCUbBmHliQr8em7AObso0vocXB8SXS5/D2l7ST8dAPIg1cs494a0+5maUM9j50Ecm6bFJC5feQc1H7JTqmKQ0YucLwlnF/z4YsU310/REGi5dFIsR2xpHnqDs/MY1lG3OppkVM1NR9URPWda+s2W7l40EsNw+atYytxXq/OQlgILJzUUg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Banyan", 
		"option_b": "Oak", 
		"option_c": "Cedar", 
		"option_d": "Pipal", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180120", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrj45xgWh/2hfvwJ3/ZBWsSomuKXa1nMHLrVbXDbfn7255rIljJj0I79HnUt7aw4Fobh6FVqYiQYjYQIcmwkDCD6ahcQtYzv4bz+XeQ", 
		"answer": "25GwZ53yxxD49sczZN8LbTMagG6YTUfsV9UP", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2A3zt4omEjXzyfT9NGXXAmxRq36HEqd9Y2XqWqTWZ/v7iZF+NUiAi1J482LPrKvjt1AHjrpa6pqaYisZe48vysnJ2vH70HhRP8MEloFr4YgMPPtGjDmoctHVM/d4yy6XJkn8dHX9B2JxlSXfhHsWqcOo8DWyUcl3zxNykIhq+dt8K96L0aGdqEu3lBKRnE+ZQa4kEEaavce87kCItZA5uY2JtCHS8/q5iurc5tcPZwwSrJJtYk+5kKEKuDoqXtyxawZC/uqQYFPsKSawM04Y4d/mxHpoysI9VXsx9QtVwoJYZoBg3pfzvzMjOt4qATu/41FSxZVyHweadbO22WbjoEYwZXIidp5kvywhqACSaFt42n+USWx5lZJq7sAYmxchVPlklUSYuCk6rUyPto3Hjw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_c": "Kalibangan", 
		"option_d": "Dholavira", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180121", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk1Avvt4gvQQqy7fztNHvAAmxRt3qRQKJ3f2X3VefEZ+rr25JiZ1GIiV4ksDb32cOlsJ9n3K1LD7UU/9I=", 
		"answer": "25OxepS+0xjh8oFgVx/g0fX6OyvTD2MI4crVtMJdS9AtiRk2l+HU2RQ=", 
		"explanation": "25i3e4Wz+Rj49pUwUxCy0fjtJ2rTDHYFoj+FW6RhYnTwFLDHfOi+xJZ1IhycnlJ19TbSq6CwyxEfhqZY4c6LdSELcIJ+3dW1laTDzHhSc89KjI9+8p8bPOdIzS2ketObI/Jv1y6CPgXgbje+DHl6k3HXhHgWpYy38S61U5o+1FUln5Nwrc41MtCay7vT6UO8xhKN03eCBP12FEeMudqh5UTcqYx4vMOZozvY9eD82vnd9J4PZxxTtop6Zxu6nq8c6iM2VNv0XBpC4qTEZFflLiGyMgtd8cLk3nhgwYo9Tikg/BoGg5FCa9Nn35ukrzk5M8EqFD2+40dSxpJoTBqXeq6w2Xik71N/YXIuJaJsriwlsQ6SaFVsjmKPTSJC1r13MhDZh43oohIUVYBY/P4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Wood", 
		"option_b": "Stone", 
		"option_c": "Metal", 
		"option_d": "Fire-baked earthen clay", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180122", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geh/gxO3vNGXDQ3AUtXqRV6c0ZHnmFKDNaun72oQxKFrJiFpp5n6Gn6vM+WEKjrtU59TfXjcOe5lg3cPJw+Hl1nBCPNJQm8B07Z0Kbv1OyS7te9KbN/Fjy2DAL0TmYnm/AXV61DfZn3JS6Iq1tQ+6Rtsn0BRwTnY0V+2I8KX4IUWQGS1mzA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z0iBiBtp93fVrKuw/kBPm6BeqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgEnI9gpI4XebRB3y6oZsDSL/Asb6tWEpnisVTnhAjPqlynnA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Av49oYvRgrzhfv2Mn7CCmwUsD+RV7NmdWLmWrOCeuX7iZB+I1iMnkg7/XCGpqTi41tDz7tT5pmccTEKcIwv3NiMl8z21nBRI8dK3ZMy9p8JeeZFwj6oNMDUN/98yn3AL0DiJfcS0I63ML0q4rhjIcb0cQQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are correct and the reason is the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are correct but the reason is not the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct but reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both assertion and reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180123", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb31/i/ImrDQ2NRr36AWeN7djHwQKjMa63pxoV6Z1WHzXN64HfWs6Sw9l0Lz4VU4YuRei1Oeop9x5C12dj59nRAIMlKwMBB8JURebRDwyihcJTVL+ouzGvAN1f/ZCyvAXQ0liiWnnRTu4b74TC0FNk+1Bw3hcXJhLeMVkg4gf2Sfs71i8Yx", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSvCBmMCrHHDU7FxMHLsRrXHbfm+yJl1Z0iBiBtp93fVrKuw/kBPm6BeqY2QYjAGfZ8vzciZ2+X5xWVIPMgEnI9gpI4XebRB3y6oZsDSL/Asb6tWEpnisVTnhAjPqlynnA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH01Bbt5YQwWhfxxPG/OWTTAnYYrHHDXaU0WHDxVbfSb63/x5MxClOBiFVx/TvCorf/t18GgqFP7IrfZCoGd5kvydOK0vfkhGVOc9VQlY53qNoNeedVwCmketObKfAuzy6MJkb7Jza7RGNgmz/Tyn9ZppCv5zK4QNM4zgZwuib9nzcEKFS0hh8wu6ZcRA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion and reason are correct and the reason is the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion and reason are correct but the reason is not the correct explanation for the assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is correct but reason is incorrect", 
		"option_d": "Both assertion and reason are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180124", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohcn3MCv4AnAQs2+CXLA0fH7sX6LGLvjuxpkxM1SMzV564GLO46Tjt1JPia1J/YeTeTYaPoxgzNSMxPe5+H99PfRBm5N96tpXTr0ajB+od9XOM/su2maFZ23xdTitFHF6h3HGmHVbqZGy+T77Rt87yRA21oh2rds5PZeLy6mX7Q25iALCyHOUWrhiHkac9dmn+VCUqZIosMnNpTretOf8m7jU/9oPZxtB/4BwcRuon60A6mooQ8eneBdZ+PDJLxbApIXnIbgUI3ZaxkWW8P1M", 
		"answer": "25T4YYKzxQv/8slgUAvmhc+/PHiQBWMdsHrBZp/Ta9Kg0XiirdPtxVfDQg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1/j4NHnUBmZRt3eGEqZ1YmXrFKbRLuy+x4JjM0mbhFV8snHJp6H15EBDz7pe74KaczYKcIwv3NiM3va3x35PPcNHjol96toLc7ROzSm4ZtGcM75oy3yULkn5cyD9BX5w1CLDmWhTpoK19iL7YNI+01UxmYl76NgofN6R36SG7UO7gwLCyHOUQa8kA1GVvMmh5FaP4IA9ucSItyGb9fr92vnB5JJLZwVCt4dsakG1ma9J7CI9Edu9bxxC9+3TYFruJWisIU4c/tnq1WFl0pc7WCk1+hsGlotTIsV9wJH2szw9OsN+V0fVxJFkj/XRsywBBp8o+Ac=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is NOT the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "Both A and R are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180125", 
		"question": "25GwZ53yxxD49sU3Uw2yxvLxJn/CFmEFpnvDX6J9fn36FLLRZ+P5iahOGGO2smQ5cy1e+KsG4RerG+zQ7IcB+w==", 
		"answer": "26asZ5/2k4wBX4N6fFy6NbklpcYtZW0=", 
		"explanation": "25GwZ53yxxD49sIzEh39y+7rJ37TF2serT+TQKZwf3zqWqbMeuHniYJlLlCAl15/smXSrKv1uxMch6dM6o+MeSwEPopr3tGH1OHzhHBTMM5NjoVx8I8NffgA3zakeNjIYNN7yiOCNUzzbCr9BX5w1CXfh35TusOs8DW+FNs70xpyk4po4cclOdPf36eBqFu5lA+NyWjRW6l2BFeNoNyt+A/cqIs/vcGEtjrP/fr+2uzb9dcZIglAvI52d16/g70b+SZ4VcGibQBY+PDJIVXjJGixIh0S7Nng0zR80oslVHM14BZJjMFoFBbYZagKN1yUoSs1C7dp", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "sto,ne,ro,ck", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180126", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohcn3MCv4AnAQs2+CXLA0YnT1UbXHaq3qwZIxN1WZjFc75mTDpuvM+W8Bva1a+oGRMGoxN9Ev/NiMl/T+1HBNc9JWn4Uy7YlfePFQxT65cdCbL/Auw2+OPgXjYjixFzBwnSLVhWpTuoa/tSGpW9d36BQgl5do7MZ8L96L3LvfqES2gg+B3W+YRrokGECK9d2p6FGZpMI3p42euDXV/fLwmfnd5J4YdglGqpU/alX8g6AM8Th4Ut24fAdZ9KqS+zy0+SXsa1kHqpcA78UCgQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBi5RonGHEpE0eWKjQK/HLu7x24V0JEjJiENr/nfIorH5+F1PgK4byMzsL+6VFW4bW6o228jH0bJh", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg0Br48oFgVBf1hentMG6cQ2YUs3aARqZwMH7tFLTHb+Hthdd5IlCNzUhr+2TPt7Dx+xMGgrhU+5qefiEGPo1g2pCd3+G37HBTMtZUm45hqNoPc+dTxT+hbZTIOfNswWKJPUz+YHm6Fn9jgDmaymtfu4e0+Gv7VdQzgAYin5Vx+d09MJea16Sa70WsgwiP2XWFCg/HDsiZzUKQUN/y2bKYNMA=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is NOT the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "Both A and R are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180127", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddjIlCAilJ052WGs7fx9EcGjK1IqYeRMAoCbIp/2NHJ3ve30GNUNpkEpo4jpK4XebRNzTSjNNDeKep3jnmPNVb4bimtAXQ0gzDFykxXu4uu5SavXZoawR0zkoJu7PQyANnNmZyb7VT4kQmQz3OYWK1hFRSY9cmn70eZs5F4psSAuD7a5rTtlbj9+dIOIg9du4J6cEj8vrsA62oxX4iRbwtb5djeXVq+YBirJgIR7NijwXt71YogTSkj9QwGjIxCItJ21ZfjsjsqOskqHD36i0VSxoRsXhnWZ7K72W3w+WkxSXR/Jb5luTR1tgCOO1x3inuZSGxFhoVu7ZxZkBdzeGxJnXrsm3+fiGDPbJrz6oy+ufw5F4avyetXbAle4WV6cw==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbYP2lgqq84o1UAqyxP/wIH+QM2MCq2qTU7d9MFziXKbGa/v/joQxLliMg09y9H/ForH5+F1Pruhd4ImKYisNe8t8wN+exKT2hGZOPsdK2pd78JJffbRQwDyjYJTcMvF5x2CHZ0rlc3myAjB8kSOWj3FUupq0uWeoXdc+zBQg1pN3rdw0OZex0KSWqEq3ggKHz2jRYa5tAhSQu46N7FqMtMIIvcyBvSfItOP2iOvb+c5LcRxTrZJ6Zxu1megh+Tg5Qdi1KBNF9aTTblr5KSa2Igpd8MWj/n1nwpdpTmY3/RpSm8NiasVqlpnorz1wKMJ4Bjuzs1RFw9RoTRKTZ/202WPhoEU2ZXsnJ75Ehqz73IJGXuY5NKLUYfg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180128", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vwz/1r3tMGfRF2cV42uMErd8dTHKWqPXfa3szJB4KFLJmlJv+jbSq6D55RMLirtY+4ePZCsMcJgv9N6l3vfjiVgbc9FNjogypLYWb+AN5RT3Ntrh/hwYQLdjp9QpQuWxXCc=", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRiqusUURRG/1/LwOG7UQ2oetmyGQeNyf2OjVbXWZ/7/x4QxJlKNzVd68HnUprfjuxMrh6dX6JiWYiNDM8tJx8KdxKTgzWVJOsgEnI9g8IlTPNlPxDijftvfIexhjiPAAFf1Zi39A2J1mjDEkzAWg4K3/CW6Wt02zlV/1rNw/805fNOWyrya5k6sxgqN33qdQaltFEfbJAk8TAe6dlGJgToWQ6ISRA==", 
		"explanation": "25e5e5T3kRbkt5EoV172wO78J2LAF2serWzDQrF7ZnjnUaOOLvn2zNdiLkiMnhtz82DD47H48kAKz6xS+pqWfiEXd51qiNaM1vDi1nRSaYZsm5Jz9IoePPxByH25Y9uWMvFhw2uEZ03/ciq4Fzw0sDnZhn1AoZG6tS+6UJoxzwcmhcdv5Nw0Ndnf36eB/F70xiuN1H6fQrJgEEaW9cap7wOIqId4st+IsCab8+b4lPnB6ZJLYwZW/4Rwd1P8v6kb+TooUIi1ZhYL2uXcaFbsLi+iKU4V+M+jwnx7w4dpWWAn4BZIgZcWbs9w15TtqDs1LI1oACf6rEpM3tRXXhufdry212nqoFwsNXslJYV9qCQ6r0+aJ0Y+k3/ex6Z28inTyNojM9XKvkT72Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Harappa,Two-roomed houses for artisans and laborers", 
		"option_b": "Dholavira,Forts within forts", 
		"option_c": "Mohenjodaro,Great granary", 
		"option_d": "Kalibangan,Three distinct localities", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180129", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQEWcdqniKXbZnMGL6WaXNYv6+3p5lLxydhV5y4DbHsLb/9FoOm61fqYebdSMQJLdh5Nmaw6SmhDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AZwWwJ3n9RDA01HGWyjwW6MP7tWf7FJp3gFVy1sc4rYh8EN6MzejB1EP4p0a22WmDSb5rBUCY9cih7FaOqYw9po2Ct3LM+/n8lLiTsJ5LIkgS/8Y/Ixv8xug+9zgrWcGkKB1NsfDYZBToITq3L04a9s/n02d6+owLHUQ1+BoGhoZfdtkz2ZakrzcxM40qVXP64wQAh9Q8H1fWNP34kCikoBV/NTprJcot/G114U/cehRalX6eWCpEmMBi+tUXgQ1ldGxBiH/vjH+ciXGHPKPi+IjplenkqflO86smLUSWNGDWdc0sbbLMK3JhivqCAKRTP4wnV2KmfZVuvHm5YNbUn3lNkJlgbzentGrZ0o21eSX689K5zpQ2VP9TduPA+tuys0jGYy/kYXucdMa0Vg6wWHPqwAZsp1gsxmE44WzcHcls+i4Em2qpdUpA0gPlZWi41r9R44ada84h2uXt0XISivV2nJPyx118B0T7zT8D8sTfDxwPjRSWXo1ThD08CbFBA5nD4WWfhTTsCuWvkTfDfvyumm389l5p", 
		"answer": "25T4JdGinVnIt8hgAFKy5r2ydTicQ0ZR7j/XEPjdHW49FpUZJH5SyM4Zv0k=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Av49oYvRgrzhfv2Mn7CCmwUsD+MVONjf3zmWufQa/3szIR0KUjJmVN+snHJp6H15EBPgK4b7I+NZCpDSoNqiN2I2+G3wHRIJ98ElY4y5doMefVMjDWsZ5TaYPph22yUIVD8JzC5AX5gnTffiX1CoYy1tTCyQNJ38BQhnpJo7Nw1fPqe0amX7Vu5xjaK3XedXa4kAk2Ut8Gk+AOOpZIqsN6Ivyab9bTrn+vD9d0fYwpeusZ5bEmx16cPuD03Q9u8YQIL+OqQSV3jJD3jNAEe8M73zzRdzodpWWw94AYGg45fZtNnlojtrDM8f894FD25q0FTh4Z5TwWTZ7i2xHuk9Ec6cDo8aph+tCQl4yF8lBQ3uuLuDs5PZwoy+I4=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "A - 1, B - 2, C - 3, D - 4", 
		"option_b": "A - 2, B - 1, C - 4, D - 3", 
		"option_c": "A - 4, B - 3, C - 2, D - 1", 
		"option_d": "A - 3, B - 4, C - 1, D - 2", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180130", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt6ghRgvgwL3XNHnRE3IQrT+QV7dgfHTuUanWfa3/25IxLliMg09y9H/Dp/qyR9mAXsJ0d/JbkUPpkhQMfg==", 
		"answer": "yOXqOic2VFP8Mh0IMgYFslfq+Po=", 
		"explanation": "25SqZ4T91Vm7p9dyEjPz0ejtMCv4AnAQs2+CXONndWX3WKLPa+Pq2td5JkqMzVl+93iGqqH1+UcGiaFe7cLfYicVe4pjwd6Ol/D/wTFEK9JBlJN78p9fbvFBzzXte9KbNPZrjkaBNUTgdzizRHN9gjjag2ZXvIq0+2e6V8g40wZygo99reEyOMKMmZ6S5EG9n0aD0n/RSrh9Hlqd9fqg4lDcrocsosKfunLU8rTqn+zH/NsGZwZGrMZ3aly0m6EO8D4rEdy8bVJK9fLRb1foJGi2NQwc94vz2nVnyIsnWik1+hsGgZZadtVh15SkuDcmOsFlBT6/rVAAyJI8Sx+TNJW5wmn08FQxZjgBTSPB8CmXOdLPPKjMihy0", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 616, 
		"option_b": 1022, 
		"option_c": 2800, 
		"option_d": 406, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180131", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl+ZElXw791/ztLCvTFm4Ftm2GErd7MFniRqbSfuzwiYRhNVmIiRt05HPU47H48hMYhqxe+prfcTAGf9QtNh8aM7pID53IFUfPQrXsFw==", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjktShYVvswbDI9MPpoC3x6YoE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hf+8ogwXQzz1+S/Nn7cF3cDpj+XWqJgMGLzRqLDaq3x35JjZ0iBiBts+3LDsLGw9kEKjuha5YGRdzEKeo4v3NiMl8z21nBRI8dK2oN78pMTde5B2DSiepTMIe0u2maFZ2fxZC2vDXE5uTDEjXVXpoL71DW4XNsyzxk9kY577MR8H9iSyaSW8A3wpCuj/zLRfLVtAhSaoMK8/lGZ4Ic2tsKAoTPI5/H92ujS4soYIgdU/4twZ16umeUN+TN4Zd2mYx9O/+3DdVXjbGiWPQwY8sLwwnVnisIdXGM9/xZVloJYLoBS0J/svTw5LNlrG3/6okpEh71uXhnaNK6w33/n4UY2e31rbJ5+/CQ7pwOJLVp9nyudTz5eh5Mr/5APlBd3PX1Fm3/vjH2xUWTWedLmRN8yEJ4R7qjq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Egyptian", 
		"option_b": "Mesopotamian", 
		"option_c": "Harappan", 
		"option_d": "Crete", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180132", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t7UyUxz6xO6/BWrEAmxRr3CAU7dxdC6hqiulaz/iLd96f1S0KScqqQ==", 
		"answer": "25KtYpDh0A2oJmc+FesUksdysJmyuevhaQ==", 
		"explanation": "24WqaZP70Aqqx4Q0UxCyzO6/OWTTAnYUpz+KXONgeHSjR7PDeui+xpExAEmDjEl65jqGiqv0/lJPprwb4YGTdDFDbI5jwdeA2PHkhGJINMhNnIlx5ZQcebRB332kYJTSM75sy2KJIlP1Y3mpCzB2kXHCgnkWuI+69iL7Q9Iy0hByuohq6YgXLt6M0aaSr174gweQyHOdUf1uHkGLu8uxq0aSpIc89fmFtHLI/eD83euT8c0YbQtbvpJ2bFX8gKEd8Go1SNy8Zx5E9v2QYFrpYCCqNBoS69Kj23Viw5FpVH109V9WkIxba8522IykrDs8ON9jGDK9pgREwodoVhmXYLS33io34YcVebExxrmG3y1lQb/t", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Punjab", 
		"option_b": "Rajasthan", 
		"option_c": "Haryana", 
		"option_d": "Gujarat", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180133", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl771r3yMGXECm0fpnvDAPIhMGXqWaLRLuTwiYN5Ihy7hFw7xHPCovqyLTwIRnsF058eznySeHvAjg==", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUpQV7/wPPrPGTeBmZR8S7WErd9fXTwFK7MLvn2zNdDLlvJu15/8zqGoquw9l0Mhq1V/c62fiYKf4Uv3NWRw6TWyGVJPNNDksB65YgbcO0AxzOiY9qbNPEu2maFZ1DiZTizRFh1hjDGmn1Yu8/74S++FNI40gY31o934cwvfMSW3qaa7kS7hwiWnHiERKlxA1WV9c+m7wOPuY86usGEsnLN9fjsn7ja/p4fag0SjY94I225k6EKuD49SdynKssfjGOWlWEMWcihN4jraG0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cow", 
		"option_b": "Elephant", 
		"option_c": "Horse", 
		"option_d": "Rhino", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRD5t5EoV178yu/rPW7CDW8esGvDXbZgYH7wQOfNaK3yyIN0Z3SIn1pr4nfI46bl+0cana0Eq20KGAPriTFH9Q9at6CkmE8=", 
		"answer": "24avaYWzxxjm+4A5EHtQGLMnvt/agE6QhN8NB5c=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH93gv+/4AyXBP91um/On7EE20Ctz+MVONgeHSjWKbWa63WyIVwN0yIgxt453rStrf1t1ocz6lPqaOefiYCMstjx9OIw+HzhHhPc9ZWn5N36o5SePVZjBesednOYP9gyi6rJlb4ajCvSDBdmjXfizx/vMOo/SisV9skxQZygo99rc0kLNaRyqGc5g23gEaq3WmQWK1lHxSQu8ik/kaSo4d4vMOZvnLP/PG5lPfB5NYOcAYSrYN4alSyhOgG/mosWc30QRxP+OXeIUf4IiusKRoU987twjYzW5XCyslETFfYCJdKL8Xl", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Swat valley", 
		"option_b": "Jammu", 
		"option_c": "Daimabad", 
		"option_d": "Mohenjodaro", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180135", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV173xO/zPG7DFyIFrGiNErR9ZHmjRKvDYOP7zddjKF2Nnht6/HKGq6rl5FYcz6FVqayefDcAdoJ83NGHiKZHZ6QOSCjPiukh0Q6c0Tuq", 
		"answer": "24e5YJzy31nO/4AyW1ymuq98Zh4pwlQ3ksQySRks", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7myurxdXzZF2pRs3OCXK1xdDHxW6bGfa3/x5MxL1Ocnl5osn/I44fx+0YMh6FI/Y+RMCsQPqZqwMKO1vb/hEVJNoZQlZd8o4lfcPVZwyi5NNXVJL5h3GmBKUzqZi20C340nDjRgnBfr4uvtTOzUZo2xAMzmIR96YgpLtWe1+iD5Ey2iA+M2zuCQ7RoHUfZusjo4leP4Is2vcyPuCba+uDq2vnd9J4fag1brcZrcVqyhKEd8SU2Edy7KAFO5fDcZFCtLCGlIkwXe0OkPa3o9EPJrqaNeTMG", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Somnath", 
		"option_c": "Rahman Dheri", 
		"option_d": "Rangpur", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180136", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ39+MUyWwj31+6/NHnVQ2AUr3aGRKZwMGXsFK/DeOi+yph/M06Aj05v93KGsKz3+VoJhqta55qTaWIXcct7wNXJ/+XlxWFRMsgEsoF59ptAPhfWjV8H0EZ3iTyzrKkJdp8=", 
		"answer": "24y5ZYT90Fnr+YFgYQvmyfj1d3qJEhdAd2rQNSPi9ryxRcM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHnxhaq5Yw2Vwzhhen3NH+QAnAU432GXqpxZnTnFLPNLuX/35IxJFOHmUly8GPSpqGw5FoIgaFd4I2efjYPZ8t7x5Cd3+G37HBTMtZUm44yzJsUbvUAzS+oNMDTJb5d23qMIk+wZje5RGR8kXHvi3FDpoL7wS++R9930hwkk5VrrdgwPc6a3eiSqE6qkwWL3XfRWrJoFBSQu46740KMqYw/9dmFtHLX9fr9ifvS4NtLYwZW/5ZtbE21k6EH/2ovUNyxelJN/vaQYFP/KSu2KxoI68rvlnVq0os/VH098QwGi40Wdsh2lorhuzs/MY/c5ac65Ihwzh1ZiBzmyyNq", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indus and Hakra", 
		"option_b": "Yamuna and Ganga", 
		"option_c": "Yamuna and Sutlej", 
		"option_d": "Indus and Sutlej", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPP8PHvRDyISsXCTEq5xfmXqW6nHaq33x9dlL1nJv1J8skDDp6SvtYL52A0iQmpBejIvOCK9Eg8=", 
		"answer": "25e5ep32yFsBrhGILVYtl8f2Ubd6Oqgw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDk9IwwUxKyxu/wJSvdBmwFqnCNV6c0eX+jQK/HLt/3ztdHIliIzVJosnTHsan17hM7h6FIqY2aYicCcsto2tGA2aTgxWIBMsgEn5Nh4ZQLdfVMjC65dcTXJb5nwC6UL0CwYzC4EDB7knHCgnkWqY24/CK1QJoezhE7l4k4/c0zLNualeiS5kn4jxKRnGiYT7NtF12atMCr7gOVs8IqsMuBtDHP8fC5k/aT+coYIg5AupdqZlWo16UM9j4xXsb0YRwL5ezVIWbkJ2iVIgoU+ovrz3ln1cDMG7kZpHJ9kR0mL6n5Whm6", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Wheat", 
		"option_b": "Rice", 
		"option_c": "Barley", 
		"option_d": "Ragi", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180138", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/PWrCB24I43SNXbR6MGXsFLPKa63r25VwKRyhjEl64mbHrbavtXIWRXguzexHAoE5D8wCVA8=", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH23Rz6/4QuRl7lxO6/PWrCB24I43SNXbR6MGXsFLPKa63r25VwKRyhjEl64mbHrba8t1Icz7xT7JyaMCsQPodmxdmd0uC3wWdIN8NKmYUy65xfdeBTjDmoZN3YNPdhwC6JKQXYZiu8FGB1mnHXmGgWqY2/tS64W9Q4xwczho9hrfw0NcTfyr2U70irkhXCyHOQXP1wGVHZpdyt+EaSo4d4usvNtD7e5Pz4lOzAsMkKcUhcsJI/Ykj8hKEO9iM+WMu1ZgYL+OqQdVzoKTrjJBsR7d7x0zRo1cIgSSkj+wpKhsNaY9R2xNjmuTE/MsgqHD36rFBIwoY8XhmVfbi2xCjn6UM2eXMxZJ5ksyMm4+kxec/AGOK8jFrF+vFfrao=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Elephant", 
		"option_b": "Tiger", 
		"option_c": "Rhino", 
		"option_d": "Horse", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180139", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQvj4YAyEg3r1un6OCvZECICrHKGRqp5dWKjVamCb+HqzIV/JkiMzVV6/3OGparit0cHiuhy54qKY2IAa4d73cKMiKb9OzUXDOxRc9mlUW9e5Cp+", 
		"answer": "24a5epDgxxj+/sfGJba73BoT5oC74r04mxoB", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA0Avr5JIhRhey9/TpMHmQEHsCt3qOEqpnMGLsWaLWZ+D72tdkNFmNzVposnfI46T841YdgalP7M6RcS8GPo1g2pCd3+G37X9FJtUEmZV+8I8NebR0xDjtR9XJIe15z3qJZ3f5cTyvSDB5kT/Cg3NYrYf7/Cn7VdQ0yRA8gsds6NAoL5vf0LvT6ki0jwOU2X/RXLIkGVWPsI6450KFpYZ4tI2euDXV/fLwmfnd5J4ZbQRX/49xI0+0kugN/Tw9XcekZRdF5aTfZxT5KC3jDw8P+Nvz13opxYs/VGU97h5Si4xYLoBy2ozssyc3N41jASD6plxBxIA8VhOTeqmx1mHn4UE2enRrd49gvSQ7sk+daEdrmGGZTzgRm4Yr+tUblBBmP+QGucANcxUQM7rlPJD75HQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Indus", 
		"option_b": "Sarasvati", 
		"option_c": "Yamuna", 
		"option_d": "Ganga", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180140", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4gpXhL3y/P2IGaQIUFRp3aHErNxf2HvUefLYK3cyJtkJFSAnk96/DbVt6Ti4xManKFV7s6SZSZDfJlmy9uaiKZdGB7iXo2XK9yOvN9ALCj9", 
		"answer": "25OxboX7kRjk88UmXQvg0fW/OGLcD2cfrXaCEoFXMhBLXY/V0cCBf3gtU1UtqY4=", 
		"explanation": "24W9Z4H/1Fnj+cUCUxLnxvX2Jn/RDSITpniCXONhY3jtU+fPe+m+y4V4JFeazV104DbFrKvj40EajLxS5oDfdDcRd4VoiMSB0qSk1nUBPs9IloV86pMKcbRi732ZfN3IYOp8z2CTLlH5aDf9AmJ7mXHTi25aoYaptSWuXdYzyRs11op5+c0uNdaTyuiH5w21kwLC3mmYS7Z3UVmYp8Wt7wOd4JY9tsWDvj7U8/36m/ST8dodYwZRuot6bU/8g6AI7Go7XsagehtJ5PDVZRT5L2i3Lwtd/c7103hm1o8sU310+xkGl5FUY84z1Z3qqDciLI1rGzf6olZDz51oWhSCYa+9kngLh8mwUsZxxosTQk4TRCc=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Third and second millennia BC", 
		"option_b": "Sixth and fifth millennia BC", 
		"option_c": "Fifth and fourth millennia BC", 
		"option_d": "First and second millennia BC", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180141", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTHr5YQwQh/8he72IW6QCnFRr3CAU7dxdDHqWufWZui+6p9+K1WamVp1snLDsKDi4xMGgehr6IWWYzYCcNQtuxLPTnGpYbjzueWY0UxsnA==", 
		"answer": "2525Y4PykRj48oRiCpk7hfGjlq7zm47gbE8H0A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7hzOn6dWffAGMFpnvDW600ZHnmFITKYeH32oNwKRyNiEh+4GKGqquwx1IEhrtP6IDfeTFDdYVg397J1ve343BPJMNWk5dz6JtfVeAA2zy+NNWbM/dpwGeGLkbxaS39EWJ2lT+WiXlYvIaptSSzVcg2wwE3hI5i6Mx8Ps7fzq2f5ACoigeM0n6VCLp2HkONvYLo6keKoYw7sMnNsCDY/P3tn/vH5cwOLkhTsYI/Zk21k60H+y94Xs70fABK9eGQYFrpYCuxJggJ6sbi2Gdhz5JrIrYjIx1TQkwoCpxfGDKgCA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappa", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjodaro", 
		"option_c": "Hakra area", 
		"option_d": "Rahman Dheri", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180142", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuyw/TtJn+QEGoetHqHErB9d3/wFKjELvr7xZs8N1CIg1V+9jbBsarn41tQzdq91b8j86AVlTuWtsslZTY=", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjktShYVvswbDI9MPpoC3x6YoE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHwxBX+4pclEgr6xOm/M2LCEHZRsHeMRaZwMGLqU6nRLuL4iYB0K1DEnVd6/HjDp+X35VwYm6Ab/o+MMDYLe8tHycKIx/T2yjFCOtBNlolo5Y4Wc/oAxSm+cdjdYMpmyy6VNUfxaXmtCHF6mjjYjTAWoY295yaoQMgiwwEnhII0rdsoPdmb2LqX4Ve9gkaV2XKWQKl3UVWXsY6l7kKPtZA9poHNsDzftPX9jPnd89sPIgxAvo9xYly517sQ6z49XNv0YRwL2eXCYET9ISbjJAcJ8M7wln1nwosqXH0xtB4GhoZaa8J2xJnwuXIxMckqGiG9okpJ3ZF4HxaGZK+30WvsoEEwNW85Z4tj/CkwtwqQJ0Rzn2WIDC1fkMBs8cYchwpic2xF3giN7vM18bUDIvCZe01ZK3o=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Egyptian", 
		"option_b": "Mesopotamian", 
		"option_c": "Harappan", 
		"option_d": "Crete", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180143", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9geh/gxO3vNGWQAGsHqnOKSKJgeX7tFK/Daq3/zYFwKV+MiRtv/WHI47X89l0BhqZcqbKRTCwxe4p8x97Tl9byx2VAPcFRloFgpJIQaedF3326fcDTYPx8x22Lakn5aTy5RHJ1gDnEhXNbu8O6+yP7UcI0xRk+k4lsrcwuPd6R2K+WqF6hlRKH0WjRSa9hUVGPvMqt5VfcqYx4tMGB8Rra5vXpivndsN0CdgFXrMSAMSdIgRy8Y+ehfyqzjcg6", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iYN5Ihy7iFpo/XiGqraw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZCTYAncMtRPcncJw+BfGIhQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXF7xzOn2MHiQEGoetHqHErB9d3/wFKjELuz635Z/JFmNzU905XiGs6nx+V0Gga8XqY+MMCcVd49qxtOM06T13TFVO8NNiMBl4ZYTMfBF3zSqetHfYPZh232FNAXxaT39F2VkkSPfhW4WrJG6/Cm6U9930wwhgoJ1/opq0Ni3l3K/6BXSlMTok6ym", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180144", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gehHg1vi/ImrDQ2EUrWuRU680ZH6jQK/HLtv7zZ5yZ1+cgU9u4HOGn6vM+WEKjrtU59TfRCoGPoNg2sOMl+3khHxEPdJNlY534NpNLaEA2DSgccebKfAu2maFZ3f5YHmLAXR11pBArgLMh3HY6jKDkVqhnTM=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iYN5Ihy7iFpo/XiGqraw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZCTYAncMtRPcncJw+BfGIhQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF1B3j9MUjWhf3w+6/MGbAC2MCqmWGVuNgeHSjXKjQfeiyiZZ/IxyAmUg74X/Braz2/lAOgbwb5IuRZCsMcMtmxpCd3+G39nhGc/BBnoEy948PbPtS2C7tYNzSM75ty2CUNUT8bi2kRHl61CXej3VE6ICu+TOuRt914OXiqLfnciUSxhgG9l/7tA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180145", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hdX+J2rAE2Mf43yKRKp4eWviQK7NYK32yJMxJhyehF9+snHDrKLi9kMHhqsb+p6NdSMHPrdh9N670uXky38bc/JMn5ky7JsbPPlP3jjtYNzaLr5vjnqIKFDjZje5RF11gCTEjzx+qZG65Te6WpokxQEmmoJ16MYoL5WzuE05gtAQj7jnCXDHCLkW", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iYN5Ihy7iFpo/XiGqraw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZCTYAncMtRPcncJw+BfGIhQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHl0Ar+t4s1Xxz3173wMyv9AnYEsXrDeqJmcWHzVamCfejq3Zt0KlmHmUg74HPAr6Dz40BPm6BeqZmWdCdDeY5gz8KIx+z+x3BNc9VUiIVz4NoQerRUxDjtXNXJIe5+z2DAJEzmbjW0HnFgnT7YyNzn5X+crN9VhxvYdb5uoqE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180146", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRj48oRgRR/hhe/6MmrCB2cV436QErd8dTHtW7XWZujsx5p+NEjJgk5v4nnVt+X/8RMDjrxeqaaeYiMTbophiNOc2/Di1nQecUW2FzeC+gcJOCfemFnIMLY=", 
		"answer": "24avaYWzxxjm+4A5EHtQGLMnvt/agE6QhN8NB5c=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzrt5clVR/gwfj7dWrDQ3YZpj+NXbFgeHTxWqrNffm+xoJlN1OamRt09DbKorH1t3sOnalL+Y+RMCEWcp962tXJ3ve36XBPN8cI2ox955sLefAAxTPtZMbeM/tg2iOEJlywTTiwCWU0lT/SyldXu4u2/DX3FPM5xBwz1rNw5Nt8L96L3OiA4EKvhQeR2WjRXLVhUVGBpc+m+EqTrsI3s42lsCDa5OT4lLja/tgHdw1cvIM/alWomOgd8C94X8emfBpO4+qQc1HqKSetNE4S/4v33nEp74wtVGg6tAxTgIBZbNR62J3qqH5wN8RtHT+zpExUzpp7HwOecbSqkGvx7EEqZ3snJZhovS494Q6SLBR3lH+ZXi1SgIlk8MNbAfwCtGKXdahzHOJ9FbKePQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Jammu", 
		"option_b": "Haryana", 
		"option_c": "Swat valley", 
		"option_d": "Punjab", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180147", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/Nm7eF3AQrz+XXeNgeHSjYqLGZ+6+yp94IlqazVp19jbLpqvk/lwBiqwbu9/KMDYKc458iNmHl/D/wTFzOsEErIV25cVdvAvLVGUXySF/q9zRD+ACKA==", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xDn9olgURv80e/+OSvEDCIFq3rDZKZweXKjV6/La+vtiZZ/IxyEiFVv+3nIpqGwpQJaz7xS5IuMMCsNPp9nzZC73uO38nRFMoZNicBm7J9fdPtS3zjtXNvJM/t9jmaFK0GwdDC6CnlynTLXhGgWu5q29yi3Xdl3wRs21pVx+d09MN6MzaGQqFu5ihOHnHKfCIthFV2a9d2n6EqZtJt09d+IoSDe5/H3jvHd954bbR9Xrco/bVS+nqQA7DN0Ecm6bFJG+OjZdVX/OWizNQEK/NjwlkBhw4s7HW8m8Q5Th41CIs122IztszxwNsMqATu/43ZJwNRKWhOfd/2wyWXq8xUtcHwnYIl5r20hqQqVOhR9j2eIWT5QmMBi88AWhxBic2xF3kGcztHaDgQjgerORIovKXE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Elephant", 
		"option_b": "Rhino", 
		"option_c": "Tiger", 
		"option_d": "Horse", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180148", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjt5YwjRxLm0O/+OSvDBnYFr3qOV61gMHfqRrTWLuzsxoR0Z12bgk519jaR8/Wgt3Es0OqPdcJGl5/SArHZGXTKhoWJ", 
		"answer": "25i9YIP00AvitcEjxmki05yh+VPloeNGkhk=", 
		"explanation": "25i9YIP00Aviu8UsXR3z0fj7dWLeQ3IDpmyGXLc5dHD6FJfDZeTt3ZZ/axyAnht0/HOGrKOw41sKz61a+4KWdTEXPoBhx8eHl+Xw1nhCJspQj5Jz6NoMeeBUwDigcdrPM756xm+UZ0D9Yiu6AXQ0lSPZn3JS6NTrpXf7dvl36QFyhY93+ss9L9KMmbyb7Q2slAeMz3KFQbJqUVKLusPo6gOSr485scSO8T7S8vHqjuHf9Z4fbUhBupJrb164164I6icxX8/4KB9K4+/Zb1OtIWigNRse8MrvlmRhx5EsHWA6tAtOh8NSZ9Z22pf0sTc+K41lE3OytklBydR/VgGfeLSi0Xzt71t9zgxZk0OO+3lDN4epT1nh9A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hakra area", 
		"option_b": "Mehrgarh", 
		"option_c": "Harappa", 
		"option_d": "Mohenjodaro", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180149", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4RgQgz7yPztLCvTC2MDonyXV7F9Y2XqV+fNaK3uxoRlakmbj1p1sl7HsaTg51IBz6tO5ZqKYicQIcmSaB3kkL5mguUIb8NtNXqI", 
		"answer": "25awaZ3w3hXj440pUVxxmsYDLCY+qtrDEKSn/Har", 
		"explanation": "25T4eIP63Bj47sUjWh/gxP7rMHnZEHYYoD+MVONkf2L3GbLQbOzwib9wNV2ZnVp1snXTr7Hl5VYcz79a+s6LeCdDbYNmzsTJ0fb4yTFNMtRDn8wy558RaOZBwDS3cdCbNexsz2DAJED+czyvFzBgm3HFh31apIaptTS+QM47xRg3mJNrrfw0OcSamauG5FmtlAORnGyYXLNhAkecsY6pq0eZo4c2od+MvTvB9eDwlfaT/9hLcgdFupQ/YlW416lJ9SUqVIi4ZxFK/e3KZFCtNym6ZwEbucfq0HElhpUgSWF09V9AjYBDcYB82NjluyA5PNhmASaopggAxIZ9WQOFeby2w2Dt8Bl/dHQvJZ5/vSkw4ytTAU8hzl52M1FgC1fPgFY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chalcolithic", 
		"option_b": "Urban", 
		"option_c": "Agrarian", 
		"option_d": "Neolithic", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180150", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcB/+0P73PHjEAmxRtH6QEqBxfmXxVauCeuK+3Z90Z1mIn1disl7HsaTg51IBz6tO5ZqKYidDQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBFsdXjoVg6toZbv1Oyzjte9KbAv9i222ILlbkZjf9DHFw1CXejzxTqZG3/CKoQJo2xwc7lZJ0+d0uPdvfyq2H/EG9iwOMyGjRSa9rBFqd9Zn4uxPcgqF6Yhl+D4BLPLAWNmjkz+aBmA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iYN5Ihy7iFpo/XiGqraw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZCTYAncMtRPcncJw+BfGIhQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e5ZITw2RD544QuFQ2ywPztOXKQAmUDqnyWXrdhYnDvFLTHevnyzJp0KUiazVd66zbSq6Cw8Vwagaxa/YeQfmIFcZkv3NiMl8z21nBRI8dK2oN78pMTde5B2DSiepbTRfnZjdez0O69hrvOi5JZ", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180151", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gYhHh0bDqJ2nRDSI5om2CQrN1fjHgQavWe//7iYBwNByNhF1992TDrbGw8UEAguh26JqKYidDVop9ycCZ1uq3x2RNJ9NWn8BO6qYRTvFB3zKjLpTrL+16g3uSJUT+JxG8FnFkhDDYyn9DpJeu5yKoFM0y0hByhpVx4MkuNduGmYub6UG7iQqLyHOYS/8GygPGzEHAKXeqOQbfCW0I", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iYN5Ihy7iFpo/XiGqraw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2pR64do+b+dF3imke9qZCTYAncMtRPcncJw+BfGIhQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg2RDs48U0XV7RzfzzNmTcCnYZqnzDRqx7fGKjQ6bRLuLwzNd+IRydhV479HfFt6ri5BMLhrtP4ICYZSsQdoJhz5CZ2PfjiWRTMcdK2qhz9psPbPVO332rZtvWYOpmy2eSZ1XiYj24B3Vnhz7EmT7SyehT56uV+ieHRLMdMh3V", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180152", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit60hQB/i1fzxdXjZF2dRp3aHErd8dTHvVbPHLsX/25ZhN12Hnhtr4HnEoqf87hMfnadf/I2aMCEMap9gxo/La2BTBOyl3zrpGLvurHEEKw==", 
		"answer": "25S0aZz02Av64pdi4wB9PueDZ3WuD7kLoHhU6Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/0A3vt60hQB/i1fzxJivcCmkUr2bDQrF7dGTgUaOCbeLq3Zh/Z1WHzU9z9zbuorfx50MOgehI4JqaMC0FPqhnyd6BwqnzxWNOc+dWmYhz4ZUTc/NJzzyhNNLSLvpnwGmTZ1blYD64F2Q0kSffjnlYq4b7+iH7V9Uj1Bo81oRt4dw1KtaL0KedqEy2gkaW2WOFQbFhUUSLusq96FeVr4x09cSDtTvY9eDwlP+T5NYOIg1RsIhwblK/17sA/yQxV8G3aRxI9KTfZxTuLzy3KABd8MWjwnxg1cI6WH0g+BpLh41CIGb/paw2lCMbSbib4So89yw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Manda", 
		"option_b": "Chandigarh", 
		"option_c": "Alamgirpur", 
		"option_d": "Mohenjodaro", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180153", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80e6/NGnfFnZRt3eGEot1YnDzRKbMLu7rxYNkNVnJjEl+snXJsbf19EdQz5RVuM62ZGIUf5gv2MKA2uXlzX1Yc8VBlJR39p8bPPVSwyijcJTYIep6wmvANUDxdTCzAzBImg3Y2DxioIb73SapVconwRsh1o956YgyM5eU16eE5Ei8gQPC033RXLVhUVyWp92tq3+SnIxr9fmFtHLz9eb4iujS/s1LdxtXu8Z9dkmyg+gL6iM7Wtv0bh1ZsebFaFjpKSakZx0J697gwmF7w5FpYWcI+ksGtotTIuhyxJn0rDM+LI16Bzq3olZJy408TAeZf7j4xGDhoHwxcXVmRJh0vSN1rQ6SL0F/nW7eVZfhfCtE7nAzd04qCwODiA==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2yzvP6IivRAW0Etz+XWqY0eH7xR6KOLuzyy5J4MxyHgk874mTJrqz+8l0bg7Eb5YeUdWIXdo4v/tWN3ue31HROI8pB2rR64YNfeexUyTO+fcLeLOcu232FIwXyciuzEDB2hjjVgW8a6IGu4WevXN8+0lU+l4l/+Mk7OZeN3KWS4UOrxhOM13WeX7MmFjkks/ID5rvPLbA+HM6LuA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "1 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180154", 
		"question": "24KxfJmzwxzs8pclXB33henwdX/YBiI5om2CQrN1fjHgQavWe//7joQxI1mKgVJ19zqGtK359FtPnLxa/YuSdSwXbctu2tXJw/biwS4BD8gV2q5389oLZeRF332icpTLL+p6y3yZZ1blYD64F2Q0kj7Ej3VRpsOy+zOpQck+zxtyqolE45p8EtKImbiW5120gxXC2mmeRf1NA1WX9c+m7wOPr5csvY2utDzP5vX12tnA+d9LZwZGupR6Zxuon61J6i8/WMe6KC5FzeqDIWDlJTqmZxkc6ovmwH1tw4wqWCk78l9Lg5BFL9Nw15Th/DE/Mct4Gj2uolBJyJo8XRKCY7i93ijo4UE6NVIqd4t9rCw7sk+dJlA+s2WYQ2Fwhplq8MNZqQpfczsAr3/njCzLj2PPdZ3w7oPpl+Hkufli/KdnP0iPOVnWVYhccrbSIid33OCfCKhIc5ZpVzbuOJUi/S38YIac3ioIkNYmb1ro/C+XmMLxOHe18SE3g2l5jlCKDzkcv7XAnX4=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9FiCReDHSYbT1Rhi+bjtXhU5A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH31Brm/oslEhH0hen3MCv4AnAQs2+CXON3ZX33QbXHLv7/3td0MVWNiFV49zbJpeX+8kRPn6dP/YuNaWIXZ5tq25CI2eC313hGPdUElYYy7ZQMefdV3jS5bZTaNL5DwWaFKU//YzivCzBAnDTEjztF6I20tSKtXd4yzhY31oh+rcl8MNaN3q3e+065igPC33SfTq9rH0CYocen5QOepZYvsMiD8SbT8bT1m+zWsPYKcAlCr4dxcBu9maxJ7CI9EeG6bB0G0PbJYFr+YjMaD4YGTBwntgxqXafuMSs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2, 3 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "1, 3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180155", 
		"question": "24KxfJmzwxzt9pckQV7myr3+MnnZAHcdt2qRV+80Z3nqV6+Cffn/3ZJ8IlKdnht64HOGt7fl8gxPs6YKqbqXdWIxd4wv/tWN1qT6wX9VOslKicBm7J9ff+FM2DS7dcDSL/AuwWjANUzzYnm8CnQ0gznTi2gWlI2H+3X7YNIygD0zhIZo/ckyL5eczKSH4Vu5kgOGnGiUW7xpBFnZtMCsq1OZoZF4icOxv2Gb1vXrlv3KsMkKcUhZsYlobRuomOgL9z4wEdy8bVJj8PbRcUTsLjvjJgAZud/r0zRbz4Vpa2ww9V96jL9YNoBB15/t/CUxLI1rVT67qUtSh5duUAfWfbP4+Gn24UUvdHRrdoN5uT51qAHcJltsjmPcZSJVnYEpJ+zrNHYmcPJwKG4SRycDow==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU179y/HmdWbVDXYYrHGQEqF1Yn3mTeuCb+P6iYN5IhyhjEl64mbHrbaw9EYDm6FN6JqadGIQe5huxcWEl+X5wDFRNsdX2rJz45Nfa/VTwnq5NNWbLf9kwXzAJFf/d3m0CjBclSPXmmxXpsOo/DO+R5o+zlU8mZVs5YgVMtOW2OonUGQQFS74R+NtJtkzqp4V", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180156", 
		"question": "24StbYLn2BbkrcUMWw3miNS/ImLECyJRj3aQRu5dWSuhaBM/PC7uzyFLO12oa468+w==", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjkt7ElQAzzxvLrIWrDQy9RhnOGQqt1fmWvFI7PfuLs3ZZ/JFnJgl072nnUsKCwuhMnhq9T5ZfffScNaoJgxtWNl+35hENINIZyn4RzqNo0cvtXwn2BddrcNf9pyy7NZ2z+YzbwJWJtlT+WhXoWnoa//CT7QNM6xQZ+1q526d0vfOScy6GD/A2LlgOD136DW/0pUWKcscerq1OZr5I0sI+VwZv27RS6xsVutJTRjowV", 
		"explanation": "25T4QJDh0An69otgZhvg1/z8On/EAnFRtHqRV+NkYn7nQaTHaq380NdlL1nJpVpp82bWoquw9FoZhqRS84+LeS0NPr9nzcnJxeHn1nRSNshQ2pR64ZMNPPVS2DS+YN3YYPt23nyFNFb5aDeuRHF6kHHVmH1QvJC29CmoXNMnjFUhnohv7skvNdmYmb6S+kS3kxXC3WiBTb5wAhSWs46s6kqQucI0vMuI/XLY4fjtj+rWvJ4KbAwSrYNzaly1mL0auCg9XcGxbgEL5ezCbkHqKGigKw8Euc3q0WF7w5EVU0t0wBdDwqpbcs9hwpnqvzdwMMsqPTyosEEAzoc8Vx6RfLGx12Dw5VF/fHRrU49ptS51ohqQPEFsnyfcWyRUhoUr9t8LhgFwPWdFkHKgkSaGgmqDdZCj/YHwkO2wsrxz4KY0LE+UPFLfFp0TcrbSayd8xeuSAa9IKtMnFizifdgn8DDtIYSNnykf384lPGSnwCKci43iPHe/85H8gMBkFbNAIt6F386zuV+Hcyr1NHyfdYv1VwywWHnq1k5jpR003SQe/G7BSIR6+zkEkXC1TQRtnGfSZXvhoLtY68KGZoM/wMni/nIkkPE4tJX4wxN8awW1impCtYHfQFoP2VzTXuUG1gg+HLUPVJXY5GSanGzRX3UCcY7kBKWGyiJbmvb/imR+toAGUJ6LKFWbi81m3B+0QdR3UXL+6JX6L/UFHiQ48rdoiviyss77ffK3bGsle1q1XOpXs5NEZA5iUQLTESFdcKqrQpgaAdRH1zXGlglPUn5OABrf66cDWArqqN2IemLbI5kdHB/yc7ILAI7qS0rOPP+6iDGJFaqen0K9SwQqSHqSL7cC7An3Op73NxaygWtsucDrNhFIVIYUKSvyYGK2q5+NL0YOdyllG5pCe0zQWQNkmziDM/FizY4OdA0+AZukC1kGglFOjTuSHUxMvEBeSquuRUEzK6BLYGwZxDuwUbMQURmKligFnlmPx2L4If8LIUYwaG2RhkDpj4smkPmpppyAHN3mJLwVkoIRaJ9VQJWbPkkFm/2k4+DuFnk4AWhkYrjcVueRtVf3Ady0rsrUwklC2qoBNR86Iz+ChZbY5DNiIeVAaTBetXZZhcTWdxXqyotL3EB8EEfp+EDtT3Rht1FnYYPiaZ3TLNuh9VJeAiGHVrRMlvs4zi/sOtPQdgl9H3GXWdPpiikL5E6ufYgeEw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Harappan Terracottas,Elephant", 
		"option_b": "Importance of Horse,Highly mentioned in Rig Veda", 
		"option_c": "Known Language,Indo-Aryan of Vedic times", 
		"option_d": "Indus Script Speakers,Vedic people", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180157", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEh391+/6Nn+QAGoDrHGMXqxzeXLiWOfNfOn729d4KRyehVJ4+jbSq6DM+VUAg6RU/oeRd2ICbptqycKM06T+yjFoPcJNm98y38tGJax98DP8NPPULPouzWGJKVbMaWv9NGV6lzmWh31Eo4a/tTSyWMwy0lUxmY52/vQyb5e2y6edqF20iROF1EefHP1RA1aYu46r/k+ItZA9icO+tD7e9+C5jvDWsN0EcBpXvJI/YlWvgK0buD8rWMazKAZD9KTTblDoM2ikLhgY94vh03hm0dhrRu24GgymNDrsLq73qb7dqg==", 
		"answer": "2+H0O92inUuoxdsIlmAhjM5OwftOZVaP9Q==", 
		"explanation": "24CqapD9kRr/+5E1QBuohcn3MCvVDmcDpHqNUaY0f3ejQbXAb+O+yoJ9M0mbiBty/DbHrab58l0bz4FV7YeeMCsQPop829+K3uXjwXUBJM9QksBm7J9fVfpE2S7tQtXXLPt3jk2JMUz8biO8EHl7mn2WhXJT6Iy9tTOzUZogzwc+ksBrrc09LtuW3LuHqFiqhAeMnHiYXrRoGE6Yocen5VDQ4IY5ocSDtnLZ9ffy2uzcsN8ZbR1cu8YtNgvs14oq3RY2bcadeh1FsfTcbkHqKHLjDhwS94v32Xtl1c5pVGc3+ApCi41RItR709jtrj0+f91mGia9qwgAxZF/XhqTNK2q1X7l7FAxYToia8pEsik8oE+dOltrlG/cHXwBxMBJ3fVZkRFxdGFH3GLoh3+HgXGKbtPV7oT1hqjgpatq/adnKE+EdUjQU80eYLTJKWl7xO7bAqAcJ5diVwv0Mttu3T78HJio0R4C3N1gLHju+jnD0ur6NWH6sJ3wgMc2A7oSM5HM59+lv1jSYiblYXSdJuL6XQHxD3D5xwt3+1gh3TMZ5mWYHIF6tQoYjmqxCVRhgC7vaDDhgbZV6YrOfYs20vus3CAfjfp834//0V1oUwz7jnpNppGNVhxs6GjYIsM30QctBPkMFYTa92nWhn/cXXkfP835CKaUmWx4z+3yhixwvoIFUIjOPxDXnNs0iBS+CPNqFXf/rYL4KflVDWsg/vJyxeSvpIq6e/fkO2A4alq+V69a+odSfQ56BQLSC2RGbviHWJkXQKBLx2fDmQAIU3dMRQzY8+gcUkT+vsyIbW/Qd6QOBxvxI5EmNoK4XlXGOPC7wTzQRruJh06wWAQxRj/dDLEF5A3xdI3iJRey03hh68jqNhNEo1GWu/dgsdNx3vGoR3h7", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "3,4,1,2", 
		"option_b": "3,4,2,1", 
		"option_c": "4,3,1,2", 
		"option_d": "4,3,2,1", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180158", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbk8sUvVF7mzfi/M2TcD20GqnGEEqJ6eXziWLSCeeztiZl+MxybiEtp92XDrbH1828BnK1a5Z3fcSwHPp9q2sKI1Ovj0HABMtRQ2o90pI4XebRozS+sZMTaLr5t22KUMlf1OHmGViAkxQyUL0b4nJTLyD3uTZ3JTVcXag==", 
		"answer": "24Gxb5Thk3F+LE+W03irzTJtvnq9OfY=", 
		"explanation": "25S1Z5/0kQ3i8sUvQgr7yvPsdXvCDHQYp3qHHuNgeHSjVanLY+zyiYN5JkjJmlposnjJt+Xi8kMdirte55qadGIKcMt7wNXJxOH2yGIBMshA2pR39ogef/tU2DztdcbPYPFojnqIIgXYZiu8FGB1mnHVn3BCvZG+tS6oFM4/xVUGn4B9/4gPOdaTyuiS5kn4kgOQznqSR6lwEBSYp9ro7VGTrcIsvcjNmTPJ9eTpm/aT88sHdh1AusZvcVKxlroA9DN4Vc2kYRFfseXeaFnsLDvjKwcW/Iv33nEpxY0+ESkx+BpWioJYdowz15bg/CA4NsNlFjaorFcMh5ZpS1eCfbq9wnuk4Uc6NXQkccpusyA4rgGQMRR4lX6SSGxYmsB/9tUQh0Rib3tXk2TrwjCZwHaWcZHs54nviKqZmm1r/964jbNUXDOcOr2P", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Cow", 
		"option_b": "Elephant", 
		"option_c": "Rhinoceros", 
		"option_d": "Tiger", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "180159", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbk8sUvVF7mzfi/M2TcD20GqnGEEqpnMH/sQOfDLsX/25ZhN12HzWhy5nOZn6vLpQNe1uUK1MxwAWqDQ5EsfPi7m3B/jOrG", 
		"answer": "25G9e5D/wQz4ta4JOJ/ES2FIdB0JW67UYcQ=", 
		"explanation": "25awaZ/7xB3r5Yp6Ej36xPP3IG/REW1RqmzDW61wdXTnFKaCRuzsyIdhJlLJnlJv9zbvt+X55BMOgeha+42XcScMcoRowdOI26TkzWVEc89K2rN76p4XMLRwzTakZ8DaLrIuz32TKEb5Zi24ADBjnSXeymhercOS+yOuR5oBwRk+k544zsEqNduWw6mH4UK2ugi+0lCeXP1AGF6Q746D5FfchIsyvI2EonLa+vvtkv3BsPYKcAlCr4dxI0i1g61FuCY3UsmgbRYL+OqQdVzoYAOrJgcP6d7xllBg1ZY7VGogtBBAwrBfbMR7mtjUvTk5LNlrG3OTtwRJ1NR3URiBev2+33qk6UEsNXs5ZoJsuSI5rgiVK1Vy2nmZQS1YmpMr+tENnApkPW1Bn32gljDLlG2KPLvi+YHslen+4Klm4KooLX2OCVLrWYUdYrLVNWYoitqUBadbMop1FmLvLpUv8Cr2YJfU9zgf0ckwLnmn5yONl43cLSWzoNL1gdd3ALoEdtjLqd+/tRzJbjH1KXiBaIvkWBrkD3P+kydrsxEkhGEZ5iLMAIw/5jkMinvwRkIkpzP0bW7hpqxd7oedd84Uy/btyzMEkft2jNv2wF0PSAy6in5WoIXfR11ZyBTEG9sCxQUrCPQpFYTQ4n2XmzbRWWgEec/1FbvHwiJMmvDlnHR+q4UcUJ+yIiXVrts1yRuhFO8jFUPou4f1LekHSm0/urx+3q2g9+K6Z/K0PGQkLwm+TeoZx51Uegc7GBidCysPaLG9QpIMSONO3jXFhUdJVXxBBF/D96cPVAerpoTNeGPaZr8fC17uar0OGsD/Dk7bdeWmiCTBA/+1m0OrTAQTTzaRJKlNxg7mc4D7PhKnmmdquejxclhIBI0YKGfyZ3i2pqqCHwM+PzssPIIHbk/QCxEqlzfGKe0npaYScQg9QKbnGkUaggRdmnxzF0pwG8xfTLdqDharhxzK", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Harappan Culture: Bronze Age Urbanization in the Indus Valley >> Religious Practices to Chronology of Harappan Archaeology", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Chanhudaro", 
		"option_b": "KotDiji", 
		"option_c": "Sohagaura", 
		"option_d": "Desalpur", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190101", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRt3qbRrA0eWKjQK/HLuLyzZJiMxyLjEh+9jbJreX38l0KnalX5ZffcSEAe5t7zdTJ0+XjwWIecaVfZ2jawTudHayCFHM0Jio=", 
		"answer": "24exb9HF1B3rtVCnnj6O+0Ospe8ZH9hxEPo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU1771r37NH/VByIDrGqEWq9tMGXsFPaXPr2+67Q9Z1GIhlJ19TbPt+Xk/1ZPgKRf7J2LMCMOcYVoiMSB0qTwzWdEPYZQn5hm99hJvm73xc54o5zL67zhGF+/", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "Zend-Avesta", 
		"option_b": "Homer's Iliad", 
		"option_c": "Rig Veda", 
		"option_d": "Odyssey", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190102", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr/9ZY0UxDxwL32JivdBmwFqnCNV6c0eX+jQK/HLuH/3ZJjZ0yGn09y/XjV46r2t3sAgq1Jrp3fZy0RdZgwisXk77aT+EbWlQ2d8q2FvyA=", 
		"answer": "25yqZ5+xM/FwQkrenY6NyQi+fslUTw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH/0A3v5cUwXQzmzPLxJivfBSI5rHKGQORnMGbsRqzRLuD7x4N4KFLJmVN+smPVpuX/8RMGnadVq8hzdWz96clK9tTSUrNXsvs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Bronze", 
		"option_b": "Gold", 
		"option_c": "Copper", 
		"option_d": "Iron", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190103", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohdTxMWSdInAIonGQErN7Y2LqVqvbLuD3zoVwM1mNzV1p/XuGgKD+40EOg+h6+oeeTCw/cMtdzdGa2Oq3jEMIaYZl2od36p8LdfcAwTy/f9HJYP1vwmKFIwXdJ2jqSDBjnDjVgjxGuoat9C63R5o+zlURk4ls/8kwfPaM0KmdqF6sgxaS2WjdCLR3UVWVpsHo7UyJroZ4s9+IoCfe+uD1g7ja/p4fag0Sloh7bBadhbEI9morQc21YxdZ4qZ7EOrP1rZ3f4Puqe+lMGCP", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxz58osjV179w73rPW6QBGcfpmuKUeN5cWPoUbWCQ62vntd4KRyLgk9zslXDrbHi9l9PrrtS6IDfYzYGbptq25CI2eC37X9FPItliJlz6toMbPFBxzi/Z5TINe5+wXyUNAXkbzz9B3x1nTyWhXoWvIu+/DX7WdMw0hQmn4h2rc4uM9rf+q2d/F+5ikajz3KQCrAAFzVqAMlBzCZt5KGzXsY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190104", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cVoc1eohcn3MCvVAnAduj+qXKd7PVT2RqjSa+zwiZtwKVucjFx+4TbRprf1t0AfgKNe586WfmIXdo4v3NWEx+HlxWVEc9xLlIVO6qYRPMZFzS6iepSTErc0jlqIIgXzazCwBWR9l3HVhXJSoZey+imoGJo1yQc2hcs47MY1MdaTyuTT6UO8xhKQ2X6CCK9hB1GYucusq1CJp4U9ptnNpTra4LTtkv2T0cwSYwZB/4J2ZxuymLxJ9CMuVIi9ZlJc8PbdZEatITqmJh1fOwMB1yxw7tpmRcSgOM9Dlg==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+1Bf+/oouEhH0he7vMGjZBWsS43yPW651ZHjgFKTNYOn33Z5+KU/FzVly4HLV7+Xx+VoCjqRIpc6efiZDaplqzcPJ3urzzXJAJ8NX2pR65Y5faPxFjBy/bdXVM75ix3iFIwX5aXmpAX1kkSPXnnkWsoy18DT7VdQzgBs9gsdx44grPcWS3LrT6V+9hxXAWP+84ZK/99CtI1LWkINx4A==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190105", 
		"question": "24GwbdHSwwDr+cUwVxHiyfi/JXnVB20cqnGCXLd4aTHxUavLa+m+xpkxGGO2smREzUmGoqv0t0MOnLxU+4+TeTEOPop8iMSB0u3lhGFTOshHk5Bz6NoMc+FSzzi+NNvdYPJn2GuMLk3/aD3/Q1xwIObSpQnA0EVdu8kEUQ==", 
		"answer": "27S/epjwxBX+4pclEC5I1c6ueA1sw+Rc4DaMAHI=", 
		"explanation": "25S/epjwxBX+4pclEh/+yvP4dXzZF2pRs36QRqxmcX3qR6qCeejszNdlL1nJnUly/3fUuuXj+EYdjK1IqYGZMC4KaI5jwdiG2OC3wn5Tc9JMn8BT9oMecucCHUa/7Ym01vDdD7JiU95eXg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "ag,ri,cu,lt,u,re", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190106", 
		"question": "25S1Z5/0kQ3i8sUJXBr9iNjqJ2TABmMf43yMX65hfnj3XaLRIq3qwZIxGGO2smREzUmGsKTz5VoJhqteqZmeY2ICPohgxd2G2aTn1nBCJ89Hn8I6ZSw/ty+k5bpqq1H6vSXb", 
		"answer": "2723eoL2kxjhbyz+tVNwlqQBF8fT+L0=", 
		"explanation": "2523eoL2kQrr9JcpVBfxwL3oNHiQE3AQoGuKUaZwMHP6FKbOYq3qwZIxDlKNghZe52TJs6Dx+RMMgKVW/ICWZCsGbck1aWc+WQqJRnNMkgNAbIH5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "hor,se,ho,rn", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190107", 
		"question": "24KxfJmzwxzs8pclXB33henwdX/YBiIwsWaCXON3ZX33QbXHNNHwmNdFL1mQzU5o93KGsLX//FYLz79T7IuTYx4NLMtbwNXJ9vbuxX9Sc8pNjIV2pJMRPPUA2C+iZN3YIfIuzWKJKkTkYgWzVzBAnDSWiWlavMO082esVc4y0lUll5Q4/do5KtaT3KaHqEy1iQiFnFKfTLIpNEGLut6t6k3cs5I9tMaIoyHn+qC5rvDW6Z4ecQ1W/4RwdEj8lqYNuCsqQ8eje1Jc+e3TaRT6JTqmZx4R+Mjm0jRgyMI4SGAi8Q1Vvo1lZ8x21YykqDo1f85lByG/oFAA1IB9SxKbcbOswyoSh9HGywKeSwxLULWNaXDG", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kU2oYXwG2MTAZOqfNg6CyLlF0w==", 
		"explanation": "24aoZ5r21Vn9/4AlXg2yxPP7dX/YBiIEsHrDXaU0cn70R+fDYOm+yIVjKEuazUt383XDp+X5+RMemqFN7JyMMCMRe8tizd6d3uv5wXUBOsgEjoh3pIoebvVH3jy9fJTvKPsu73yZJkvjJzW0EnVw1DjYyn0WvIa25SKpVc4ygBY+n4p5+c1wfNaR3eiH4Ej4hROOyDueTv1iGEac9c+m7wOPr485+Y2Dviab4/Xtn+qfsMkKcUhCrYNpYle5mbxLhK5NxhicFZBW0aVVc5ttRw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "1 and 4", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190108", 
		"question": "25e5e5T3kRbkt5ElSgrhn8HxZCv4DG8UsTiQErR7YnrwFKPDeui+y5ZyLBydghsuoiaGgYbM+W8B3ehp4InfRicHf8tm25Cd3+G3y31FNtVQ2oF/65QYPOBIyX2gcdrPKfFgy2rAM0DocyqBCkx6x3Hsj3JS5aKt8DSvVZo6xRsmn4h2/ogoNNLfzLuWqEK+xg+Q03WtRoFqRRS4u8el6k/cs4M7p8SLuDHetOP4ibjQ/9MGbQYSvotwbVz8lqQFuAM2Vcf5TQdZ/vTVYFqtIyeuKhsT8N/q02dVyLEsUWw34F9SioYWYc9hxJ3nqHIjK8x+ED6/rVBThXsk1S6k1oxFqDwyDoOBa4I=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24exb9HF1B3rt4wzEhrz0fj7dX/fQ3AetniLXro0ISSzBOfgTa3zyJx4KVvJhE875n7D46r881Ycm+ha54rfcSwKc4pjiMOI1Pb+wnhCNoZTm5My55UScftOjDyge9rcYNdgymHNAlDiaCm4BX40lz7bh2lYoZey8DT7fNU6xQd1hcdv4to3L5eey63T7EysgwLCyHTREe00XAzJ5Y6KyAOdroZ4ocWIozec57T3lbjA4NsIaw5bvMZyZlWonqcHuCU+EcGmZxwL+OqQW1HjJGWCMQsO7cqj33op0oosHXk15h5BkIJGaoJXiRy+pSrrKgyYJnz9KWs9", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190109", 
		"question": "25a3ZpL2wxfj+YJgRhb3hfLtPGzZDSIQrXvDWqJ2eWXiQOfNaK3Xx5N+anmcn1Rr93fI47bg8lIEirpIs7KRIWI3do4v6cKQ1urkhGFOINVNmIxrpJYWavFEjDSjNMPaMvNr3C6BNUDxdAWzOH4m1AXejzx/poe0uAapTds501U/n4Bq7Nw5OJeZy6eeqG69iBKQ3XfRaa5tEGiXicD7q3eUpcI/sMOIpTvYtPn4iPPW4p4mIlkF/49sI12zgqYNuCU2XdH0YRwL0uHedUbsLGiCNAccxcXf2CAp8oosHWw15hNfwqpYZs8+8432syI1PsMqGTK0pFFBwJFvHwCTZrj4w3jr61AxNXMlJZ5luW0hpAKMLUZ/jm7cViNfkbxlzdUVkAd3PXtImTbjjS2ZhWabPID36pT5iO3+tKoh1Mp9GCHNd7FKYeogzdApsw==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3luqQySx/81r3vOnjDCmAduj+OW6RmcWXmUOfEfOLzibR0KUibjFc702XPouX04lZPm6cb/YaaMDIRe5hqxtOMl+vxhGVJNoZp2tElpJ0acvFUxT7tedXJK/t8gi6BKUGwczG4RHV1hj3PylVYrIz20DKpW8oywRtymoZ26t09O9KMmb+W+kj4lRaN136fCLRqUUCRsI687k6MpZA5ocjNqz3V8bTNkv2T0cwSYwZB/4J2ZxuymLxJ9CMuVIi9ZlJc8PbdZEatITqmJh1d+MXnlmBhw8IEHThjtBJHkIhTcIB6xdjqsyZwOtVpGSapqlJFh4BzHzSTeqmq0WSkwUY2dDoqdspkqGom4Q6QO1s+nGSJQigRlY1k8NdZvApnciJhjm/hjH+YkGCOd5bx+MIvvnyEFXXbKaIqkdGESzip", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "2 and 4", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4", 
		"option_d": "2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190110", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt5EpXxvhhfnwMHiQF2oU42uGQK40TDPiR7HDUq++xpRyMk7JhFU75n7D45f58BM5iqxatszDfQ6EajH61/cvCYbvQFX0", 
		"answer": "y+Tte2mXYin3WCG7i6dZX6KeYg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liUw3kxMG9dSPYDHACpjbDU7NkdXDxR+eQP7i+3Z58Ik/JhFU75n7D45f58BM5iqxapc6ScSkKcIwvwcTJ2OryhH5Hc9JMn8B/64kLPPJSySy4cdrPLOcuw2uOM0z/aTy5RHF6nTzXhm8WoY374S++FM4y2AFwdxfMfrsjXGGLTLspjInNOA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 176, 
		"option_b": 215, 
		"option_c": 170, 
		"option_d": 200, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190111", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4cvXRWyyvu/IWPVQ1AYpD+1V6d1MHDxUefWeeK+wY58KU/JiV5t/WLDp+Xk+BMHgLpI7M6McSERd41my9XWlU0eISi+gs5vNzeuE6CfDKs=", 
		"answer": "24G9ZoX7k/iGH3p5V37zm7HPv+6EKlg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU1nhhen6O3/YQ2AerHTDUax6ZHDqWrSCevrxiZ9oKlKazV9+9n/ForH18xMbgOhP4YvfeC0RbY4v29GKxe3xzXJEcSScafVrEqExcMiNvcUbbiM=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ninth", 
		"option_b": "Tenth", 
		"option_c": "Eleventh", 
		"option_d": "Twelfth", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190112", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t5EoV173xO/zPG7DFyIVrHKGQbd9c3D3UaOCZuLs2pIxIVOcg18ksLE+ycD5qWH33+BUkAkYHwM=", 
		"answer": "25e9fIb21Beq440lEjr8zPjvMHmQAmwV40mMXqR1MGPqQqLQfa+iWnod800S6qAgk7YAYVn3", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywxzrt4clRgn3wPO/IWPVQ0YfqnqTV7E0cX/nFJHNYur/iYV4MVmbnhty4TbIrLH18xMbgOhT6JiaMDYLe8tjycKO0vfjhH9UPsRBiMB94toXc+ZTyS7hNN3VJPdtz3qJKUKwczG4RHV1hj3fj29C6Iat/CO+WtkygBo01o93/9s5fNOQ1K2A/ES7hxKL03XTFBOWR7XWiSIBnOKDXQ8WnQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Anatolia", 
		"option_b": "Black Sea", 
		"option_c": "Between the Dnieper and Volga rivers", 
		"option_d": "South Siberia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRr/+5E1QBuyxO3vMGrCECIFrD+QWqxjMGXrUefHb//ywJJiMxydn05+sn7Jsbb1t1oBz5tU/JqXMAMQd4ovycKGwurzhCAWY5YEuKMtpsdQ95eggId022PC1lxSwd4=", 
		"answer": "24WxepD4k2Ru/Iglo0zgw6HaFI3n+hE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD2Avr/MUjXRPiyfjndWXVAnBRt3eGEoF7fHDtFLfDff6+2YV+MVWNiEg792DPp6D+9FZPiadJqZqXdWIGf5ljwdWaw6Tj1mREc85LiJN3pJMRPMdP2SmlNPXIKf8uz3yPMkv0J2jqVCA0thKUSSEbryaLkxnReomlaOEUyw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gandhara", 
		"option_b": "Mohenjo-daro", 
		"option_c": "Pirak", 
		"option_d": "Harappan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190114", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ/v/4wjXhuyzO6/NmTdDm0fr2bDU7Bnf3LqVbPHaq3pwIN5Z0iBiBtS/HLJ7oDl5VwfiqlV+s6WfmICcIhmzd6dl/Dy3GVSbISncnAdKcDrKhYOMSdiVPDQ", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2nB349pIuEh36xO/2On/DQSOFvvPebcl+opPxzaoJJYE=", 
		"explanation": "24O9bJjwnVnL4YAzRh/8ib3+O2+QK20cpm2KUeNgdWn3R+fEfOjv3JJ/M1CQzVZ+/GLPrKuw41sKz6BU+52aPSYRf5xhiNOB1vb+y2VSf4ZNlIR755sLdfpHjCmlcd3JYO1nyWCJIUzzZje+ATB9mnH/hHhZ5aau5yirUds5gBYnmpNt/80vfsNHG1S+/If1yGVb7RUbq+M=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Carriages", 
		"option_b": "Horse-drawn chariots", 
		"option_c": "Carts", 
		"option_d": "Wagons", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/G0TkQ28UrWuKXa1xdDHqWufWZui++552Z2qMiVoksNOF38W29KcIUacN2zfrV+U=", 
		"answer": "24ewYZ/80hz4+JZisHP5SSX6w1bOWhXRjL9lJw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU172yvjsdWXfFyIcpnGXW6x6MGXrUefQZuTwxpR0NVOawRto53HBprbk/l0Iz6kbyouRZDACcstO29mI2aT+yndNJsNKmYUy65RfaPxFjCmobMCbN/Zr3GvAM035dHm8Cnl5lT2Wg28WqYGo8CmvFvaXhRWeV1xFeyzDJx0dHBY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Horse", 
		"option_b": "Elephant", 
		"option_c": "Bull", 
		"option_d": "Rhinoceros", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190116", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kR3j88U0Whuy1u3wPm7UQ3UZpnqPQeNyeWPwQOfDfv37yIUuZanpf7hP69OYPRqydT4Iu7c=", 
		"answer": "252xe4Lyw1nj+cUJQB/8hfzxMSveDHAFqz+gU7Z3cWL2R+V9kojTMbjbe7ODNGGtksz3", 
		"explanation": "24aoZ5r21Vn9/4AlXg2yw/TtJn+QAnIBpn6REqp6MFnqR7TDfK33x9dYNV2HzVp19jbPreXk/1ZPgadJ/YbfUyMWfYp83cPJ1vb40X9Fc5QXytAyxrldAE+LztX/x8cnZatE/MCU9w==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Anatolia", 
		"option_b": "South Siberia", 
		"option_c": "South Russia", 
		"option_d": "Hissar in Iran and north Caucasus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190117", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl771r3yMGXECm0fpnvDRqtxMH3mVbTWLuTwiYN5Ihy7hFw7xHPCouXx+lwBiOhP4YvfdysVe4Uvx8Cd3uv51y4DDBJgp+hO11/lZ0BSr62FRA==", 
		"answer": "25C0bYH70Bf+taeMWG/hfLPC5v4UPyQ/nRQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH23Rz6/4QuRl76xO6/M27HQ3AUpXqRV613dWKjXamCeuX7iaV4IBy/iF96snXJrrXx5VYLz7xUqZqXdWILcZl8zZzJ1OvgiDFAPcIEmJV+6NivnXYvqoe27V6mdipBew4w", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cow", 
		"option_b": "Bull", 
		"option_c": "Horse", 
		"option_d": "Elephant", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190118", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hen6J2aQAnEHoj+KQeNkYnT1VavHYPm+wJkxDlKNghZe52TJs6Dx+RMDjqZc/I+YdTFDQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBB85B2pR39pdffedWzX2setCbKep9jm2PIEvxczyuRHFkhDTXmDxfpsOI9CmoX8g+1Flyt5F9/tw9Mpvf/rqW7Ub0xiqDyHKfBP1lH1DZutqg7lHciYw8uoCopCDU5PH4lLjf8dAMdwlVupU9cm1jmdHXOJQabguYjDj3uQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCb+P6iaV0Jk+Ggxty4TbSq6Cw9Fwdna1Y/c6aaDIPf4Vu3NmG2aTxy2MBEtVXn5Jm7ZURPgrdoVJMfsMHRmmfI6x7LmU=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liUw3kxMG9dWreByIYt2zDV7JheWfiWKLMev6+yIV0Z0ybiE16/nPIt+Xx9EEAnLsb/4+NeS0WbctGxtSGmsHi1n5RNsdK2oxz6p0KffNF33HtfdrYLOtqx2CHZ3bxaSq2Fnlg2HH3nHlFvIK1uWecRt8yy1lyl4l8reQ9KN6RmwbeS9PEQrbmgdTOnFPP7Wg=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and Reason is the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but Reason is not the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190119", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfXwJ3jVQ3EQoG2KVKp3dTH0VbSCevTuwJRwKxyGg1disnnA47H48hM5iqxS6s6PdS0Tco4v9N612dbyxWJOPZwEt5Vx7NoebvdIzTiieNvcKf1vwi6FMUz0Yje+ATB1lj7DnjxCoIb75TW+Qts7xRsxk8d364g0M8WM3OiA6U6qjwCL337RQa4kF1uMu8ro4k3chZcqut2I8TPV8LTan/bH4t8HIilBtoc9l53tZJ9Ci2FVOsFW1uP6Sg==", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV70xPHsMCvSFnZRkXqCQax6MHjwFLPQe+i8cVaaHTsygqvf0VXTmmIffg==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQ3i8sUoXQzhwL3sNGjCCmQYoHrDRaJnMHjtUKLHaq3twJB/LlqAjlp15jbSrOXk/1ZPua1f4I3fYCcMbodqhJCAw6TgxWIBPclQ2pV87YsKebRUw325fNHWYN98zWaBIkr8aD60B3F41DTAg3hTpoC+tTSzW80kgAE6l5M45ccuL9LfyqmQ+kS+jwWHzzuGTa9hUVWVpsHo+1Gdo5YxtsiJ8TvVtOb8nfHc/s1LbQ4SmpNtbEu516kH/GobVMagehNHscXDaFWvT347LCsMfeK5OrwqMCFESw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and Reason is the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but Reason is not the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is false but Reason is true", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190120", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he7vOmDVByIGq3qGXuNjcWKjX6nNeeO+wJkxDlKNhFo79mPUqqv3t0cHiuhz6JyeYDICcMt/zcKA2OC3+H99PfRBm5N96sBfXbRT3DKmcdCbN/Zry2LALlawaTy0EHhxhnHfjnlYvIq9/CK/FNsjgD0zhIZo/cl8MtiNmYWc4Ei2jAnP2HqDR/1zGVGLsI6p50/ctI0h9c6MoybItPz4jP2T49EHawwSqI56Zlev1fuS38cGE7HnXdzEnYoBZyA=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKCbPjqiaV0Jk+Ggxty4TbIrLGw41sKz6tU+5yaczZDe5N/xNGH1vD+y38BNclW2qFh958NaP1Pwn+d2KCPsTe2xHFJtEQt+NzI", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRD+t4wzEgrg0Pi/IWPRFyICs3CIV6c0Z3nmUavRLvr725IxKVOdzVJ/93jSqqP58ldPjrwb+oeLdTFDcoJkzZCh1vb21GFAc8lW2q197J8RdvsNyDy/e5ibNPZn3S6GJkbkJz2yAWM0mj7CympXpIq/9DO+FM4/xVUzhZR9/9w1M9nf7aCWqF+9hxWN0jucTa9hHU3Zpdyn/UqYpZF4tMmJuCbS+/r4lrja/tgEcAVTq49wbRuukq8I6i4xX8/0fBpOsfDJcVGtLy7jMAYY/Mfwln1tw4w9VG898RsEnghu8Ui6w5FpM7wWG6NaKA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true and Reason is the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true but Reason is not the correct explanation for Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true but Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Both Assertion and Reason are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190121", 
		"question": "25y2KJD90hDv+ZFgRhvq0e6zdWbRDXtRs3qRQax6cX2jWqbPa/6+yIV0Z2O2smREzUn57qb1+UcKna1fq7NRZPorFVD2v6s20D0WW3s=", 
		"answer": "2723eoL2kxjhbyz+tVNwlqQBF8fT+L0=", 
		"explanation": "24W9eoL83xjmt4shXxvhhfTxdWreAGsUrWvDRqZsZGKvFLfDfPn3yoJ9Jk6FlBtN93LPoOXx+VdPrr5e+pqefm5DaY59zZCG0fDyyjFCNshQn5J34NoebvtVwjntYNzeYPZh3H2FZVp7UviNgdf/GGs31wn5Eos=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "hor,se,bu,ll", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190122", 
		"question": "24GwbdH73gv58sIzEhvz1/H2MHjEQ2cHqnuGXKBxMHjwFKHNe+P6iZ5/Z0iBiBto/WPSq+XF5VIDz7pe7oeQfmICcI8v3NiMl9vI+05+DPl72oFg4ZtfdfoA2DWoNMfSOOpmjmOJK0n1aTe0EX00thKUg9AUqrjqXnvgg43IuBZk8w==", 
		"answer": "27e0aZL44hzrtS22VfH1c+qrT+1nxFJTDuw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl730/T7MGXTBiIepT+XWqY0eH7xR6KCZ/6+xZhyJkiMiRty/DbSq6Cw5Fwam6Ab3JyefGIRe4xmx97J1urzhGVJNoZmloFx79osefUAzS+odZTaMvF7wGrAcRWgN3mfJzJgYI2O94xLY08vGZT7XErs", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "bla,ck,sea,we,ed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190123", 
		"question": "24GwbdH73gv58sUhXBqy0fX6dWPfEXEU7nuRU7R6MHLrVbXLYfm+yIV0Z1OPzUhy9XjPpazz9l0bz6FW+YGNZCMNfY4vwd7Jw+zyhGZOIc1X2o90pKUgQ8t/8wKSNqFgkZafbbwLHDZAL3YydNY=", 
		"answer": "2723ZZThk416sORKrL3l7JCZKLtZaV8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUhXBqy0fX6dWPfEXEU7nuRU7R6MHLrVbXLYfm+yIV0Z1qbiEpu93jSr7yw+lYBm6FU54ubMCMNestnx9yNl+361H5TJ8dKmYUy7ZRfaPxFjCqiZt/IYPFojnqIIgXxaTq0AX5g1BbEj3ld6JO08DP3FPI4zRAg1MbWLR0LWXH3wCn8t5/FLc0=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "hom,er,ed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190124", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV771r3+dWjfDm8erT+XV7F5MHjtFLPKa63RzY5iNFmQzUl+9HPUsaz+8BMbgOhP4YvfYCcRbYRhiNmHl+f/xWNGNoZLnMBm7J9fdPtS3zi+NsXcbctKFrbHiJoJOQZ8+KY=", 
		"answer": "27CpfZThwwCooj4mlCnWmX+ymyQnBOLPWw==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71FnF85wzQRvrib3rPW6QF2cDrj+/EIZlZXTxRr7+LK332tdkNFmNzU90snLDrark8hMbh60b+YuNYy0NPplq28CG2ff+xn1Ec8BLiMBm7J9fdPtS3zi+NNvdYP8uzWaJIkOwaCv9CHV1kDTEyBXO0OtXANVbIQXLiUbJ/O8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "eq,ue,rry,ie", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190125", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fLfa3Q5qMxM06ciARH/ErIguuw1l0GgqlXqZ2eczAKeIJszZCe1ve31GNEJcdIn45mpJsSc/pHjDCses2bNOxnzG+MZ1X1aCmxAWM6qD/qhF4Y6Lez8GezW8gkxVUhl4Rq5M41P9LfzqmAqEO3kkaB1HqDSb5wFEaQptqh6AOTpsIsvcjNmDzf+7ncj+rc4NsKbBscg4hDbXjy15wB/WoRX8y7JTde4+vAZFXjM2izNQ8e7cLg03Ap1Is9SGg4519HjIcWYcVh05Xrsjs1LI1jGyW1r1JJyZM8TBaVZrS+2Wvh8xsDe0YlQcQtiCUw4RyVL1p3nGKfTSJSkcBk+JANnQEjdWBSj3OglT6YwGCZdZfm5ZS8jOaws7x197EmJQGBO1/RU4MIJZrOI2g/7/yJArZZMpEnFDfqKcA8+Sq3Yu62UFNPadYgRV4L4mp68YQ=", 
		"answer": "27q2ZIiz81upMMmG+lYVtnXtSjSZvzNf", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUzUx3gzPv2Nm6cQ2kfrGiNEqJnMFDwXLHDY+j6wZY9Z0uInhty/HLDpqGw9FsOnalY/YuNeTEXd4gvx9bJw+zyhFhPN8kJv5Vg64oaffpTgH2oZ8TeI/dvwmKZZ0Dmbj24CmQ0nT+WvHlSoYD75y6vQds701tyv5M4+skvfNbfyqGU5kS+jwWD0m/RWrRwFBSNvc+8q0aStIMxuciJ8SbT8bTqm/vB+dgCYQ0SsIA/Yhu0mLoa/WosXoi9ZgRE+uGQY1joMzuqKQkOucrt0jRs1ZYoX2U95xcGlotTIsFmwpDrrjskJo1lB3OqrFNF1dRzWVeXNLax3m+qoHovYXMka8pP/Cs0rRyZJE0+mWedRSFC1JRj/8RZgQxmPWdPjmXlwiyKg3eGeprg7sDrhPuwrrZ3sqJnKkmBJ13bQogObKDULmQyxe/bGa5Zc7ZpEy2rGMA88yn8IZiHk3kA0dIpIXCn/T7ZhsXweWy0sJ3rnNF1AP8TItDR7MayvkiHYC7uL3rTcsPxGQfgW3X33R0lpwoq3igU7WaWSoDIiNJZRRud4w3Lt3psmrE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "only B", 
		"option_b": "only A", 
		"option_c": "only C", 
		"option_d": "only D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190126", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4QuURf3y+m/IW7IFyIVrHqQErd8dTH3UbXPLuzt35Yxb1SGn0h+uzbAsaDh4lYBm6RCqY+PYCcCbNQtttFB5CuZkb82K44qnIDfRA==", 
		"answer": "24exb9HF1B3rtVCnnj6O+0Ospe8ZH9hxEPo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU1771r3+OyvRDWEYpnGXEop6dHjiWufRbf/32YNkNVnJmlN+4HOGt631t0cKnaUb1cyeYzQCQskvx9OKwvbkhCMQZoZQk41399ZfdfpExT6sYN3VJ75n2n3ANEz3aTC7DXN1mjLTyMITPwWsJi25RfpEbxw1xfQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "Odyssey", 
		"option_b": "Avesta", 
		"option_c": "Homer", 
		"option_d": "Rig Veda", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190127", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRD5t5EoV173xO/zPG7DFyIVrHKGQbd9c3D3UaOCZuLs2pIxIVOcg1875X/Sq+Xi8kAfiqtPqZqQMDYLe8tGxtSA1uq312RDMMlKjol84ZQLI7Z9jcmakFYwepB3i86UeMtZ", 
		"answer": "25e9fIb21Beq04spVw73173+O2+QNW0dpH7DQKpidWPwFuLD+U2RB182nCapQEAdk2U=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl730/T7MGXTBiIepT+HXa5xY2XqV6bWa+m+wZhjNFmazVJosn/I47H48hMOna1aqYyaZDUGe4Uv3NiMl8D5zXRRNtQEm452pKwQcPNBjC+kYtHJM7wgxf5aBEVby+kc1F7rgch5", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Anatolia", 
		"option_b": "Indian subcontinent", 
		"option_c": "Near Black Sea", 
		"option_d": "Between Dnieper and Volga rivers", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190128", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0Bfzt405XxDhhfztMCvUBnQet3qHErd7MGXrUefKYf/tzNd4KRydhV47wH/B45P181JQzYI0GOX30lKP64KqP9vC7y8=", 
		"answer": "24GvZ9OdkFsb6JLbiIzg+EikJlkR", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU172wPn2NmrEBnFRt2iMEqB7fWHvUbPHLuXnxJliZ0ybjFJo+3jB47H48hMHgLpI7Mz8saG1k4JXkmG6OKY7NFDF", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Two", 
		"option_b": "Three", 
		"option_c": "Four", 
		"option_d": "Five", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190129", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjk/oghXl7lxO6/O2TEQ3AUs3CRRqZwMHjtFKrNffm+25JyIlKdzV5j8XfQorH5+F0cz6lPqaaeYiMTboovzsKG2qSmnSkXfp8RxcL9TOCtcNbufYQVu6NFznk6", 
		"answer": "2523eoL2k47I0Ns/odwnEVSSLYdUQS4=", 
		"explanation": "25G9e4H6xRyq4YQyWxHn1r35PGXUCmwWsDPDRqtxMHT7XbTWa+P9zNd+IRydhV47+nnUsKCw4FIcz6ZU/c6NdTIMbJ9qzJCPxev6hGVJNoZJlZNmpIgaf/FO2H2obNfaNv96x2GONAXxc3mVBWJ1hCHXynhDuoq18mfqDYJhjUxn1BnsKed5mJq2Geuk+uEtMwE=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "Elephant", 
		"option_b": "Cow", 
		"option_c": "Horse", 
		"option_d": "Rhino", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190130", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7lzfj6OXiQBWsDsGvDU7NkdXDxFK7MLsX32oRwNRDJpEl6/DbHraGw+Vwdm6Abyo+KcyMQa5gvycKGwurzhCMSY5YEuKMtps76/ZeOPWca9X8vRP7ChgQ=", 
		"answer": "24aoZ5r21Vn9/4AlXg2wrQhSMLAkXvikZj3JxflcgA==", 
		"explanation": "24aoZ5r21Vn9/4AlXg2+her3PGjYQ3UUsXrDU+NneXbtXaHLbezw3ddwI0qIg1h+/3PIt+X/4VYdz7tU5YebMDULe45j25zJ0e3l12UBMtZUn4Fg4Z5ffeZP2TOpNIaIcK4u7E3ALkuwdTy6DX96h3Hag3dT6Kuy5jS6Rpo2zhFygo99rcYzLsOXmYuS/U65lRORnrkOeKjm8Z70ntlv/0Fe2jI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Clay wheels", 
		"option_b": "Solid wheels", 
		"option_c": "Square wheels", 
		"option_d": "Spoked wheels", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190131", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfXwJ3jVQ3EQoG2KVKp3dTH0VbSCevTuwJRwKxyGixtv+nOGiqv0+B4qmrpU+YuefjFDQoVTxuKM1vf4yisBB85B2qZg4ZQcdLR2yTmkd5TII/Zhwm+SZ2n/cjCuREJxmj7Dyn9ZppCy8SKpR5o+1FUmmcd66Ig9Mpe216ycpWitlAmS2XqfCK9tBUGYuYykKR+Qxddpo0WcxcgweB71", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "2523eoL2kQrr9JcpVBfxwL3oNHiQAiISrHKOXa00YGPiV7PLbei+yJp+KVvJmVN+sl/Ip6q90kYdgLhe6ICMMCMNestDx8WAxKTFwX9OJoFX2pJ3958ebvdIjC64ZMTUMup9jnqILlawZiquAWJgnT7YyGvsdfw+X9l7q4ryfAiYTNY=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190132", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfXwJ3jVQ2oQpz+CXON9fWHsRrPDYPm+25h9IhyAgxtN93LPoOXz4l8bmrpeqbKRTCwxe4p8x97Tl9D/wTFzOsEErIV25dobeeJP2Di+NMDML75twWOQK0DkYnm1HX16h3HfhDxGuoKy5iL7W9x31B031o93/9s5fjMCCXS7nKFklM5qMXFSfjk=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHB2B6qwYAkU1nhhfn6MWLTAnYYrHHDXaU0ZGbsFKTNY/3yzIN0Z1SQgFVosmLJ47H48hMHgLpI7M6MeSUNd41mzcPJ3vDkhHhMI8lWjoF8559fdfoA+jipfdebI+ti2nuSIgfhq02hVxKhvBm9yNExBYm8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190133", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hfXwJ3jVQ2AUoH6OV+NkYn7uXanHYPm+wJkxM1SMzVV0/Dvuorfx50MOgedL5p2LPQoCbIp/2NGHl+fiyGVUIcNX2rx82JQtefVTwzP3NPzUMu1rjnyFKkT5aSr9E3VmkXHQhWlYrMOy+2e3Vc4ygD0zhIZo/ckyfMeX2LuW+w25kkaU3WmYR6h3UUSVtM2t+AGzP90znALzG+P2h/+E7zCs", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arp+JMlQAeyyvu/PWTCEGdRsXqOU6p6YzHqWufWZui+xZZlIhyhjEl64mbHreXg/1IciuhI/ImYdTEXbctm3MPJx/b4yXhPNshHn8B76toPc+dUgRWsZtXLMP9gjm2VK1HldTyuRiUC/kDKll6KS3KSmxg2Tgk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190134", 
		"question": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl730/T7MGXTBiIepT+XWqY0eH7xR6KCZ/6+z5hkKVjJhFU75n7D45rPyGwwsJdkqZyadysMcMtuxtTJw+zyhFNNMsVP2rN35doebvFBjDSjNMDTJb59x3aULwX9bjWxAX56nSTbyl516m76Z4bVanYqs6qPgUGuGoM=", 
		"answer": "26a3fYX75Avr+8fL08CRsOWXrH06JC83CZ4W", 
		"explanation": "252xe4X8wxDp9olgVwj7wfjxNm6QE24QoHqQErd8dTHmVbXOZ+jt3dd6KVOegxt//XvDsLH59FIbhqdVqYGZMCoMbJhq25CA2aTjzHQBIMlRjogy0YgecLRSyTqke9qZEoBNdfbs95hS19Qj6ioW5g==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "so,ut,hU,ral", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190135", 
		"question": "25ehKIX71Fn+/4wyVl7/zPHzMGXeCncc412gHuN8f2PwUbSCeejszNd3KEmHiRty/DbKorf38hMBmqVZ7JyMMCsNPrRQ9++26NvIhmWHSSeAesMP9fbVWw8pZkw=", 
		"answer": "26a3fYX74hDo8pcpU1xCcpRnYekDyYyRfnB/UkNO", 
		"explanation": "25ehKIX71Fn+/4wyVl7/zPHzMGXeCncc412gHuNgeHSjQbTHLuzwzddhNVmaiFV49zbJpeX4+EEcirsb7JaPcSwHe48v3N/JxeHwzX5PIIZIk4t3pIkQaeBIjA6kdtHJKf8sOQmIcM609N0F2OY6ul6gBw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "Moderate", 
		"option_a": "so,uth,Si,be,ria", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190136", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLofbV7lzfj6OSvZECIfpnaXWqZmMHjnUanWZ+v3zJMxJkjJpVpp82bWouX++EFPoqdT7ICVf28Hf5lginaFjg7l+tZeKaBrCvw64oU=", 
		"answer": "26aoZ5r21VuzSJeqZC3x54N7JuRnVJX0", 
		"explanation": "2525epDjwRiq9oskEjP9zfjxP2SdB2MDrD+CQLd9dnDgQLSCauK+x5hlZ0+Bgkw792DPp6D+9FZPgK4b+p6QeycHPpxnzdWFxKbnMNXpQRSFmMySm7jTrcGb", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "sp,ok,ed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190137", 
		"question": "24KxfJmzwxzs8pclXB33henwdX/YBiIYrm+MQLd1fnLmFKjELuXx24R0NByAgxt+82TKuuXZ+VcAwo1O+4GPdSMNPoh6xMScxeHkiDFWO89HksB94toLdPEAyjKheNvMKfBpjn2UJlH1ajyzEGM0lSPTyn9ZupG+9jPkaNQLzkRyoo99rcAzLsSamaGAqEO3kkaP2XWFQbJqFFDZvMDo/0uZ4LAxso27tDbayPqr2szb9Z4fZxpf/7o9YkiqlpRLuCs2VYi9fAEL8uvXb1X5JTvjJA8TucnmlnJm04wtHWA6tBJTjpdfcsx2lrHquD19Gth4GiO/okoAy5VyWAKXc7ir7Ga3oHY+YW4nYMp/uSwnqAGbaEN/iSuQST9C1JNi+d4Qkw1gfGFU3GLogzHLiGqdb5aj6ZL5gOz5rr4j+61nLECSOUWYYIgYbLCAJHJ+3vyJCJpSZ99PGDD1OMZu6zzrJdaa0C1N29cvOHmn4CXZhsXweWC7oZ7wi8diVKwQM9DO7Nmk8FPBIQrvJXLeQ97mVhj1TnK43w9rsA0kzyQDqvMSMHHqB6q5C9GlOEO4lg0=", 
		"answer": "2+f4Z5//yFuwo8gtRcpR5VdHb9SvxQyG", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUpQV701/juIG7eF24I43KGXLd9f3/mUOfLYK3qwZIxFVWOzW1+9neK46T+8xMbh60b/YuNfWI/PIp83tG1laT0xX8BMcMEnI9n6p5fdfoAwSihYN3LLPsuwm+OIFDxYDyuREd8nT3Tyn9XvJe38GepUdslyRs11pB5/ogvNdCR0K6a60y2kkrC1HSDW7gkE0acsMqh5UTct4Mr9cmCvDvV9frt2szb9Z4OYxpetoNsdxuvh60I8y8qQoi7blJi/+DfLHH4MiezIg8Tucfi2HN8x4UsTikj8Q1DwpRTbsw+15v1qTM5MdlvEXOtqlBIh4B0Wleee6+r1SoYjnal6aPfWj2ulyICgNuL", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "2 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190138", 
		"question": "24e9b5Dh1RDk8MU0WhuywPztOWLVEHZRp3COV7BgeXLiQK7NYK3/x5MxMk+MzVR9sn7Jsbb15B9PmKBS6obffyRDaoNqiNaG2+j403hPNIZXjoFm4ZcacuBTjDy/cZTaI/173G+UIhrMaQWzVTBAnDSWj31EpIq+5jP7UNU6xQYmn4R5+c04fN+Qy7uWqFq5lUaE026fTP1tHxSNvcvowk2YqYM29d6YszHU+uDwlP3d5OIFXgYA/6RmI0+0kugd8CMqVYi5YR5H9OreaEHgYAqAa04V9tnw02cp0Yc7WCky+wpIhsNfbIB/14rjuXI+KsBoECGp401Oh4dzSgOeNI6x0m326VQDe0YlNspZtCh1pA6OJF17iX/cSTpYkIVl/dVZmgIjaWdF3H7vkCyOwGycPJXx5I28keD14Lhx96JnK0SUIlndWM0IbbaAA2l7z/meH+ZdPZsnIS3qOtRu7jDvJYSH4zcx3o1gBnmn4CKc0tn9MHe+85/wgthzGrEJI9yFy+j78EjPZDHkYWqSdYvxTwH0SnL71k5qsVgxwCRQ4G3KG4w//CNNv3CxXUtomyaiL1lRIradltZFT6ElXagw+A==", 
		"answer": "2+f0KMK/kRjk88V0EI6SY5cPqUZXjD1VltMONEE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl72yvD6Jn/ZAGMFpnvDWqxmY3SjQ6bRLuPx3dd3KEmHiRty/DbSq6Cw3l0LhqlVqZ2KciEMcJ9mxtWHw6T10WUBMcNQjYV36toLdPEA6DOkccTeMr5vwGrAEUr8YDj9FnlikSPFyl5P6Jez8GevXNMlxFU/n4t06MYyNcKSmYqwpA2wiRSR2WjRX7h2FBSausOl5E3cqYx4psKYpTqbx/37n+ra8ZJLYwZW/5J3Zkm50LtJ/TwxVc26axcL/uKQdVzoYCCsNR0YucLtllVnx5YmUWA1tBtTkIpYZYBn3p2krzM9Oo16ECGzrEACBY9iGCbXozFk+ebvmcMuvg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, and 3", 
		"option_b": "2, 3, and 4", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4", 
		"option_d": "1, 3, and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190139", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yKP2wtrVOKQbc5WTH0XbPKLsH32oM8DnXTzz16QZCSjj7tngdh/Z7gvT4=", 
		"answer": "24exb9HF1B3rt4glXAr7yvPsdSaQN3Ue43eaX61nMHjtFLfQb+TtzNd+IRydhV47+nnUsKC8t3UGnbtPqYqQfScQaoJsycSM06T/y2NSNoFX2ox955sLdftOjHDtVtHPN/trwC6kKUz1dzyvRHF6kHHghXBRqcOp/DG+Rsl7gCYimYx96YgrNNKa1bvT7kSqlRLC3WuBTbx2EFqasI7lq2ads5Y9p8PNsjfV4Ob4lrjE9c0fZxpc/4dxZxuymLod8C8qX4iRfQBE4eGcIXziMjumZx0c+tnq0H1qw8I5T2wi9RNDjIBTIo0z/5aklDsjLMx4VRqookoAxpp4HxmZZqmwkEvl9VY+Zm84J/ReiUkFP08LTDsPFJtzY98=", 
		"explanation": "25T4Wpj0kS/v84RgXxv80fTwO3iQTiJC40uUXeN8aXztR+fLYK3u25Z4NFnJgl075n7D463/5UAKs6Zv4YvfQisEPr1qzNHFl+v5wTFONYZQkoUy5ZQcdfFO2H2EetDSIfAu3W2SLlXkciu4Fzw0lz7Ynn1fppD7/T62Wsl31B0zgsd16MYoNdiRmamd7A2olAeLz37RXrx2GFuMpo6s7kqIqYcr9cyDtXLa5+T8mezAsNENIgRbuYM/Qlazma9J7CI9XIi1ehcL+f3db0etJC2nLg0c7c7nlmBmhpYhWCk8+w1Vh79YQIBV34r3qHI0MMBvBiezoEVUwpA8VxiEZ7j/wyjo71Y+YXMka8og/Hx1gwqIP1F7lCu4QiVUhIV5vtEXkURVcmNHnTbyiymOknazcqfr7sD5hPr8qbxw5uMiP0iEMFLbU80TY/PIKHVhz6mfAqtZIItuFCPyNNogvDr2LZOHnz8f39RgO3/itA+MgMzmMGS084Hti8RmEaxMdsLV7Mi+tlXEYC/tOD2RY9/jXA3+D2jw1k5BuREg2CQCqGPWDMlJ+iEKnz6iQFJhgDTcYl/hpa5T4YeKP5k51vDgznIWkeZri9v2xA05Rha6g3xG8snfHRxmwxT+F94UxRtiTJ0TFZiR82OS1XjfWWgFP+33FKuG0Dlb5u3FhmQ9rIABXomKbA7Tj9sqhFewQe5wUmnkro/6PPIBSnAp+bp/xeGusMO4dP/kLWE8bhS0XK9Q/dVQZgFyFAXJRTBGbb29Gt0TQORKknbClhVBSGtaRVbF/KAcWBbqq8rMLmzfcKUZHF7Wa7ZFFs/qQk7KJuXpzSbAArqSlkL+UEJlXS+eKfAa7QL1dp+yLBKg02ph/M+lNF5OSodXNSmzZm6+rKyNGEY2dicgaKJOaVTUWVAtmn7qNfhpzaYOdFg5Sa3nF18EghkPvD/HDVlWpV8iUYHtaFw1OawFM1oS3z6zGKMaHAzYgywLglOSwSesZLofcWwiaHCWnUKs25Fjkev7g4LNSsPnPqkewINPaLdVQNrYEEkIkvb24aHFBH42FmhLINDHTPHU8Fz3Adr9pMrZwE8Lwb8eMx85IDyFyZTX/y1jb7FAL39JvmYL7MvRcAm5yshP1EJhX0D/tULxTXM0pBRgItPqZNmcPpOg6RBIEzbCF7dMjP160TWkJc3UchszAm0h0Q6eNsLL1SCQfaP9gIgcFxey0tnPUJhk4k85ytW0xUlSrjVhz2znGX/VZvSvE/N57BYmumTLct7XlI53hg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Rig Veda mentions,Two hymns in praise of the horse", 
		"option_b": "First domesticated horse's location,Between Dnieper and Volga rivers", 
		"option_c": "Spoked wheels first appearance,Eastern central western and northern Europe", 
		"option_d": "Horse sacrifice prevalence,In Hissar Iran and north Caucasus", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190140", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yKP2wtrVOKQbc5WTH0XbPKLsH32oM8DnXTzz16QZCSjj7tngdh/Z7gvT4=", 
		"answer": "25y2KLr6wx7j7YwhEgr6wL3eOX/RCiILrHGGEo57fnbsWK7DLqC+74V+Khza3QsrslTl46r+4FIdi7sXqaaQYjEGPophzJCK3+XlzX5Vc89K2qh96Z8NPLkA+ziheJTQLvF5wC6UKAXkbzz9MnVwnTKWq2pTu5e6+2evUcIj01lyvohq/s18LtKS2KGd+w2xiEaW1H7RW6hmEluXocem7k2I4M94lMuZtCCbpaOpyrjx054CbEhCs4d8Zkj8m6EC/WoIWNq1Y14L0uzRc13iNDvjLgBd6sT2wnwp9Jc6TmA1tFIGoJoWM5UjhtjGn3IiOt14ECC/rVBFw9aRrnvgYMixs4fXQzCTwCai", 
		"explanation": "25T4QZ+z+hD48Iw6Wx++hen3MCvxD3YQqj+ZXa1xPDHOW6nFYeH3yNc8Zw/Jq0l0/zaV8/Wgt3Esz6dV/o+NdDE/cL9nzZCb0uP+y39Sc8lC2qt79p0WZv1BgH25fNGbAfJ6z2fAPUr+YnX9BX5w1BzZhHtZpIq6tS+6Qt930x09gYk46N41ONKR2q3T50v4jgmQz37RTLJpFEeNvM2p/0qTrsI+p8KA8TPJ++H3nriAoI5bIipx/4lxdFquk7s19gh4ecemexcL8OrUIVflITqqKBpd8MWj/ntkw5BpEClltD1fwtIDMpAz9LukrjcgLch5ED2upkB8ybxzUhKEM6741Xjt4xUven8mdsYtrzg2qU+dOxRqkm7cZSBYlYQr/94d1RBreC9vmG/zkTqSzCWHfYXmq5L5g+3ipbdg97BnPU7ANlTZRIQTcaCAJml2iuGUH7VZINMnFizifcEm+SC5MpOEzTwe1dc0b2Pv8Wq+gMjwMiWesoDyzvVxEaxAftLM+8i28A2VMXOSeS3DJunXEEjYQGv9xQt3+1gxwCRQ/XHZD4w/+itNnXaxW01rhjSgZXLhgb9O7IOces4w3fGs0iYYneY4nJT5wBgkUxf7mnBWvoDfR11ZyBTUG8gJhAIgA6MPVJTIsjzDxSaQaV8xce22KaeV0CkIyOb8j2hzrNAHW8yaJBybmcskyxi/FfR3UGn56Mu5abw0DHAp6PIgnb3x9+iYNfqqbHUmbhmySq9V+p5UKDJyAwrWOSpqdrGqU5MdRKBA1DXCmBVbQj9bAFfN8qYbHQ2k6tDAayr3bbUVDxCicKYHEMH2Wk7BMP+9iDjIFf+ekEKwH0IqWzSZYbkDpRf8e4/3N1O/mmNhufHsIFBQBIIZOGf6Zyu9pLeGD0YucGwkLp5CaAeEHEB01BzgG/dDzYQIcQokTry0WVkY1gJAiiraTmpQo18XXuXgAAFnHaxJLBYawziiH+ALU1zejj9KuFOYyyGgadtdNFo3emrTm0n4j4Fakcvhh86gHNHxObwVkpkGMKJIBJvYGxsIkvak2eTkEH95B39ybuvHS/DStVy2FsD1toPOxFBAib8KOUovZTyKm5PAsBNjK6oCRmJLs3oYoorRdwq+zJpcxhBpXlGs4UnhSHVhsBB+Z5/ia8/VPoLl51lLHmTTX7wDkPNqzimkNNHVJBk3BnE8nhPQQtrPhyeTL6n6xO0GA1ih35jZTIV5rFx8zdS8zEBPrCI1hnL2BDbJbfL54F5mN29rQrXfG1NZxgMq0Hqiylb4LYq5x7EGm7xFmLcWoQ/4rDJ/nEqJQV6OdHr+1raKv2OGs04m26t3VWmtSDNiyEwwTPU49zlHTikuBIRhrrnlKbDK3ma9IYmo3sBN5FhQBrPCKrSp/dbpKbfQPaTgmYWPKn/k/4d6ROKgMNIBYHTIJC8aorLxYZDBaUmaMiuQ2r7YBi6WMTMZGz8CwpbdcKJ13alqc0kLKA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "In Kirgizia the Altai zone Mongolia,From 3000 BC onwards", 
		"option_b": "Horse and chariot in Homer,Well known to the Vedic Avestan texts", 
		"option_c": "Horse remains in the subcontinent,After 1700 BC in places like Pirak", 
		"option_d": "Chariots in south Russia,By 1500 BC represented", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190141", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuOvgNdFL1nJhVRp4XOGqraw+lwcm6RCqYOafjYKcYVqzJCA2aTjzHQBAc9D2rZ34JtfQPp8wm/kNODTJb56y3yNZ0b/cHmyB3NhhiKWh3NErcOv/Sa1FM4/xVUmk5V1rckvKtbf0KbT2kS/xjCH2HrRdLNYHwfQ9fqg7gOIqYU9p42Mvzab5vzwlPfQ9cwEcUhTrYM/ZUm5hr0M9j40SIi5bRxf+OveZFCtKSbjMwYYufnq0TRfw4YoHVU6yBESy8NiasUz05n2sDs1LNkqETy3pldUzpd9SxKSNLW3wnvhoFwsNXwkcIRp/C45rhyZaEBx2n+USWx4moRi/95ZhhFhfmBOiH/uhzGfwhQHb6c0Ewj8DmIzu2KEJQs=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kU2q9pclEhf8xvLtJ27TFyB9Lmyvp6UUNihV1AImSHbd", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUpQV7mzfi/OGTDFyIcpnGXW6x6dXWjXamCeuX7iaV4IBy/iF96skLOpuXk8kECz69UqcacfzVKPoJ8iN2M2fD+y39EN4YVzdYy8JMSeecMjCqlccbeIe0uz32WJgW4bzavF3U91D7ViWlEu8PppHL7QNM6xQZyoo5/6Np8Pdmbmbqb4UO3hQOQ02jRSa9hUVqWoY6l7k2IqY02sMnNuDyb4Pz82sra9549ZwxT/7J3Zhu5lroF8S8rRYiwZx9O4vDZYlX5JSzjLwEP6s6j32cpwI08U2109hpSlYZTbIBn3p2kmDw5Ot1vB3O7rUAA05x5HyGZeLq5kHrt9lAtZjZra4V5/C45rhyZaEBx2n+USWx4moRi/95ZhhFhfmBOiH/uhzGfwpBRQ6qgrUcCefk/J54zYlQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 are incorrect", 
		"option_b": "3 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"option_d": "2 and 3 are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190142", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuOvgNdFL1nJhVRp4XOGsKTz5VoJhqteqZmeY2IXZ5tmy9GFl+v5yGgBPMAEjoh3pKwaeP1DjC2oe8TXJb5SwFKOdQywUzG4RHFngjDbj3heqcOy5mevXN930xQ/k8d5/ogoNNLf0aeB+0j4lQeBznKXQb5hUV2X9dqg7gOIpYwsvY2Pvj3QtPv/2uzb9Z45aw8SiYN7YhuAmZQHq2N4ecemexcL4uXTc13rKSumZwsL8M/m2Hdshos6HWg24RFCg41CIsl9lr3xrj0gOo1rGzf6gEFO04Z9U1e3Z7S5kFTq3FtrPDoJcIxrvSE64RydK0Z3nGKfSWxGlZMr7sIcgwVveGFU3H/uwhyOjnGdfZ+jypP1hKrbDaPugmg5A+mkhTDgO/c1", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kU2q9pclEhf8xvLtJ27TFyB9Lmyvp6UUNihV1AImSHbd", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH73gv58sUzUx3gzPv2Nm6QFGMC42uaQqp3cX2jW6GCeuX7ib5/I1PEqE5p/WbDoqvjuxMBgLwb5oCTaWIXdo4v/tWN3ue31HROI8pB2rR64doXc+ZTyX2+ddfJKfhnzWvALkuwczG4RGRxmiXeyn5Zp4j7+iH7QNIygCc7kcdO6Mw9fMON2KaA7kKqiwOGnHKfXLIkEEePtMOt70ud4Is29cGMpTfJtML8nvHQsMoOehxB/7J3Zkm516EauCsqUsC1bR1H/uPZYlXhYC21LgoY98jmlntvhoomT3oxtAxHgZFfZMlw09jtsnIVKt9lBTb6okpEh7d5UQOEdbH48Xvt4RUdYHwtZIZi/D40oh2VLl19nyuLTT8Rmo9/vsALkBJicWpOiDbpjH+ohWubbpLvq6HvjOmybEzZez5Sit9eNfyL/eqIQQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 are incorrect", 
		"option_b": "1 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3 are incorrect", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190143", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuOvgNdFL1nJjlN64H/Jt+Xi9lAKz6FIqY/fRicHd4gv2MKI1PD+x3QBNt5HlpVh7YwacO0A8DOReoaSYMlmy2uMIkGwZDG8Fnl7gCKWhW5fr4q19DO+UJo+zlUbmINx7IgAMuuRiuHT20K0jwLCy3OUTbF3UUSLsMqp/0bcs5I3vsiJ8SXT8fH1ibjv/uIFNkESkol3ZlW2mOUN+Tg3EcC1e1JO5+3UZFruJWisIU4O6cTo03Ap0YosWGUntsCQxLwPvtjI+aIhUunnGXE=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2q9pclEhf8xvLtJ27TFyAAzW97IOkbE5d8+EcOSdFa", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2Rj4/oo0Egzzxvi/PHiQAW0Fqz+CEpVxdHjgFKbMaq3Z25J0LByZn1p45n/FpuXE/1ZPmKBe7IKadGIAdop9wd+dl+vlzXZIPcdQn4Qy7ZRfa/FT2Di/epT6M/dvgi6OKFGwTje5DXE0pz7ag3gWv4u+8CuoFN4+xFUihIJ87Nw5fMSP1qOW7A2vjgOH0GjRe61rGlGd9dmg7kaQs8I5p8jNvzfS4Pz8iLja9NsFdgFUtoN7I1qo14AI6isoQcn0Zh1ZscnfaVHjKifuIw8P9okte6Irz8aCEU+MKHmhS+x9", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 are incorrect", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3 are incorrect", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190144", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuOvgNdFL1nJiFpp/n/DsLGw8kUGi61V6ovffyRDaoNqiNiGxffyhHhSc8BLj452pJMRPOBIyX2PeNXYK75dy2/AJlf1ZnmBCkx6xniWvnRT6Iu05zS+FM0201Ulk4t0rcMyM8CRmbycqEK2ih/CyHOUCIthFV2a9c+m7wO1soM2vMyD8Sbe7ODq2sTdzNBYK0h6sJRsZkj8nqZJ9CsqVs30ZgdG8+HCchT6JTqmZwgS7MXnln1nhpEmSH08tCxPgIZEa8Ez1IGkqDo1f9liHCG+40lJy5h5URmfYbD48kuk3FsDey5iJaJirj4wsk+LLUZ72mKSDCtUmoV5/9xZgBdmPWZO3FP1kD6YiWTPfoqjvdCs1ajSg/st4UKS31UMhOnlTr8ibeOk", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2q9pclEhf8xvLtJ27TFyAAzW97IOkbE5d8+EcOSdFa", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl730/T7MGXTBiIepT+XWqY0eH7xR6KCZ/6+z5hkKVjJhFU75n7D47b/4kcHz51J6ILfYicEd4RhiNGH06TjzHQBEcpFmYsy158ePPVSyTztXNvJM/t9jnmFNUCwbDeyE340gD6WvHlSoYD3tQ6pVdQ+wRt+1oZ26YgbLtKa0uiH7VWslUaryDyCCKl2BFHZocap/wOeucIsvcjNpTrS5vC5l/Hf/NsFbAFHssZdQBf8n6cb6y8rEd+xehcL9+vFb1CtKSbjKw8P/s6j2GFkxIc7Tik9+l9VjZZCaoBA35rhrjsxf+VlByC/sARDxpl5Hx6YYLL4123q5Uc+eTo+do8ttSN1hBqOKUd3myuTQiBI1IF58cUXkUQxLT8Q3FTDwHgoReP9KLIl8KP0g0y0gA8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 are incorrect", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3 are incorrect", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4 are incorrect", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190145", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQvv8sUpQV7gwPv6J3nVByIFrD+CQeN2eGTxXqaCZ+O++pZ/NFebhE8ksEbvKZYJZj9IZVGyfFc0f4Q=", 
		"answer": "25exepL7k71VkDULIGrCq3eDTbLl408=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KKLy3wrh5Yw0Hl7mzfi/IXnVBiIDpnmGQLFxdDH3W+fDfa3Ci5V5Mk6DjGc5sn/V47H48hMthrpY4c6LYicGPr9nwcPJw/bywTFIIIZPlI9l6toZc+YAxSm+NMLeMu1v2meMIgXldDyuRFlgh3HUi25d6Iu65me5Ud85gAAhk4M468cufMCN0Lya5kr4iweW2WmYSbEoUUeap8Gk51DQ4IM2sY2ZtCrP57TwlLjS/t0CZwZG/4Vqb0+pha0aupGotTIJWYpccVW7iTUAI/8=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Oak", 
		"option_b": "Birch", 
		"option_c": "Pine", 
		"option_d": "Cedar", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190146", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kQ7v5YBgRhb3hfj+J2fZBnEF422GX6J9fmKjW6GCbOTsyp8xIVOcg18ksE3yk0T2umSpn5IinriZEdc=", 
		"answer": "2525epDjwRjkt5YlRgr+wPD6O3/DQRTrLosfiZmg8Jz5vd2U5nI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20Avm/oAzRl7gwPD+PGXDQ20X432KQKB8MGbmRqKCauTtyphnIk6MiRt6/3/CsLGw41sKz6xe65yWY2IMeMt7wNXJ/+XlxWFRMsgEmYlk7ZYWZvVUxTKjOJTSLvpnzW+ULkv3JzCpFzB8nSLChW5fq4K3tTSyU9Q+xhwxl4l76IgeNcWc0eiR6V+zxg6DzzuTTbhqUVKWoMCsq0qSs4EqvM+ItXLM/eDx2uzW6MoYIglcu8Zsela+mKQatGorRM+zbQFf+OrXIV35M2i2NAtd+Nij1zRkw4YgSGR08hBUwoBZb81m2JHnvSY5MMMqFD2+41ZFxJtuWx6Yc/2x3m7r8lg+YXMka8iF2HgH8IrtR9xdIGMIR0AT", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappan settlements", 
		"option_b": "Andronovan settlements", 
		"option_c": "Ukrainian settlements", 
		"option_d": "Mesopotamian settlements", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190147", 
		"question": "25aqbZzyxRDl+cUkVwj3yfLvMG+QAnFRoj+XQKJ9ZDHsUufVZuT9wddyMlCdmEl+rTRyeK7VtvvjZgb2k8l9XzId", 
		"answer": "25SqcZD9k6UVi8gVijHkxPBD3GPDBbM=", 
		"explanation": "25aqbZzyxRDl+cUkVwj3yfLvMG+QAnFRoj+QW6R6eXfqV6bMeq3q25Z4MxyGixtv+nOGgrfp9l1PjL1X/ZuNdWIqast4ycPJ1uq3zX9VNsFWm4wy9JsNaLRPyn25fNHSMr58y2KJIEz/cir9FGJ1lyXfiXlF6IK18We5UdY+xRMh2sd17No3NdmYmbyb7Q2slAeMz3KFQbJqUVuf9dqg7gOYpYE9tN6ItXXItOf2j/ST5NFLdgBX/4d5d16um6EP/WoMWcGnKBFe/fDFc1XhYDixJg0J8Mjmln16hpAsW2Ux9wtDhsNfbIBn3p2kjjs3f/tvETL240UA1JV/TRKSNKm9yHyk71N/YXIuJat/pSw74R+ZJ0Rynyl/mfP4OAcZ/vysVl0kQ6qu", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Harappan", 
		"option_b": "Aryan", 
		"option_c": "Dravidian", 
		"option_d": "Mesopotamian", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190148", 
		"question": "24GwbdH12Avvt4QsRh/ghfLtdX3VB2tRqmzDX6Z6ZHjsWqLGLuTwiYB5Ll+BzU9+6mKZ4Y2OE3M8RvL9vtbCF6FM/o0=", 
		"answer": "24exb9HF1B3rtVCnnj6O+0Ospe8ZH9hxEPo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hfp8pU0EhH0hen3MCvWCnAU436PRqJmMH7xFJuAeOj6wKszZ1WazV5j5nPIsKzm8l8Wz6Ve55qWfywGestmxpCd3+G39nhGc/BBnoEy0JIaPOJFyDTtY9XIYP8uzWuOM1fxa3m4CHV5kT/CynVY6Jez8C6pFMg+1AAzmpQ0rdslMdWQ1aGJ4UO/xhKK2TuSR7NqFFeNvMGmq0GZtJU9sMPNpTretOTxg+va898HIglcu8Zsc1Kunrwc+SZ4Q821ZB9Ysc3EIUThITGmI04cud3qwnVlhpAmUWx0/REGlIJEa89mxdj2uT45OMRlACD6oEFSwplzUR6TZ/281Xvn8lw9cH5rbIQtqCUw4T2VLxRIn2+dDhs61ZESQOBo+uH68E9xMXw=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Bible", 
		"option_b": "Avesta", 
		"option_c": "Quran", 
		"option_d": "Rig Veda", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190149", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrz+ocvXl7lxO6/NG/fE3YUpz+BS+NgeHSjeqbYZ/6hi/HySw9BwCTGa9M18eAhJFY=", 
		"answer": "24auaYLn2BLrtRJAPXfIu9qAUWJOk0hjsQc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHAxxj544wrU1KyxPO/NGXTCmcftz+QS652f32vFLDDfa3/zZhhM1mNzVlismLOpuXe9kkGnOpJQbnIKG5g8PPSRhKsOaxR", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Star of David", 
		"option_b": "Crescent Moon", 
		"option_c": "Om", 
		"option_d": "Svastika", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190150", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRXr+YI1Uxn3hfTsdWjfDXEYp3qRV6c0ZHnmFKrNffm+wJphKE6djFVvsnfSt7f59UYbiuhU786LeCdDX5l2yd7J1PH70GRTNpkGF/hp6cjwqFHaTzxM1VUKVw==", 
		"answer": "24a5ZoL4wxD+tdPvQBhPfD9x5lmUI6yltdk=", 
		"explanation": "24a5ZoL4wxD+t4wzEh39y+72MW7CBmZRt3eGEq57Y2WjXarSYf/qyJllZ12dmUly8GPSpuX/8RMbh60byJyGcSxDfZ5j3MWb0qTe0DFSNtRSn4Qy5YlfaPxFjDGsetPOIflrjmGGZ1H4YjCvRGN1lyPTjjxCrZuv5mv7XdQ0zAA2n4l/rdw0OZet0K/T3ki8h0rC3XWVCKplAhSQu9qt7FGdrMIsuo2ZuTfS5rTrn/Ta99cEdxsSrY9rdlqwhORJ8DM1X9v4KBNF9aTAaV3hLzusNwYU+srvlnBg1YEmSHsn8V91g41FadJ6wt/3/Ds+OcF/ED25pgRF34B5UROTcP2s3yj36FQvfHQsJYl4sDkgsw6QaFFminmZXz9Ym454vtEXkURwfmdPkHfyjibLgWabdYXq/4n5lqoq7B0qSaGZ2+/PNX0kzftO", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Dravidian", 
		"option_b": "Indo-European", 
		"option_c": "Sumerian", 
		"option_d": "Sanskrit", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190151", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kR3j88U0WhuyxujzISvfBSIirHKCEqxmeXbqWqbWa7K82WGtbx1Dg81ttEYMl6PAvw==", 
		"answer": "25yqaZ/60Beq9oskEij3wfT8dXvVDHIdpmzBO8CNE+X43sAMTyPQOk/dyQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHwxBX+t4omEi39yPyzdWLeFW0dtXaNVeNgeHSjR6bBfOj6iYd9JlKdzU5o93KGqquw5VobmqlX+sLffzAKeYJhycSM06TgzWVJOsgEjoh3pLMNffpJzTPtddrfYMhrymeDZ1X1aCmxAWM0oDnTymxaqY2vtQKrXN8z0hRyn5Q47scyL96b3LqW7A2siUaA2TuiR7BlXRSYu8ro4leP4JAxodiMvXLO5/G5jfnAsN9LYQ1cq5R+bxu9hLgM+z54Xs70fBpO+PaQc1HhKS+qKBsOudvx13d9z4EsTiV05B5UlopVd8xyxJT9/Ds+f85vBza3rEpJwoc8UhKYYLS33m3goFwxNW4jYMpftSp1lwqYKRamZR5BtD/CMdSxYtamO/xd", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Mesopotamian and Egyptian peoples", 
		"option_b": "Iranian and Vedic peoples", 
		"option_c": "Dravidian and Sumerian peoples", 
		"option_d": "Greek and Roman peoples", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190152", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQnm9os0Ehfhhf7wO3jZB2cDpnvDRqw0cnSjR6jPb7K88nXmgCTZ90ZSGjQR/dXMNQ==", 
		"answer": "25CoYJT3wxioz2r0dCddv43KhmgnCR0oTg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj3Rjk48UFQhb3we/+dWLDQ2EerWyKVqZmdXWjQKiCbOi++ph8JhyAgxtv+nOGgrfp9l1PjL1X/ZuNdWIqast4ycPJwvD+yHhbNsIEk44y9pMLafVM332re8abKep9jn2VN1X/dDy5RGN1lyPTjjxXpof74TW6Wskxzwc/l5Nx+818LMWQya2B/ES9lUrC33SfRrhnBV2Xso646lGIqYExpcyDpSGb4/3tkrjX+cgCbA0SuYltYF6v16wc6iM2VoimbR5C9u3fdEetIy2xIgMS98LmxTYSWIn7BVT30FW1321PuWdf", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Cannabis", 
		"option_b": "Ephedra", 
		"option_c": "Aloe Vera", 
		"option_d": "Basil", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190153", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ34/oclEhz3yfT6I27DQ28Yr3TDW7A0fXTiWrOCaOLsiYN5IhyKjFd9rTSv3Zf4wU/E9KikYGHL2ad7", 
		"answer": "25KtYpvyw1n+5YwiV1wOizKtvTtHaDp08RRwtZuG", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHUxBPg9pdgRgz7x/i/IXnRB2sFqnCNU694aTHhUavLa/v72tdlL12dzVZy/n2Gqraw50EGgqlJ4IKGMC8Gf4V7iNaGxaTjzHQBMMdInMwy9p8ZcPFD2DSjc5TPKPtn3C6DMknkciu8CDBilT3Dj28WqY2/tTepVdkjyRY3hcdq6MQ9KNKbmbycqE65khKO2TaDTbx2GFqe9c+m7wOYoYsqrI2YojPc8bTNkvHAsNwObgFXucZsa1qskrtJ7CI9WNr0ehdH8PDZblr+KCGzZxkU7cOj13pgy4MlTik1+hsGkZZFdsV915bnuXDUhg1LrZKdlmBnvUX2AdlV", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Maasai tribe", 
		"option_b": "Gond tribe", 
		"option_c": "Zulu tribe", 
		"option_d": "Gujjar tribe", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190154", 
		"question": "24KwbYP2kRj48sUnVxD30fT8dXjZBGwQr2zDf+MlJzHuW7TWLv3szIFwK1mHmQQ55vGg9m27z0l4ktwoA0lyrQ==", 
		"answer": "25a9ZoXh0BWq1pYpU1x37D/c5Ulg0bjUPSWaUtrz", 
		"explanation": "25j4Ocaz1hzk8pEpUV7hzPrxNGfDQ2MDpj+TQKZwf3zqWqbMeuHniZF+MlKNzVJ1smLOpuXg8lwfg60b5ojfUycNapluxJCoxO32hi8mWqHWEo7TY2nByVZVfIk=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "South Asia", 
		"option_b": "East Asia", 
		"option_c": "Central Asia", 
		"option_d": "West Asia", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190155", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3he7pNHjECmkQ42yaX6F7fDHsRq7FZ+P/3ZJ1Z1WHzX5383uGn6vM+WEKjrtU59TfXSMAdYp2iN2M2fD+y39EN4ZQkoUy94web+BJxzzqZ5TUMvdpx2DALkuwQjW8CTB2kTfZmHkWoZeotSarRN820hQ8lYI45MZ8KN+amYCS+kyolgeMnHiERKlxA1Hb2vTZdDyRl5UnfgCqyj9pXQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLuzwzddlL1nJv1564XnI46zjt0cHiuhY5pyNdSEXPo532NyI2eXjzX5Pc8BLiMBm7J9fXedTyS+5fdvVYhJktxINFlX72tLMb/NylJc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2yQnm9oshRhf9y73vJ2TGCmYUpz+KQeN2cWLmUOfNYK3TyJR6JkXOnht08GXDsbPx41oAgbsb+4uYcTAHd4VoiMSB0qTk0nBSJ89Pm8dhpJUNdfNJwn9ucbSNmtRzx4ufdX4Uco28", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190156", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gZhb3hf/2J2jYQ2sC436QQax3eXD3UaOCeeTqwddQNUWIgxt453rStrf1t28Bs6Zp7I+MfyxZPqZuxsnJ2uX50WJCIc9UjpMy7ZRfcfFExTi7ddibCfBqx2/AMEDiYnmqFnlggDTYynNY6IGy5ySzFNYywQM3hcXYtIJMdpOcF+F8eQC569PY", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Ar58pc0WxH8hfzxMSviBmMCrHHDU7FxMGXxQaKOLu/r3ddlL1nJv1564XnI46zjt10Am+hP4Yvfcy0RbI5s3JCMz/T7xX9AJ89LlMB064hfaPxFjBy+Z9HJNPdhwCztAHk+T05ZrJM1o8cVgBgw", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRvl441gQQrz0fjyMGXEECIQsXrDRrFhdT2jQK/HLvjtzNd+IRyLhEl4+jbArLew4EEGm6FV7s6ScSwWbYh9wcCdxKT+yjFMNsJNn5Zz6No2cvBJzX2pe9HILrl6jmuTM0TyazCuDDB9gHHXmTxXpsOa5z66WpoxxRQmg5V9r8EhWpXqqIbtUMig0qBsiMQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190157", 
		"question": "25Sre5ThxRDl+d9gcQz3yPzrPGTeQ3UQsD+CEqB7fXzsWufSfOz93Z5yIhyIgFR19TbSq6Cw31IdjrhL6ICMMB4NQoVdzdGa2OqthEVJNoZsm5Jz9IoecucA3C+sd8DSI/tqjmuBNVH4JzuoFnl1mH2WnXRfq4v79i+6Wt0yxFU7mMds5c01LpeT2LyW+g2ojgeR2TkVgarvV84XKXkVt6XUcoOh", 
		"answer": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV70xPHsMCeQAXcF42uLV+NGdXDwW6mCZ/6+3YVkIh6t0NylEI7lLrVbLbWaqU7S", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2ywfT7dWXfFyIBsXaOU7F9fGijRLXDbfn3ypIxJE6MgFpv+3nI46fl4xMYirpeqYWRfzUNPo1g2pCM1vbjzDFDJtRNm4wwcqgj9U2oTnvij9ZSLuB26Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, and the Reason is the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both Assertion and Reason are true, but the Reason is not the correct explanation for the Assertion", 
		"option_c": "Assertion is true, but the Reason is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion is false, but the Reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190158", 
		"question": "24GwbdHmwhyq+INgUBfgxvWyImTfByICpnqOQeNgfzHhUefDYK3B9qhOGGPJi1565mPUpuckKlxf+Oovm7JXKDVu4Mch", 
		"answer": "27SqcZD9kzM8ND/Unr6zQwDQ5iNEvCA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEhP3y+n2OmXDQ2AYsXyLH7R7f3WjVbSCb63twJB/LlqAjlp15jbApqTk4kEKz6ddqa+NaSMNPoh6xMScxeG1dBrdPo50qw0uoAOo9Q/apA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ary,an,ad,hi", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190159", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb0Avr55UhXA2y1e/+Nn/ZAGcV43qCQLd8ME7ca5j9UdKyiYB5Ll+BzVd65nPU47D+81YdmK1V/c6eMCELf4VozZIpK6mC29YhFmfuwvykHn/d", 
		"answer": "27etepjy3VsBtxk5XgysCymEZQLKMpeq", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEhr71v7qJnjVECIFq3rDeqJmcWHzVamCfv//yoN4JFnJgl0793fUt62w9UYdhqlXqZqXcTZDfYNuxteM06T40nRTc9JNl4UwqaMI03wHdPP1Y1lkuGpypQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "bu,ri,al,az", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190160", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLpgUQv+0b32JivTDGwCqnuGQKZwMGXsFKXHLuy+2od0JFWIgRtv4HfPt+X/8RMbh60bwICbf28ibJJuxsPJ1urzhFhPN8kJs5Jz6pMecucCIRbn3MYYynZp8u23/5cFJA==", 
		"answer": "27OxepSxobP8hgTYMTYjvFCHLrGSOw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEgrzyfbsdWrSDHcF42uLV+NyeWPmFKTXYvm+y5J4KVvJjBto4nPFqqP59BMMh6lJ6I2LdTAKbZ9my5CG0aTeynVOfudWg4F899oecvAA5TOpe5nyMv9gx2+ONAfkFKiVVvg6U+ALJZmoaCCN", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "fi,re,wa,ter", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190161", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt8IzRB/h0fT0NCyQAnIBpn6RQeN9fjH3XKKCeujm3YQxKFrJmVN+snPHsanpt2wwsJdk1rHfcycNap59wdWaldNpi+ijR10ckeLsl5MB32I=", 
		"answer": "27awepjgxRDr+ccFklcReXZkOiBv1A6/3UwH", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxxj544wrU17mwO/ydWLDQ28UrWuKXa1xdDHqWufHb//y0NdSL06Ank9y83iGt6Do40BDz6lIqZ2LcTYGestmxpCd3+G31HBSIMdDn8JD5XgfKQAqTJQg26nC9Vfi", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "chr,is,ti,an,mu,gal", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190162", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyLpgWw2yxPO/PGbADHAFonGXEoJmaXDtFLXLevj/xdUIipJ9wE1pxRwqfV8H43ff", 
		"answer": "25S2YZzy3Qrr9JcpVBfxwL/xEjMCZOkZzA7+09cOpiGi", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj0Ar59oIlEhb7wvXzPGzYF3FRonGKX6J4MGLiV7XLaOT9zNdwNByIzUhy9XjPpazz9l0bz4lJ8I+RMDAKap5uxJIwbr9pnag1shvtdejk1jH7", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "An,im,al,sa,cr,if,ice", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190163", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjn+IsnEgr6wL35OmfcDHUYrXjDW7A7cWPmFLPQe+i+yJV+MkjJnVJvv3LRpqn8/l0I0Ohn59/fQCsXM494zdyF3urwhHNENMdK2ol8pI4XebR13jyhB+LULPlvjnyFIEz/aXmBCkx6xnH/njxBqZD78D+4WM8kyQM3mp447IgsLtaczaGQ7Q23gEaW1H7Raa99EFrZttuk/1aOpcIEu/GD4nLv/PG5qe/S5J4dYwReup8/cFOzgLtJ/TwxVc26axcL/uKQcV35bSy0IgIR8MXkxTRo1I08U210pUoW0sN0QYKcyIX6u7lR11b7WYAYtsqu", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kQnj48gkRRv+yfTxMivSBmUQrT+KXONgeHSjYbXDYp7Ixpt2JhybiFxy/XiGoqv0t1YZhqxe542aMC0FPoJ7iNWR3vfj1zFIPYZQkoUy140eaLRWzTGhcc2bIexh22CEZxSlN2n9JlM41DjCymtXu4384We+TNk71QY7gII4+cd8KN+amYmB8Uy2xgWX0G+EWrgmTCGdWOvKCeuJTycT3+7VJQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only 1", 
		"option_b": "Only 2", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190164", 
		"question": "24e9b5Dh1RDk8MU0Whuy0O76dWTWQ2AYsXyLHuNjeHjgXOfReuzqzJp0KUiazVpp9zbSsbD1qBMzgfkbwJrfeTFDbI5pzcKb0uC30H4BMtUEmIhn9pAePP1OjA6sesfQMvd6jlKOG0uiJxu0FnN81DjFynlOq4+u5i6tUdYugBM9g4l8rcEyfPaR3bqc5kKuhwjCz36FXLFhHFGXod3o102grtF4mMyDpCHY5v3pjuuT+dBLbw1WtoNpYlf8vqYN8St4Rs2mbVJc4+3EdVHjYCetZwwU68jrlnhsx5QsTivs9MJPY8kSAen8zVPi0pT2", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "25exepL7kRD5t5clVBvg1/j7dX/fQ2MC432LR7F+cTHqWufxb+PtwoV4MxyIg187/3fItrbz5Vofm7sb4IDffScHd455ydzJ/urzzXABJMNWn8B76p4aefAA2y+kYMDeLr5hwC6CLlfzb3mxAXFikSKayn5DvMO5/DW4XJo+01U8mZM46NA/MMKM0L6WqFm3xieM2GmeRrJyEFrZpsu8/0+ZrYc2od7PBqeYPp+WABxTyh07pSIZyA==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only 1", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "Only 2", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190165", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80e6/NGnfFnZRoG2GX6JgeX7tFKbQa639xoVjIl+d0htH/CeGgLf1+lIbhqdVqZmeY2ICPo1qycScxeG3y3cBJ85B2o1z8I8NebRozS+sZMTaLr5t22KUMlf1JwWzOH4m1AXejzxTqZG3/CKoQJoy1hw2k4l76IgzOpecy62e6VmxiQjC1XXRXLVhUX2Xscep5QOPtYA7usOZuDze+uC5k+uT+dBLdgBX/7VoYk/8gakF9C8hEfS6VBwYscfCZFnsNCGsKU4Z+N/mxTRrx4EiHX07tAtOh8NQa8Zn3tjptT48OsNkHCa342ZjhYD7CcJ/fcxwCSaM1ZP42Go=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "25aqbZzyxRDl+cU3Uw2yy/LrdWqQBWcQt2qRV+N7djH3XKKCY+zq3IV0Z3SIn1pr4nfI46bl+0cana0bwYGIdTQGbMcv3NiMl+H21n1INtVQ2oVk7Z4acvdFjDS+NN3VYOpmyy6zMETkJy+8CHxxjXHXhHgWoZf78SavUcl3whQxncds4ogoNNLf36GV/EX4iw+O0H6fRrRxHBS7lozxe27TMHCOCvwuputRKPpl", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "Only 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190166", 
		"question": "25a3ZpL2wxfj+YJgRhb3hfv2J26QAHcdtzPDW6dxfmXqUr6CeuX7iYNjMlnJnk965nPLpqvk5AlPs6YKqaiWYidDaYR929iAx6T+1zFSOsFKk4Z755sRaLRJwn25fNGbAehr3XqBZ3n+WzfvRFZ9hjSWi3BCqZGotSq6QNk/yRs11rF96cE/fNOayquB4V2sjwmMzzuGTa9hUVKWoMCsq0qS4Ko5p8ydoTPVtPf2lOzW6MoYIjRcg4gsI2+0kugP8Tg9EcuhZAYL+PeQYlvjMyGnIhwY/YvwxnFqz4QgXikg+19vjIdZL+Fhz5nqr3IxMckqPD2+rAlp1ZVyVhaYZ/8FRwSBd+BFSqnI6GF1AeoZ", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "25OxepSzxhb45I0pQl771r3sPGzeCmQYoH6NRuN9fjH3XKKCT/v72oNwZ12HiRtv+nOGpazi8hMMmqRPqYeMMDETe4hmztmKl/D4hFhPN8kJu5Jr5ZQMPPVOyH2EetDUbdd8z2CJJkvjJxGyE3VikSOaynpfuob79CuvVcgkgBMgmYo4xckuPceP2KbT60K2kgOayGjRTLJqVkDZuM+86Evcloc8vM7NtTfI9+bwiuza/9AYIJTLzndUVqV2ciIrhQbpZmI=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "1 and 3", 
		"option_c": "Only 2", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190167", 
		"question": "24e9b5Dh1RDk8MU0Whuy9uv+Jn/ZCGNd42iLW6B8MH7lFLPKa/77iYRlJkiMgF515mWGorf1t1AAnbpe6prAMB4NL8tbwNXJ5PL212VIOMcElZJ745MRfeBFyH2kepT+LP9jjmyFIUriYnnvVCAk1BP1ykBYlI3ptROzUZok2RgwmYs45Nt8LMWQ1KGd7UOsxg+MnE2UTLRnUViQocu66leJsod4icOxv2GbwPz82svF8c0fawNT/5F+cBu9k6cZ7C88EcmnKBML4v3dY1vhYCelZy8P4Mrt32dkhoAwHX088V9og5lfcYIbJ/hwdn5Vdb6JPlzGJvGN", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHAxxj544wrU1791/T4PGXRF2cV43aNEoZ4cXyjVqLEYf/7icUhdwzJr3g783jC47Lx5BMOi6dL/YubMCAaPp9nzZCn1v7+1zFAIIZF2pNr6ZgQcLRPyn2MZs3aLvd9wy6oKFL1cTyvSDB9gHbFynJZvMOr5yi2XdQyzgFyn4k42804NdTf1aGH7V+5khOQ2TnNnFCV3AfjEdZFgWvgMpK8", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Only 3", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190168", 
		"question": "25e5e5T3kRbkt5EoV177y/vwJ2bRF2serT+CUKxhZDHvVanFe+z5zNdwKVjJhFVo8WTPs7H5+F0cw+hM4YeceGIMeMt7wNXJ0ev7yH5WOshD2oFg4doLbuFFk32ReoWbFPZrjnqFNUiwICqrBWNgnTrXzTxQoZGo4We6RMoywQch1o52rdw0OZeL3LCH+w23gEaW1H7RTbx2HU3Zlsa64lCIqYM29c6IvybO5v38ibjv/uIFMEhmt4M/ZVKuhLxJ9CM2Vt29ewZC8qTEc1XuJTvjKAhd6dnswnsk74wtUiQd5h5Ii4JYIsRywp2kvjMzNI1+GnPo8RQQh7ZfHyuYSLPrkFrx80Y2dHRrZIRp/AQ7pQDRCUZnm2XcQC1fk5Vq+dUK1Qxia2oAj3/tizOKkmybdZbwq4nyxfz4pfl24aZnJkfAJV3LQs0IYL3TIiVfYq5kvt15IIhIwBUoAgNC", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25S0ZNHn2Qvv8sUzRh/mwPD6O3/DQ2MDpj+XQLZxMHPiR6LGLuLwiYN5IhyZn1Rt+3LDp+Xg9kAcjq9es86LeCdDao59xZDOxPL212VIOMcD2oFi9J8ebucAxTPtcdXJLOcu7WaSLlbkbjizRGRxjCXFxjxCoIb7+S61U88+0wE7lcds/8k/OcTf3amH7Q2siUbQjivBCJ9HXRSYu8ro2VaPs4s5u42Mvzab3fr9lbXy4scKbEhevoh4dlq7krtJ/CV4WcmibVJY+OnZbVX/KTyqIh1d8MWjwnxshpIoTn104BpIkYYUxgQmdBggMSUJH619eHx5Qg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "Only 1", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190169", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHwmNdBLkjEiUx+/nrPraKw9FIBz6peqYKWfikGest7x5Cd3+G35WNYMsgEmZV+8I8NebRBwjntZNvIM/dswnfAKFf5YDCzBWRxkHHfhDxVp4+/tSS0Wt4+1Bw9mJRE4/Qybper0a3T6kSqhQ7C1WjRS7xoHVGd9fLq6UuTr5AytPHP8TvVtMf4lOvY4tcfXgZusdU/V1O514AI6isoQcm6e1JK/fPReEetMDqiJBoU+s7nlnd7w48oSWA7+iNIvo0CIvR709jXqjMjK8RhFHOpuklCyJg8VgTWerys2X7hoEEwNUwuYYNu/CE8tQqOKUBriG6gQhtZnYNjvt8f1RBreC9Bnnn2h3+YlGSbeZ7m5ZTvxenipflq/KAoO1OFNkiHFAjiMNXFDfQkK3KjGFTqGCY=", 
		"answer": "2+f0KMK/kU2q+IssS1xbm0C92Z9F2Zzv2R0Qiuyp", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VyEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+CQeNgeHSjVq7QbeW+wIQxJF2FgV5/skqEoa3l5VkOs+ob4IDfQyMNbYB9wcTFl+r40DF9ccRMlY9g7psjPrRz2Dy5cdneLuounS6JNAX5aTqyFmJxlyWWiHlVqZao8GevXN936BQgl5do7MYvfMeN2KuH4U69gkaH3WmFQP1mBEaQtMLo2FedtIc1sMOZ8Wab/ee5k/bQ/8wZZwtG/4dsI0+0kug67isrRcG/aVJC4qTFb1/jLz+tZxoSuf3m0n1qho4gSWwm9QtTkIYU8sOebInaky/84J+LCGJ1Sw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4 only", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "2, 3, 4 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190170", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHwmNdFL1nJi1Jp4WKGr6z+8EYGnLxS6s6LYiMAe5gvx9bJx/b40H4MGshAlc1b9psRdfVOjDK/NP3VJPEj73yZJkuwazizA2V1kzSWi25T6IWp+ir7BY9nkFUQtbt20cZufPaYy6GQ/UGskxSHnGyQW/1wGVHZpdyh5kKOucI+us6YonLU8rTtkv2T9d8ZbgFXrJI/cEu5lqMM6jl4Xs70fBpOsc3eZVugBT2xKB4Y+MWj2nVnwZcoWmwI+iNI0cNxZ852wpHn/CE5OMNrGSD6oEVMy5F4HzrWJer40XrhoFMwYHQvJYNj/Cx1sgabJl14k2idQjgRhI956tkWm0Rsey9olXjki3+YkGCOd5bx+MD1i6jUpbVr+58pFU/UdW7NRZ4VZL2AJml2iuSaA78cGpFjGG/HL8wv8nn1IZiTyjgK1cpgJ3bx8WqXnY3mMGizv5Prh8B/EaxAP9+F/cOy8EnUZGPuJz2Hbs60SQnjWzzs1gB2siQr9C8n4GvbAMlw820ZlnvwSEZrhCKgf2iggrtR74yabM4wwfCs1DwTl+Zqmpjji18Qq60EnalB8qR31xgPCkYg", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMO/kU2q+IssS1yGPLTSmstW6FALLgtZAjMu", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhfTxNmTCEWcStz+CQeNgeHSjUbHLaujwypIxI1OMnht1/WKGp6Tk8hMKjrpX4IuNMDYLf4UvmoLZh6TV5zFyJ8dQn4136o5fLrRJ332ketfUMuxrzXrAJUDzZiyuATB1kyPfiWlavJap8GesVcl3zhom1o51/ccuKNaRzeia5g2sjgPC0HKXTf1rFxSNvcvo7kKOrIs9ptnNoiLe9f/8iOuT/9hLdgBX/69xZ1Txsr0b9zo9UMb0ZBNF9vHRZlGtEzyiMwsQ/MX3liApz5FpSns7+hgGg5AWdsh2xJ2ktSFwPo15ASGzqE1OwNRvVhqfeLyq2Xz9oFwxNW4jYMp4ryh1rgncPFx72nudXzgRgIVl7dVZnAojT3pTj3/hjH+KjmHPcZLt8sDVi+z/7Zhx66IpaU2BO1vNV4oZdvFNxIIQZHZFN1mC6q7HmkqA", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, 4 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "1,2,3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190171", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kTXj5JFte1665PP8PG7eFyICqmuGG+NjeWXrFIvLffmz4L4xb32bjlN693nKrKL59FIDz65S54qWfiVKPophzJCa0ujyx2UBJ85B2oN99ogaf+AAzTO+Y9HJYOt9x2CHZ1H4Ynm+C3Rxh3HRg2pTpr+19yK3W8131B031otx/twvZpeki/jDunD4ugih03+UW+dYH3iQptrlwgPc4MJ49Y3N8XKbtLS52rj/+c0fLyF7g4g3QlW/nq0H7GorWNyxIVID0PbTaVXoLySsIAce+Mej0H1nwosnWiAI+j4GroxCasF/ltik/HJwf40qRHOKr0tVwJx5W1eQfbi01FTqwhUUdHYiZ4tjuyw74V3cDFt9kXKdXihtmqMr2tgWmQV1dH1B3DagwmzLtGCdbpDs/5T9xfr1sLVq8aJnJkfANBzIWoIJYrv8KUMy6OiVDLFdP5YnV2KmaZUP8nnwLoWXzTAdxNAvITfk+yeJgMTmMGu984b8gJaCTW844CbuL6rGxJ9P7dAv", 
		"answer": "25T1Osqz81S7rMUDH0qphdmyZinivSZVVdUraB66k+J7F1zY", 
		"explanation": "25m3fJny3Vmnt6EvURXrxO/7dSOCSjhRj3CXWqJ4MHjwFKbMLuzwyp50KUjJnlJv9zbPreXX4lkOnalPpc62fiYKf8cvzsKG2qTjzHQBGshAj5My0psTcPFZjB6kYt3XKeRv2mePKQXgYiu0C3Q0uz/TynNQ6Iqv5meoXd05yRM7lYZ2+Yg9LtSX2K2c5EK/jwWD0DuXQbNgGFqepo6h+AOd4JU9ucHAoT7a+vr8nrjS/tpLYwxEvoh8Zl/8k6cK8zM5Q8z4KAVD+OfYIUf4Jy+mNBoOud/r12Ap6o09VWg4tAhHkcNXItB8xIykvzskJo1vGzS7pEFEh51yHxqXZrSs2WXhoEEtdH4uWYRRsg91ig6QIVZ/lGydQmwc1LBn8cUenQFnPWlJmXrkwnfayT/PV5Lv4oL9i+/xrvlq4eMmJ06UPVnKFowSZrrFKXMy2eCPCOZaIZBqVzbuOJUH8j3sM9ai3jUB1cBgDH7x/SaQiMzhMGq08572jdViEbtAP9+F28q9sU/TaSLvbT26aM/9WEjRQnP21E5xvx1lyTMT4GPdB4Vw8iQOn3LwT01qli7ua2/hl6ocwYOCdoww3fLt03IZi7R9iZLz0RM/QkS0iz9TvouKSFRKyRTQF8gLwBpiTL0PEJ/S83mfm3GQSnsfds3jDbyS0S1EmuLymmhrtoQHUJ/OLRffysouzVekEvg5WmGtuIr2KPsdGVgixrxSismpuMa6Y/q2LSVnLzu5GeZX4JZDYRJvGATTRSdAbai8X44XT+cPxnDE108cDiUJIVLD96keVBar6s3bLmvScL5cDxCiSr0BBt24eEbDOfSwiBPAELaQnF2/S00qQHqOKKQIpRT5bpnzMBa302FqudH3N0JeSpdaOCbqNEysr6KRChJ6UCIgaIVBOk7BWFAlhj3LJvxogagHeRssTeijEEMVmQdKjTfXHRhMowwfUeWkTkAkOKBVNFIew3e2Hq0PThXZjzQNzkKZzGLgKOhMNAkwcmOdnACgjJpvnPepi53BC9qiKKUa350PLfZUQtrCF15cifD25vH0UXkqA2k3J/aISurU8E74AcHxrNea7FJP3K1IAF43KTySybzQ5jNhJr9Oe3lFs08XkMT2IiSr14lO1FxhEBiswUT2U2YiuQVnb9P5b83QI5iksF9ZViWHR7VMjftwnWS3fIWRRhsxBnQ0nQ7Qf8GKxjqMKaT+0u0aDAynl4vOSYt56Uw52tPy10RF6xJ7i2nxS0Dbbuvo8V53K2pxR72FG0lUiRli3DTx9lL6JI6khupJp75F0bRTwAH4rCY2hkqfD0zHbXfj0PGN92/V/kZh3a9xTmegVGd5z0w2QeAn+3pvACInCaA0rLr6ObbM0iGmIJixzo0Z7FhTBrPCKv2urtC8KqWFP6njzIeLPDLo/9NoA+emJssJNGPfZTFftKz1YZDNbgyAfG+RwLKWFWuaLSFPrmlriGuBUFoojB+m+BgCKtMvfT6tNSDb", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A-1; B-2; C-3; D-4", 
		"option_b": "A-2; B-1; C-4; D-3", 
		"option_c": "A-1; B-2; C-4; D-3", 
		"option_d": "A-2; B-1; C-3; D-4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190172", 
		"question": "24e9b5Dh1RDk8MU0Whuy7PP7IHiQNWMdr3qaEoB9ZnjvXb3DeuTxx9sxJFOHnlJ/92SGt631y10JgKRX5pmWfiVDbZ9u3NWE0urj1ysBc/0WytEjqcsiQPp8wmztXcCbN/99jn6SIkH/ajCzBX5gmCiWizxFrYCu+SapFNk+1hw+n515+cEzMpee16zT/EW9ugiQ2XeYT7RrBEfZsMKt5kaStM54ocWCpDXTtOTrn+vW/spHIgxbu8ZxbE/8k6cE8SQ5Rc2IZgZD9KTDYlHjJRStGwBPue/2xH1nwcI9VWAntA9DkIpZZowz1ZfwqD0+f9prBnOvsEFEh5JzTVebdbOt1mnn9EAtfHQsWYR5uTUhqAOZOxR3lCu1QihYlbxlwt4unQ1gdS9Pmjb0ijrLk3GOaJbu7o7olqj3qa9m/OMmK06WMBzRRcIdd7aAJGhg2OyYGfke+GJ0RndoBNBaCqh2eI2z8A==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzgFnr+YFgAFzg8zjTQ4/C3MLdV1iB1uLE", 
		"explanation": "25ysKIbywln65YAkXRP7y/zxIWfJQ2NRsHqAR691YjHgXbHLYuTkyIN4KFLFzVp19jbSq6Cw5VYDhq9S5puMMCcPe4ZqxsTFl/D/y2RGO4ZUiIVh4ZQLMLRExTntetvPYPphw2eOJlH1Jy21ATBnlzTYjzwb6Lep4CKHWu4/xVUbmINt/ogKPduT3LHTy0SujwqLxnqFQbJqUV2K9cGu/0aS4IE3u96EtTfJ8fC5jveT8ttLY0hBuoVqb1qu16sA7iM0WNK1fBtE/6TSZFfsNTumZxoV/Nnmln16hoNpT2w49QtPlIYWY8Jg05bnuXI/OY1nGj2vrkFO05VwHwWTeLS/2Wfx8xUsYWg+Zp54rigm4QyTJUR/iG6YDDhe1I9/9tUL1QVtfmZFkmKggTadiWmGZpL34o/ylqjEqLBwsqcoLFLAO1PMFoAZZL2AM2932OzbGqdPc5FoVzDjMdwp9Tb3bNaWyi1Nwtg0J3L1tD6Rk9m1MHH6t5v9ztp5AP8EOdzM58qjtRzTaSahIG+QbsLgXAvkWm75305pthYh2yIR+GfkBrVx0Tgfl3C3CVBsmzSgfHmzn7FYpsKNcJol3PusyjMD2OFrmp+30hIuBwm6g2pFs4eLWk5Gw1OWCsgf0AAiCadBHZiR22OSnHeQBjw5bdvzPaakzDhc1e2xmWBu/5kAUYmLKFnOmdsiiBG+E710VGn4rof6KekHA2oruqZ00vmou8+oNfexPmwkaFqjUeoZ2ptVfRE7JwrRCSFWIJunQJQSSPpOxnzFmUdpVXxBBF/D96cPVAerpoTOZ2Taar8bHV7rbbAJBsr9DkLZPPWsxjPMRrCa1USxS1AqQHqeNLwZ7BHxboX9Kl/zknsk7sTpPhFaV8MUMzPne2X5o6KBGQ85bG5cPlR07Xz6CWNeoQWgcxMv", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "Both 1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "Neither 1 nor 2", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190173", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHeCQKJ3ZHTxXb3Hfa2xiZR5Jk6Ijk9+4H/cpuXk/1ZPn61U+YKaTCwMeMtGxtScxKTUzWdIP89em5R765RAPM8SnGz+NJmKHcJg8mDRZ3H4YiD9FH9nhzTFmXlS6ISp8CavFMo2zBQxk5Q47MY4fMOa1Lif7V6EiDqMjjulQLh9UUOWp92g4lOMpYZ4t8KZuXLW9fj82vnd9J4NZwVTs4M/Z161g6EM6xY2bcbnKCZD9P2QZFn9LCe6Igpd8cTxxXEkwpAoSmd09xdHkIpZdtMz35akqzMiOcx4EA+0n0pzwph5XAPWYLW9kGvr8kc6dm5rdp5sqCg4pAGIZ0dqm3+ZQSlfgJMr68MQmwMjaWdF3HXvhjqYvGuIdYXm5cD+gOT/t/vJAIez0ziW6rG0O6wzhwaN", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuq+IssS1zFcTLAp79rBM9JHXd+bJt+", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfjmdXvfEHEUsGyGVuNzYnTiQOfSb+H/ypJiZ12HiRtv93vWr6Djtx5PqalX+oujfhYLe8tu2tOB3vDyx2VUIcMElYYy8JIaPN1OyCi+NOLaLPJr1y6jLlP5azCnBWR9mz+Wg28Wq4u65ya4QN8lyQ83ksd69IgrOduTlLif6UO2gwLC33KFQbh3XRSboNro/0uZsod4vN7Nvz2b8eLwnv3d89tLbQ4SuJR+bV/8h6kF+Sk9Qoi7elJf9OnAbVH+HCaQMw8J/Mbm2GAplNhpaWEx7V9RjZFFasljxp3g/DA/K8UqGDK2pgRByZA8WRKbdbG9kGzh6UE2cGlrKMpZrjgwnQG9Old2m26TQCNWnYNq8pAfnApndGFHjzbzlziMhXabPJKj74nqgPrjqa16sqwhaUWFPEjRU55QJbrOJGtnzuCVCuZPPJJiVzbuPMFu/SnpJZeGny0CkNslb3Hi+SuVl4G1MGu+upH4mt14E/8BdsHK5dKjuFnOcjfoIj2BY8f9XgH/Wm+4wBd2ox0o9C8j/GPMDYR6+zlNzSTwfUxhi2flYWytmadZ7sKGcJwi1rjozzMHlrR7l5rl3RIoVESygz9Us5aZTk5KjRmWOMwL1wwSAoAJEYTUsmSF1XjfC3kbdsrzD6uCgyNOmuv+nHJ48pQcVJuAbBrTi8wvxwOiQfR3FXPlrcbQM/gAGSQa+759z/ThlMOtfP+tNmQ+ZhW5G2vU2Ro+DXkY0d9Op0obzDs=", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 only", 
		"option_c": "1,2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "None of the statements given above is correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190174", 
		"question": "24KxfJmzwxzs8pclXB33henwdX/YBiIVqnmFV7FxfnLmFKXHevr7zJkxM1SMzVhu/mLTsaCw+FUzgZpS7piadCsAPqp90dGHxKT2ynUBGshAj5My0psTcPFZjC2oe8TXJbIu2WaJJE2waD/9EHhxqD/QhXBap5Sy+yD7R8421BA/k4ls/og1L5iey63T60KqlAOByCTRc+80QAPU5POU5X+S8cIKvMqbtDbS97TYiOHS/s1LdxtXu8Zra178lKcI7Go3V4i5aRtHseXeZRTlJSSuIhpd8MXf2GNo1IQoT2x04xdDkIZXcYBn3p2krDc/L8FvVTy8421Ow4FvHyGXeLG9yVTqw1wpfHYif4t5tSI74QuVLBRwlX/cQClQgoUr/94A1QF1dGtFknXlwjCNwHCcdZ3kq5T0gOXMroVtoOMVIEaWMFjRVc09d6rBKXQyweeeGuZbPJNjW2L1NNk4+Su5IZiQnzoCwMklPUvp4yKcgMj0KiWTvZbsnZRAFbMMM8iF+c64oFDCISjvJGrTacX4QEjzQGzo1hwlthYh9C8Z+m3WNIdD+35NrHe3X0FgmySgTW64l7BPqoqPe8413PjpziYZm/Vsmp+3wBU5Bwy0n2xG8pOXSk5KzEfqENkPwRsrTL0SVJjesmiAnHLVRX8IP8HwQYGJxzlbmtXwgm14ptAeUIOeIBybgt8wwRm2PfN7UGLj6IfuPO4QSmsquqZ5w/7htsSyePKoEGsWYSmyVepa59VFYAc7EgTPFyFMdPivWI4JRPIPx2bDmQAIU3dMRVnD/61IWg28r8qIbG/SbKZGTO6oHgR05tmIb55rrfmP6BI=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqq+IssS1wji07jg50EhYK2o3/aFidB", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7AzPrpMG/ZACIwsWaCXLA0ZWLmUOfWZui+yphwMxyGixt283/K46T+8xMHiqRW7JrfeSxDaYp9ztGb0qTgzHRTNsdX2pR64doPeftQwDjte9KbCfBq233AEUT8azykRFN9gjjag2ZXvIq0+2e/Xd53zhom1ot97N45fNaRwOiW/kS8gwiB2TueTv1xAl2Xso6840aR4M94gd+YtA7VwPz82sra98gOZgFR/6dtelqyhOgI6i94Wsa7fxwL5euQaVX7JWi2NAsZucjmxGBoz4xpXHs5+w0Gg41SIsh22pXhqCFwNsMqAjKopUVSwtg8SB+feLj43mek80A8fTouc4NpuSM2pE+VOxR4lX6SSGxYmsB/9tVZvApnaHwAqnfsjjqSwEaGaprv4pr9keH/roVtwbcmPUSNMFLMFt9GJYHJIHF3zuCYTYdOKp5pBGLtM9A5vD72LJLYnyoE3M8lPTun9SSd0s76KXW/odLuhtFkEb4TdvjL7d6k8GrGbS/kOD2DY8TkVQ2wRHL9xE5quRQ8iCIf+HLdGsl++ylNl2y/RwQp0gHhYG+kqrB+5ZaGP5o51rXe1DUGnfBxnNvWxgQ9SRf7jHFH8pCXShxmw1DDDY0xxQUiCa1BBJPe4mGT1X7RTzwGccHhDa2DxCkI1eWxmGBvtp8bRsyDKQ3ahs1qiB6/AvFsUW7jr8b6MuwFD3Zs+7x1iu+zuMShcM+qH3Erex+6XOFNs8YLKDByFh3YAS1MIJm8T5wQUqBH03GKkwhFQmxdDFnN760MHRCir4TAYXjNZvELBhvwZrIWU9rwS1XKdfi6iD7GRrqKnEO7UUcgDjWbYZkD4RLjOrrzKB+2iih0/M71PlQbTIIBNSn0NGm8oK3DChE7bSllJ4wHbk/cWFAlmjfOJvUnwOc0Yg0ofaaTEVVWpBhIiTvWB1sFkV4HXqu+AEQiOKwFK1Ue2jn1F68NHAjCgzMYzkOPx2LjL7pDPlswfnffz1vokp5j3+vhh5yESt3xbbMUko4MJrVXUYnfCV5cn+Xt6+TuEml5CWs3JvfaTeeRtED7B9vgq8Db0VVEx/4BOB8vLTzLoJHd5SktGaRDY3VT/VAQusPeaxyrzYFW2xImUN9I5MNxtgyptBm/XYWc", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190175", 
		"question": "25e9fIb21Beq4I0pURayyvu/IWPVQ2Qer3OMRap6dzH0VbSCeuX7iZZ/JFWMg0875nnRreX/8W8Bu6lQ+oaeYysPf8tjx9OIw+HzmzF6YZYUzL0w1/5lgk9iocJIMsMJTZ/B1w==", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgkRjk88UKWhv+0PC9mt1rOZVbKlG6i+5Fkndlsg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3xrj8os0Egr90vO/Om2QN2MasHeCQat9fHCjQ6bRLv733YJwM1mNzVl+5mHDpquw41sKz7pS/4uNY2IqcI9625CI2eC37nlEP9NJ2rR67YlfdP1T2DK/fdfaLPJ3jn2JIEv5YTC+BX5g1CLfnnkWoZD7/im0Q9R3xhog1o5s/og9L8SQ2qGS/ES3iEaV1W+ZCLxqEl2cu9rowk2YqYM29ciJpDHa4P32lLjS/tpLdQlB/45wbl78g6dJ9yQ9EceyKAZD9KTHbkbhJG+wZwER/c7wwjRiyI0+Uykh+hZQh5FFa9R604umFnbvyYjJrHy9Tl+cm9+SAw==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indus and Jhelum", 
		"option_b": "Jhelum and Chenab", 
		"option_c": "Chenab and Ravi", 
		"option_d": "d) Ravi and Beas", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "190176", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt8IBQAfzy7q/MW7eDHYUsCXDafItKSjeFud6q2ZNrVHrh5dLhNRZBik=", 
		"answer": "27T4e4H21Brit4IyXQvih0ODGUPMZliwJFRRx1FBBdE=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7licwzrxPPDdyvYCnEFrG2KUaJ4fGijRqLEa//szJMxM1PJjBt3+3jBtqzj41oMz6lV7c6cZS4Xa5luxJCOxevi1DFTMtJMn5Iy8JIecrRBwn2oYNzVKf0uwXzANUTzbjixRH96kXH/njxBqZD74DS+UJojz1U2k5R7/8E+OZeL0a3T+Ei3lgqHnGyZR/13AVuSsI6B5UeT7aMqrMyD8T7a+vPsm//W45JLdQBbvI4/Ykm516lJ+jg5X8u8KB1NsfDYZBTELiysaisI68Tz03Vnho4oU24h9RhDwoVXb8l/z9jQtDcjOo1mFD29tkVHwoc8XgWTNLyrw2fn6VQrcH5rcoN5tG0hqQrcHlF6k2jcWClJgJMr/94d1QVtfmZFkmKgqzGPiWSBPJD255Tpl+2wia0k4eMuJFGPJ0jZWJlccbyAKWhmz6mPBadIc4tvEmLyOMcjvAW7AYSN3jcxkpkzJ3jy+C7ZnMLheWe/84fqi9A2ALBAJsPK5MSjtRzOZSbgMj2cYIvmWAv5TnC4wBt1sgosxzMZ/HuUSIhstSQZ3naxWgRmlyLuLHGohatP74bOdoBxx/3pnSIRi+A4mZTllA4pRAz7nWpRoouMSk8NLEyjFmL6OcVLJBP7pGSLXg==", 
		"topic_name": "Ancient History >> Identity of Aryan Culture >> Texts for Traits of Aryan Culture to Dispersal of the IndoAryans", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "an ethnic group", 
		"option_b": "a nomadic people", 
		"option_c": "a speech group", 
		"option_d": "a superior race", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	}
]